{
	"description": "Kanji entries marked as Common in JMdict",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "あだ名", "answers": [ "あだな" ], "comment": "nickname" },
	{ "question": "あっという間", "answers": [ "あっというま" ], "comment": "a blink of time; the time it takes to say \"Ah!\"" },
	{ "question": "あっという間に", "answers": [ "あっというまに" ], "comment": "just like that; in the twinkling of an eye; in the blink of an eye; in the time it takes to say \"ah!\"" },
	{ "question": "あなた方", "answers": [ "あなたがた" ], "comment": "you (plural)" },
	{ "question": "あの世", "answers": [ "あのよ" ], "comment": "the other world; world of the dead; netherworld" },
	{ "question": "あの人", "answers": [ "あのひと" ], "comment": "he; she; that person\nyou" },
	{ "question": "あの方", "answers": [ "あのかた" ], "comment": "that gentleman (lady); he; she" },
	{ "question": "ある意味で", "answers": [ "あるいみで" ], "comment": "in a sense; in some way; to an extent" },
	{ "question": "ある意味では", "answers": [ "あるいみでは" ], "comment": "in a sense; in some way; to an extent" },
	{ "question": "按摩", "answers": [ "あんま" ], "comment": "massage, esp. the Anma Japanese type of massage\nmasseur; masseuse; massager\nblind person (as many were traditionally massagers)" },
	{ "question": "いい加減にしろ", "answers": [ "いいかげんにしろ" ], "comment": "that's enough!; cut it out!; get a life!" },
	{ "question": "いつの間にか", "answers": [ "いつのまにか" ], "comment": "before one knows; before one becomes aware of; unnoticed; unawares" },
	{ "question": "いつも通り", "answers": [ "いつもどおり" ], "comment": "as always; as usual" },
	{ "question": "いつ頃", "answers": [ "いつごろ" ], "comment": "about when; how soon" },
	{ "question": "お一人様", "answers": [ "おひとりさま" ], "comment": "one person; one customer\nunmarried woman (with no children) over the age of 30" },
	{ "question": "お世辞", "answers": [ "おせじ", "おせいじ" ], "comment": "flattery; compliment" },
	{ "question": "お中元", "answers": [ "おちゅうげん" ], "comment": "mid-year gift; summer gift" },
	{ "question": "お久しぶり", "answers": [ "おひさしぶり" ], "comment": "it's been a long time; long time no see" },
	{ "question": "お互いに", "answers": [ "おたがいに" ], "comment": "mutually; with each other; reciprocally; together; both" },
	{ "question": "お代わり", "answers": [ "おかわり" ], "comment": "second helping; another cup; seconds\ncommand to have dog place its second paw in one's hand" },
	{ "question": "お使い", "answers": [ "おつかい" ], "comment": "errand; mission; going as envoy\nmessenger; bearer; errand boy; errand girl\nfamiliar spirit" },
	{ "question": "お兄さん", "answers": [ "おにいさん" ], "comment": "older brother; elder brother\n(vocative) young man; buddy; fella; laddie" },
	{ "question": "お前", "answers": [ "おまえ", "おめえ", "おまい" ], "comment": "you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)\npresence (of a god, nobleman, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "お化け", "answers": [ "おばけ" ], "comment": "goblin; monster; demon\nghost; apparition" },
	{ "question": "お医者さん", "answers": [ "おいしゃさん" ], "comment": "doctor" },
	{ "question": "お参り", "answers": [ "おまいり" ], "comment": "worship; shrine visit" },
	{ "question": "お土産", "answers": [ "おみやげ" ], "comment": "present; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "お坊さん", "answers": [ "おぼうさん" ], "comment": "Buddhist priest; monk\nson (of others)" },
	{ "question": "お大事に", "answers": [ "おだいじに" ], "comment": "take care of yourself; get well soon; God bless you; bless you" },
	{ "question": "お姉さん", "answers": [ "おねえさん" ], "comment": "elder sister\n(vocative) young lady\nmiss (referring to a waitress, etc.)\nma'am (used by geisha to refer to their superiors)\nolder girl (no relation)" },
	{ "question": "お嬢さん", "answers": [ "おじょうさん" ], "comment": "daughter\nyoung lady" },
	{ "question": "お子さま", "answers": [ "おこさま" ], "comment": "child (someone else's)" },
	{ "question": "お子様", "answers": [ "おこさま" ], "comment": "child (someone else's)" },
	{ "question": "お宅", "answers": [ "おたく" ], "comment": "your house; your home; your family\nyour husband\nyour organization\nyou (referring to someone of equal status with whom one is not especially close)" },
	{ "question": "お守り", "answers": [ "おまもり" ], "comment": "charm; amulet" },
	{ "question": "お客さま", "answers": [ "おきゃくさま" ], "comment": "guest; visitor\ncustomer; client; shopper; spectator; audience; tourist; sightseer; passenger" },
	{ "question": "お客様", "answers": [ "おきゃくさま" ], "comment": "guest; visitor\ncustomer; client; shopper; spectator; audience; tourist; sightseer; passenger" },
	{ "question": "お帰り", "answers": [ "おかえり" ], "comment": "return\nwelcome home" },
	{ "question": "お帰りなさい", "answers": [ "おかえりなさい" ], "comment": "welcome home" },
	{ "question": "お年玉", "answers": [ "おとしだま" ], "comment": "New Year's gift (usu. money given to a child by relatives and visitors)" },
	{ "question": "お弁当", "answers": [ "おべんとう" ], "comment": "bento; Japanese box lunch" },
	{ "question": "お手上げ", "answers": [ "おてあげ" ], "comment": "all over; given in; given up hope; bringing to knees; throwing up one's hands" },
	{ "question": "お手伝い", "answers": [ "おてつだい" ], "comment": "maid; helper\nhelp; assistance" },
	{ "question": "お手伝いさん", "answers": [ "おてつだいさん" ], "comment": "maid" },
	{ "question": "お手数", "answers": [ "おてすう", "おてかず" ], "comment": "trouble; bother" },
	{ "question": "お手数ですが", "answers": [ "おてすうですが" ], "comment": "sorry to bother you, but ..." },
	{ "question": "お手洗い", "answers": [ "おてあらい" ], "comment": "toilet; restroom; lavatory; bathroom" },
	{ "question": "お歳暮", "answers": [ "おせいぼ" ], "comment": "year-end gift\nend of the year; year end" },
	{ "question": "お母さん", "answers": [ "おかあさん" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "お気に入り", "answers": [ "おきにいり" ], "comment": "favorite; favourite; pet (e.g. teacher's pet)\nbookmark (in web browser)" },
	{ "question": "お父さん", "answers": [ "おとうさん" ], "comment": "father; dad; papa; pa; pop; daddy; dada" },
	{ "question": "お産", "answers": [ "おさん" ], "comment": "(giving) birth; childbirth; delivery; confinement" },
	{ "question": "お疲れさま", "answers": [ "おつかれさま" ], "comment": "thank you; many thanks; much appreciated\nthat's enough for today" },
	{ "question": "お疲れ様", "answers": [ "おつかれさま" ], "comment": "thank you; many thanks; much appreciated\nthat's enough for today" },
	{ "question": "お礼", "answers": [ "おれい", "おんれい" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude\nmanners; etiquette\nbow\nreward; gift\nceremony; ritual" },
	{ "question": "お祝い", "answers": [ "おいわい" ], "comment": "congratulation; congratulations; celebration; festival; congratulatory gift" },
	{ "question": "お節料理", "answers": [ "おせちりょうり" ], "comment": "food served during the New Year's Holidays" },
	{ "question": "お腹", "answers": [ "おなか" ], "comment": "belly; abdomen; stomach" },
	{ "question": "お腹の子", "answers": [ "おなかのこ" ], "comment": "child one is expecting; child in one's womb" },
	{ "question": "お茶", "answers": [ "おちゃ" ], "comment": "tea (usu. green)\ntea break (at work)\ntea ceremony" },
	{ "question": "お菓子", "answers": [ "おかし" ], "comment": "confections; sweets; candy" },
	{ "question": "お詫び", "answers": [ "おわび" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "お話", "answers": [ "おはなし" ], "comment": "story; tale" },
	{ "question": "お話し", "answers": [ "おはなし" ], "comment": "story; tale" },
	{ "question": "お話し中", "answers": [ "おはなしちゅう" ], "comment": "busy (phone)" },
	{ "question": "お買い得", "answers": [ "おかいどく" ], "comment": "bargain; good buy; budget" },
	{ "question": "お買得", "answers": [ "おかいどく" ], "comment": "bargain; good buy; budget" },
	{ "question": "お辞儀", "answers": [ "おじぎ" ], "comment": "bow; bowing" },
	{ "question": "お返し", "answers": [ "おかえし" ], "comment": "return gift; return favour (favor)\nrevenge\nchange (in a cash transaction)" },
	{ "question": "お金", "answers": [ "おかね" ], "comment": "money" },
	{ "question": "お釣り", "answers": [ "おつり" ], "comment": "change (i.e. money); balance" },
	{ "question": "お願い", "answers": [ "おねがい" ], "comment": "request; wish\nplease" },
	{ "question": "お願いいたします", "answers": [ "おねがいいたします" ], "comment": "please" },
	{ "question": "お願いします", "answers": [ "おねがいします" ], "comment": "please" },
	{ "question": "お願い致します", "answers": [ "おねがいいたします" ], "comment": "please" },
	{ "question": "かき氷", "answers": [ "かきごおり", "カキごおり" ], "comment": "shaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup); Italian ice; Sno-cone; snow cone" },
	{ "question": "か弱い", "answers": [ "かよわい" ], "comment": "frail; feeble" },
	{ "question": "くじ引き", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "怪我人", "answers": [ "けがにん" ], "comment": "wounded person; injured person" },
	{ "question": "この前", "answers": [ "このまえ" ], "comment": "some time ago; recently; lately\nlast (Sunday, etc.); previous" },
	{ "question": "この間", "answers": [ "このかん", "このあいだ" ], "comment": "the other day; lately; recently; during this period\nmeanwhile; in the meantime" },
	{ "question": "この頃", "answers": [ "このごろ" ], "comment": "recently; nowadays; these days; now; at present" },
	{ "question": "ご主人", "answers": [ "ごしゅじん" ], "comment": "your husband; her husband" },
	{ "question": "ご存じ", "answers": [ "ごぞんじ" ], "comment": "knowing\n(an) acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "ご無沙汰", "answers": [ "ごぶさた" ], "comment": "not writing or contacting for a while; neglecting (failing) to write (call, visit, etc.); long silence" },
	{ "question": "ご苦労さま", "answers": [ "ごくろうさま" ], "comment": "thank you very much for your ...; I appreciate your efforts" },
	{ "question": "ご褒美", "answers": [ "ごほうび" ], "comment": "reward; prize" },
	{ "question": "ご覧になる", "answers": [ "ごらんになる" ], "comment": "to see; to look; to watch\ntry to" },
	{ "question": "ご連絡", "answers": [ "ごれんらく" ], "comment": "to contact; to get in touch\ncontacting; getting in touch; communication; (your) call; (your) message" },
	{ "question": "ご遠慮ください", "answers": [ "ごえんりょください" ], "comment": "please refrain from ~ (e.g. smoking, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "ご遠慮下さい", "answers": [ "ごえんりょください" ], "comment": "please refrain from ~ (e.g. smoking, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "ご飯", "answers": [ "ごはん" ], "comment": "cooked rice\nmeal" },
	{ "question": "ご馳走", "answers": [ "ごちそう" ], "comment": "feast; treating (someone)\nto treat (someone, e.g. to a meal)" },
	{ "question": "しきい値", "answers": [ "いきち", "しきいち" ], "comment": "threshold (amount, dose, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "し続ける", "answers": [ "しつづける" ], "comment": "to continue to do; to persist in doing" },
	{ "question": "すき焼", "answers": [ "すきやき" ], "comment": "sukiyaki; thin slices of beef, cooked with various vegetables in a table-top cast-iron pan" },
	{ "question": "すき焼き", "answers": [ "すきやき" ], "comment": "sukiyaki; thin slices of beef, cooked with various vegetables in a table-top cast-iron pan" },
	{ "question": "その上", "answers": [ "そのうえ" ], "comment": "in addition; furthermore\nabove (which); on top of (which)" },
	{ "question": "その他", "answers": [ "そのた", "そのほか" ], "comment": "etc.; otherwise; besides; in addition; the rest; the others; and so forth" },
	{ "question": "その外", "answers": [ "そのほか" ], "comment": "etc.; otherwise; besides; in addition; the rest; the others; and so forth" },
	{ "question": "そよ風", "answers": [ "びふう", "そよかぜ" ], "comment": "gentle breeze; soft wind; breath of air; zephyr" },
	{ "question": "たどり着く", "answers": [ "たどりつく" ], "comment": "to arrive at (after a struggle); to finally reach; to find one's way to; to finally hit on (e.g. an idea)" },
	{ "question": "ため息", "answers": [ "ためいき" ], "comment": "sigh" },
	{ "question": "ちり取", "answers": [ "ちりとり" ], "comment": "dustpan" },
	{ "question": "ちり取り", "answers": [ "ちりとり" ], "comment": "dustpan" },
	{ "question": "ちり紙", "answers": [ "ちりがみ", "ちりし" ], "comment": "tissue paper; toilet paper" },
	{ "question": "つかの間", "answers": [ "つかのま" ], "comment": "moment; brief time; brief; transient" },
	{ "question": "つま先", "answers": [ "つまさき" ], "comment": "toes; tips of the toes; toe of a shoe, sock, etc." },
	{ "question": "できるだけ早く", "answers": [ "できるだけはやく" ], "comment": "as soon as possible" },
	{ "question": "どの辺", "answers": [ "どのへん" ], "comment": "whereabout; about where\nhow much" },
	{ "question": "なんとも言えない", "answers": [ "なんともいえない" ], "comment": "indescribable; inexpressible; unspeakable; indefinable; nobody can tell" },
	{ "question": "にぎり寿司", "answers": [ "にぎりずし" ], "comment": "nigirizushi; hand-formed sushi with a topping of seafood, etc." },
	{ "question": "によって異なる", "answers": [ "によってことなる" ], "comment": "to differ depending on ..." },
	{ "question": "に加えて", "answers": [ "にくわえて" ], "comment": "in addition" },
	{ "question": "に向けて", "answers": [ "にむけて" ], "comment": "towards (a destination); for the purpose of; with the goal of; targeting (a group, a demographic)" },
	{ "question": "に対して", "answers": [ "にたいして" ], "comment": "towards; against; regarding; in contrast with" },
	{ "question": "に対する", "answers": [ "にたいする" ], "comment": "regarding; in; to; towards; with regards to" },
	{ "question": "に従って", "answers": [ "にしたがって" ], "comment": "in accordance with; according to; as X, then Y (e.g. as we age we gain wisdom, as wine matures it becomes more valuable, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "に違いない", "answers": [ "にちがいない" ], "comment": "I am sure; no doubt that; must; must have (done)" },
	{ "question": "に関して", "answers": [ "にかんして" ], "comment": "related to; in relation to" },
	{ "question": "に限って", "answers": [ "にかぎって" ], "comment": "(particularly) when ... (often in phrases like \"the bus just has to be on-time when we are late\"); (only) for ...; if we are restricting the discussion to...; in the particular case of" },
	{ "question": "に際して", "answers": [ "にさいして" ], "comment": "on the occasion of; at the time of" },
	{ "question": "ばい菌", "answers": [ "バイきん", "ばいきん" ], "comment": "germ; germs; bacteria; mold; mould\nsomething harmful; vermin" },
	{ "question": "ひっくり返る", "answers": [ "ひっくりかえる" ], "comment": "to be overturned; to be upset; to topple over; to be reversed; to fall down; to tip over" },
	{ "question": "ひな祭り", "answers": [ "ひなまつり" ], "comment": "Hinamatsuri (March 3rd); Girls' Festival; Dolls' Festival" },
	{ "question": "びしょ濡れ", "answers": [ "びしょぬれ" ], "comment": "sopping wet; sodden; wet to the skin" },
	{ "question": "ぶら下がる", "answers": [ "ぶらさがる" ], "comment": "to hang from; to dangle; to swing" },
	{ "question": "ぶら下げる", "answers": [ "ぶらさげる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend; to dangle; to swing; to carry" },
	{ "question": "みじん切り", "answers": [ "みじんぎり" ], "comment": "finely chopped (cooking)" },
	{ "question": "めぐり合う", "answers": [ "めぐりあう" ], "comment": "to meet fortuitously (e.g. running into an old friend); to meet by chance; to happen across" },
	{ "question": "もう一度", "answers": [ "もういちど" ], "comment": "once more; again" },
	{ "question": "もつ鍋", "answers": [ "もつなべ" ], "comment": "hot pot stew made with offal, vegetables and (often) miso" },
	{ "question": "やむを得ない", "answers": [ "やむをえない" ], "comment": "cannot be helped; unavoidable" },
	{ "question": "やり方", "answers": [ "やりかた" ], "comment": "manner of doing; way; method; means" },
	{ "question": "やり直し", "answers": [ "やりなおし" ], "comment": "redoing" },
	{ "question": "やり直す", "answers": [ "やりなおす" ], "comment": "to do over again; to redo; to start over; to remake; to resume; to recommence" },
	{ "question": "やり過ごす", "answers": [ "やりすごす" ], "comment": "to let something (or somebody) go past\nto do too much" },
	{ "question": "ゆうちょ銀行", "answers": [ "ゆうちょぎんこう" ], "comment": "JP Bank (former Postal Savings Bank, created when the Postal Services were privatized)" },
	{ "question": "よくあるご質問", "answers": [ "よくあるごしつもん" ], "comment": "frequently asked questions; FAQ" },
	{ "question": "よくある質問", "answers": [ "よくあるしつもん" ], "comment": "frequently asked questions; FAQ" },
	{ "question": "よそ行き", "answers": [ "よそいき", "よそゆき" ], "comment": "going out\none's best (clothes, looks, manners, behaviour, etc.)\nformal behaviour (manners, speech, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "よそ見", "answers": [ "よそみ" ], "comment": "looking away; looking aside" },
	{ "question": "アカデミー賞", "answers": [ "アカデミーしょう" ], "comment": "Academy Award" },
	{ "question": "アキレス腱", "answers": [ "アキレスけん" ], "comment": "Achilles tendon; calcaneal tendon\nAchilles' heel; vulnerable point" },
	{ "question": "アミノ酸", "answers": [ "アミノさん" ], "comment": "amino acid" },
	{ "question": "アメリカ人", "answers": [ "アメリカじん" ], "comment": "American person" },
	{ "question": "アメリカ合衆国", "answers": [ "アメリカがっしゅうこく" ], "comment": "United States of America" },
	{ "question": "アルカリ性", "answers": [ "アルカリせい" ], "comment": "alkalinity; alkaline" },
	{ "question": "アルファベット順", "answers": [ "アルファベットじゅん" ], "comment": "alphabetical order" },
	{ "question": "イスラム教", "answers": [ "イスラムきょう" ], "comment": "Islam" },
	{ "question": "ウォール街", "answers": [ "ウォールがい" ], "comment": "Wall Street" },
	{ "question": "エックス線", "answers": [ "エックスせん" ], "comment": "X-ray" },
	{ "question": "エッフェル塔", "answers": [ "エッフェルとう" ], "comment": "Eiffel Tower" },
	{ "question": "オリーブ色", "answers": [ "オリーブいろ", "オリーヴいろ" ], "comment": "olive (colour, color); olive brown" },
	{ "question": "オレンジ色", "answers": [ "オレンジいろ" ], "comment": "orange (colour, color)" },
	{ "question": "オープン戦", "answers": [ "オープンせん" ], "comment": "exhibition game; open game" },
	{ "question": "カスピ海", "answers": [ "カスピかい" ], "comment": "Caspian Sea" },
	{ "question": "カトリック教会", "answers": [ "カトリックきょうかい" ], "comment": "Catholic Church" },
	{ "question": "カリブ海", "answers": [ "カリブかい" ], "comment": "Caribbean Sea" },
	{ "question": "ガラス張り", "answers": [ "ガラスばり" ], "comment": "glass-sided\naboveboard; open to scrutiny" },
	{ "question": "ガラス戸", "answers": [ "ガラスど" ], "comment": "glass door" },
	{ "question": "キリスト教", "answers": [ "キリストきょう", "きりすときょう" ], "comment": "Christianity" },
	{ "question": "クラシック音楽", "answers": [ "クラシックおんがく", "クラッシックおんがく" ], "comment": "classical music" },
	{ "question": "クラブ活動", "answers": [ "クラブかつどう" ], "comment": "club activities (usu. clubs in association with a school); extracurricular activities" },
	{ "question": "グアテマラ共和国", "answers": [ "グアテマラきょうわこく" ], "comment": "Republic of Guatemala" },
	{ "question": "グローバル化", "answers": [ "グローバルか" ], "comment": "globalization" },
	{ "question": "ケーソン工法", "answers": [ "ケーソンこうほう" ], "comment": "caisson method" },
	{ "question": "ケ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "コピー機", "answers": [ "コピーき" ], "comment": "copier; copy machine; photocopier" },
	{ "question": "ゴミ箱", "answers": [ "ごみばこ", "ゴミばこ" ], "comment": "garbage can; garbage box; rubbish bin; trash can; dust bin; dustbin" },
	{ "question": "サイン会", "answers": [ "サインかい" ], "comment": "signing; autograph session" },
	{ "question": "サイン入り", "answers": [ "サインいり" ], "comment": "autographed; signed" },
	{ "question": "サハラ砂漠", "answers": [ "サハラさばく" ], "comment": "Sahara Desert" },
	{ "question": "サービス業", "answers": [ "サービスぎょう" ], "comment": "service industry; service sector" },
	{ "question": "シャボン玉", "answers": [ "シャボンだま", "しゃぼんだま" ], "comment": "soap bubble" },
	{ "question": "シーア派", "answers": [ "シーアは" ], "comment": "Shia (Islam)" },
	{ "question": "ジェット機", "answers": [ "ジェットき" ], "comment": "jet aeroplane; jet airplane" },
	{ "question": "スペイン語", "answers": [ "スペインご" ], "comment": "Spanish (language)" },
	{ "question": "スポーツ新聞", "answers": [ "スポーツしんぶん" ], "comment": "sporting newspaper" },
	{ "question": "スワヒリ語", "answers": [ "スワヒリご" ], "comment": "Swahili (language); Kiswahili" },
	{ "question": "セーラー服", "answers": [ "セーラーふく" ], "comment": "sailor suit; middy uniform" },
	{ "question": "セ氏", "answers": [ "セし" ], "comment": "Centigrade; Celsius" },
	{ "question": "ソ連", "answers": [ "ソれん", "それん" ], "comment": "Soviet Union; Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; USSR" },
	{ "question": "タンパク質", "answers": [ "タンパクしつ", "たんぱくしつ" ], "comment": "protein" },
	{ "question": "ダウ平均株価", "answers": [ "ダウへいきんかぶか" ], "comment": "Dow-Jones average" },
	{ "question": "テレビ局", "answers": [ "テレビきょく" ], "comment": "television station" },
	{ "question": "テレビ番組", "answers": [ "テレビばんぐみ" ], "comment": "television program; tv program" },
	{ "question": "デパ地下", "answers": [ "デパちか" ], "comment": "basement of a department store (where foodstuffs are usually sold)" },
	{ "question": "デボン紀", "answers": [ "デボンき" ], "comment": "Devonian period" },
	{ "question": "デモ隊", "answers": [ "デモたい" ], "comment": "demonstrators" },
	{ "question": "データ通信", "answers": [ "データつうしん" ], "comment": "data communication" },
	{ "question": "ト長調", "answers": [ "トちょうちょう" ], "comment": "G major" },
	{ "question": "ドイツ語", "answers": [ "ドイツご" ], "comment": "German (language)" },
	{ "question": "ドラム缶", "answers": [ "ドラムかん" ], "comment": "drum" },
	{ "question": "ドラ息子", "answers": [ "どらむすこ", "ドラむすこ" ], "comment": "lazy son; profligate son" },
	{ "question": "ドル買い", "answers": [ "ドルかい" ], "comment": "dollar purchase" },
	{ "question": "ノーベル賞", "answers": [ "ノーベルしょう" ], "comment": "Nobel Prize" },
	{ "question": "ハンセン病", "answers": [ "ハンセンびょう" ], "comment": "Hansen's disease; leprosy" },
	{ "question": "バス停", "answers": [ "バスてい" ], "comment": "bus stop" },
	{ "question": "バベルの塔", "answers": [ "バベルのとう" ], "comment": "Tower of Babel" },
	{ "question": "バラ色", "answers": [ "ばらいろ", "バラいろ" ], "comment": "rose-colour; rose-color" },
	{ "question": "バンタム級", "answers": [ "バンタムきゅう" ], "comment": "bantam-weight (boxer)" },
	{ "question": "パン屋", "answers": [ "パンや" ], "comment": "bakery; baker; pastry shop" },
	{ "question": "パン粉", "answers": [ "パンこ" ], "comment": "breadcrumbs; panko\nbread flour" },
	{ "question": "ビー玉", "answers": [ "ビーだま" ], "comment": "marble; glass marble" },
	{ "question": "フライ級", "answers": [ "フライきゅう" ], "comment": "fly-weight (boxer)" },
	{ "question": "フランス料理", "answers": [ "フランスりょうり" ], "comment": "French food" },
	{ "question": "フランス語", "answers": [ "フランスご" ], "comment": "French (language)" },
	{ "question": "ブチ切れ", "answers": [ "ぶちきれ", "ぶちぎれ" ], "comment": "livid" },
	{ "question": "ブラウン管", "answers": [ "ブラウンかん" ], "comment": "cathode-ray tube; CRT; Braun tube" },
	{ "question": "プロ野球", "answers": [ "プロやきゅう" ], "comment": "professional baseball" },
	{ "question": "ベニヤ板", "answers": [ "ベニヤいた" ], "comment": "plywood" },
	{ "question": "ペン先", "answers": [ "ペンさき" ], "comment": "pen nibs" },
	{ "question": "マルクス主義", "answers": [ "マルクスしゅぎ" ], "comment": "Marxism" },
	{ "question": "ミドル級", "answers": [ "ミドルきゅう" ], "comment": "middleweight class" },
	{ "question": "メキシコ湾", "answers": [ "メキシコわん" ], "comment": "Gulf of Mexico" },
	{ "question": "メモ帳", "answers": [ "メモちょう" ], "comment": "memo book; memo pad; notebook; notepad; scratchpad; scratch pad; writing pad; jotter" },
	{ "question": "ユダヤ教", "answers": [ "ユダヤきょう" ], "comment": "Judaism" },
	{ "question": "ラテン語", "answers": [ "らてんご", "ラテンご" ], "comment": "Latin (language)" },
	{ "question": "リーグ戦", "answers": [ "リーグせん" ], "comment": "league match" },
	{ "question": "ロケット弾", "answers": [ "ロケットだん" ], "comment": "rocket" },
	{ "question": "ローマ字", "answers": [ "ローマじ", "ろーまじ" ], "comment": "romaji; romanization; romanisation; transliteration of Japanese in Latin or \"Roman\" letters\nLatin alphabet; Roman alphabet" },
	{ "question": "ヵ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "ヶ国", "answers": [ "かこく" ], "comment": "counter for countries" },
	{ "question": "ヶ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "一", "answers": [ "ひい", "ひ", "ひと", "いち" ], "comment": "one\nbest\nfirst; foremost\nbeginning; start\nbottom string (on a shamisen, etc.) /\n one" },
	{ "question": "一つ", "answers": [ "ひとつ" ], "comment": "one\nfor one thing\nonly\n(not) even\njust (e.g. \"just try it\")" },
	{ "question": "一つ一つ", "answers": [ "ひとつひとつ" ], "comment": "one-by-one; separately; in detail" },
	{ "question": "一ヶ月", "answers": [ "いっかげつ" ], "comment": "one month" },
	{ "question": "一一九番", "answers": [ "ひゃくじゅうきゅうばん" ], "comment": "ambulance and fire brigade emergency tel. no. (in Japan)" },
	{ "question": "一丁", "answers": [ "いっちょう" ], "comment": "one sheet; one page; one leaf\none block of tofu; one serving (in a restaurant)\none long and narrow thing (e.g. guns, scissors, spades, hoes, inksticks, palanquins, candles, jinrikishas, shamisen, oars, etc.)\none cho (unit of distance, 109.09 m)\none game; one task\nwell then; come then" },
	{ "question": "一世", "answers": [ "いっせい" ], "comment": "generation; lifetime\nthe age; the day\nthe First\nissei; first-generation Japanese (or Korean, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "一両", "answers": [ "いちりょう" ], "comment": "one vehicle\none ryou (an old coin)" },
	{ "question": "一丸", "answers": [ "いちがん" ], "comment": "lump; (into) one" },
	{ "question": "一二", "answers": [ "いちに" ], "comment": "the first and second; a few" },
	{ "question": "一人", "answers": [ "いちにん", "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "一人っ子", "answers": [ "ひとりっこ" ], "comment": "(an) only child" },
	{ "question": "一人で", "answers": [ "ひとりで" ], "comment": "alone; by oneself; voluntarily; spontaneously; automatically" },
	{ "question": "一人一人", "answers": [ "ひとりひとり", "ひとりびとり" ], "comment": "one by one; each; one at a time" },
	{ "question": "一人前", "answers": [ "ひとりまえ", "いちにんまえ" ], "comment": "one portion; one serving; one person\nadult; grown-up; person who has come of age\nfully fledged; established; qualified" },
	{ "question": "一人娘", "answers": [ "ひとりむすめ" ], "comment": "only daughter" },
	{ "question": "一人息子", "answers": [ "ひとりむすこ" ], "comment": "only son" },
	{ "question": "一人暮らし", "answers": [ "ひとりぐらし" ], "comment": "a single life; a solitary life; living alone" },
	{ "question": "一人物", "answers": [ "いちじんぶつ" ], "comment": "person to be reckoned with; person of importance\none person; one character; someone" },
	{ "question": "一介", "answers": [ "いっかい" ], "comment": "mere; only a ..." },
	{ "question": "一代", "answers": [ "いちだい" ], "comment": "generation; lifetime; age" },
	{ "question": "一件", "answers": [ "いっけん" ], "comment": "(one) matter; (one) item; (one) case" },
	{ "question": "一任", "answers": [ "いちにん" ], "comment": "entrusting" },
	{ "question": "一休み", "answers": [ "ひとやすみ" ], "comment": "(short) rest; breather; break" },
	{ "question": "一体", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "...the heck (e.g. \"what the heck?\"); ...in the world (e.g. \"why in the world?\"); ...on earth (e.g. \"who on earth?\")\none object; one body; unity\none form; one style\none Buddhist image (or carving, etc.)\ngenerally; in general" },
	{ "question": "一例", "answers": [ "いちれい" ], "comment": "example; an instance" },
	{ "question": "一個", "answers": [ "いっこ" ], "comment": "piece; fragment; one (object)" },
	{ "question": "一億", "answers": [ "いちおく" ], "comment": "100,000,000; one hundred million" },
	{ "question": "一元", "answers": [ "いちげん" ], "comment": "unitary" },
	{ "question": "一元化", "answers": [ "いちげんか" ], "comment": "unification; centralization; centralisation" },
	{ "question": "一党", "answers": [ "いっとう" ], "comment": "party; clique" },
	{ "question": "一円", "answers": [ "いちえん" ], "comment": "one yen\nthroughout (an area); whole district" },
	{ "question": "一分", "answers": [ "いちぶ" ], "comment": "one tenth; one hundredth; one percent; one tenth of a sun; one quarter ryou (an old coin)" },
	{ "question": "一切", "answers": [ "いっさい" ], "comment": "all; everything; the whole; lock, stock, and barrel\nabsolutely not (with negative); without exception; entirely not" },
	{ "question": "一刻", "answers": [ "いっこく" ], "comment": "minute; moment; an instant\nstubborn; hot-headed" },
	{ "question": "一助", "answers": [ "いちじょ" ], "comment": "help; assistance" },
	{ "question": "一千", "answers": [ "いっせん" ], "comment": "1,000; one thousand" },
	{ "question": "一口", "answers": [ "ひとくち" ], "comment": "mouthful; morsel; bite\ngulp; sip; draft; draught\none word; in short\none share; one contribution" },
	{ "question": "一同", "answers": [ "いちどう" ], "comment": "all present; all concerned; all of us" },
	{ "question": "一向", "answers": [ "いっこう" ], "comment": "completely; absolutely; totally\n(not) at all; (not) a bit; (not) in the least\nearnestly; intently; determinedly\nJōdo Shinshū" },
	{ "question": "一向に", "answers": [ "いっこうに" ], "comment": "completely; absolutely; totally\n(not) at all; (not) a bit; (not) in the least\nearnestly; intently; determinedly" },
	{ "question": "一周", "answers": [ "いっしゅう" ], "comment": "a round; a circuit; a revolution; a lap; a turn" },
	{ "question": "一周年", "answers": [ "いっしゅうねん" ], "comment": "one full year" },
	{ "question": "一味違う", "answers": [ "ひとあじちがう" ], "comment": "to be somewhat different (from before, from others, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "一品", "answers": [ "ひとしな", "いっぴん" ], "comment": "item; article\ndish; course" },
	{ "question": "一員", "answers": [ "いちいん" ], "comment": "person; member" },
	{ "question": "一問", "answers": [ "いちもん" ], "comment": "one question" },
	{ "question": "一回", "answers": [ "いっかい" ], "comment": "once; one time; one round; one game; one bout; one heat; one inning" },
	{ "question": "一回り", "answers": [ "ひとまわり" ], "comment": "one turn; one round\n(a) size\nto go around; to make a circuit; to take a turn\ntwelve years; one cycle of the Chinese zodiac" },
	{ "question": "一因", "answers": [ "いちいん" ], "comment": "cause" },
	{ "question": "一団", "answers": [ "いちだん" ], "comment": "body; group; party; gang; troupe; troop" },
	{ "question": "一国", "answers": [ "いっこく" ], "comment": "whole country\nhotheaded; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "一堂", "answers": [ "いちどう" ], "comment": "one building (hall, temple, shrine, room)\nsame room; same place; same building" },
	{ "question": "一塁", "answers": [ "いちるい" ], "comment": "first base\nfirst baseman\none fort" },
	{ "question": "一変", "answers": [ "いっぺん" ], "comment": "complete change; about-face" },
	{ "question": "一夜", "answers": [ "いちや", "ひとよ", "ひとや" ], "comment": "one night; all night; overnight; one evening" },
	{ "question": "一大", "answers": [ "いちだい" ], "comment": "one large ...; a great ..." },
	{ "question": "一女", "answers": [ "いちじょ" ], "comment": "one daughter\neldest daughter; first-born daughter" },
	{ "question": "一字", "answers": [ "いちじ" ], "comment": "letter; character" },
	{ "question": "一定", "answers": [ "いってい", "いちじょう" ], "comment": "fixed; settled; constant; definite; uniform; regularized; regularised; defined; standardized; standardised; certain; prescribed" },
	{ "question": "一室", "answers": [ "いっしつ" ], "comment": "one room" },
	{ "question": "一家", "answers": [ "いっか", "いっけ" ], "comment": "a house; a home; a family; a household; one's family; one's folks; a style" },
	{ "question": "一審", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "first instance; first trial" },
	{ "question": "一対一", "answers": [ "いったいいち", "いちたいいち" ], "comment": "one-to-one; one-on-one" },
	{ "question": "一局", "answers": [ "いっきょく" ], "comment": "one game (checkers, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "一層", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "much more; still more; all the more; more than ever\nsingle layer (or storey, etc.)\nrather; sooner; preferably" },
	{ "question": "一帯", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "region; zone; whole place" },
	{ "question": "一幕", "answers": [ "ひとまく" ], "comment": "one act" },
	{ "question": "一年中", "answers": [ "いちねんじゅう", "いちねんぢゅう" ], "comment": "all year round" },
	{ "question": "一年生", "answers": [ "いちねんせい" ], "comment": "annual (plant)\nfirst-year student" },
	{ "question": "一度", "answers": [ "ひとたび", "いちど" ], "comment": "once; one time; on one occasion\ntemporarily; for a moment\none degree; one tone; one musical interval" },
	{ "question": "一度に", "answers": [ "いちどに" ], "comment": "all at once" },
	{ "question": "一座", "answers": [ "いちざ" ], "comment": "party; those present; troupe\nfirst seat" },
	{ "question": "一式", "answers": [ "いっしき" ], "comment": "complete set; all; everything" },
	{ "question": "一律", "answers": [ "いちりつ" ], "comment": "uniform; even; across-the-board; equal" },
	{ "question": "一心", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "one mind\nwholeheartedness; one's whole heart" },
	{ "question": "一心に", "answers": [ "いっしんに" ], "comment": "wholeheartedly; single-mindedly; fervently; intently" },
	{ "question": "一応", "answers": [ "いちおう" ], "comment": "more or less; though not quite satisfactorily; after a fashion; pretty much; roughly; so far as it goes\ntentatively; for the time being\njust in case\nonce" },
	{ "question": "一戦", "answers": [ "いっせん" ], "comment": "battle; game; bout" },
	{ "question": "一戸建て", "answers": [ "いっこだて" ], "comment": "detached house; stand-alone house; single-family home" },
	{ "question": "一手", "answers": [ "いって" ], "comment": "move (in game); method; single-handed; monopoly" },
	{ "question": "一打", "answers": [ "いちだ" ], "comment": "stroke; blow" },
	{ "question": "一括", "answers": [ "いっかつ" ], "comment": "all together; batch; one lump; one bundle; summing up" },
	{ "question": "一挙", "answers": [ "いっきょ" ], "comment": "one effort; one action" },
	{ "question": "一挙に", "answers": [ "いっきょに" ], "comment": "at a stroke; with a single swoop" },
	{ "question": "一掃", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "clean sweep; purging; doing away with; eradication" },
	{ "question": "一握り", "answers": [ "ひとにぎり" ], "comment": "handful; small handful" },
	{ "question": "一敗", "answers": [ "いっぱい" ], "comment": "one defeat" },
	{ "question": "一文", "answers": [ "いちもん" ], "comment": "something insignificant; one mon (10th sen)" },
	{ "question": "一斉", "answers": [ "いっせい" ], "comment": "simultaneous; all at once" },
	{ "question": "一斉に", "answers": [ "いっせいに" ], "comment": "simultaneously; all at once; in unison" },
	{ "question": "一新", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "complete change; reform; restoration; remodeling; remodelling; renewal" },
	{ "question": "一方", "answers": [ "いっぽう" ], "comment": "one (esp. of two); the other; one way; the other way; one direction; the other direction; one side; the other side; one party; the other party\non the one hand; on the other hand\nwhereas; although; but at the same time; meanwhile; in turn\njust keeps; being inclined to ...; tending to be ...; tending to do ...; continuously ...; just keeps on ...ing; only" },
	{ "question": "一方的", "answers": [ "いっぽうてき" ], "comment": "one-sided; unilateral; arbitrary" },
	{ "question": "一方通行", "answers": [ "いっぽうつうこう" ], "comment": "one-way traffic" },
	{ "question": "一族", "answers": [ "いちぞく" ], "comment": "family; relatives; dependents\nhousehold" },
	{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "ついたち", "いちにち", "さくじつ", "いちじつ", "いっぴ" ], "comment": "one day\nfirst day of the month /\n first day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month" },
	{ "question": "一日中", "answers": [ "いちにちじゅう", "いちにちぢゅう" ], "comment": "all day long; all the day; throughout the day" },
	{ "question": "一昔", "answers": [ "ひとむかし" ], "comment": "ages; long time; decade; the past ten years" },
	{ "question": "一昨年", "answers": [ "いっさくねん", "おととし" ], "comment": "year before last" },
	{ "question": "一昨日", "answers": [ "おとつい", "いっさくじつ", "おととい" ], "comment": "day before yesterday" },
	{ "question": "一時", "answers": [ "いちじ" ], "comment": "one o'clock\nonce; at one time; formerly; before\nfor a time; for a while; for the time being; for the present; for the moment; temporarily\na time; one time; once" },
	{ "question": "一時期", "answers": [ "いちじき" ], "comment": "a period (of time)" },
	{ "question": "一時的", "answers": [ "いちじてき" ], "comment": "temporary" },
	{ "question": "一時金", "answers": [ "いちじきん" ], "comment": "lump sum; bonus; one-off payment" },
	{ "question": "一時間", "answers": [ "いちじかん" ], "comment": "one hour" },
	{ "question": "一晩", "answers": [ "ひとばん" ], "comment": "one night; one evening\nall night; overnight" },
	{ "question": "一晩中", "answers": [ "ひとばんじゅう" ], "comment": "all night long; all through the night" },
	{ "question": "一曲", "answers": [ "いっきょく" ], "comment": "tune (melody, piece of music)" },
	{ "question": "一月", "answers": [ "いちがつ", "ひとつき" ], "comment": "January\none month" },
	{ "question": "一期", "answers": [ "いちご" ], "comment": "one's life time; lifetime" },
	{ "question": "一本", "answers": [ "いっぽん" ], "comment": "one long cylindrical thing; one film, TV show, etc.; one goal, home run, etc.; one telephone call\none version\none book; a certain book\nippon; one point; a blow\nexperienced geisha\nsingle-minded focus on ..." },
	{ "question": "一条", "answers": [ "いちじょう" ], "comment": "one long straight object; streak; beam; ray (of light); wisp (of smoke)\none item (in an itemized form); one clause; one passage (in a book)\none matter (affair, event, case, incident)\nthe same logic; the same reason" },
	{ "question": "一枚", "answers": [ "いちまい" ], "comment": "one thin flat object; one sheet" },
	{ "question": "一枚岩", "answers": [ "いちまいいわ" ], "comment": "monolith; large slab of rock" },
	{ "question": "一校", "answers": [ "いっこう" ], "comment": "whole school; the first proof; one proofreading" },
	{ "question": "一概に", "answers": [ "いちがいに" ], "comment": "unconditionally; as a rule" },
	{ "question": "一様", "answers": [ "いちよう" ], "comment": "uniformity; evenness; similarity; equality; impartiality; homogeneity" },
	{ "question": "一歩", "answers": [ "いっぽ" ], "comment": "(a) step\nlevel; stage\nsmall degree; small amount" },
	{ "question": "一段", "answers": [ "いちだん" ], "comment": "more; much more; still more; all the more\nstep; rung; level; rank\nparagraph; passage\nichidan (verb, verb conjugation)" },
	{ "question": "一段落", "answers": [ "いちだんらく", "ひとだんらく" ], "comment": "completing the first stage; reaching a point where one can pause" },
	{ "question": "一気", "answers": [ "いっき" ], "comment": "chug!; drink! (said repeatedly as a party cheer)" },
	{ "question": "一気に", "answers": [ "いっきに" ], "comment": "in one go; in one gulp; in one breath; without stopping; without pausing; without resting; in one sitting; at a stretch; all at once\nimmediately; instantly; right away; straight away; straightaway" },
	{ "question": "一泊", "answers": [ "いっぱく" ], "comment": "stopping one night" },
	{ "question": "一派", "answers": [ "いっぱ" ], "comment": "school; sect; party" },
	{ "question": "一流", "answers": [ "いちりゅう" ], "comment": "first-class; top grade; foremost; top-notch; leading\ncharacteristic; peculiar; unique\nschool (e.g. of a performance art)\none flag; one banner; one streamer" },
	{ "question": "一点", "answers": [ "いってん" ], "comment": "speck; dot; point; only a little; particle; only one" },
	{ "question": "一環", "answers": [ "いっかん" ], "comment": "link (e.g. a part of a larger plan)" },
	{ "question": "一生", "answers": [ "いっしょう" ], "comment": "whole life; a lifetime; all through life; one existence; a generation; an age; the whole world; the era\n(the only, the greatest, etc.) of one's life" },
	{ "question": "一生懸命", "answers": [ "いっしょうけんめい" ], "comment": "very hard; with utmost effort; with all one's might; for dear life" },
	{ "question": "一男", "answers": [ "いちなん" ], "comment": "boy; eldest son" },
	{ "question": "一番", "answers": [ "いちばん" ], "comment": "number one; first; first place\nbest; most\ngame; round; bout\nas a test; as an experiment; by way of experiment; by way of trial; tentatively\nsong (e.g. in noh); piece" },
	{ "question": "一番乗り", "answers": [ "いちばんのり" ], "comment": "leader of a charge; first to arrive" },
	{ "question": "一番手", "answers": [ "いちばんて" ], "comment": "first player; first worker" },
	{ "question": "一発", "answers": [ "いっぱつ" ], "comment": "shot; charge; explosion\nblow; punch\nhome run\ntry; attempt" },
	{ "question": "一目", "answers": [ "ひとめ" ], "comment": "glance; look; glimpse\ncomplete view; bird's-eye view" },
	{ "question": "一直線", "answers": [ "いっちょくせん" ], "comment": "straight line" },
	{ "question": "一着", "answers": [ "いっちゃく" ], "comment": "first arrival; first in race\nsuit of clothes" },
	{ "question": "一瞬", "answers": [ "いっしゅん" ], "comment": "instant; moment; for an instant" },
	{ "question": "一石", "answers": [ "いっせき" ], "comment": "one game (of go)" },
	{ "question": "一石二鳥", "answers": [ "いっせきにちょう" ], "comment": "killing two birds with one stone" },
	{ "question": "一票", "answers": [ "いっぴょう" ], "comment": "ballot; vote" },
	{ "question": "一種", "answers": [ "ひとくさ", "いっしゅ" ], "comment": "species; kind; variety" },
	{ "question": "一端", "answers": [ "いったん" ], "comment": "one end; an end\npart; fragment" },
	{ "question": "一筋", "answers": [ "ひとすじ" ], "comment": "one long straight object (e.g. strand of hair, beam of light, wisp of smoke)\na single bloodline\nearnest; resolute; intent; devoted\nordinary; common" },
	{ "question": "一節", "answers": [ "いっせつ", "ひとふし" ], "comment": "a verse (e.g. in the Bible); stanza; paragraph; passage; a joint; section; a tune; note; strain; measure" },
	{ "question": "一級", "answers": [ "いっきゅう" ], "comment": "one grade; first-class; primary" },
	{ "question": "一緒", "answers": [ "いっしょ" ], "comment": "together\nat the same time\nsame; identical" },
	{ "question": "一緒に", "answers": [ "いっしょに" ], "comment": "together (with); at the same time; in a lump" },
	{ "question": "一線", "answers": [ "いっせん" ], "comment": "line" },
	{ "question": "一義", "answers": [ "いちぎ" ], "comment": "reason; principle; meaning\nfirst meaning; first principle; first consideration" },
	{ "question": "一翼", "answers": [ "いちよく" ], "comment": "wing; one wing\nrole; part" },
	{ "question": "一致", "answers": [ "いっち" ], "comment": "coincidence; agreement; union; match\nconformity; consistency\ncooperation" },
	{ "question": "一般", "answers": [ "いっぱん" ], "comment": "general; universal\nordinary; average; common" },
	{ "question": "一般に", "answers": [ "いっぱんに" ], "comment": "in general; generally" },
	{ "question": "一般的", "answers": [ "いっぱんてき" ], "comment": "popular; typical; general" },
	{ "question": "一色", "answers": [ "いっしょく", "ひといろ", "いっしき" ], "comment": "one color; one colour; one article; monochrome\nsame tendency; everyone being caught up in the same thing" },
	{ "question": "一行", "answers": [ "いっこう", "いちぎょう" ], "comment": "line; row; troupe; party" },
	{ "question": "一見", "answers": [ "いっけん" ], "comment": "look; glimpse; glance\napparently; seemingly\nfirst meeting" },
	{ "question": "一覧", "answers": [ "いちらん" ], "comment": "look; glance; sight; inspection\nsummary; list; table; catalog; catalogue" },
	{ "question": "一覧表", "answers": [ "いちらんひょう" ], "comment": "list; table; schedule; catalogue; catalog" },
	{ "question": "一言", "answers": [ "いちげん", "いちごん", "ひとこと" ], "comment": "single word; a few words; brief comment" },
	{ "question": "一貫", "answers": [ "いっかん" ], "comment": "consistency; coherence; integration\none kan (approx. 3.75 kg, 8.3 lb)\none piece of sushi" },
	{ "question": "一足", "answers": [ "いっそく", "ひとあし" ], "comment": "pair (footwear) /\n step\nshort distance; short time" },
	{ "question": "一躍", "answers": [ "いちやく" ], "comment": "suddenly (rising to fame, etc.); instantly; immediately; overnight\none bound; one leap" },
	{ "question": "一身", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "oneself; one's own interests; throughout the body" },
	{ "question": "一軍", "answers": [ "いちぐん" ], "comment": "one army; whole army\nfirst string players" },
	{ "question": "一辺倒", "answers": [ "いっぺんとう" ], "comment": "complete devotion to one side" },
	{ "question": "一途", "answers": [ "いちず" ], "comment": "wholehearted; earnest" },
	{ "question": "一通", "answers": [ "いっつう" ], "comment": "one copy (of a document); one letter\none-way traffic\npure straight; winning hand containing nine consecutive tiles of the same suit (i.e. 1-9)" },
	{ "question": "一通り", "answers": [ "ひととおり" ], "comment": "(in) general; broad (e.g. knowledge); the basics\nordinary; usual; common\nbriefly; roughly\none method" },
	{ "question": "一連", "answers": [ "いちれん" ], "comment": "series; chain; sequence\ntwo reams (i.e. 1000 sheets of paper)\nverse; stanza" },
	{ "question": "一週間", "answers": [ "いっしゅうかん" ], "comment": "one week" },
	{ "question": "一過", "answers": [ "いっか" ], "comment": "passing away" },
	{ "question": "一部", "answers": [ "いちぶ" ], "comment": "one part; one portion; one section; some\none copy (e.g. of a document)" },
	{ "question": "一部分", "answers": [ "いちぶぶん" ], "comment": "part; portion; section" },
	{ "question": "一酸化炭素", "answers": [ "いっさんかたんそ" ], "comment": "carbon monoxide" },
	{ "question": "一重", "answers": [ "ひとえ" ], "comment": "one layer; single; onefold" },
	{ "question": "一門", "answers": [ "いちもん" ], "comment": "family; clan; kin\nsect; school; adherents; followers; disciples\ngroup of related sumo stables" },
	{ "question": "一階", "answers": [ "いっかい" ], "comment": "one floor; first floor" },
	{ "question": "一面", "answers": [ "いちめん" ], "comment": "one face; one surface\nthe whole surface\none aspect; one side\n(on) the other hand\none broad, flat object\nfront page (e.g. newspaper)" },
	{ "question": "一風", "answers": [ "いっぷう" ], "comment": "oddity; eccentricity; peculiarity" },
	{ "question": "一首", "answers": [ "いっしゅ" ], "comment": "tanka; poem" },
	{ "question": "一騎打ち", "answers": [ "いっきうち" ], "comment": "personal combat; one-to-one fight" },
	{ "question": "丁寧", "answers": [ "ていねい" ], "comment": "polite; courteous; civil\ncareful; close; thorough; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "丁目", "answers": [ "ちょうめ" ], "comment": "district of a town; city block (of irregular size)" },
	{ "question": "丁重", "answers": [ "ていちょう" ], "comment": "polite; courteous; hospitable" },
	{ "question": "七", "answers": [ "な", "なな", "しち" ], "comment": "seven\nhepta-" },
	{ "question": "七つ", "answers": [ "ななつ" ], "comment": "seven" },
	{ "question": "七十", "answers": [ "しちじゅう", "ななじゅう" ], "comment": "seventy" },
	{ "question": "七夕", "answers": [ "しちせき", "たなばた" ], "comment": "Star Festival (held in July or August); Tanabata; Festival of the Weaver" },
	{ "question": "七日", "answers": [ "なのか", "なぬか" ], "comment": "the seventh day of the month\nseven days" },
	{ "question": "七月", "answers": [ "しちがつ" ], "comment": "July" },
	{ "question": "万", "answers": [ "まん", "よろず" ], "comment": "10,000; ten thousand\nmyriad\neverything; all\nvarious" },
	{ "question": "万が一", "answers": [ "まんがいつ", "まんがいち" ], "comment": "if by any chance; just in case; in the worst case; in the unlikely event that; 10000 to 1" },
	{ "question": "万一", "answers": [ "まんいち" ], "comment": "emergency; unlikely event\nby some chance; by some possibility" },
	{ "question": "万事", "answers": [ "ばんじ" ], "comment": "all; everything" },
	{ "question": "万人", "answers": [ "ばんにん", "ばんじん", "まんにん" ], "comment": "all people; everybody\nten thousand people" },
	{ "question": "万全", "answers": [ "ばんぜん" ], "comment": "perfection; flawlessness" },
	{ "question": "万国", "answers": [ "ばんこく" ], "comment": "all countries; the whole world; universal; all nations" },
	{ "question": "万年", "answers": [ "まんねん" ], "comment": "ten thousand years\neternity" },
	{ "question": "万年筆", "answers": [ "まんねんひつ", "まんねんふで", "まんねんぴつ" ], "comment": "fountain pen" },
	{ "question": "万引", "answers": [ "まんびき" ], "comment": "shoplifting; shoplifter" },
	{ "question": "万引き", "answers": [ "まんびき" ], "comment": "shoplifting; shoplifter" },
	{ "question": "万歳", "answers": [ "ばんざい", "ばんぜい", "まんざい" ], "comment": "door-to-door comedic duo /\n crying \"banzai\" (or raising one's hands in the banzai gesture)\nsomething worthy of celebration\ngiving up\nlong time\neternal life (and prosperity)\nbanzai (a celebratory cheer); hurrah (hooray, hurray)" },
	{ "question": "万能", "answers": [ "まんのう", "ばんのう" ], "comment": "all-purpose; utility\nalmighty; omnipotent" },
	{ "question": "万里", "answers": [ "ばんり" ], "comment": "thousands of miles" },
	{ "question": "丈", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "height; stature\nlength (esp. of clothing)\nall (one has); everything\nmagnificence (of a waka poem, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "丈夫", "answers": [ "じょうぶ" ], "comment": "healthy; robust; strong; solid; durable" },
	{ "question": "三", "answers": [ "み", "さん" ], "comment": "three\ntri-" },
	{ "question": "三つ", "answers": [ "みつ", "みっつ" ], "comment": "three" },
	{ "question": "三人", "answers": [ "さんにん", "みたり" ], "comment": "three people" },
	{ "question": "三代", "answers": [ "さんだい" ], "comment": "three generations; three periods\nthird generation" },
	{ "question": "三冠馬", "answers": [ "さんかんば" ], "comment": "winner of Japan's three main horse races" },
	{ "question": "三十", "answers": [ "さんじゅう" ], "comment": "thirty" },
	{ "question": "三十八度線", "answers": [ "さんじゅうはちどせん" ], "comment": "the Thirty-eighth Parallel" },
	{ "question": "三千", "answers": [ "さんぜん" ], "comment": "3000\nmany" },
	{ "question": "三味線", "answers": [ "しゃみせん", "さみせん" ], "comment": "shamisen; samisen; three-stringed Japanese lute" },
	{ "question": "三国", "answers": [ "さんごく" ], "comment": "three countries\nJapan, China & India; Japan, Korea & China; all the world\nThree Kingdoms (of ancient China: Wei, Shu, Wu)" },
	{ "question": "三塁", "answers": [ "さんるい" ], "comment": "third base" },
	{ "question": "三塁手", "answers": [ "さんるいしゅ" ], "comment": "third baseman" },
	{ "question": "三塁打", "answers": [ "さんるいだ" ], "comment": "three-base hit; triple" },
	{ "question": "三女", "answers": [ "さんじょ" ], "comment": "third daughter" },
	{ "question": "三度", "answers": [ "みたび", "さんど" ], "comment": "three times; thrice\nthird (musical interval)\nseveral times; often; frequently" },
	{ "question": "三役", "answers": [ "さんやく" ], "comment": "three highest ranks (wrestling, unions, etc.)\nthree parts; three divisions" },
	{ "question": "三振", "answers": [ "さんしん" ], "comment": "strikeout; strike out; fanning out" },
	{ "question": "三方", "answers": [ "さんぽう", "さんぼう" ], "comment": "three sides\nsmall offering stand" },
	{ "question": "三日", "answers": [ "みっか" ], "comment": "the third day of the month\nthree days" },
	{ "question": "三日月", "answers": [ "みかづき" ], "comment": "new moon; crescent moon" },
	{ "question": "三時", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "3 o'clock\n3 o'clock snack" },
	{ "question": "三月", "answers": [ "さんがつ" ], "comment": "March" },
	{ "question": "三本", "answers": [ "さんぼん" ], "comment": "three (long cylindrical things)" },
	{ "question": "三枚", "answers": [ "さんまい" ], "comment": "three flat objects (e.g. tickets, pieces of cloth, etc.)\nfilleting (a fish)" },
	{ "question": "三権", "answers": [ "さんけん" ], "comment": "the three powers of government (legislative, executive and judicial)" },
	{ "question": "三次", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "three times; cubic" },
	{ "question": "三流", "answers": [ "さんりゅう" ], "comment": "third-rate; third-class" },
	{ "question": "三男", "answers": [ "さんなん" ], "comment": "three sons\nthird son" },
	{ "question": "三百", "answers": [ "さんびゃく" ], "comment": "300; three hundred\n300 mon; trifling amount; two-bit item\nshyster" },
	{ "question": "三省", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "frequent reflection (meditation)" },
	{ "question": "三種", "answers": [ "さんしゅ" ], "comment": "three kinds; three varieties" },
	{ "question": "三者", "answers": [ "さんしゃ" ], "comment": "three persons; three parties" },
	{ "question": "三角", "answers": [ "さんかく" ], "comment": "triangle; triangular" },
	{ "question": "三角形", "answers": [ "さんかっけい", "さんかくけい" ], "comment": "triangle" },
	{ "question": "三輪", "answers": [ "さんりん" ], "comment": "three wheels" },
	{ "question": "三選", "answers": [ "さんせん" ], "comment": "third-term election" },
	{ "question": "三部", "answers": [ "さんぶ" ], "comment": "three parts; three copies" },
	{ "question": "三部作", "answers": [ "さんぶさく" ], "comment": "trilogy" },
	{ "question": "三重", "answers": [ "さんじゅう", "みえ" ], "comment": "triple; treble; threefold; three-ply; triplicate" },
	{ "question": "上", "answers": [ "うえ", "じょう", "かみ" ], "comment": "above; up; over; elder (e.g. daughter)\ntop; summit\nsurface; on\nbefore; previous\nsuperiority; one's superior (i.e. one's elder)\non top of that; besides; what's more\nupon (further inspection, etc.); based on (and occurring after)\nmatters concerning...; as concerns ...\nsince (i.e. \"for that reason\")\nsuffix indicating higher social standing\nplace of one's superior (i.e. the throne)\nemperor; sovereign; shogun; daimyo\nnoblewoman (esp. the wife of a nobleman) /\n upper reaches (of a river); upper stream\ntop; upper part; upper half (of the body)\nlong ago\nbeginning; first\nperson of high rank (e.g. the emperor)\ngovernment; imperial court\nimperial capital (i.e. Kyoto); capital region (i.e. Kansai); region (or direction of) the imperial palace\nhead (of a table)\nwife; mistress (of a restaurant) /\n from the standpoint of; as a matter of (e.g. fact); in the field of; being of the type of\naboard (a ship or vehicle); on top of; on; above\nfirst volume (e.g. book)\nsuperior quality; best; top; high class\ngoing up\ngovernmental; imperial\npresenting; showing\nana- (medical, biol.)" },
	{ "question": "上々", "answers": [ "じょうじょう" ], "comment": "the very best; excellent; superb" },
	{ "question": "上がったり", "answers": [ "あがったり" ], "comment": "doomed (business, trade, etc.); in a bad state; poor" },
	{ "question": "上がり", "answers": [ "あがり" ], "comment": "rise; increase; ascent\nincome; proceeds; return; profit; crop yield\nfreshly-drawn green tea (esp. in sushi shops)\ncompletion; stop; finish\nend result (e.g. of crafts like painting, pottery, etc.); how something comes out\nafter (rain, illness, etc.)\nex- (e.g. ex-bureaucrat)" },
	{ "question": "上がる", "answers": [ "あがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be arrested\nto turn up (of evidence, etc.)\nto be deep fried\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion" },
	{ "question": "上げ", "answers": [ "あげ" ], "comment": "tuck (e.g. in a dress)\nrise (e.g. in price)" },
	{ "question": "上せる", "answers": [ "のぼせる" ], "comment": "to raise; to record; to bring up (a matter); to serve (food); to send some on out" },
	{ "question": "上っ調子", "answers": [ "うわっちょうし" ], "comment": "flippant; frivolous; shallow" },
	{ "question": "上り", "answers": [ "のぼり" ], "comment": "ascent; climbing; ascending (path); climb\nup-train (e.g. going to Tokyo)\nnorthward (towards Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "上る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "上下", "answers": [ "うえした", "じょうげ" ], "comment": "top and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\nupside-down /\n top and bottom; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends; up and down\ngoing up and down; rising and falling; fluctuating\ngoing and coming back\nupper and lower classes; ruler and ruled; the government and the people\nfirst and second volumes" },
	{ "question": "上乗せ", "answers": [ "うわのせ" ], "comment": "adding; addition; extra" },
	{ "question": "上京", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "上位", "answers": [ "じょうい" ], "comment": "superior (in rank); top; ranking\nhigher order (e.g. byte)\nhost computer (of connected device)" },
	{ "question": "上体", "answers": [ "じょうたい" ], "comment": "upper body" },
	{ "question": "上半期", "answers": [ "かみはんき" ], "comment": "the first half-year; first half of the year" },
	{ "question": "上半身", "answers": [ "じょうはんしん" ], "comment": "upper half of body; bust" },
	{ "question": "上司", "answers": [ "じょうし" ], "comment": "superior authorities; boss" },
	{ "question": "上向き", "answers": [ "うえむき", "うわむき" ], "comment": "pointing up; pointing upward; upturn; uptrend; upward tendency" },
	{ "question": "上告", "answers": [ "じょうこく" ], "comment": "final appeal to the highest court" },
	{ "question": "上品", "answers": [ "じょうひん" ], "comment": "elegant; refined; polished" },
	{ "question": "上唇", "answers": [ "じょうしん", "うわくちびる" ], "comment": "upper lip" },
	{ "question": "上場", "answers": [ "じょうじょう" ], "comment": "listing (on the stock exchange, etc.); taking a company public\npresentation (e.g. of a play, opera); performance" },
	{ "question": "上層", "answers": [ "じょうそう" ], "comment": "upper stratum (classes, stories, storeys)" },
	{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうしゅ", "じょうて", "じょうず" ], "comment": "skill; skillful; dexterity\nflattery" },
	{ "question": "上手投げ", "answers": [ "うわてなげ" ], "comment": "overhand throw\na throw using the outside of the arm" },
	{ "question": "上方", "answers": [ "かみがた" ], "comment": "Kyoto and vicinity; Kyoto-Osaka region; Kansai region (esp. during Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "上旬", "answers": [ "じょうじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of month" },
	{ "question": "上昇", "answers": [ "じょうしょう" ], "comment": "rising; ascending; climbing" },
	{ "question": "上映", "answers": [ "じょうえい" ], "comment": "screening (a movie); showing\nto screen a movie" },
	{ "question": "上期", "answers": [ "かみき" ], "comment": "first half of the year" },
	{ "question": "上機嫌", "answers": [ "じょうきげん" ], "comment": "good humour (humor); good mood" },
	{ "question": "上流", "answers": [ "じょうりゅう" ], "comment": "upper stream; upper course; upper reaches\nupstream\nupper classes" },
	{ "question": "上演", "answers": [ "じょうえん" ], "comment": "performance (e.g. music, theatre, opera); staging" },
	{ "question": "上田", "answers": [ "じょうでん" ], "comment": "high rice field; very fertile rice field" },
	{ "question": "上申", "answers": [ "じょうしん" ], "comment": "report to a superior" },
	{ "question": "上着", "answers": [ "じょうい", "うわぎ" ], "comment": "coat; tunic; jacket; outer garment" },
	{ "question": "上積み", "answers": [ "うわづみ" ], "comment": "deck cargo; upper layer of goods\nextra\nto pile on top of" },
	{ "question": "上空", "answers": [ "じょうくう" ], "comment": "sky; the skies; high-altitude sky; upper air" },
	{ "question": "上等", "answers": [ "じょうとう" ], "comment": "superior; first-class; excellent; top quality\n(that's) just fine!; bring it on!" },
	{ "question": "上級", "answers": [ "じょうきゅう" ], "comment": "advanced level; high grade; senior" },
	{ "question": "上記", "answers": [ "じょうき" ], "comment": "above-mentioned; above-named; above" },
	{ "question": "上越", "answers": [ "じょうえつ" ], "comment": "area on Japan Sea side of Japan, including Niigata" },
	{ "question": "上達", "answers": [ "じょうたつ" ], "comment": "improvement (e.g. in skill, ability); advance; progress\ncommunication of opinions of the general populace to those of high rank" },
	{ "question": "上部", "answers": [ "じょうぶ" ], "comment": "top part; surface" },
	{ "question": "上限", "answers": [ "じょうげん" ], "comment": "upper limit\nsupremum" },
	{ "question": "上院", "answers": [ "じょういん" ], "comment": "Upper House; Senate; Lords" },
	{ "question": "上陸", "answers": [ "じょうりく" ], "comment": "landing; disembarkation; landfall" },
	{ "question": "下", "answers": [ "した", "もと" ], "comment": "below; down; under; younger (e.g. daughter)\nbottom\nbeneath; underneath\njust after; right after\ninferiority; one's inferior (i.e. one's junior)\ntrade-in\npreliminary; preparatory /\n under (esp. influence or guidance)" },
	{ "question": "下がり", "answers": [ "さがり" ], "comment": "fall; decline; lowering; hanging down; drooping; slanting (downward)\nstring apron; ornamental cords hanging from the front of a sumo wrestler's belt\nfood offering to the gods; leftovers; hand-me-downs\nleaving (one's master's place for home)\na little after ..." },
	{ "question": "下がる", "answers": [ "さがる" ], "comment": "to come down; to go down; to fall; to drop; to sink; to get lower\nto hang; to dangle\nto move back; to step back; to withdraw; to retire\nto deteriorate; to fall off; to be downgraded\nto get closer to the present day\nto go south" },
	{ "question": "下げる", "answers": [ "さげる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend; to wear (e.g. decoration)\nto lower; to reduce; to bring down\nto demote; to move back; to pull back\nto clear (plates); to remove (food, etc. from table or altar)" },
	{ "question": "下す", "answers": [ "くだす" ], "comment": "to make a decision; to draw a conclusion\nto give a judgement; to hand down a verdict; to pass a sentence; to give an order\nto let go down; to lower\nto do oneself; to do by oneself\nto beat; to defeat\nto have loose bowels; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to discharge from the body\nto do in one go; to do to the end without stopping" },
	{ "question": "下っ腹", "answers": [ "したっぱら" ], "comment": "abdomen; stomach; under parts" },
	{ "question": "下り", "answers": [ "くだり" ], "comment": "down-train (going away from Tokyo)\ndown-slope; downward going" },
	{ "question": "下りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "下り坂", "answers": [ "くだりざか" ], "comment": "descent; downhill; decline; waning" },
	{ "question": "下る", "answers": [ "くだる" ], "comment": "to descend; to go down; to come down\nto be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.)\nto pass (of time)\nto surrender; to capitulate\n(often in neg. form) to be less than; to be inferior to\nto have the runs; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to be discharged from the body" },
	{ "question": "下ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "下位", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "low rank; subordinate; lower order (e.g. byte); low-end" },
	{ "question": "下値", "answers": [ "したね" ], "comment": "lowest price" },
	{ "question": "下半期", "answers": [ "かはんき", "しもはんき" ], "comment": "the last half-year; second half of the year" },
	{ "question": "下半身", "answers": [ "かはんしん", "しもはんしん" ], "comment": "lower half of body" },
	{ "question": "下品", "answers": [ "げひん" ], "comment": "vulgar; indecent; coarse; crude" },
	{ "question": "下唇", "answers": [ "したくちびる", "かしん" ], "comment": "lower lip" },
	{ "question": "下地", "answers": [ "したじ" ], "comment": "groundwork; foundation\ninclination; aptitude; elementary knowledge of; grounding in\nundercoat; first coat\nsoy sauce" },
	{ "question": "下宿", "answers": [ "げしゅく" ], "comment": "boarding; lodging; boarding house" },
	{ "question": "下山", "answers": [ "げざん", "げさん" ], "comment": "descending (mountain)" },
	{ "question": "下手", "answers": [ "したで", "したて", "へた" ], "comment": "humble position; inferior\nunderarm grip on opponent's belt /\n unskillful; poor; awkward\nimprudent; untactful" },
	{ "question": "下手投げ", "answers": [ "したてなげ" ], "comment": "underhand throw\nunderarm throw" },
	{ "question": "下敷", "answers": [ "したじき" ], "comment": "desk pad; sheet of plastic (or cardboard, felt, etc.) placed under writing paper; underlay\nbeing pinned under; being caught under; being trapped under; being buried under; being crushed beneath\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "下敷き", "answers": [ "したじき" ], "comment": "desk pad; sheet of plastic (or cardboard, felt, etc.) placed under writing paper; underlay\nbeing pinned under; being caught under; being trapped under; being buried under; being crushed beneath\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "下方", "answers": [ "かほう" ], "comment": "lower region; lower part" },
	{ "question": "下旬", "answers": [ "げじゅん" ], "comment": "last third of a month; 21st to the last day of a month" },
	{ "question": "下書き", "answers": [ "したがき" ], "comment": "rough copy; draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "下期", "answers": [ "しもき" ], "comment": "second half of the fiscal year" },
	{ "question": "下水", "answers": [ "げすい" ], "comment": "drainage; ditch; gutter; sewerage\nsewage; black water" },
	{ "question": "下水道", "answers": [ "げすいどう" ], "comment": "drain; sewer; drainage system" },
	{ "question": "下流", "answers": [ "かりゅう" ], "comment": "downstream; lower reaches of a river\nlower classes" },
	{ "question": "下火", "answers": [ "したび" ], "comment": "burning low; waning; declining" },
	{ "question": "下町", "answers": [ "したまち" ], "comment": "low-lying part of a city (usu. containing shops, factories, etc.)\nShitamachi (low-lying area of eastern Tokyo near Tokyo Bay, incl. Asakusa, Shitaya, Kanda, Fukugawa, Honjo, Nihonbashi, Kyobashi and surrounds)" },
	{ "question": "下痢", "answers": [ "げり" ], "comment": "diarrhoea; diarrhea" },
	{ "question": "下着", "answers": [ "したぎ" ], "comment": "underwear" },
	{ "question": "下等", "answers": [ "かとう" ], "comment": "inferior; base; vulgar; low grade; lower class" },
	{ "question": "下級", "answers": [ "かきゅう" ], "comment": "lower grade; low class; junior (officer)" },
	{ "question": "下落", "answers": [ "げらく" ], "comment": "depreciation; decline; fall; slump" },
	{ "question": "下見", "answers": [ "したみ" ], "comment": "preview; preliminary inspection\npreparatory reading; preparation for a lesson; rehearsal\nsiding (on a house); clapboard; weatherboard" },
	{ "question": "下調べ", "answers": [ "したしらべ" ], "comment": "preliminary investigation; preparation" },
	{ "question": "下請け", "answers": [ "したうけ" ], "comment": "subcontract\nsubcontractor (person or company)" },
	{ "question": "下車", "answers": [ "げしゃ" ], "comment": "alighting (from train, bus, etc.); getting off" },
	{ "question": "下部", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "lower part; substructure\nsubordinate (office); good and faithful servant" },
	{ "question": "下野", "answers": [ "げや" ], "comment": "retirement from public office\ngoing into opposition; losing power" },
	{ "question": "下降", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "descent; fall; drop; decline; downturn; subsidence" },
	{ "question": "下限", "answers": [ "かげん" ], "comment": "lower limit\ninfimum" },
	{ "question": "下院", "answers": [ "かいん" ], "comment": "lower house; lower (legislative) body" },
	{ "question": "下駄", "answers": [ "げた" ], "comment": "geta; Japanese wooden clogs\nturn (in set-type proofing); upside-down character" },
	{ "question": "不人気", "answers": [ "ふにんき" ], "comment": "unpopular" },
	{ "question": "不仲", "answers": [ "ふなか" ], "comment": "discord" },
	{ "question": "不作", "answers": [ "ふさく" ], "comment": "poor crop; crop failure" },
	{ "question": "不便", "answers": [ "ふべん" ], "comment": "inconvenience; inexpediency; unhandiness" },
	{ "question": "不信", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "distrust; mistrust; disbelief; discredit\ninsincerity\nimpiety; faithlessness" },
	{ "question": "不信任", "answers": [ "ふしんにん" ], "comment": "non-confidence; lack of confidence" },
	{ "question": "不倫", "answers": [ "ふりん" ], "comment": "adultery; immorality; impropriety" },
	{ "question": "不備", "answers": [ "ふび" ], "comment": "defect; deficiency; imperfection; inadequacy\nYours in haste" },
	{ "question": "不充分", "answers": [ "ふじゅうぶん" ], "comment": "insufficient; inadequate; imperfect; shortage" },
	{ "question": "不全", "answers": [ "ふぜん" ], "comment": "partial; incomplete; imperfect" },
	{ "question": "不公平", "answers": [ "ふこうへい" ], "comment": "unfairness; injustice; partiality" },
	{ "question": "不利", "answers": [ "ふり" ], "comment": "disadvantage; handicap; unfavorable position" },
	{ "question": "不利益", "answers": [ "ふりえき" ], "comment": "disadvantage; handicap; drawback; inadvisability; inexpediency" },
	{ "question": "不動", "answers": [ "ふどう" ], "comment": "immobility; firmness; fixed; steadfastness; motionless; idle" },
	{ "question": "不動産", "answers": [ "ふどうさん" ], "comment": "real estate" },
	{ "question": "不動産屋", "answers": [ "ふどうさんや" ], "comment": "real estate agent; realtor" },
	{ "question": "不十分", "answers": [ "ふじゅうぶん" ], "comment": "insufficient; inadequate; imperfect; shortage" },
	{ "question": "不協和音", "answers": [ "ふきょうわおん" ], "comment": "discord; dissonance" },
	{ "question": "不可", "answers": [ "ふか" ], "comment": "wrong; bad; improper; unjustifiable; inadvisable\nnot allowed; not possible\nfailing grade" },
	{ "question": "不可侵", "answers": [ "ふかしん" ], "comment": "inviolability; sacredness; nonaggression" },
	{ "question": "不可分", "answers": [ "ふかぶん" ], "comment": "atomic; indivisibility" },
	{ "question": "不可欠", "answers": [ "ふかけつ" ], "comment": "indispensable; essential" },
	{ "question": "不可能", "answers": [ "ふかのう" ], "comment": "impossible" },
	{ "question": "不可解", "answers": [ "ふかかい" ], "comment": "mystery; baffling; inexplicable; incomprehensible" },
	{ "question": "不可避", "answers": [ "ふかひ" ], "comment": "inevitable; inescapable; unavoidable" },
	{ "question": "不合格", "answers": [ "ふごうかく" ], "comment": "(examination) failure; rejection; disqualification" },
	{ "question": "不合理", "answers": [ "ふごうり" ], "comment": "unreasonable; irrational; absurd; inconsistent" },
	{ "question": "不吉", "answers": [ "ふきつ" ], "comment": "ominous; sinister; unlucky; inauspicious" },
	{ "question": "不問", "answers": [ "ふもん" ], "comment": "something not questioned; something not asked about; something not relevant; something of no object" },
	{ "question": "不器用", "answers": [ "ぶきよう" ], "comment": "clumsy; awkward; unskillfulness; lack of ability\ntactless; awkward (e.g. socially); gauche\nmean; cowardly; base" },
	{ "question": "不在", "answers": [ "ふざい" ], "comment": "absence\ndisregard; indifference" },
	{ "question": "不在者投票", "answers": [ "ふざいしゃとうひょう" ], "comment": "absentee ballot; absentee voting" },
	{ "question": "不均衡", "answers": [ "ふきんこう" ], "comment": "imbalance; lack of balance; lopsidedness; disproportion; inequality; disparity" },
	{ "question": "不変", "answers": [ "ふへん" ], "comment": "eternal; everlasting; unchangeable; immutable; immovable; constant; permanent; indestructible" },
	{ "question": "不妊", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "infertility; sterility; barrenness" },
	{ "question": "不始末", "answers": [ "ふしまつ" ], "comment": "omission; failure; incompleteness\nirregularity; mismanagement; misconduct; malpractice; carelessness; wastefulness; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "不孝", "answers": [ "ふこう", "ふきょう" ], "comment": "undutifulness to one's parents; lack of filial piety\n(the crime of) cursing one's parents\ndisowning one's child" },
	{ "question": "不安", "answers": [ "ふあん" ], "comment": "anxiety; uneasiness; insecurity; suspense" },
	{ "question": "不安定", "answers": [ "ふあんてい" ], "comment": "instability; insecurity; crankiness" },
	{ "question": "不完全", "answers": [ "ふかんぜん" ], "comment": "imperfect; incomplete; faulty; defective" },
	{ "question": "不定", "answers": [ "ふてい", "ふじょう" ], "comment": "uncertainty; insecurity; inconstancy; indefinite; undecided" },
	{ "question": "不審", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "incomplete understanding; doubt; question; distrust; suspicion; strangeness; infidelity" },
	{ "question": "不平", "answers": [ "ふへい" ], "comment": "complaint; discontent; dissatisfaction" },
	{ "question": "不平等", "answers": [ "ふびょうどう" ], "comment": "inequality; unequal (treaties); unfair" },
	{ "question": "不幸", "answers": [ "ふこう" ], "comment": "unhappiness; sorrow; misfortune; disaster; accident\ndeath (usu. of a relative); bereavement" },
	{ "question": "不幸せ", "answers": [ "ふしあわせ" ], "comment": "unhappiness; misfortune; ill luck" },
	{ "question": "不当", "answers": [ "ふとう" ], "comment": "injustice; impropriety; unreasonableness; undeserved; unfair; invalid" },
	{ "question": "不得意", "answers": [ "ふとくい" ], "comment": "one's weak point" },
	{ "question": "不必要", "answers": [ "ふひつよう" ], "comment": "unnecessary; needless" },
	{ "question": "不快", "answers": [ "ふかい" ], "comment": "displeasure; discomfort; unpleasantness\nindisposition; ailment" },
	{ "question": "不思議", "answers": [ "ふしぎ" ], "comment": "wonder; miracle; strange; mystery; marvel; curiosity" },
	{ "question": "不愉快", "answers": [ "ふゆかい" ], "comment": "discomfort; unpleasantness; disagreeableness; unhappiness" },
	{ "question": "不意", "answers": [ "ふい" ], "comment": "sudden; abrupt; unexpected; unforeseen" },
	{ "question": "不意に", "answers": [ "ふいに" ], "comment": "suddenly; abruptly; unexpectedly" },
	{ "question": "不慣れ", "answers": [ "ふなれ" ], "comment": "inexperienced; unfamiliar (with); unversed; lacking experience" },
	{ "question": "不慮", "answers": [ "ふりょ" ], "comment": "unforeseen; accidental" },
	{ "question": "不成立", "answers": [ "ふせいりつ" ], "comment": "failure; rejection; rupture" },
	{ "question": "不戦", "answers": [ "ふせん" ], "comment": "war renunciation; anti-war\nbout cancelled due to absence of one of the wrestlers" },
	{ "question": "不払い", "answers": [ "ふばらい" ], "comment": "nonpayment; default" },
	{ "question": "不振", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "dullness; depression; slump; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "不整脈", "answers": [ "ふせいみゃく" ], "comment": "irregular pulse; arrhythmia" },
	{ "question": "不断", "answers": [ "ふだん" ], "comment": "constant; persistent; unremitting; ceaseless\nindecisiveness" },
	{ "question": "不明", "answers": [ "ふめい" ], "comment": "unclear; obscure; indistinct; uncertain; ambiguous\nunknown; unidentified\nignorance; lack of wisdom; lack of insight" },
	{ "question": "不時着", "answers": [ "ふじちゃく" ], "comment": "emergency landing" },
	{ "question": "不景気", "answers": [ "ふけいき" ], "comment": "economic slump; hard times; recession; depression\npoor (business); dull; slack; inactive\ngloomy; cheerless; dismal" },
	{ "question": "不服", "answers": [ "ふふく" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; discontent; disapproval; objection; complaint; protest; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "不本意", "answers": [ "ふほんい" ], "comment": "reluctant; unwilling; involuntary; unintentional" },
	{ "question": "不条理", "answers": [ "ふじょうり" ], "comment": "absurdity; irrationality; inconsistency" },
	{ "question": "不機嫌", "answers": [ "ふきげん" ], "comment": "pout; displeasure; ill humor; ill humour; sullenness" },
	{ "question": "不正", "answers": [ "ふせい" ], "comment": "injustice; unfairness; iniquity; impropriety; irregularity; dishonesty; illegality; fraud" },
	{ "question": "不毛", "answers": [ "ふもう" ], "comment": "sterile; barren; unproductive; sour" },
	{ "question": "不気味", "answers": [ "ぶきみ" ], "comment": "weird; ominous; eerie; uncanny; ghastly" },
	{ "question": "不況", "answers": [ "ふきょう" ], "comment": "recession; depression; slump" },
	{ "question": "不法", "answers": [ "ふほう" ], "comment": "lawlessness; injustice; illegality; unlawfulness" },
	{ "question": "不注意", "answers": [ "ふちゅうい" ], "comment": "carelessness; inattention; thoughtlessness" },
	{ "question": "不渡り", "answers": [ "ふわたり" ], "comment": "non-payment; dishonouring (bill); dishonoring (bill); bouncing (cheque, check)" },
	{ "question": "不満", "answers": [ "ふまん" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; displeasure; discontent; complaints; unhappiness; disgruntled" },
	{ "question": "不潔", "answers": [ "ふけつ" ], "comment": "unclean; dirty; filthy; impure" },
	{ "question": "不燃物", "answers": [ "ふねんぶつ" ], "comment": "non-inflammables; incombustible (usu. waste)" },
	{ "question": "不用意", "answers": [ "ふようい" ], "comment": "unpreparedness; carelessness" },
	{ "question": "不発", "answers": [ "ふはつ" ], "comment": "misfire" },
	{ "question": "不相応", "answers": [ "ふそうおう" ], "comment": "unsuited; inappropriate; improper; undeserved" },
	{ "question": "不眠", "answers": [ "ふみん" ], "comment": "sleeplessness; insomnia; wakefulness" },
	{ "question": "不確か", "answers": [ "ふたしか" ], "comment": "unreliable; uncertain; indefinite; unclear" },
	{ "question": "不確実", "answers": [ "ふかくじつ" ], "comment": "uncertain; unreliable; inauthentic; acataleptic" },
	{ "question": "不祥事", "answers": [ "ふしょうじ" ], "comment": "scandal; deplorable event" },
	{ "question": "不穏", "answers": [ "ふおん" ], "comment": "disquieting; threatening; turbulent; restless; unsettled; disturbing" },
	{ "question": "不純", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "impurity; adulteration; dishonesty; irregularity" },
	{ "question": "不能", "answers": [ "ふのう" ], "comment": "incompetency; inefficiency; impossibility; weak point; imbecility" },
	{ "question": "不自然", "answers": [ "ふしぜん" ], "comment": "unnatural; artificial; affected; strained" },
	{ "question": "不自由", "answers": [ "ふじゆう" ], "comment": "discomfort; inconvenience\npoverty; want; destitution\ndisability; impairment (physical, mental, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "不良", "answers": [ "ふりょう" ], "comment": "bad; poor; inferior\ndelinquent; hoodlum; hooligan" },
	{ "question": "不要", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "unnecessary; unneeded" },
	{ "question": "不規則", "answers": [ "ふきそく" ], "comment": "irregularity; unsteadiness; disorderly" },
	{ "question": "不親切", "answers": [ "ふしんせつ" ], "comment": "unkindness; unfriendliness" },
	{ "question": "不評", "answers": [ "ふひょう" ], "comment": "bad reputation; disgrace; unpopularity" },
	{ "question": "不詳", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "unknown; unidentified; unspecified" },
	{ "question": "不調", "answers": [ "ふちょう" ], "comment": "bad condition; not to work out (i.e. a deal); disagreement; break-off; disorder; slump; out of form" },
	{ "question": "不起訴", "answers": [ "ふきそ" ], "comment": "nonprosecution; nonindictment" },
	{ "question": "不足", "answers": [ "ふそく" ], "comment": "insufficiency; shortage; deficiency; lack; dearth" },
	{ "question": "不退転", "answers": [ "ふたいてん" ], "comment": "determination; conviction" },
	{ "question": "不透明", "answers": [ "ふとうめい" ], "comment": "opaque; obscure; murky; turbid\nopacity; obscurity\nunclear; unpredictable; uncertain" },
	{ "question": "不通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "suspension; interruption; stoppage; tie-up; cessation" },
	{ "question": "不運", "answers": [ "ふうん" ], "comment": "misfortune; bad luck; ill luck; ill fortune; bad break; tough luck; mischance" },
	{ "question": "不適当", "answers": [ "ふてきとう" ], "comment": "inadequacy; inappropriateness; unfitness; impropriety" },
	{ "question": "不都合", "answers": [ "ふつごう" ], "comment": "inconvenient; inexpedient; unfavourable; troublesome; difficult\nwrong; improper; objectionable; unjustifiable" },
	{ "question": "不順", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "irregularity; unseasonableness" },
	{ "question": "与える", "answers": [ "あたえる" ], "comment": "to give (esp. to someone of lower status); to bestow; to grant; to confer; to present; to award\nto provide; to afford; to offer; to supply\nto assign\nto cause\nto pass (a variable to a function)" },
	{ "question": "与党", "answers": [ "よとう" ], "comment": "ruling party; government party; party in power; government" },
	{ "question": "与野党", "answers": [ "よやとう" ], "comment": "ruling and opposition parties; parties in and out of power" },
	{ "question": "世", "answers": [ "よ" ], "comment": "world; society; age; generation" },
	{ "question": "世の中", "answers": [ "よのなか" ], "comment": "society; the world; the times" },
	{ "question": "世代", "answers": [ "せだい" ], "comment": "generation; the world; the age" },
	{ "question": "世帯", "answers": [ "しょたい", "せたい" ], "comment": "household; home; family; housekeeping" },
	{ "question": "世界", "answers": [ "せかい" ], "comment": "the world; society; the universe\nsphere; circle; world\nrenowned; world-famous; well-known outside of Japan\nrealm governed by one Buddha; space" },
	{ "question": "世界一", "answers": [ "せかいいち" ], "comment": "best in the world" },
	{ "question": "世界各国", "answers": [ "せかいかっこく" ], "comment": "countries all over the world; all the countries of the world" },
	{ "question": "世界各地", "answers": [ "せかいかくち" ], "comment": "every part of the world; all over the world; the four corners of the world" },
	{ "question": "世界大戦", "answers": [ "せかいたいせん" ], "comment": "the World War" },
	{ "question": "世界的", "answers": [ "せかいてき" ], "comment": "global; international; world-famous" },
	{ "question": "世界観", "answers": [ "せかいかん" ], "comment": "world view; outlook on the world; Weltanschauung (philosophy)\nappearance of a world (e.g. in fiction)" },
	{ "question": "世界銀行", "answers": [ "せかいぎんこう" ], "comment": "World Bank" },
	{ "question": "世相", "answers": [ "せそう" ], "comment": "phase of life; sign of the times\nworld (social) conditions; society" },
	{ "question": "世紀", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "century; era" },
	{ "question": "世紀末", "answers": [ "せいきまつ" ], "comment": "end of a century (esp. 19th); fin-de-siècle" },
	{ "question": "世襲", "answers": [ "せしゅう" ], "comment": "heredity; heritage" },
	{ "question": "世話", "answers": [ "せわ" ], "comment": "looking after; help; aid; assistance" },
	{ "question": "世話人", "answers": [ "せわにん" ], "comment": "sponsor; manager; go-between; mediator; agent; caretaker" },
	{ "question": "世論", "answers": [ "せろん", "よろん" ], "comment": "public opinion; popular voice; public sentiment; consensus" },
	{ "question": "世銀", "answers": [ "せぎん" ], "comment": "World Bank" },
	{ "question": "世間", "answers": [ "せけん" ], "comment": "world; society" },
	{ "question": "丘陵", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "hill" },
	{ "question": "両側", "answers": [ "りょうがわ", "りょうそく" ], "comment": "both sides" },
	{ "question": "両党", "answers": [ "りょうとう" ], "comment": "both political parties" },
	{ "question": "両国", "answers": [ "りょうごく", "りょうこく" ], "comment": "both countries\nRyougoku (area of Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "両岸", "answers": [ "りょうぎし", "りょうがん" ], "comment": "both banks (of a river)" },
	{ "question": "両手", "answers": [ "もろて", "りょうて", "そうしゅ" ], "comment": "(with) both hands\napprovingly" },
	{ "question": "両方", "answers": [ "りょうほう" ], "comment": "both; both sides; both parties" },
	{ "question": "両日", "answers": [ "りょうじつ" ], "comment": "both days; two days" },
	{ "question": "両替", "answers": [ "りょうがえ" ], "comment": "change; money exchange" },
	{ "question": "両氏", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "both persons" },
	{ "question": "両立", "answers": [ "りょうりつ" ], "comment": "compatibility; coexistence; standing together" },
	{ "question": "両端", "answers": [ "りょうはし", "りょうはじ", "りょうたん" ], "comment": "both ends; either end; both edges\ndouble-mindedness; sitting on the fence" },
	{ "question": "両者", "answers": [ "りょうしゃ" ], "comment": "pair; the two; both persons; both things" },
	{ "question": "両腕", "answers": [ "りょううで", "もろうで" ], "comment": "both arms" },
	{ "question": "両親", "answers": [ "ふたおや", "りょうしん" ], "comment": "parents; both parents" },
	{ "question": "両論", "answers": [ "りょうろん" ], "comment": "both arguments (theories)" },
	{ "question": "両足", "answers": [ "もろあし", "りょうそく", "りょうあし" ], "comment": "both feet\nboth legs" },
	{ "question": "両軍", "answers": [ "りょうぐん" ], "comment": "both armies; both teams" },
	{ "question": "両輪", "answers": [ "りょうりん" ], "comment": "two wheels" },
	{ "question": "両院", "answers": [ "りょういん" ], "comment": "both Houses of Parliament" },
	{ "question": "両面", "answers": [ "りょうめん" ], "comment": "both sides; two sides; double-sided" },
	{ "question": "並", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "average; medium; common; ordinary\nline; row of (e.g. houses)\nmid-grade\nsame level; equal; each (e.g. month); set of (e.g. teeth)" },
	{ "question": "並び", "answers": [ "ならび" ], "comment": "line; row; rank; list" },
	{ "question": "並びかえる", "answers": [ "ならびかえる" ], "comment": "to reorganize; to rearrange; to put (things) in order" },
	{ "question": "並びに", "answers": [ "ならびに" ], "comment": "and (also); both ... and; as well as" },
	{ "question": "並び替える", "answers": [ "ならびかえる" ], "comment": "to reorganize; to rearrange; to put (things) in order" },
	{ "question": "並ぶ", "answers": [ "ならぶ" ], "comment": "to line up; to stand in a line\nto rival; to match; to equal" },
	{ "question": "並べる", "answers": [ "ならべる" ], "comment": "to line up; to set up; to arrange in a line\nto enumerate; to itemize\nto be equal (to); to compare well (with); to be as good (as)" },
	{ "question": "並み", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "average; medium; common; ordinary\nline; row of (e.g. houses)\nmid-grade\nsame level; equal; each (e.g. month); set of (e.g. teeth)" },
	{ "question": "並列", "answers": [ "へいれつ" ], "comment": "running in parallel; lined up alongside\nparallel (electronics, computing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "並木", "answers": [ "なみき" ], "comment": "roadside tree; row of trees" },
	{ "question": "並立", "answers": [ "へいりつ" ], "comment": "standing abreast" },
	{ "question": "並行", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "(going) side-by-side; abreast\nconcurrent; occurring together; at the same time\nparallel" },
	{ "question": "中", "answers": [ "ちゅう", "なか" ], "comment": "inside; in\namong; within\ncenter (centre); middle\nduring; while /\n medium; average; middle\nmoderation\nmiddle school\nChina\nvolume two (of three)\nduring (a certain time when one did or is doing something); under (construction, etc.); while\nin; out of (e.g. three out of ten people)" },
	{ "question": "中でも", "answers": [ "なかでも" ], "comment": "among (other things); especially; particularly; inter alia; above all (else)" },
	{ "question": "中にも", "answers": [ "なかにも" ], "comment": "among (other things); especially; particularly; inter alia; above all (else)\nat the same time; simultaneously; at once; both" },
	{ "question": "中世", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "Middle Ages (in Japan esp. the Kamakura and Muromachi periods ); medieval times; mediaeval times" },
	{ "question": "中京", "answers": [ "ちゅうきょう" ], "comment": "Nagoya and environs" },
	{ "question": "中佐", "answers": [ "ちゅうさ" ], "comment": "lieutenant colonel; commander (navy)" },
	{ "question": "中傷", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "slander; libel; defamation; calumny; smear" },
	{ "question": "中元", "answers": [ "ちゅうげん" ], "comment": "15th day of the 7th lunar month; (last day of) Bon lantern festival\nmid-year gift; summer gift; Bon Festival gifts" },
	{ "question": "中前", "answers": [ "ちゅうぜん" ], "comment": "front of center field; front of centre field" },
	{ "question": "中卒", "answers": [ "ちゅうそつ" ], "comment": "junior high school graduate; middle school graduate" },
	{ "question": "中南米", "answers": [ "ちゅうなんべい" ], "comment": "Central and South America" },
	{ "question": "中原", "answers": [ "ちゅうげん" ], "comment": "middle of a field; middle of a country; field of contest" },
	{ "question": "中古", "answers": [ "ちゅうぶる", "ちゅうこ" ], "comment": "used; second-hand; old\nMiddle Ages" },
	{ "question": "中古車", "answers": [ "ちゅうこしゃ" ], "comment": "used car; secondhand car" },
	{ "question": "中和", "answers": [ "ちゅうわ" ], "comment": "neutralizing; neutralising; counteracting\nneutral; unbiased" },
	{ "question": "中国", "answers": [ "ちゅうごく" ], "comment": "China\nChugoku region of western Honshu (incl. Okayama, Hiroshima, Shimane, Tottori and Yamaguchi prefectures)\ncentral part of a country; main region" },
	{ "question": "中国人", "answers": [ "ちゅうごくじん" ], "comment": "Chinese person" },
	{ "question": "中国語", "answers": [ "ちゅうごくご" ], "comment": "Chinese (language)" },
	{ "question": "中型", "answers": [ "ちゅうがた" ], "comment": "medium size" },
	{ "question": "中執", "answers": [ "ちゅうしつ" ], "comment": "Central Executive Committee" },
	{ "question": "中堅", "answers": [ "ちゅうけん" ], "comment": "main body (of troops)\nnucleus; backbone; mainstay; key figure\ncenter field; centre field; center fielder; centre fielder\nathlete competing in the middle-number match in a team competition, i.e. second in 3-on-3, third in 5-on-5 (kendo, judo, etc.)\nmedium-level; mid-level; midsize" },
	{ "question": "中央", "answers": [ "ちゅうおう" ], "comment": "centre; center; middle; heart\nmetropolis; capital city; central government" },
	{ "question": "中央集権", "answers": [ "ちゅうおうしゅうけん" ], "comment": "centralized authoritarian rule; centralised authoritarian rule" },
	{ "question": "中学", "answers": [ "ちゅうがく" ], "comment": "middle school; junior high school" },
	{ "question": "中学校", "answers": [ "ちゅうがっこう" ], "comment": "junior high school; middle school; lower secondary school" },
	{ "question": "中学生", "answers": [ "ちゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "junior high school student; middle school pupil" },
	{ "question": "中将", "answers": [ "ちゅうじょう" ], "comment": "lieutenant general; vice-admiral" },
	{ "question": "中尉", "answers": [ "ちゅうい" ], "comment": "first lieutenant; lieutenant junior grade" },
	{ "question": "中小", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "small to medium" },
	{ "question": "中小企業", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょうきぎょう" ], "comment": "small to medium enterprises; smaller companies" },
	{ "question": "中島", "answers": [ "なかじま" ], "comment": "island in a pond or river" },
	{ "question": "中年", "answers": [ "ちゅうねん" ], "comment": "middle-age; middle age; midlife; one's middle years" },
	{ "question": "中庭", "answers": [ "なかにわ" ], "comment": "courtyard; quadrangle; middle court" },
	{ "question": "中心", "answers": [ "ちゅうしん" ], "comment": "center; centre; middle; heart; core; focus; pivot; emphasis; balance\n-centered; -centred; -focussed; -oriented; centered on; focussed on" },
	{ "question": "中性", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "neutrality (incl. chemical, electrical, etc.); indifference\nsexlessness; androgyny; androgyne; neuter\nneuter gender" },
	{ "question": "中性子", "answers": [ "ちゅうせいし" ], "comment": "neutron" },
	{ "question": "中指", "answers": [ "なかゆび", "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "middle finger; long finger; second finger; tall finger\nmiddle toe; third toe" },
	{ "question": "中断", "answers": [ "ちゅうだん" ], "comment": "interruption; suspension; break" },
	{ "question": "中日", "answers": [ "ちゅうにち", "なかび" ], "comment": "China and Japan\nthe middle day\nthe equinoctial day" },
	{ "question": "中旬", "answers": [ "ちゅうじゅん" ], "comment": "middle of a month; second third of a month; 11th to 20th day of a month" },
	{ "question": "中期", "answers": [ "ちゅうき" ], "comment": "middle period\nmedium-term" },
	{ "question": "中東", "answers": [ "ちゅうとう" ], "comment": "Middle East" },
	{ "question": "中枢", "answers": [ "ちゅうすう" ], "comment": "centre; center; pivot; mainstay; nucleus; backbone; central figure; pillar; key man" },
	{ "question": "中核", "answers": [ "ちゅうかく" ], "comment": "kernel; core; nucleus; center; centre" },
	{ "question": "中次ぎ", "answers": [ "なかつぎ" ], "comment": "joining; joint; intermediation; relaying; intermediary; relay; agency; brokerage\nmid-relief pitcher; middle reliever" },
	{ "question": "中欧", "answers": [ "ちゅうおう" ], "comment": "Central Europe" },
	{ "question": "中止", "answers": [ "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "suspension; stoppage; discontinuance; interruption" },
	{ "question": "中毒", "answers": [ "ちゅうどく" ], "comment": "poisoning\naddiction" },
	{ "question": "中流", "answers": [ "ちゅうりゅう" ], "comment": "mid-stream; middle course; middle class" },
	{ "question": "中産階級", "answers": [ "ちゅうさんかいきゅう" ], "comment": "middle class; bourgeoisie" },
	{ "question": "中略", "answers": [ "ちゅうりゃく" ], "comment": "omission (of middle part of a text); ellipsis" },
	{ "question": "中盤", "answers": [ "ちゅうばん" ], "comment": "middle (stage)" },
	{ "question": "中立", "answers": [ "ちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "neutrality" },
	{ "question": "中等", "answers": [ "ちゅうとう" ], "comment": "second grade; medium quality; average; middle class; secondary grade" },
	{ "question": "中級", "answers": [ "ちゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "intermediate level" },
	{ "question": "中絶", "answers": [ "ちゅうぜつ" ], "comment": "abortion\nto be interrupted; to be discontinued; to be suspended; to fall into abeyance" },
	{ "question": "中継", "answers": [ "ちゅうけい" ], "comment": "relay; hook-up\nrelay broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "中継ぎ", "answers": [ "なかつぎ" ], "comment": "joining; joint; intermediation; relaying; intermediary; relay; agency; brokerage\nmid-relief pitcher; middle reliever" },
	{ "question": "中腹", "answers": [ "ちゅうふく" ], "comment": "mountain side; halfway up" },
	{ "question": "中華", "answers": [ "ちゅうか" ], "comment": "Chinese food\nChina" },
	{ "question": "中越", "answers": [ "ちゅうごし" ], "comment": "over center field (centre)" },
	{ "question": "中身", "answers": [ "なかみ" ], "comment": "contents; interior; substance; filling; (sword) blade" },
	{ "question": "中軸", "answers": [ "ちゅうじく" ], "comment": "axis; pivot; central figure; key man" },
	{ "question": "中退", "answers": [ "ちゅうたい" ], "comment": "leaving school during a term" },
	{ "question": "中途", "answers": [ "ちゅうと" ], "comment": "in the middle; half-way" },
	{ "question": "中途半端", "answers": [ "ちゅうとはんぱ" ], "comment": "halfway; half measures; unfinished; incomplete; by halves; half-baked; half-cocked" },
	{ "question": "中道", "answers": [ "ちゅうどう" ], "comment": "middle of the road; moderation; golden mean\nthe middle (of what one is doing); half-way\nmiddle way; middle path" },
	{ "question": "中部", "answers": [ "ちゅうぶ" ], "comment": "center; centre; middle; heart\nChubu region (incl. Aichi, Nagano, Shizuoka, Niigata, Toyama, Ishikawa, Fukui, Yamanashi and Gifu prefectures)" },
	{ "question": "中間", "answers": [ "ちゅうかん" ], "comment": "middle; midway; interim" },
	{ "question": "中隊", "answers": [ "ちゅうたい" ], "comment": "company, battery, troop" },
	{ "question": "中高", "answers": [ "ちゅうこう" ], "comment": "middle and high school\nmedium and high (level)" },
	{ "question": "丸", "answers": [ "まる" ], "comment": "circle\nentirety; whole; full; complete\nmoney; dough; moola\nenclosure inside a castle's walls\nsoft-shelled turtle\nsuffix for ship names; suffix for names of people (esp. infants); suffix for names of swords, armour, musical instruments, etc.; suffix for names of dogs, horses, etc." },
	{ "question": "丸々", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "plump; rotund; chubby\nentirely; completely; wholly" },
	{ "question": "丸い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "丸まる", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "to become rounded; to roll into a ball" },
	{ "question": "丸み", "answers": [ "まるみ" ], "comment": "roundness; rotundity\nmellowness; maturity" },
	{ "question": "丸める", "answers": [ "まるめる" ], "comment": "to make round; to roll up; to curl up\nto seduce; to cajole; to explain away\nto round off (a fraction)\nto lump together" },
	{ "question": "丸め込む", "answers": [ "まるめこむ" ], "comment": "to coax; to seduce; to win over\nto roll up and put in (to something); to bundle up" },
	{ "question": "丸刈り", "answers": [ "まるがり" ], "comment": "close clipping" },
	{ "question": "丸太", "answers": [ "まるた" ], "comment": "log" },
	{ "question": "丹", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "red earth (i.e. containing cinnabar or minium); vermilion" },
	{ "question": "丹念", "answers": [ "たんねん" ], "comment": "painstaking; careful; meticulous; scrupulous; detailed; elaborate" },
	{ "question": "丹誠", "answers": [ "たんせい" ], "comment": "working earnestly; sincerity; diligence; effort; pains" },
	{ "question": "主", "answers": [ "ぬし", "しゅ", "おも", "しゅじん" ], "comment": "chief; main; principal; important\nmain secondary or supporting role (in kyogen) /\n (one's) master\nLord (Christian ref. to Jesus or God)\nthe main thing; the majority; the primary concern /\n head (of a household, etc.); leader; master\nowner; proprietor; proprietress\nsubject (of a rumour, etc.); doer (of a deed)\nguardian spirit (e.g. long-resident beast, usu. with mystical powers); long-time resident (or employee, etc.)\nhusband\nyou /\n head (of a household); proprietor (of a store); proprietress; landlord; landlady\none's husband\n(one's) employer; (one's) master\nhost; hostess" },
	{ "question": "主たる", "answers": [ "しゅたる" ], "comment": "main; principal; major" },
	{ "question": "主として", "answers": [ "しゅとして" ], "comment": "mainly; chiefly; primarily; for the most part" },
	{ "question": "主に", "answers": [ "おもに" ], "comment": "mainly; primarily" },
	{ "question": "主人", "answers": [ "しゅじん" ], "comment": "head (of a household); proprietor (of a store); proprietress; landlord; landlady\none's husband\n(one's) employer; (one's) master\nhost; hostess" },
	{ "question": "主人公", "answers": [ "しゅじんこう" ], "comment": "protagonist; main character; hero(ine) (of a story)\nhead of household" },
	{ "question": "主任", "answers": [ "しゅにん" ], "comment": "person in charge; responsible official; senior staff" },
	{ "question": "主体", "answers": [ "しゅたい" ], "comment": "main constituent; core; nucleus\nsubject (philosophical); protagonist" },
	{ "question": "主体的", "answers": [ "しゅたいてき" ], "comment": "independent; responsible; active; proactive\nsubjective" },
	{ "question": "主催", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "sponsorship (i.e. conducting under one's auspices); promotion; organizing; organising; hosting; staging" },
	{ "question": "主力", "answers": [ "しゅりょく" ], "comment": "main force; chief object; mainline" },
	{ "question": "主因", "answers": [ "しゅいん" ], "comment": "primary cause; main factor" },
	{ "question": "主婦", "answers": [ "しゅふ" ], "comment": "housewife; mistress (of the house); homemaker" },
	{ "question": "主宰", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "supervision; superintendence; chairmanship; chairman" },
	{ "question": "主審", "answers": [ "しゅしん" ], "comment": "chief umpire" },
	{ "question": "主将", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "commander-in-chief; (team) captain" },
	{ "question": "主導", "answers": [ "しゅどう" ], "comment": "leadership; initiative; spearhead" },
	{ "question": "主導権", "answers": [ "しゅどうけん" ], "comment": "hegemony; leadership; initiative" },
	{ "question": "主席", "answers": [ "しゅせき" ], "comment": "head; chief\nchairman; governor; president\ntop student; head of the class\ntop seat; first desk (in orchestra)" },
	{ "question": "主幹", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "chief editor; managing editor\nmanager; person in charge" },
	{ "question": "主張", "answers": [ "しゅちょう" ], "comment": "claim; request; insistence; assertion; advocacy; emphasis; contention; opinion; tenet" },
	{ "question": "主役", "answers": [ "しゅやく" ], "comment": "leading part; leading actor; leading actress" },
	{ "question": "主戦", "answers": [ "しゅせん" ], "comment": "advocacy of war" },
	{ "question": "主査", "answers": [ "しゅさ" ], "comment": "chief examiner or investigator" },
	{ "question": "主権", "answers": [ "しゅけん" ], "comment": "sovereignty; supremacy; dominion" },
	{ "question": "主治医", "answers": [ "しゅじい" ], "comment": "attending physician; physician in charge; (one's) family doctor" },
	{ "question": "主流", "answers": [ "しゅりゅう" ], "comment": "mainstream; commonplace\nmain course (of a river); main stream" },
	{ "question": "主演", "answers": [ "しゅえん" ], "comment": "starring; playing the leading part" },
	{ "question": "主犯", "answers": [ "しゅはん" ], "comment": "principal offence; principal offense; principal offender" },
	{ "question": "主眼", "answers": [ "しゅがん" ], "comment": "main point" },
	{ "question": "主砲", "answers": [ "しゅほう" ], "comment": "main battery; main armament" },
	{ "question": "主税局", "answers": [ "しゅぜいきょく" ], "comment": "(Japanese) Tax Bureau" },
	{ "question": "主筆", "answers": [ "しゅひつ" ], "comment": "editor-in-chief" },
	{ "question": "主管", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "supervision; management; supervisor; manager" },
	{ "question": "主義", "answers": [ "しゅぎ" ], "comment": "doctrine; rule; principle; -ism" },
	{ "question": "主義者", "answers": [ "しゅぎしゃ" ], "comment": "advocate (of a theory or principle); ideologist; ideologue\n-ist (i.e. adherent to a belief system)\nsocialist; communist; anarchist" },
	{ "question": "主要", "answers": [ "しゅよう" ], "comment": "chief; main; principal; major" },
	{ "question": "主観", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "subjectivity; subject (philosophical); ego\none's personal opinion; one's own idea" },
	{ "question": "主観的", "answers": [ "しゅかんてき" ], "comment": "subjective" },
	{ "question": "主計", "answers": [ "しゅけい" ], "comment": "paymaster; accountant" },
	{ "question": "主計局", "answers": [ "しゅけいきょく" ], "comment": "budget bureau" },
	{ "question": "主軸", "answers": [ "しゅじく" ], "comment": "main spindle; main shaft\nlinchpin; pivot\nprincipal axis; main axis" },
	{ "question": "主題", "answers": [ "しゅだい" ], "comment": "subject; theme; motif" },
	{ "question": "主食", "answers": [ "しゅしょく" ], "comment": "staple food" },
	{ "question": "丼", "answers": [ "どん", "どんぶり" ], "comment": "porcelain bowl\nbowl of rice with food on top" },
	{ "question": "久々", "answers": [ "ひさびさ" ], "comment": "(in a) long time; long time (ago); while (ago); long ago; long while (ago); (in a) long while" },
	{ "question": "久しい", "answers": [ "ひさしい" ], "comment": "long; long-continued; old (story)" },
	{ "question": "久しぶり", "answers": [ "ひさしぶり" ], "comment": "a long time (since the last time); it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)" },
	{ "question": "久し振り", "answers": [ "ひさしぶり" ], "comment": "a long time (since the last time); it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)" },
	{ "question": "乏しい", "answers": [ "とぼしい", "ともしい" ], "comment": "meagre; meager; scarce; limited; destitute; hard up; lacking; scanty; poor" },
	{ "question": "乗じる", "answers": [ "じょうじる" ], "comment": "to take advantage of; to follow blindly\nto multiply" },
	{ "question": "乗ずる", "answers": [ "じょうずる" ], "comment": "to take advantage of; to follow blindly\nto multiply" },
	{ "question": "乗せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "to place on (something)\nto give (someone) a ride; to give a lift; to pick up; to help on board\nto load (luggage); to carry; to take on board\nto send out (on the airwaves, etc.)\nto deceive; to take for a ride\nto (sing) along with (musical accompaniment)\nto let (someone) take part\nto excite (someone)\nto publish (an article); to run (an ad)" },
	{ "question": "乗っ取り", "answers": [ "のっとり" ], "comment": "capture; takeover; hijack; skyjacking" },
	{ "question": "乗っ取る", "answers": [ "のっとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to capture; to seize; to commandeer; to occupy; to usurp\nto hijack (a vehicle)" },
	{ "question": "乗り出す", "answers": [ "のりいだす", "のりだす" ], "comment": "to set out; to set sail\nto embark on (a new venture); to set out (to achieve something)\nto begin to ride\nto lean forward" },
	{ "question": "乗り切る", "answers": [ "のりきる" ], "comment": "to weather (a storm, rough seas); to ride across; to sail across\nto get through (adversity); to weather; to get over; to tide over; to overcome; to survive\nto load completely (e.g. books on a shelf, people or luggage in a car)" },
	{ "question": "乗り回す", "answers": [ "のりまわす" ], "comment": "to drive (a car) around; to ride (a bicycle) around" },
	{ "question": "乗り場", "answers": [ "のりば" ], "comment": "place for boarding vehicles; bus stop; bus terminal; railway platform; taxi stand; jetty; wharf" },
	{ "question": "乗り換え", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer (trains, buses, etc.); connection; connexion\nswitching (stock)\nchromosomal crossover; crossing over" },
	{ "question": "乗り換える", "answers": [ "のりかえる" ], "comment": "to transfer (trains); to change (bus, train)\nto change one's mind; to move on to (e.g. a new love interest); to change methods; to change one's way of thinking" },
	{ "question": "乗り気", "answers": [ "のりき" ], "comment": "interest; eagerness; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "乗り物", "answers": [ "のりもの" ], "comment": "vehicle; conveyance; transport\nride (playground, fair, carnival); playground facility" },
	{ "question": "乗り越える", "answers": [ "のりこえる" ], "comment": "to climb over; to get over; to ride across\nto surmount; to overcome\nto surpass; to overtake" },
	{ "question": "乗り越し", "answers": [ "のりこし" ], "comment": "riding past (one's station)" },
	{ "question": "乗り越す", "answers": [ "のりこす" ], "comment": "to ride past (one's stop); to overshoot\nto climb over; to get over\nto overtake (in a vehicle); to pass" },
	{ "question": "乗り込む", "answers": [ "のりこむ" ], "comment": "to board; to embark on; to get into (a car); to man (a ship); to help (someone) into\nto march into; to enter" },
	{ "question": "乗り遅れる", "answers": [ "のりおくれる" ], "comment": "to miss (train, bus, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乗り降り", "answers": [ "のりおり" ], "comment": "getting on and off (a vehicle); boarding and alighting" },
	{ "question": "乗る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.); to get in; to board; to take; to embark\nto get on (e.g. a footstool); to step on; to jump on; to sit on; to mount\nto reach; to go over; to pass\nto follow; to stay (on track); to go with (the times, etc.)\nto take part; to participate; to join\nto get into the swing (and sing, dance, etc.)\nto be deceived; to be taken in\nto be carried; to be spread; to be scattered\nto stick; to attach; to take; to go on" },
	{ "question": "乗務員", "answers": [ "じょうむいん" ], "comment": "crew member; crewman" },
	{ "question": "乗員", "answers": [ "じょういん" ], "comment": "crew" },
	{ "question": "乗回す", "answers": [ "のりまわす" ], "comment": "to drive (a car) around; to ride (a bicycle) around" },
	{ "question": "乗場", "answers": [ "のりば" ], "comment": "place for boarding vehicles; bus stop; bus terminal; railway platform; taxi stand; jetty; wharf" },
	{ "question": "乗客", "answers": [ "じょうかく", "じょうきゃく" ], "comment": "passenger" },
	{ "question": "乗換", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer (trains, buses, etc.); connection; connexion\nswitching (stock)\nchromosomal crossover; crossing over" },
	{ "question": "乗換え", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer (trains, buses, etc.); connection; connexion\nswitching (stock)\nchromosomal crossover; crossing over" },
	{ "question": "乗気", "answers": [ "のりき" ], "comment": "interest; eagerness; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "乗物", "answers": [ "のりもの" ], "comment": "vehicle; conveyance; transport\nride (playground, fair, carnival); playground facility" },
	{ "question": "乗用車", "answers": [ "じょうようしゃ" ], "comment": "passenger vehicle; automobile" },
	{ "question": "乗組員", "answers": [ "のりくみいん" ], "comment": "crew" },
	{ "question": "乗越し", "answers": [ "のりこし" ], "comment": "riding past (one's station)" },
	{ "question": "乗越す", "answers": [ "のりこす" ], "comment": "to ride past (one's stop); to overshoot\nto climb over; to get over\nto overtake (in a vehicle); to pass" },
	{ "question": "乗車", "answers": [ "じょうしゃ" ], "comment": "taking a train, bus, etc.; entraining" },
	{ "question": "乗車券", "answers": [ "じょうしゃけん" ], "comment": "passenger ticket" },
	{ "question": "乗降", "answers": [ "じょうこう" ], "comment": "getting on and off; embarking and disembarking" },
	{ "question": "乗馬", "answers": [ "じょうば" ], "comment": "horse riding\nriding horse; saddle horse" },
	{ "question": "乙", "answers": [ "おつ" ], "comment": "second (party to an agreement); the B party (e.g. in a contract); the latter; defendant\nstylish; chic; spicy; witty; tasty; romantic\nstrange; quaint; queer\nthank you; good job; goodbye; goodnight" },
	{ "question": "九", "answers": [ "ここ", "ここの", "きゅう", "この", "く" ], "comment": "nine" },
	{ "question": "九つ", "answers": [ "ここのつ" ], "comment": "nine" },
	{ "question": "九九", "answers": [ "くく" ], "comment": "multiplication table; times table" },
	{ "question": "九十", "answers": [ "くじゅう", "きゅうじゅう" ], "comment": "ninety" },
	{ "question": "九州", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "Kyushu (southernmost of the four main islands of Japan)" },
	{ "question": "九日", "answers": [ "ここのか" ], "comment": "the ninth day of the month\nnine days" },
	{ "question": "九月", "answers": [ "くがつ" ], "comment": "September" },
	{ "question": "九重", "answers": [ "ここのえ" ], "comment": "ninefold; imperial palace; the Court" },
	{ "question": "乞食", "answers": [ "こつじき", "こじき" ], "comment": "beggar\nbegging" },
	{ "question": "乱す", "answers": [ "みだす" ], "comment": "to throw out of order; to disarrange; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "乱れ", "answers": [ "みだれ" ], "comment": "disorder; disturbance; unrest" },
	{ "question": "乱れる", "answers": [ "みだれる" ], "comment": "to be disordered; to be disarranged; to be disarrayed; to be disheveled; to be dishevelled\nto be discomposed; to be upset; to get confused; to be disturbed\nto lapse into chaos (due to war, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乱売", "answers": [ "らんばい" ], "comment": "underselling; panic selling" },
	{ "question": "乱暴", "answers": [ "らんぼう" ], "comment": "rude; violent; rough; lawless; unreasonable; reckless" },
	{ "question": "乱獲", "answers": [ "らんかく" ], "comment": "excessive fishing; overfishing; overhunting; excessive taking" },
	{ "question": "乱用", "answers": [ "らんよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; misappropriation; using to excess" },
	{ "question": "乱発", "answers": [ "らんぱつ" ], "comment": "random firing; reckless firing; excessive issue" },
	{ "question": "乱立", "answers": [ "らんりつ" ], "comment": "standing together in a disorderly fashion; standing close around; crowding together\nflooding in (applicants, election candidates, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乱調", "answers": [ "らんちょう" ], "comment": "confusion" },
	{ "question": "乱闘", "answers": [ "らんとう" ], "comment": "fray; fighting; brawling; scuffle" },
	{ "question": "乱雑", "answers": [ "らんざつ" ], "comment": "clutter; disorder; promiscuity; affray; confusion; muddle" },
	{ "question": "乳", "answers": [ "ちち", "ち" ], "comment": "milk\nbreast\nloop\ndecorative bump (on a hanging bell)" },
	{ "question": "乳児", "answers": [ "にゅうじ" ], "comment": "infant (below 1 years old); suckling baby" },
	{ "question": "乳幼児", "answers": [ "にゅうようじ" ], "comment": "infants; babies" },
	{ "question": "乳房", "answers": [ "ちぶさ", "にゅうぼう" ], "comment": "breast; nipple; udder" },
	{ "question": "乳製品", "answers": [ "にゅうせいひん" ], "comment": "dairy products" },
	{ "question": "乳首", "answers": [ "ちちくび", "ちくび" ], "comment": "nipple; teat" },
	{ "question": "乾かす", "answers": [ "かわかす" ], "comment": "to dry (clothes, etc.); to desiccate" },
	{ "question": "乾く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "to get dry" },
	{ "question": "乾季", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "dry season" },
	{ "question": "乾期", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "dry season" },
	{ "question": "乾杯", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "toast; drink (in celebration or in honor of something)\ndrinking one's glass dry\ncheers" },
	{ "question": "乾燥", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "dryness; aridity; insipidity; dehydration; desiccation" },
	{ "question": "乾物", "answers": [ "かんぶつ", "ひもの" ], "comment": "dry provisions; dried food; dried goods; groceries" },
	{ "question": "乾電池", "answers": [ "かんでんち" ], "comment": "dry cell; battery" },
	{ "question": "亀", "answers": [ "かめ" ], "comment": "tortoise; turtle" },
	{ "question": "亀裂", "answers": [ "きれつ" ], "comment": "crack; crevice; fissure; chap; rift" },
	{ "question": "了", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "finish; completion; understanding" },
	{ "question": "了承", "answers": [ "りょうしょう" ], "comment": "acknowledgement; acknowledgment; understanding (e.g. \"please be understanding of the mess during our renovation\"); noting; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "了解", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "comprehension; consent; understanding; agreement; roger (on the radio)" },
	{ "question": "予備", "answers": [ "よび" ], "comment": "preparation; preliminaries; reserve; spare" },
	{ "question": "予備校", "answers": [ "よびこう" ], "comment": "prep school (ronin year)" },
	{ "question": "予備費", "answers": [ "よびひ" ], "comment": "reserve funds; emergency funds" },
	{ "question": "予告", "answers": [ "よこく" ], "comment": "advance notice; previous note; preliminary announcement" },
	{ "question": "予報", "answers": [ "よほう" ], "comment": "forecast; prediction" },
	{ "question": "予定", "answers": [ "よてい" ], "comment": "plans; arrangement; schedule; program; programme; expectation; estimate" },
	{ "question": "予想", "answers": [ "よそう" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; prediction; forecast; conjecture" },
	{ "question": "予想外", "answers": [ "よそうがい" ], "comment": "unexpected; unforeseen; strange" },
	{ "question": "予感", "answers": [ "よかん" ], "comment": "presentiment; premonition; hunch\nto have a premonition; to have a hunch" },
	{ "question": "予断", "answers": [ "よだん" ], "comment": "guessing; prediction; conclusion" },
	{ "question": "予期", "answers": [ "よき" ], "comment": "expectation; assume will happen; forecast" },
	{ "question": "予期せぬ", "answers": [ "よきせぬ" ], "comment": "unexpected; unforeseen" },
	{ "question": "予測", "answers": [ "よそく" ], "comment": "prediction; estimation" },
	{ "question": "予知", "answers": [ "よち" ], "comment": "foresight; foreknowledge; intimation; premonition; prediction" },
	{ "question": "予算", "answers": [ "よさん" ], "comment": "estimate; budget" },
	{ "question": "予約", "answers": [ "よやく" ], "comment": "reservation; appointment; booking; advance order\ncontract; subscription; pledge\nprogramming (e.g. a device); setting (e.g. a timer)" },
	{ "question": "予習", "answers": [ "よしゅう" ], "comment": "preparation for a lesson" },
	{ "question": "予言", "answers": [ "よげん" ], "comment": "prediction; prophecy; prognostication" },
	{ "question": "予選", "answers": [ "よせん" ], "comment": "preliminary contest; qualifying round; trial; heat; primary" },
	{ "question": "予防", "answers": [ "よぼう" ], "comment": "prevention; precaution; protection against" },
	{ "question": "予防接種", "answers": [ "よぼうせっしゅ" ], "comment": "immunization; immunisation; vaccination; inoculation" },
	{ "question": "争い", "answers": [ "あらそい" ], "comment": "dispute; strife; quarrel; dissension; conflict; rivalry; contest" },
	{ "question": "争う", "answers": [ "あらそう" ], "comment": "to compete; to contest; to contend\nto quarrel; to argue; to dispute; to be at variance; to oppose\n(usu. in negative form) to deny (e.g. evidence)" },
	{ "question": "争奪", "answers": [ "そうだつ" ], "comment": "struggle; contest" },
	{ "question": "争点", "answers": [ "そうてん" ], "comment": "point at issue" },
	{ "question": "争議", "answers": [ "そうぎ" ], "comment": "dispute; quarrel; strike" },
	{ "question": "事件", "answers": [ "じけん" ], "comment": "event; affair; incident; case; plot; trouble; scandal" },
	{ "question": "事例", "answers": [ "じれい" ], "comment": "example; precedent; case" },
	{ "question": "事例集", "answers": [ "じれいしゅう" ], "comment": "collection of cases; collection of instances" },
	{ "question": "事典", "answers": [ "ことてん", "じてん" ], "comment": "cyclopedia; encyclopedia" },
	{ "question": "事前", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "prior; beforehand; in advance; before the fact; ex ante" },
	{ "question": "事務", "answers": [ "じむ" ], "comment": "business; office work; administration" },
	{ "question": "事務員", "answers": [ "じむいん" ], "comment": "clerk; office worker; office staff" },
	{ "question": "事務官", "answers": [ "じむかん" ], "comment": "administrative official; secretary; commissioner" },
	{ "question": "事務室", "answers": [ "じむしつ" ], "comment": "office" },
	{ "question": "事務局", "answers": [ "じむきょく" ], "comment": "secretariat; executive office" },
	{ "question": "事務当局", "answers": [ "じむとうきょく" ], "comment": "officials in charge" },
	{ "question": "事務所", "answers": [ "じむしょ" ], "comment": "office" },
	{ "question": "事務次官", "answers": [ "じむじかん" ], "comment": "permanent vice-president; undersecretary; vice-minister" },
	{ "question": "事務的", "answers": [ "じむてき" ], "comment": "businesslike; practical" },
	{ "question": "事変", "answers": [ "じへん" ], "comment": "accident; disaster; incident; uprising; emergency" },
	{ "question": "事実", "answers": [ "じじつ" ], "comment": "fact; truth; reality" },
	{ "question": "事実上", "answers": [ "じじつじょう" ], "comment": "(as a) matter of fact; actually; in reality" },
	{ "question": "事実無根", "answers": [ "じじつむこん" ], "comment": "groundless; entirely contrary to fact" },
	{ "question": "事後", "answers": [ "じご" ], "comment": "after-; post-; ex-; after the fact; ex post" },
	{ "question": "事情", "answers": [ "じじょう" ], "comment": "circumstances; consideration; conditions; situation; reasons; state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "事態", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "situation; (present) state of affairs; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "事故", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "accident; incident; trouble\ncircumstances; reasons" },
	{ "question": "事柄", "answers": [ "ことがら" ], "comment": "matter; thing; affair; circumstance" },
	{ "question": "事業", "answers": [ "じぎょう", "ことわざ" ], "comment": "project; enterprise; business; industry; operations; venture; service\nact; deed; conduct" },
	{ "question": "事業所", "answers": [ "じぎょうしょ" ], "comment": "plant; enterprise place; office" },
	{ "question": "事象", "answers": [ "じしょう" ], "comment": "event; phenomenon; matter" },
	{ "question": "事項", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "matter; item; facts" },
	{ "question": "二", "answers": [ "に", "ふう", "ふ", "ふた" ], "comment": "two" },
	{ "question": "二つ", "answers": [ "ふたつ" ], "comment": "two" },
	{ "question": "二つ目", "answers": [ "ふたつめ" ], "comment": "one after next; second" },
	{ "question": "二の次", "answers": [ "にのつぎ" ], "comment": "secondary; subordinate" },
	{ "question": "二世", "answers": [ "にせい" ], "comment": "nisei; second-generation Japanese (or Korean, etc.); foreigner of Japanese parentage\nthe Second (king, etc. of the same name); second generation; junior\nson" },
	{ "question": "二人", "answers": [ "ふたり", "ににん" ], "comment": "two persons; two people; pair; couple" },
	{ "question": "二人とも", "answers": [ "ふたりとも" ], "comment": "both (people)" },
	{ "question": "二人三脚", "answers": [ "ににんさんきゃく" ], "comment": "three-legged race\ncooperation with singleness of purpose (e.g. between companies); operating in tandem" },
	{ "question": "二人前", "answers": [ "ふたりまえ", "ににんまえ" ], "comment": "for two people; (work) of two; (meals) for two" },
	{ "question": "二分", "answers": [ "にぶん" ], "comment": "halving; bisection\nthe two equinoxes (vernal and autumnal)" },
	{ "question": "二割", "answers": [ "にわり" ], "comment": "20 percent" },
	{ "question": "二十", "answers": [ "にじゅう" ], "comment": "twenty" },
	{ "question": "二十世紀", "answers": [ "にじっせいき", "にじゅっせいき" ], "comment": "twentieth century" },
	{ "question": "二十四時間制", "answers": [ "にじゅうよじかんせい" ], "comment": "around-the-clock system" },
	{ "question": "二十日", "answers": [ "はつか" ], "comment": "twentieth day of the month\ntwenty days" },
	{ "question": "二十歳", "answers": [ "はたち" ], "comment": "20 years old\ntwenty" },
	{ "question": "二号", "answers": [ "にごう" ], "comment": "number two\nmistress; concubine" },
	{ "question": "二塁", "answers": [ "にるい" ], "comment": "second base" },
	{ "question": "二塁手", "answers": [ "にるいしゅ" ], "comment": "second baseman" },
	{ "question": "二塁打", "answers": [ "にるいだ" ], "comment": "two-base hit; double" },
	{ "question": "二宮", "answers": [ "にぐう" ], "comment": "the Two Ise Shrines" },
	{ "question": "二度", "answers": [ "にど" ], "comment": "two times; twice\ntwo degrees" },
	{ "question": "二度と", "answers": [ "にどと" ], "comment": "never again (with negative verb)" },
	{ "question": "二度寝", "answers": [ "にどね" ], "comment": "going back to sleep (e.g. after waking up in the morning)" },
	{ "question": "二日", "answers": [ "ふつか" ], "comment": "second day of the month\ntwo days" },
	{ "question": "二月", "answers": [ "にがつ" ], "comment": "February\nsecond month of the lunar calendar" },
	{ "question": "二期", "answers": [ "にき" ], "comment": "two periods or terms" },
	{ "question": "二本立て", "answers": [ "にほんだて" ], "comment": "double feature (movie)" },
	{ "question": "二枚", "answers": [ "にまい" ], "comment": "two sheets (pieces) (of paper)" },
	{ "question": "二枚目", "answers": [ "にまいめ" ], "comment": "handsome man\nactor in a love scene" },
	{ "question": "二次", "answers": [ "にじ" ], "comment": "secondary; subordinate" },
	{ "question": "二死", "answers": [ "にし" ], "comment": "two out; two down (and one to go)" },
	{ "question": "二流", "answers": [ "にりゅう" ], "comment": "second-rate; inferior" },
	{ "question": "二番", "answers": [ "にばん" ], "comment": "second; number two; runner-up" },
	{ "question": "二百", "answers": [ "にひゃく" ], "comment": "two hundred; 200" },
	{ "question": "二者択一", "answers": [ "にしゃたくいつ" ], "comment": "two alternatives; selecting an option (from two alternatives)" },
	{ "question": "二軍", "answers": [ "にぐん" ], "comment": "second string players" },
	{ "question": "二輪車", "answers": [ "にりんしゃ" ], "comment": "two-wheeled vehicle (bicycle, motorcycle, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "二部", "answers": [ "にぶ" ], "comment": "two parts; two copies; the second part" },
	{ "question": "二重", "answers": [ "にじゅう", "ふたえ" ], "comment": "double; two-fold; two layers; duplex\ndiplo-; dipl-\ndouble-edged eyelid; double eyelid; creased eyelid" },
	{ "question": "二院", "answers": [ "にいん" ], "comment": "the two houses of legislature" },
	{ "question": "二階", "answers": [ "にかい" ], "comment": "second floor; upstairs" },
	{ "question": "二階建て", "answers": [ "にかいだて" ], "comment": "two-storied building" },
	{ "question": "互い", "answers": [ "たがい" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal" },
	{ "question": "互いに", "answers": [ "たがいに" ], "comment": "mutually; with each other; reciprocally; together" },
	{ "question": "互い違い", "answers": [ "たがいちがい" ], "comment": "alternate; alternation" },
	{ "question": "互助", "answers": [ "ごじょ" ], "comment": "mutual aid; cooperation; benefit" },
	{ "question": "互換", "answers": [ "ごかん" ], "comment": "interchange\ntransposition\ncompatible (e.g. PC)" },
	{ "question": "互角", "answers": [ "ごかく" ], "comment": "equality; evenness; par; good match" },
	{ "question": "五", "answers": [ "いつ", "ご", "い" ], "comment": "five" },
	{ "question": "五つ", "answers": [ "いつつ" ], "comment": "five" },
	{ "question": "五分", "answers": [ "ごぶ" ], "comment": "half; 50%; tie; evenness\n5 parts; 5%" },
	{ "question": "五十", "answers": [ "ごじゅう" ], "comment": "fifty" },
	{ "question": "五十三次", "answers": [ "ごじゅうさんつぎ" ], "comment": "the 53 Toukaidou stages" },
	{ "question": "五十音", "answers": [ "ごじゅうおん" ], "comment": "the Japanese syllabary" },
	{ "question": "五日", "answers": [ "いつか" ], "comment": "the fifth day of the month\nfive days" },
	{ "question": "五月", "answers": [ "ごがつ" ], "comment": "May" },
	{ "question": "五輪", "answers": [ "ごりん" ], "comment": "Olympic rings; Olympics" },
	{ "question": "井戸", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "water well" },
	{ "question": "亜熱帯", "answers": [ "あねったい" ], "comment": "subtropics" },
	{ "question": "亜鉛", "answers": [ "あえん" ], "comment": "zinc (Zn)" },
	{ "question": "亡くなる", "answers": [ "なくなる" ], "comment": "to die" },
	{ "question": "亡命", "answers": [ "ぼうめい" ], "comment": "flight from one's country; seeking asylum; defection; emigration (for political reasons); (going into) exile; becoming a (political) refugee" },
	{ "question": "亡骸", "answers": [ "なきがら" ], "comment": "remains; corpse; (dead) body" },
	{ "question": "交える", "answers": [ "まじえる" ], "comment": "to mix; to combine\nto exchange (words, fire, etc.)\nto cross (e.g. swords); to join together" },
	{ "question": "交ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join" },
	{ "question": "交じり", "answers": [ "まじり" ], "comment": "mixed; mingled" },
	{ "question": "交じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join" },
	{ "question": "交ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to stir; to blend" },
	{ "question": "交わす", "answers": [ "かわす" ], "comment": "to exchange (messages, greetings, arguments, etc.)\nto intersect; to cross; to interlace\n... with one another; ... to each other" },
	{ "question": "交わる", "answers": [ "まじわる" ], "comment": "to cross; to intersect; to join; to meet\nto associate with; to mingle with; to consort with\nto have a sexual relationship; to copulate" },
	{ "question": "交互", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal; alternate" },
	{ "question": "交付", "answers": [ "こうふ" ], "comment": "delivery; issuance; handing over; granting" },
	{ "question": "交代", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "alternation; change; relief; relay; shift; substitution (sports, etc.); taking turns" },
	{ "question": "交信", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "telecommunications; correspondence" },
	{ "question": "交友", "answers": [ "こうゆう" ], "comment": "friend; companion; acquaintance\nfriendship; companionship" },
	{ "question": "交差", "answers": [ "こうさ" ], "comment": "crossing; intersection\n(genetic) crossing over" },
	{ "question": "交差点", "answers": [ "こうさてん" ], "comment": "crossing; intersection" },
	{ "question": "交戦", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "war; battle; hostilities" },
	{ "question": "交換", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "exchange; interchange; switching; reciprocity; barter; substitution; replacement; clearing (of checks, cheques)" },
	{ "question": "交易", "answers": [ "こうえき" ], "comment": "trade; commerce" },
	{ "question": "交替", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "alternation; change; relief; relay; shift; substitution (sports, etc.); taking turns" },
	{ "question": "交流", "answers": [ "こうりゅう" ], "comment": "(cultural) exchange; interchange; interaction; (inter-) mingling; (social, etc.) networking; intercourse\nalternating current; AC" },
	{ "question": "交渉", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "negotiations; discussions\nconnection" },
	{ "question": "交番", "answers": [ "こうばん" ], "comment": "police box; small neighborhood police station\nalternation; alternating (e.g. current)" },
	{ "question": "交通", "answers": [ "こうつう" ], "comment": "traffic; transportation; communication; exchange (of ideas, etc.); intercourse" },
	{ "question": "交通事故", "answers": [ "こうつうじこ" ], "comment": "traffic accident" },
	{ "question": "交通機関", "answers": [ "こうつうきかん" ], "comment": "transportation facilities" },
	{ "question": "交通網", "answers": [ "こうつうもう" ], "comment": "transportation network; transport network; traffic network" },
	{ "question": "交通費", "answers": [ "こうつうひ" ], "comment": "traveling expenses; travelling expenses; carfare" },
	{ "question": "交際", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "company; friendship; association; society; acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "交際費", "answers": [ "こうさいひ" ], "comment": "entertainment expenses" },
	{ "question": "交響曲", "answers": [ "こうきょうきょく" ], "comment": "symphony" },
	{ "question": "交響楽", "answers": [ "こうきょうがく" ], "comment": "symphony (orchestra)" },
	{ "question": "享受", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "reception; acceptance; enjoyment; being given" },
	{ "question": "京", "answers": [ "きょう", "けい" ], "comment": "imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)\nfinal word of an iroha-uta\n10^16; 10,000,000,000,000,000; ten quadrillion" },
	{ "question": "京都", "answers": [ "きょうと" ], "comment": "Kyoto" },
	{ "question": "京阪", "answers": [ "けいはん" ], "comment": "Kyoto-Osaka" },
	{ "question": "亭主", "answers": [ "ていしゅ" ], "comment": "household head; master; host (e.g. of a tea gathering); innkeeper; owner (e.g. of an hotel)\nhusband" },
	{ "question": "人", "answers": [ "ひと", "にん", "じん", "り", "たり" ], "comment": "-ian (e.g. Italian); -ite (e.g. Tokyoite); indicates nationality, race, origin, etc.\n-er (e.g. performer, etc.); person working with ...; indicates expertise (in a certain field)\n(usu. in compound words) man; person; people /\n counter for people\nperson" },
	{ "question": "人々", "answers": [ "にんにん", "ひとびと" ], "comment": "each person; people; men and women; everybody" },
	{ "question": "人ごみ", "answers": [ "ひとごみ" ], "comment": "crowd of people" },
	{ "question": "人たち", "answers": [ "ひとたち" ], "comment": "people" },
	{ "question": "人だかり", "answers": [ "ひとだかり" ], "comment": "crowd; throng" },
	{ "question": "人一倍", "answers": [ "ひといちばい" ], "comment": "more than others; exceedingly; redoubled; exceptional" },
	{ "question": "人並み", "answers": [ "ひとなみ" ], "comment": "being average (capacity, looks, standard of living); ordinary" },
	{ "question": "人中", "answers": [ "ひとなか" ], "comment": "society; company; the public; the world" },
	{ "question": "人事", "answers": [ "たにんごと", "じんじ", "ひとごと" ], "comment": "personnel affairs; human affairs; human resources; HR /\n other people's affairs; somebody else's problem" },
	{ "question": "人事異動", "answers": [ "じんじいどう" ], "comment": "personnel change; personnel shift; reshuffle; (annual) staff reassignment" },
	{ "question": "人事院", "answers": [ "じんじいん" ], "comment": "National Personnel Authority" },
	{ "question": "人件費", "answers": [ "じんけんひ" ], "comment": "personnel expenses; labor cost; labour cost\nindirect labour costs; indirect labor costs" },
	{ "question": "人体", "answers": [ "じんたい" ], "comment": "human body" },
	{ "question": "人出", "answers": [ "ひとで" ], "comment": "crowd; turnout" },
	{ "question": "人前", "answers": [ "ひとまえ", "にんまえ" ], "comment": "portion of food /\n the public; company" },
	{ "question": "人口", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "population\ncommon talk" },
	{ "question": "人名", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "person's name" },
	{ "question": "人命", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "(human) life" },
	{ "question": "人員", "answers": [ "じんいん" ], "comment": "number of persons; personnel" },
	{ "question": "人妻", "answers": [ "ひとづま" ], "comment": "married woman\nanother's wife" },
	{ "question": "人工", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "artificial; man-made; human work; human skill; artificiality" },
	{ "question": "人工呼吸", "answers": [ "じんこうこきゅう" ], "comment": "artificial respiration" },
	{ "question": "人工的", "answers": [ "じんこうてき" ], "comment": "artificial; unnatural" },
	{ "question": "人工衛星", "answers": [ "じんこうえいせい" ], "comment": "man-made satellite" },
	{ "question": "人差し指", "answers": [ "ひとさしゆび" ], "comment": "index finger; forefinger" },
	{ "question": "人形", "answers": [ "にんぎょう" ], "comment": "doll; puppet; figure" },
	{ "question": "人影", "answers": [ "じんえい", "ひとかげ" ], "comment": "figure of a person; figures of people\nshadow of a person" },
	{ "question": "人心", "answers": [ "ひとごころ", "じんしん" ], "comment": "human nature; human heart; human spirit; kindness; sympathy" },
	{ "question": "人情", "answers": [ "にんじょう" ], "comment": "humanity; empathy; kindness; sympathy\nhuman nature; common sense; customs and manners" },
	{ "question": "人数", "answers": [ "ひとかず", "にんずう", "にんず" ], "comment": "the number of people\nmany people; a large number of people" },
	{ "question": "人文", "answers": [ "じんぶん", "じんもん" ], "comment": "humanity; civilization; civilisation; culture" },
	{ "question": "人文科学", "answers": [ "じんぶんかがく" ], "comment": "humanities; social sciences; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "人材", "answers": [ "じんざい" ], "comment": "capable person; talented person\nhuman resources; personnel" },
	{ "question": "人柄", "answers": [ "ひとがら" ], "comment": "personality; character; personal appearance; gentility" },
	{ "question": "人格", "answers": [ "じんかく" ], "comment": "personality; character; individuality" },
	{ "question": "人権", "answers": [ "じんけん" ], "comment": "human rights; civil liberties" },
	{ "question": "人権擁護", "answers": [ "じんけんようご" ], "comment": "protection of human rights" },
	{ "question": "人殺し", "answers": [ "ひとごろし" ], "comment": "murder; murderer" },
	{ "question": "人民", "answers": [ "じんみん" ], "comment": "people; public" },
	{ "question": "人民戦線", "answers": [ "じんみんせんせん" ], "comment": "popular front" },
	{ "question": "人気", "answers": [ "にんき" ], "comment": "popularity; public favor\ncondition (e.g. market); tone; character; nature" },
	{ "question": "人気者", "answers": [ "にんきもの" ], "comment": "popular person; favorite; favourite" },
	{ "question": "人為", "answers": [ "じんい" ], "comment": "human work; human agency; art; artificiality" },
	{ "question": "人為的", "answers": [ "じんいてき" ], "comment": "artificial; unnatural" },
	{ "question": "人物", "answers": [ "じんぶつ" ], "comment": "person; character; figure; personage; man; woman\none's character; one's personality\nable person; talented person" },
	{ "question": "人生", "answers": [ "じんせい" ], "comment": "(human) life (i.e. conception to death)" },
	{ "question": "人生観", "answers": [ "じんせいかん" ], "comment": "view of life" },
	{ "question": "人的", "answers": [ "じんてき" ], "comment": "human; personal" },
	{ "question": "人目", "answers": [ "ひとめ", "じんもく" ], "comment": "public gaze; public notice; attention" },
	{ "question": "人相", "answers": [ "にんそう" ], "comment": "looks; countenance; facial features\nphysiognomy" },
	{ "question": "人種", "answers": [ "じんしゅ" ], "comment": "race (of people)\ntype of person" },
	{ "question": "人脈", "answers": [ "じんみゃく" ], "comment": "personal connections" },
	{ "question": "人見知り", "answers": [ "ひとみしり" ], "comment": "shyness; fear of strangers; stranger anxiety" },
	{ "question": "人質", "answers": [ "ひとじち" ], "comment": "hostage" },
	{ "question": "人通り", "answers": [ "ひとどおり" ], "comment": "pedestrian traffic" },
	{ "question": "人造", "answers": [ "じんぞう" ], "comment": "man-made; synthetic; artificial" },
	{ "question": "人道", "answers": [ "じんどう", "にんどう" ], "comment": "humanity\nsidewalk; footpath\nhuman realm" },
	{ "question": "人道主義", "answers": [ "じんどうしゅぎ" ], "comment": "humanism; humanitarianism" },
	{ "question": "人道的", "answers": [ "じんどうてき" ], "comment": "humane" },
	{ "question": "人達", "answers": [ "ひとたち" ], "comment": "people" },
	{ "question": "人違い", "answers": [ "ひとちがい" ], "comment": "mistaking one person for another; (case of) mistaken identity" },
	{ "question": "人選", "answers": [ "じんせん" ], "comment": "personnel selection" },
	{ "question": "人間", "answers": [ "にんげん" ], "comment": "human being; person; man; mankind; humankind\ncharacter (of a person)" },
	{ "question": "人間ドック", "answers": [ "にんげんドック" ], "comment": "medical check-up; thorough physical examination" },
	{ "question": "人間像", "answers": [ "にんげんぞう" ], "comment": "image of (an ideal) person" },
	{ "question": "人間国宝", "answers": [ "にんげんこくほう" ], "comment": "living national treasure" },
	{ "question": "人間性", "answers": [ "にんげんせい" ], "comment": "humanity; human nature" },
	{ "question": "人間的", "answers": [ "にんげんてき" ], "comment": "human; human-like; as a person" },
	{ "question": "人間関係", "answers": [ "にんげんかんけい" ], "comment": "human relations" },
	{ "question": "人類", "answers": [ "じんるい" ], "comment": "mankind; humanity" },
	{ "question": "人類学", "answers": [ "じんるいがく" ], "comment": "anthropology" },
	{ "question": "人骨", "answers": [ "じんこつ" ], "comment": "human bones" },
	{ "question": "仁", "answers": [ "にん", "じん" ], "comment": "benevolence (esp. as a virtue of Confucianism); consideration; compassion; humanity; charity\nhuman\nkernel\nnucleolus" },
	{ "question": "今", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "now; the present time; just now; soon; immediately; (one) more" },
	{ "question": "今ごろ", "answers": [ "いまごろ" ], "comment": "about this time" },
	{ "question": "今すぐ", "answers": [ "いますぐ" ], "comment": "at once; immediately; right now" },
	{ "question": "今に", "answers": [ "いまに" ], "comment": "before long; even now" },
	{ "question": "今にも", "answers": [ "いまにも" ], "comment": "at any time; soon" },
	{ "question": "今まで", "answers": [ "いままで" ], "comment": "until now; so far; up to the present" },
	{ "question": "今や", "answers": [ "いまや" ], "comment": "now (esp. in contrast to the past); now at last; at present; right now" },
	{ "question": "今回", "answers": [ "こんかい" ], "comment": "now; this time; lately" },
	{ "question": "今夏", "answers": [ "こんか" ], "comment": "this summer; next summer; last summer" },
	{ "question": "今夜", "answers": [ "こんや" ], "comment": "this evening; tonight" },
	{ "question": "今季", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "this season" },
	{ "question": "今年", "answers": [ "こんねん", "ことし" ], "comment": "this year" },
	{ "question": "今年度", "answers": [ "こんねんど" ], "comment": "this year; this fiscal year; this school year" },
	{ "question": "今度", "answers": [ "こんど" ], "comment": "this time; now\nnext time; another time; shortly; soon\nrecently; previous; last" },
	{ "question": "今後", "answers": [ "こんご" ], "comment": "from now on; hereafter" },
	{ "question": "今日", "answers": [ "こんにち", "こんち", "きょう", "こんじつ" ], "comment": "today; this day\nthese days; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "今日この頃", "answers": [ "きょうこのごろ" ], "comment": "these days; nowadays; recently" },
	{ "question": "今日的", "answers": [ "こんにちてき" ], "comment": "modern; up-to-date" },
	{ "question": "今春", "answers": [ "こんしゅん" ], "comment": "this spring; spring this year" },
	{ "question": "今晩", "answers": [ "こんばん" ], "comment": "tonight; this evening" },
	{ "question": "今更", "answers": [ "いまさら" ], "comment": "now (after such a long time); at this late hour (i.e. it is too late for something); at this point of time\nafresh; anew; again" },
	{ "question": "今月", "answers": [ "こんげつ" ], "comment": "this month" },
	{ "question": "今朝", "answers": [ "けさ", "こんちょう" ], "comment": "this morning" },
	{ "question": "今期", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "the present term" },
	{ "question": "今秋", "answers": [ "こんしゅう" ], "comment": "this (next, last) autumn (fall)" },
	{ "question": "今週", "answers": [ "こんしゅう" ], "comment": "this week" },
	{ "question": "今頃", "answers": [ "いまごろ" ], "comment": "about this time" },
	{ "question": "介入", "answers": [ "かいにゅう" ], "comment": "intervention" },
	{ "question": "介助", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "help; assistance; aid\nto assist; to help; to aid" },
	{ "question": "介在", "answers": [ "かいざい" ], "comment": "mediation; interposition; intervention" },
	{ "question": "介護", "answers": [ "かいご" ], "comment": "nursing; care; caregiving; caring" },
	{ "question": "仏", "answers": [ "ほとけ" ], "comment": "Buddha; merciful person; Buddhist image\nthe dead; dead person; spirit of the dead" },
	{ "question": "仏像", "answers": [ "ぶつぞう" ], "comment": "statue of Buddha; image of Buddha; Buddhist statue; Buddhist image" },
	{ "question": "仏壇", "answers": [ "ぶつだん" ], "comment": "Buddhist (household) altar" },
	{ "question": "仏教", "answers": [ "ぶっきょう" ], "comment": "Buddhism" },
	{ "question": "仏文", "answers": [ "ふつぶん" ], "comment": "French; French writing; French literature" },
	{ "question": "仏語", "answers": [ "ふつご" ], "comment": "French (language)" },
	{ "question": "仕上がり", "answers": [ "しあがり" ], "comment": "finish; end; completion" },
	{ "question": "仕上げ", "answers": [ "しあげ" ], "comment": "end; finishing touches; being finished" },
	{ "question": "仕上げる", "answers": [ "しあげる" ], "comment": "to finish up; to complete; to finish off; to get through; to polish off" },
	{ "question": "仕事", "answers": [ "しごと" ], "comment": "work; job; business; occupation; employment; vocation; task\nwork" },
	{ "question": "仕事中", "answers": [ "しごとちゅう" ], "comment": "at work; in the midst of work; working" },
	{ "question": "仕事場", "answers": [ "しごとば" ], "comment": "place where one works; construction site; working area" },
	{ "question": "仕事始め", "answers": [ "しごとはじめ" ], "comment": "resuming work after the New Year's vacation; first time that one works in the year" },
	{ "question": "仕入れ", "answers": [ "しいれ" ], "comment": "stocking; buying up" },
	{ "question": "仕入れる", "answers": [ "しいれる" ], "comment": "to lay in stock; to replenish stock; to procure; to learn something that might be useful later" },
	{ "question": "仕出し", "answers": [ "しだし" ], "comment": "catering; shipment" },
	{ "question": "仕切り", "answers": [ "しきり" ], "comment": "partition; division; boundary; compartment\nsettlement of accounts\npreliminary warm-up ritual; toeing the mark\ndirecting; controlling; managing; taking responsibility for" },
	{ "question": "仕掛け", "answers": [ "しかけ" ], "comment": "device; contrivance; mechanism; gadget\ntrick; trap; calculated manipulation; gambit\n(small) scale; half finished\ncommencement; initiation\nset up; laying out; preparation\nchallenge; attack" },
	{ "question": "仕掛ける", "answers": [ "しかける" ], "comment": "to start; to begin; to commence\nto challenge; to pick (a fight); to make (war)\nto set (traps); to plant (explosives); to lay (mines)" },
	{ "question": "仕方", "answers": [ "しかた" ], "comment": "way; method; means; resource; course" },
	{ "question": "仕方がない", "answers": [ "しかたがない" ], "comment": "it can't be helped; it's inevitable; it's no use; can't stand it; being impatient; being annoyed" },
	{ "question": "仕方ない", "answers": [ "しかたない" ], "comment": "it can't be helped; it's inevitable; it's no use; can't stand it; impatient; annoyed" },
	{ "question": "仕業", "answers": [ "しわざ" ], "comment": "deed (esp. negative); act; action; one's doing" },
	{ "question": "仕様", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "way; method; means; resource; remedy\n(technical) specification" },
	{ "question": "仕立て", "answers": [ "したて" ], "comment": "tailoring; dressmaking; sewing; making; preparation" },
	{ "question": "仕立てる", "answers": [ "したてる" ], "comment": "to tailor; to make (clothing)\nto train; to bring up\nto make it seem like; to pass off\nto turn into a play or movie\nto prepare; to send; to despatch" },
	{ "question": "仕組み", "answers": [ "しくみ" ], "comment": "structure; construction; arrangement; contrivance; mechanism; workings\nplan; plot; contrivance" },
	{ "question": "仕草", "answers": [ "しぐさ" ], "comment": "action; acting; gesture; bearing; treatment; behavior; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "仕込み", "answers": [ "しこみ" ], "comment": "training; education; upbringing\nstocking up; laying in\npreparation (e.g. ingredients)\ngirl studying to become a geisha" },
	{ "question": "仕送り", "answers": [ "しおくり" ], "comment": "allowance; remittance; sending (someone) an allowance" },
	{ "question": "他", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "other (esp. people and abstract matters)" },
	{ "question": "他に", "answers": [ "ほかに" ], "comment": "in addition; besides" },
	{ "question": "他人", "answers": [ "たにん", "ひと" ], "comment": "another person; other people; others\nunrelated person (i.e. not related by blood)\noutsider; stranger" },
	{ "question": "他人事", "answers": [ "たにんごと", "ひとごと" ], "comment": "other people's affairs; somebody else's problem" },
	{ "question": "他国", "answers": [ "たこく" ], "comment": "foreign country; other country\nanother province\nstrange land; alien land" },
	{ "question": "他方", "answers": [ "たほう" ], "comment": "one (esp. of two); the other; one way; the other way; one direction; the other direction; one side; the other side; one party; the other party\non the other hand" },
	{ "question": "他殺", "answers": [ "たさつ" ], "comment": "murder" },
	{ "question": "他派", "answers": [ "たは" ], "comment": "the other group" },
	{ "question": "他社", "answers": [ "たしゃ" ], "comment": "another company; other company" },
	{ "question": "他者", "answers": [ "たしゃ" ], "comment": "another person; others" },
	{ "question": "他面", "answers": [ "ためん" ], "comment": "other side; another side; different angle\non the other hand" },
	{ "question": "付き合い", "answers": [ "つきあい" ], "comment": "association; socializing; socialising; fellowship" },
	{ "question": "付き合う", "answers": [ "つきあう" ], "comment": "to associate with; to keep company with; to go out with; to go steady with; to get on with\nto go along with; to follow someone's lead; to accompany someone; to compromise" },
	{ "question": "付き添い", "answers": [ "つきそい" ], "comment": "attendance on; attendant; escort; chaperon; retinue" },
	{ "question": "付く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to be attached; to be connected with; to adhere; to stick; to cling\nto remain imprinted; to scar; to stain; to dye\nto bear (fruit, interest, etc.)\nto be acquired (of a habit, ability, etc.); to increase (of strength, etc.)\nto take root\nto accompany; to attend; to follow; to study with\nto side with; to belong to\nto possess; to haunt\nto be lit; to be lighted\nto be settled; to be resolved; to be decided\nto be given (of a name, price, etc.)\nto be sensed; to be perceived\nto be lucky\nto become (a state, condition, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "付ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment)\nto furnish (a house with)\nto wear; to put on\nto keep a diary; to make an entry\nto appraise; to set (a price)\nto allot; to budget; to assign\nto bring alongside\nto place (under guard or doctor)\nto follow; to shadow\nto load; to give (courage to)\nto keep (an eye on)\nto establish (relations or understanding)\nto turn on (light)\nto produce flowers; to produce fruit" },
	{ "question": "付け加える", "answers": [ "つけくわえる" ], "comment": "to add one thing to another" },
	{ "question": "付け根", "answers": [ "つけね" ], "comment": "root; joint; base; crotch" },
	{ "question": "付け足す", "answers": [ "つけたす" ], "comment": "to add to" },
	{ "question": "付け込む", "answers": [ "つけこむ" ], "comment": "to take advantage of; to impose on\nto make an entry (in an account book)" },
	{ "question": "付与", "answers": [ "ふよ" ], "comment": "grant; allowance; endowment; bestowal; assignment; conferment" },
	{ "question": "付加", "answers": [ "ふか" ], "comment": "addition; annexation; appendage" },
	{ "question": "付属", "answers": [ "ふぞく" ], "comment": "attached; belonging (to); included; enclosed; affiliated; annexed; associated; subordinate; incidental; dependent; auxiliary" },
	{ "question": "付帯", "answers": [ "ふたい" ], "comment": "incidental; ancillary; accessory; secondary; collateral" },
	{ "question": "付添い", "answers": [ "つきそい" ], "comment": "attendance on; attendant; escort; chaperon; retinue" },
	{ "question": "付着", "answers": [ "ふちゃく" ], "comment": "sticking to; clinging to; adhesion; cohesion; agglutination" },
	{ "question": "付近", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity; environs\napproaching" },
	{ "question": "付録", "answers": [ "ふろく" ], "comment": "appendix; supplement; annex; extra (of a newspaper or magazine)" },
	{ "question": "代", "answers": [ "よ" ], "comment": "world; society; age; generation" },
	{ "question": "代々", "answers": [ "よよ", "だいだい" ], "comment": "for generations; hereditary; generation after generation" },
	{ "question": "代える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "代わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "substitute; replacement; substituting; replacing\nstand-in; proxy; alternate; deputy; relief; successor\ncompensation; exchange; return\nsecond helping; another cup; seconds\nupcoming program; upcoming programme" },
	{ "question": "代わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to succeed; to relieve; to replace\nto take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent\nto be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch" },
	{ "question": "代わる代わる", "answers": [ "かわるがわる" ], "comment": "alternately; by turns" },
	{ "question": "代人", "answers": [ "だいにん" ], "comment": "substitute; deputy; proxy; representative; agent" },
	{ "question": "代代", "answers": [ "よよ", "だいだい" ], "comment": "for generations; hereditary; generation after generation" },
	{ "question": "代償", "answers": [ "だいしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; indemnification; reparation; consideration" },
	{ "question": "代名詞", "answers": [ "だいめいし" ], "comment": "pronoun\nsynonym; classic example; pattern; byword; representative" },
	{ "question": "代官", "answers": [ "だいかん" ], "comment": "Edo-period prefectural governor (magistrate, bailiff)" },
	{ "question": "代弁", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "pay by proxy; act for another; speak for another" },
	{ "question": "代役", "answers": [ "だいやく" ], "comment": "substitute (e.g. actor); substitution; stand-in; double" },
	{ "question": "代打", "answers": [ "だいだ" ], "comment": "pinch-hitting" },
	{ "question": "代替", "answers": [ "だいたい", "だいがえ" ], "comment": "substitution; alternation\nalternative; substitute" },
	{ "question": "代理", "answers": [ "だいり" ], "comment": "representation; agency; proxy; deputy; agent; attorney; substitute; alternate; acting (principal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "代理店", "answers": [ "だいりてん" ], "comment": "agent; agency" },
	{ "question": "代用", "answers": [ "だいよう" ], "comment": "substitution" },
	{ "question": "代行", "answers": [ "だいこう" ], "comment": "acting as agent" },
	{ "question": "代表", "answers": [ "だいひょう" ], "comment": "representative; representation; delegation; type; example; model" },
	{ "question": "代表作", "answers": [ "だいひょうさく" ], "comment": "most important work (of a writer, artist, etc.); representative work; masterpiece" },
	{ "question": "代表的", "answers": [ "だいひょうてき" ], "comment": "representative; exemplary; model" },
	{ "question": "代謝", "answers": [ "たいしゃ" ], "comment": "renewal; regeneration; metabolism" },
	{ "question": "代議", "answers": [ "だいぎ" ], "comment": "representing others in a conference" },
	{ "question": "代議士", "answers": [ "だいぎし" ], "comment": "parliamentarian; member of a congress" },
	{ "question": "代金", "answers": [ "だいきん" ], "comment": "price; cost; charge; payment; bill; fee" },
	{ "question": "令", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "command; order; dictation" },
	{ "question": "令状", "answers": [ "れいじょう" ], "comment": "warrant; summons; written order" },
	{ "question": "以上", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "not less than; ... and more; ... and upwards\nbeyond ... (e.g. one's means); further (e.g. nothing further to say); more than ... (e.g. cannot pay more than that)\nabove-mentioned; foregoing\nsince ...; seeing that ...\nthis is all; that is the end; the end" },
	{ "question": "以下", "answers": [ "いげ", "いか" ], "comment": "not exceeding; and downward; ... and below\nbelow (e.g. standard); under (e.g. a level)\nthe below-mentioned; the following; the rest" },
	{ "question": "以内", "answers": [ "いない" ], "comment": "within; inside of; less than" },
	{ "question": "以前", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "ago; since; before; previous" },
	{ "question": "以外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "with the exception of; excepting" },
	{ "question": "以後", "answers": [ "いご" ], "comment": "after this; from now on; hereafter\nthereafter; since (verb) (after -te form of verb); after (time); since (then)" },
	{ "question": "以来", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "since; henceforth" },
	{ "question": "以降", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "on and after; as from; hereafter; thereafter; since" },
	{ "question": "仮", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "temporary; provisional; interim\nfictitious; assumed (name); alias\nhypothetical; theoretical" },
	{ "question": "仮に", "answers": [ "かりに" ], "comment": "temporarily; provisionally; for the time being\nsupposing; for argument's sake" },
	{ "question": "仮処分", "answers": [ "かりしょぶん" ], "comment": "provisional disposition; temporary injunction" },
	{ "question": "仮名", "answers": [ "かな", "かめい" ], "comment": "alias; pseudonym; pen name; nom de plume /\n kana; Japanese syllabary (i.e. hiragana, katakana)" },
	{ "question": "仮名遣い", "answers": [ "かなづかい" ], "comment": "kana orthography; syllabary spelling" },
	{ "question": "仮定", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "assumption; supposition; hypothesis" },
	{ "question": "仮想", "answers": [ "かそう" ], "comment": "imagination; supposition; virtual; potential (enemy)" },
	{ "question": "仮称", "answers": [ "かしょう" ], "comment": "temporary name; provisional name" },
	{ "question": "仮設", "answers": [ "かせつ" ], "comment": "temporary; provisional\nto do something temporarily (esp. build temporary facilities); to do something provisionally" },
	{ "question": "仮説", "answers": [ "かせつ" ], "comment": "hypothesis; supposition; fictional" },
	{ "question": "仮面", "answers": [ "かめん" ], "comment": "mask\ndisguise" },
	{ "question": "仮題", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "tentative title" },
	{ "question": "仰ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "to look up (at)\nto look up (to); to respect; to revere\nto ask for; to seek\nto turn to someone; to depend on\nto gulp down; to quaff; to take (e.g. poison)" },
	{ "question": "仰向け", "answers": [ "あおむけ" ], "comment": "face up" },
	{ "question": "仲", "answers": [ "なか" ], "comment": "relation; relationship" },
	{ "question": "仲人", "answers": [ "ちゅうにん", "なこうど" ], "comment": "matchmaker\ngo-between; intermediary; middleman; mediator; intercessor" },
	{ "question": "仲介", "answers": [ "ちゅうかい" ], "comment": "agency; intermediation" },
	{ "question": "仲直り", "answers": [ "なかなおり" ], "comment": "reconciliation; make peace with" },
	{ "question": "仲良く", "answers": [ "なかよく" ], "comment": "on good terms with; on cordial terms with; getting along well with; happily; peacefully\nto make friends with; to be good friends with; to get along with" },
	{ "question": "仲良し", "answers": [ "なかよし" ], "comment": "intimate friend; close friend; bosom buddy; chum" },
	{ "question": "仲裁", "answers": [ "ちゅうさい" ], "comment": "arbitration; intercession; mediation" },
	{ "question": "仲買", "answers": [ "なかがい" ], "comment": "brokerage" },
	{ "question": "仲間", "answers": [ "なかま" ], "comment": "company; fellow; colleague; associate; comrade; mate; group; circle of friends; partner\nmember of the same category" },
	{ "question": "仲間入り", "answers": [ "なかまいり" ], "comment": "joining a group" },
	{ "question": "件", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "matter; case; item; affair; subject" },
	{ "question": "件数", "answers": [ "けんすう" ], "comment": "number of events (e.g. accidents, crimes, meetings, housing starts, hits on a web page)" },
	{ "question": "任", "answers": [ "にん" ], "comment": "obligation; duty; charge; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "任す", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "to entrust; to leave to a person" },
	{ "question": "任せる", "answers": [ "まかせる" ], "comment": "to entrust (e.g. a task) to another; to leave to\nto passively leave to someone else's facilities\nto leave to take its natural course\nto continue (something) in a natural fashion (without particular aim)\nto rely fully on one's (full strength, great ability, long time taken) to get something done" },
	{ "question": "任務", "answers": [ "にんむ" ], "comment": "duty; function; office; mission; task" },
	{ "question": "任命", "answers": [ "にんめい" ], "comment": "appointment; nomination; ordination; commission; designation" },
	{ "question": "任意", "answers": [ "にんい" ], "comment": "optional; voluntary; arbitrary; random; discretionary; facultative; spontaneous; any\narbitrary" },
	{ "question": "任期", "answers": [ "にんき" ], "comment": "term of office" },
	{ "question": "企てる", "answers": [ "くわだてる" ], "comment": "to plan; to plot; to propose; to design; to intend; to contemplate\nto attempt (e.g. suicide, murder); to undertake (e.g. business)\nto stand on tip-toes" },
	{ "question": "企み", "answers": [ "たくらみ" ], "comment": "plan; design; artifice; trick; intrigue" },
	{ "question": "企業", "answers": [ "きぎょう" ], "comment": "enterprise; undertaking; corporation; business" },
	{ "question": "企業家", "answers": [ "きぎょうか" ], "comment": "industrialist; entrepreneur" },
	{ "question": "企画", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "planning; project; plan; design" },
	{ "question": "企画室", "answers": [ "きかくしつ" ], "comment": "planning office" },
	{ "question": "伏せる", "answers": [ "ふせる" ], "comment": "to lay something upside down; to turn something over; to lay something face down\nto cover; to lay (pipes); to lay (an ambush); to hide; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "伏兵", "answers": [ "ふくへい" ], "comment": "ambush; troops in ambush" },
	{ "question": "伏線", "answers": [ "ふくせん" ], "comment": "foreshadowing\npreparation; precautionary measures" },
	{ "question": "伐採", "answers": [ "ばっさい" ], "comment": "lumbering; felling; deforestation" },
	{ "question": "休する", "answers": [ "きゅうする" ], "comment": "to come to an end\nto rest" },
	{ "question": "休まる", "answers": [ "やすまる" ], "comment": "to be rested; to feel at ease; to repose; to be relieved" },
	{ "question": "休み", "answers": [ "やすみ" ], "comment": "rest; recess; respite\nvacation; holiday; absence; suspension\ndormancy (of a silkworm prior to moulting)" },
	{ "question": "休む", "answers": [ "やすむ" ], "comment": "to be absent; to take a day off\nto rest; to have a break\nto go to bed; to (lie down to) sleep; to turn in; to retire\nto stop doing some ongoing activity for a time; to suspend business" },
	{ "question": "休める", "answers": [ "やすめる" ], "comment": "to rest; to suspend; to give relief" },
	{ "question": "休刊", "answers": [ "きゅうかん" ], "comment": "suspension of publication" },
	{ "question": "休場", "answers": [ "きゅうじょう" ], "comment": "theater closure; theatre closure; stage absence\nwrestler's absence from the tournament" },
	{ "question": "休学", "answers": [ "きゅうがく" ], "comment": "temporary absence from school" },
	{ "question": "休息", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "rest; relief; relaxation" },
	{ "question": "休憩", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "rest; break; recess; intermission" },
	{ "question": "休憩所", "answers": [ "きゅうけいじょ" ], "comment": "rest area; rest stop; service area; SA; parking area (e.g. off highways); PA" },
	{ "question": "休戦", "answers": [ "きゅうせん" ], "comment": "cease-fire; truce; armistice" },
	{ "question": "休日", "answers": [ "きゅうじつ" ], "comment": "holiday; day off" },
	{ "question": "休暇", "answers": [ "きゅうか" ], "comment": "holiday; day off; furlough; absence (from work)" },
	{ "question": "休校", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "closing school (temporarily); dropping one's studies" },
	{ "question": "休業", "answers": [ "きゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "closed (e.g. store); business suspended; shutdown; holiday" },
	{ "question": "休止", "answers": [ "きゅうし" ], "comment": "pause; cessation; rest" },
	{ "question": "休職", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "temporary retirement; suspension from office" },
	{ "question": "休講", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "lecture cancellation; cancelling (lecture, class, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "休養", "answers": [ "きゅうよう" ], "comment": "rest; break; recreation" },
	{ "question": "休館", "answers": [ "きゅうかん" ], "comment": "closure (of a library, museum, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "会", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "meeting; assembly; party\nassociation; club" },
	{ "question": "会合", "answers": [ "かいごう" ], "comment": "meeting; assembly; gathering\nassociation\nconjunction" },
	{ "question": "会員", "answers": [ "かいいん" ], "comment": "member; the membership" },
	{ "question": "会堂", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "church; chapel; synagogue; tabernacle" },
	{ "question": "会報", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "bulletin; report" },
	{ "question": "会場", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; meeting place; venue; grounds" },
	{ "question": "会心", "answers": [ "かいしん" ], "comment": "congeniality; satisfaction" },
	{ "question": "会期", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "session (of a legislature)" },
	{ "question": "会社", "answers": [ "かいしゃ" ], "comment": "company; corporation\nworkplace" },
	{ "question": "会社更生法", "answers": [ "かいしゃこうせいほう" ], "comment": "Corporate Rehabilitation Law" },
	{ "question": "会見", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "interview; audience" },
	{ "question": "会計", "answers": [ "かいけい" ], "comment": "account; finance; accountant; treasurer; paymaster; reckoning; bill" },
	{ "question": "会計年度", "answers": [ "かいけいねんど" ], "comment": "fiscal year" },
	{ "question": "会計検査院", "answers": [ "かいけいけんさいん" ], "comment": "Board of Audit" },
	{ "question": "会話", "answers": [ "かいわ" ], "comment": "conversation" },
	{ "question": "会談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "conversation; conference (usu. between important people); discussion; interview" },
	{ "question": "会議", "answers": [ "かいぎ" ], "comment": "meeting; conference; session; assembly; council; convention; congress" },
	{ "question": "会議室", "answers": [ "かいぎしつ" ], "comment": "conference room; council room" },
	{ "question": "会費", "answers": [ "かいひ" ], "comment": "membership fee" },
	{ "question": "会釈", "answers": [ "えしゃく" ], "comment": "slight bow (as a greeting or sign of gratitude); nod; salutation\nconsideration; thoughtfulness" },
	{ "question": "会長", "answers": [ "かいちょう" ], "comment": "president (of a society); chairman" },
	{ "question": "会頭", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "society president" },
	{ "question": "会食", "answers": [ "かいしょく" ], "comment": "dining together; mess" },
	{ "question": "会館", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "meeting hall; assembly hall" },
	{ "question": "伝う", "answers": [ "つたう" ], "comment": "to go along; to walk along; to follow" },
	{ "question": "伝える", "answers": [ "つたえる" ], "comment": "to convey; to report; to transmit; to communicate; to tell; to impart; to propagate; to teach; to bequeath" },
	{ "question": "伝わる", "answers": [ "つたわる" ], "comment": "to be handed down; to be introduced; to be transmitted; to be circulated; to go along; to walk along" },
	{ "question": "伝承", "answers": [ "でんしょう" ], "comment": "handing down (information); legend; tradition; folklore; transmission" },
	{ "question": "伝染", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "contagion; infection" },
	{ "question": "伝染病", "answers": [ "でんせんびょう" ], "comment": "infectious disease; contagious disease; epidemic" },
	{ "question": "伝票", "answers": [ "でんぴょう" ], "comment": "chit; sales slip; voucher" },
	{ "question": "伝統", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "tradition; convention" },
	{ "question": "伝統文化", "answers": [ "でんとうぶんか" ], "comment": "traditional culture" },
	{ "question": "伝統的", "answers": [ "でんとうてき" ], "comment": "traditional; conventional" },
	{ "question": "伝言", "answers": [ "でんごん" ], "comment": "verbal message; word" },
	{ "question": "伝記", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "biography; life story" },
	{ "question": "伝説", "answers": [ "でんせつ" ], "comment": "tradition; legend; folklore" },
	{ "question": "伝送", "answers": [ "でんそう" ], "comment": "transmission; communication; circulation; dissemination; diffusion; propagation; delivery" },
	{ "question": "伝道", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "proselytizing; evangelism; missionary work" },
	{ "question": "伝達", "answers": [ "でんたつ" ], "comment": "transmission (e.g. news, chemical signals, electricity); communication; delivery; conveyance; transfer; relay; propagation; conduction" },
	{ "question": "伯母", "answers": [ "はくぼ", "おば", "しゅくぼ" ], "comment": "aunt" },
	{ "question": "伯爵", "answers": [ "はくしゃく" ], "comment": "count; earl" },
	{ "question": "伯父", "answers": [ "はくふ", "しゅくふ", "おじ" ], "comment": "uncle" },
	{ "question": "伴", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "companion; follower; attendant; retinue" },
	{ "question": "伴う", "answers": [ "ともなう" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go hand in hand with; to be consequent upon\nto be accompanied by; to bring with; to take with; to be involved in" },
	{ "question": "伴奏", "answers": [ "ばんそう" ], "comment": "(musical) accompaniment" },
	{ "question": "伸し", "answers": [ "のし" ], "comment": "stretching\nsidestroke (in swimming)" },
	{ "question": "伸ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "to grow long (e.g. hair, nails)\nto lengthen; to extend; to stretch\nto reach out; to hold out\nto straighten; to smooth out\nto spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.)\nto dilute; to thin out\nto postpone\nto prolong\nto strengthen; to develop; to expand" },
	{ "question": "伸び", "answers": [ "のび" ], "comment": "growth; development\nstretching (e.g. body when waking up)\nspread; elongation; extension; carry (e.g. of sound); sustain" },
	{ "question": "伸びやか", "answers": [ "のびやか" ], "comment": "comfortable; carefree" },
	{ "question": "伸びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "to stretch; to extend; to lengthen; to spread\nto make progress; to grow (beard, body height)\nto grow stale (soba)\nto be straightened; to be flattened; to be smoothed\nto be exhausted\nto be postponed; to be prolonged" },
	{ "question": "伸び悩む", "answers": [ "のびなやむ" ], "comment": "to be sluggish (business); to make little progress; to not grow as much as expected" },
	{ "question": "伸び率", "answers": [ "のびりつ" ], "comment": "growth rate; coefficient of extension" },
	{ "question": "伺う", "answers": [ "うかがう" ], "comment": "to ask; to inquire; to hear; to be told\nto implore (a god for an oracle); to seek direction (from your superior)\nto visit\nto speak to (a large crowd at a theatre, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "似せる", "answers": [ "にせる" ], "comment": "to copy; to imitate; to counterfeit; to forge" },
	{ "question": "似る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "to resemble; to look like; to take after\nto be similar (in status, condition, etc.); to be close; to be alike; to be like" },
	{ "question": "似合い", "answers": [ "にあい" ], "comment": "well-matched; becoming; suitable" },
	{ "question": "似合う", "answers": [ "にあう" ], "comment": "to suit; to match; to become; to be like" },
	{ "question": "似通う", "answers": [ "にかよう" ], "comment": "to resemble closely" },
	{ "question": "似顔", "answers": [ "にがお" ], "comment": "portrait; likeness" },
	{ "question": "似顔絵", "answers": [ "にがおえ" ], "comment": "portrait; likeness" },
	{ "question": "佃", "answers": [ "つくだ", "てん" ], "comment": "cultivated rice field" },
	{ "question": "位", "answers": [ "くらい", "い" ], "comment": "throne; crown; (nobleman's) seat\ngovernment position; court rank\nsocial standing; rank; class; echelon; rung\ngrade (of quality, etc.); level; tier; rank\ndigit (e.g. the tens, the hundreds, etc.); place\ndegree; extent; amount /\n rank; place (e.g. first place)\ndecimal place\ncounter for ghosts" },
	{ "question": "位置", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "place; situation; position; location" },
	{ "question": "位置付け", "answers": [ "いちづけ", "いちつけ" ], "comment": "placement; fixed position; mapping out; location" },
	{ "question": "位置付ける", "answers": [ "いちづける" ], "comment": "to place (in relation to the whole); to rank; to position; to locate" },
	{ "question": "低い", "answers": [ "ひくい" ], "comment": "low (rank, degree, value, content, quality, etc.)\nlow (position); close to the ground\nshort (height)\ndeep (voice); in a low key; low (volume)" },
	{ "question": "低める", "answers": [ "ひくめる" ], "comment": "to lower; to be lowered" },
	{ "question": "低下", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "fall; decline; lowering; deterioration; degradation" },
	{ "question": "低価格", "answers": [ "ていかかく" ], "comment": "low price" },
	{ "question": "低利", "answers": [ "ていり" ], "comment": "low interest rate" },
	{ "question": "低学年", "answers": [ "ていがくねん" ], "comment": "lower grades of primary school (first, second, and sometimes third grades)" },
	{ "question": "低料金", "answers": [ "ていりょうきん" ], "comment": "low rates" },
	{ "question": "低気圧", "answers": [ "ていきあつ" ], "comment": "low (atmospheric) pressure; low-pressure system; depression; cyclone\nbad temper; foul mood; tense situation" },
	{ "question": "低水準", "answers": [ "ていすいじゅん" ], "comment": "substandard; low-level" },
	{ "question": "低減", "answers": [ "ていげん" ], "comment": "decrease; reduction; fall; depreciation; mitigation" },
	{ "question": "低温", "answers": [ "ていおん" ], "comment": "low temperature" },
	{ "question": "低落", "answers": [ "ていらく" ], "comment": "fall; decline; slump" },
	{ "question": "低調", "answers": [ "ていちょう" ], "comment": "inactive; slow; sluggish; slack; low tone; undertone; dullness; (market) weakness" },
	{ "question": "低迷", "answers": [ "ていめい" ], "comment": "hanging low (over); hovering around (price level); low hanging (e.g. clouds); sluggish (e.g. economy); slump; recession" },
	{ "question": "低音", "answers": [ "ていおん" ], "comment": "low tone; bass; low voice" },
	{ "question": "住", "answers": [ "じゅう" ], "comment": "dwelling; living" },
	{ "question": "住まい", "answers": [ "すまい", "じゅうきょ" ], "comment": "dwelling; house; residence; address" },
	{ "question": "住み心地", "answers": [ "すみごこち" ], "comment": "comfort (in living place)" },
	{ "question": "住む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to live (of humans); to reside; to inhabit; to dwell; to abide" },
	{ "question": "住人", "answers": [ "じゅうにん" ], "comment": "dweller; inhabitant; resident" },
	{ "question": "住宅", "answers": [ "じゅうたく" ], "comment": "residence; housing; residential building" },
	{ "question": "住宅地", "answers": [ "じゅうたくち" ], "comment": "housing district; residential district" },
	{ "question": "住宅街", "answers": [ "じゅうたくがい" ], "comment": "residential area" },
	{ "question": "住専", "answers": [ "じゅうせん" ], "comment": "housing-loan corporation" },
	{ "question": "住居", "answers": [ "すまい", "じゅうきょ" ], "comment": "dwelling; house; residence; address" },
	{ "question": "住所", "answers": [ "じゅうしょ" ], "comment": "address (e.g. of house); residence; domicile" },
	{ "question": "住民", "answers": [ "じゅうみん" ], "comment": "citizens; inhabitants; residents; population" },
	{ "question": "住民票", "answers": [ "じゅうみんひょう" ], "comment": "certificate of residence" },
	{ "question": "住民税", "answers": [ "じゅうみんぜい" ], "comment": "municipal tax" },
	{ "question": "住職", "answers": [ "じゅうしょく" ], "comment": "chief priest (of a Buddhist temple)" },
	{ "question": "体", "answers": [ "からだ" ], "comment": "body\ntorso; trunk\nbuild; physique; constitution\nhealth\ncorpse; dead body" },
	{ "question": "体つき", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "body build; figure" },
	{ "question": "体付き", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "body build; figure" },
	{ "question": "体内", "answers": [ "たいない" ], "comment": "interior of the body" },
	{ "question": "体制", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "order; system; structure; set-up; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "体力", "answers": [ "たいりょく" ], "comment": "stamina; endurance; physical strength; resilience; resistance to disease\nstrength of an organization (e.g. profitability, productivity, economic clout, stability, growth potential)" },
	{ "question": "体勢", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "posture; stance" },
	{ "question": "体型", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "figure; body shape; build; physique; form\nsomatotype; biotype; habitus; (type of) physique" },
	{ "question": "体外受精", "answers": [ "たいがいじゅせい" ], "comment": "in vitro fertilization; in vitro fertilisation" },
	{ "question": "体形", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "figure; body shape; build; physique; form\nsomatotype; biotype; habitus; (type of) physique" },
	{ "question": "体得", "answers": [ "たいとく" ], "comment": "mastery; knack; realization; realisation; experience; comprehension" },
	{ "question": "体感", "answers": [ "たいかん" ], "comment": "bodily sensation; sense; experience" },
	{ "question": "体操", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "gymnastics; physical exercises; calisthenics" },
	{ "question": "体格", "answers": [ "たいかく" ], "comment": "physique; constitution" },
	{ "question": "体温", "answers": [ "たいおん" ], "comment": "temperature; body temperature (human, animal)" },
	{ "question": "体温計", "answers": [ "たいおんけい" ], "comment": "medical thermometer" },
	{ "question": "体積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "capacity; volume" },
	{ "question": "体系", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "system; organization; organisation; architecture" },
	{ "question": "体罰", "answers": [ "たいばつ" ], "comment": "corporal punishment" },
	{ "question": "体育", "answers": [ "たいいく" ], "comment": "physical education; gymnastics; athletics" },
	{ "question": "体育館", "answers": [ "たいいくかん" ], "comment": "gymnasium" },
	{ "question": "体裁", "answers": [ "たいさい", "ていさい" ], "comment": "(outward) appearance\n(proper) format (e.g. of an essay); form; style\nappearances; decency; show; display\nlip-service; insincere words; glib talk" },
	{ "question": "体調", "answers": [ "たいちょう" ], "comment": "physical condition" },
	{ "question": "体質", "answers": [ "たいしつ" ], "comment": "constitution (physical); genetic make-up; predisposition (to disease)\nstructure (e.g. of an organization); innate characteristics; make-up; nature; culture" },
	{ "question": "体重", "answers": [ "たいじゅう" ], "comment": "body weight; one's weight" },
	{ "question": "体長", "answers": [ "たいちょう" ], "comment": "length of an animal (sometimes including and sometimes excluding the tail)" },
	{ "question": "体験", "answers": [ "たいけん" ], "comment": "personal experience; physical experience; one's own experience" },
	{ "question": "何", "answers": [ "なん", "なに" ], "comment": "what\nhow many\nyou-know-what; that\nwhatsit; what's the expression; what do you call them\nwhat?\nhey!" },
	{ "question": "何か", "answers": [ "なんか", "なにか" ], "comment": "something" },
	{ "question": "何かと", "answers": [ "なにかと" ], "comment": "one way or another" },
	{ "question": "何と", "answers": [ "なんと" ], "comment": "what; how; whatever" },
	{ "question": "何とぞ", "answers": [ "なにとぞ" ], "comment": "please; kindly; I beg of you; if it pleases you\nby all means; without fail" },
	{ "question": "何とも", "answers": [ "なんとも", "なにとも" ], "comment": "quite; really; very; extremely\nnothing; not a bit; not at all" },
	{ "question": "何とも言えない", "answers": [ "なんともいえない" ], "comment": "indescribable; inexpressible; unspeakable; indefinable; nobody can tell" },
	{ "question": "何なのか", "answers": [ "なんなのか", "なになのか" ], "comment": "what is it (that); the meaning of something; what something is about" },
	{ "question": "何にも", "answers": [ "なんにも" ], "comment": "nothing at all" },
	{ "question": "何も", "answers": [ "なにも" ], "comment": "nothing (with neg. verbs); not any\nand everything else (with noun plus \"mo\"); all" },
	{ "question": "何より", "answers": [ "なにより" ], "comment": "most; best; above all" },
	{ "question": "何ら", "answers": [ "なんら" ], "comment": "whatever; what; what sort of; any kind of\nnothing whatever (with neg. verb)" },
	{ "question": "何を隠そう", "answers": [ "なにをかくそう" ], "comment": "to be frank with you; to tell you the truth; I'm going to lay my cards on the table" },
	{ "question": "何事", "answers": [ "なにごと" ], "comment": "what; something; everything\nnothing (with neg. verb)\nsomething or other; unspecified matter" },
	{ "question": "何人", "answers": [ "なにびと", "なんびと", "なんぴと" ], "comment": "everyone; every person; all; anyone" },
	{ "question": "何人か", "answers": [ "なんにんか" ], "comment": "some people; a few people; several people" },
	{ "question": "何分", "answers": [ "なにぶん" ], "comment": "some; any; (a) little; of some kind; of some sort\nplease\nanyway; anyhow; at any rate; after all" },
	{ "question": "何十", "answers": [ "なんじゅう" ], "comment": "several tens" },
	{ "question": "何千", "answers": [ "なんぜん" ], "comment": "many thousands" },
	{ "question": "何卒", "answers": [ "なにとぞ" ], "comment": "please; kindly; I beg of you; if it pleases you\nby all means; without fail" },
	{ "question": "何回", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "how many times?" },
	{ "question": "何度", "answers": [ "なんど" ], "comment": "how many times?; how often?" },
	{ "question": "何度でも", "answers": [ "なんどでも" ], "comment": "any number of times" },
	{ "question": "何時", "answers": [ "なんどき", "なんじ" ], "comment": "what time?" },
	{ "question": "何時の間にか", "answers": [ "いつのまにか" ], "comment": "before one knows; before one becomes aware of; unnoticed; unawares" },
	{ "question": "何時頃", "answers": [ "いつごろ" ], "comment": "about when; how soon" },
	{ "question": "何気ない", "answers": [ "なにげない" ], "comment": "casual; unconcerned; nonchalant" },
	{ "question": "何気なく", "answers": [ "なにげなく" ], "comment": "unintentionally; calmly; inadvertently; innocently" },
	{ "question": "何気無く", "answers": [ "なにげなく" ], "comment": "unintentionally; calmly; inadvertently; innocently" },
	{ "question": "何百", "answers": [ "なんびゃく" ], "comment": "hundreds" },
	{ "question": "何者", "answers": [ "なにもの" ], "comment": "who; what kind of person" },
	{ "question": "何遍", "answers": [ "なんべん" ], "comment": "how many times; how often" },
	{ "question": "余す", "answers": [ "あます" ], "comment": "to save; to leave over; to spare" },
	{ "question": "余る", "answers": [ "あまる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left over; to be in excess; to be too many" },
	{ "question": "余人", "answers": [ "よじん", "よにん" ], "comment": "others; other people" },
	{ "question": "余儀ない", "answers": [ "よぎない" ], "comment": "unavoidable; inevitable; beyond one's control" },
	{ "question": "余儀なく", "answers": [ "よぎなく" ], "comment": "unavoidably; necessarily; inevitably" },
	{ "question": "余分", "answers": [ "よぶん" ], "comment": "extra; excess; surplus" },
	{ "question": "余剰", "answers": [ "よじょう" ], "comment": "redundant; surplus; residue; balance" },
	{ "question": "余力", "answers": [ "よりょく" ], "comment": "spare energy, time or money; remaining strength; reserve power; money to spare" },
	{ "question": "余命", "answers": [ "よめい" ], "comment": "remainder of one's life; one's remaining years" },
	{ "question": "余地", "answers": [ "よち" ], "comment": "place; room; margin; scope" },
	{ "question": "余念", "answers": [ "よねん" ], "comment": "another idea" },
	{ "question": "余暇", "answers": [ "よか" ], "comment": "leisure; leisure time; spare time" },
	{ "question": "余波", "answers": [ "よは", "なごり" ], "comment": "waves that remain after the wind has subsided\nafter-effect; aftermath" },
	{ "question": "余裕", "answers": [ "よゆう" ], "comment": "surplus; margin; leeway; room; time; allowance; flexibility; scope; rope\ncomposure; placidity; complacency; calm" },
	{ "question": "余計", "answers": [ "よけい" ], "comment": "too many; too much; excessive; superfluous; superabundant; extra; spare; surplus\nunnecessary; needless; uncalled-for; otiose\nabundantly; excessively; needlessly; all the more" },
	{ "question": "余談", "answers": [ "よだん" ], "comment": "digression; sequel (of a story)" },
	{ "question": "余震", "answers": [ "よしん" ], "comment": "aftershock" },
	{ "question": "余韻", "answers": [ "よいん" ], "comment": "reverberation; swelling (of a hymn); trailing note\nlingering memory; aftertaste\nsuggestiveness (of a book, poem, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "作", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "work (e.g. of art); production\nharvest; cultivation; farming; crop; yield\ntechnique" },
	{ "question": "作り", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "making; producing; manufacturing; building; construction; make; structure\nappearance (i.e. attire, make-up)\nbuild (i.e. physique)\nsashimi\nforced (smile, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "作り上げる", "answers": [ "つくりあげる" ], "comment": "to make up; to fabricate; to build up; to complete; to construct" },
	{ "question": "作り出す", "answers": [ "つくりだす" ], "comment": "to manufacture; to produce; to raise (crops)\nto invent; to dream up; to create" },
	{ "question": "作り笑い", "answers": [ "つくりわらい" ], "comment": "forced laugh; forced smile" },
	{ "question": "作り話", "answers": [ "つくりばなし" ], "comment": "fiction; made-up story; fable; fabrication; myth" },
	{ "question": "作る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "作付け", "answers": [ "さくつけ", "さくづけ" ], "comment": "planting" },
	{ "question": "作付面積", "answers": [ "さくづけめんせき" ], "comment": "planted area" },
	{ "question": "作動", "answers": [ "さどう" ], "comment": "operation; functioning; running" },
	{ "question": "作品", "answers": [ "さくひん" ], "comment": "work (e.g. book, film, composition, etc.); opus; performance; production" },
	{ "question": "作家", "answers": [ "さっか" ], "comment": "author; writer; novelist; artist" },
	{ "question": "作成", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "drawing up (e.g. legal document, contract, will, etc.); preparing; writing; framing; making; producing; creating; creation" },
	{ "question": "作戦", "answers": [ "さくせん" ], "comment": "tactics; strategy\nmilitary or naval operations" },
	{ "question": "作文", "answers": [ "さくぶん" ], "comment": "writing (an essay, prose, etc.); composition\nformal writing with little real meaning" },
	{ "question": "作曲", "answers": [ "さっきょく" ], "comment": "composition; setting (of music)" },
	{ "question": "作柄", "answers": [ "さくがら" ], "comment": "crop conditions\nquality (of art)" },
	{ "question": "作業", "answers": [ "さぎょう" ], "comment": "work; operation; manufacturing; fatigue duty" },
	{ "question": "作業環境", "answers": [ "さぎょうかんきょう" ], "comment": "work environment" },
	{ "question": "作況指数", "answers": [ "さっきょうしすう" ], "comment": "rice-crop index" },
	{ "question": "作法", "answers": [ "さほう", "さくほう" ], "comment": "manners; etiquette; propriety\nmanner of production (esp. of prose, poetry, etc.); way of making" },
	{ "question": "作物", "answers": [ "さくもつ" ], "comment": "produce (e.g. agricultural); crops" },
	{ "question": "作用", "answers": [ "さよう" ], "comment": "action; operation; effect; function" },
	{ "question": "作者", "answers": [ "さくしゃ" ], "comment": "author; authoress; writer; composer; artist" },
	{ "question": "作製", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "manufacture" },
	{ "question": "作詞", "answers": [ "さくし" ], "comment": "(writing) song lyrics" },
	{ "question": "作風", "answers": [ "さくふう" ], "comment": "literary style" },
	{ "question": "佳作", "answers": [ "かさく" ], "comment": "good piece of work\nhonourable mention (honorable)" },
	{ "question": "併せる", "answers": [ "あわせる" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "併合", "answers": [ "へいごう" ], "comment": "merger; joining into one; melding; merging; annexation; absorption" },
	{ "question": "併殺", "answers": [ "へいさつ" ], "comment": "double play" },
	{ "question": "併用", "answers": [ "へいよう" ], "comment": "using together (jointly); used at the same time" },
	{ "question": "併設", "answers": [ "へいせつ" ], "comment": "joint establishment (esp. schools of different levels or different courses of study); establishment as an annex (e.g. of a school); juxtaposition; placing side by side" },
	{ "question": "使い", "answers": [ "つかい" ], "comment": "errand; mission; going as envoy\nmessenger; bearer; errand boy; errand girl\nfamiliar spirit\nuse; usage; user; trainer; tamer; charmer" },
	{ "question": "使い分け", "answers": [ "つかいわけ" ], "comment": "proper use; using (different things) for different purposes" },
	{ "question": "使い捨て", "answers": [ "つかいずて", "つかいすて" ], "comment": "throwaway; disposable" },
	{ "question": "使い方", "answers": [ "つかいかた" ], "comment": "way to use something; treatment; management (of help)" },
	{ "question": "使い道", "answers": [ "つかいみち" ], "comment": "purpose; utility; objective\nway to use something" },
	{ "question": "使う", "answers": [ "つかう" ], "comment": "to use (a thing, method, etc.); to make use of; to put to use\nto use (a person, animal, puppet, etc.); to employ; to handle; to manage; to manipulate\nto use (time, money, etc.); to spend; to consume\nto use (language); to speak" },
	{ "question": "使命", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "mission; errand\ntask; duty; obligation" },
	{ "question": "使用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "use; application; employment; utilization; utilisation" },
	{ "question": "使用人", "answers": [ "しようにん" ], "comment": "employee; servant" },
	{ "question": "使用料", "answers": [ "しようりょう" ], "comment": "rent; hire" },
	{ "question": "使用済み", "answers": [ "しようずみ" ], "comment": "already finished being used; second-hand; no longer used" },
	{ "question": "使用者", "answers": [ "しようしゃ" ], "comment": "user; consumer\nemployer" },
	{ "question": "使節", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "envoy; embassy; mission; delegate" },
	{ "question": "使者", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "messenger; envoy; emissary" },
	{ "question": "使途", "answers": [ "しと" ], "comment": "purpose for which money is spent; the way money is spent; how goods are used" },
	{ "question": "例", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "custom; practice; habit; usual\nsaid; aforementioned\ninstance; example; case; illustration; usage\nprecedent" },
	{ "question": "例え", "answers": [ "たとえ" ], "comment": "example\nsimile; metaphor; allegory; fable; parable" },
	{ "question": "例えば", "answers": [ "たとえば" ], "comment": "for example; for instance; e.g." },
	{ "question": "例える", "answers": [ "たとえる" ], "comment": "to compare; to liken; to speak figuratively; to illustrate; to use a simile" },
	{ "question": "例会", "answers": [ "れいかい" ], "comment": "regular meeting" },
	{ "question": "例外", "answers": [ "れいがい" ], "comment": "exception" },
	{ "question": "例外的", "answers": [ "れいがいてき" ], "comment": "exceptional" },
	{ "question": "例年", "answers": [ "れいねん" ], "comment": "average (normal, ordinary) year\nevery year; annually" },
	{ "question": "例文", "answers": [ "れいぶん" ], "comment": "example sentence; illustrative sentence; model sentence" },
	{ "question": "例題", "answers": [ "れいだい" ], "comment": "example; exercise (for the reader)" },
	{ "question": "侍", "answers": [ "さむらい", "さぶらい" ], "comment": "warrior (esp. of military retainers of daimyos in the Edo period); samurai\nman in attendance (on a person of high standing); retainer" },
	{ "question": "侍従", "answers": [ "じじゅう" ], "comment": "chamberlain" },
	{ "question": "供", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "companion; follower; attendant; retinue" },
	{ "question": "供える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to offer; to sacrifice; to dedicate" },
	{ "question": "供与", "answers": [ "きょうよ" ], "comment": "giving; provision; furnishing" },
	{ "question": "供給", "answers": [ "きょうきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; provision" },
	{ "question": "供述", "answers": [ "きょうじゅつ" ], "comment": "affidavit; deposition; testimony" },
	{ "question": "供養", "answers": [ "くよう" ], "comment": "memorial service for the dead; holding a service" },
	{ "question": "依存", "answers": [ "いそん", "いぞん" ], "comment": "dependence; dependent; reliance" },
	{ "question": "依然", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "still; as yet; as it has been" },
	{ "question": "依然として", "answers": [ "いぜんとして" ], "comment": "still; as yet; as of old" },
	{ "question": "依頼", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "request; commission; dispatch; despatch\ndependence; trust" },
	{ "question": "価値", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "value; worth; merit" },
	{ "question": "価値観", "answers": [ "かちかん" ], "comment": "sense of values; values; value system" },
	{ "question": "価格", "answers": [ "かかく" ], "comment": "price; value; cost" },
	{ "question": "侮る", "answers": [ "あなどる", "あなずる" ], "comment": "to disdain; to look down on; to make light of; to hold in contempt; to scorn; to despise" },
	{ "question": "侮蔑", "answers": [ "ぶべつ" ], "comment": "scorn; disdain; contempt; slight" },
	{ "question": "侮辱", "answers": [ "ぶじょく" ], "comment": "insult; affront; slight; contempt (e.g. of court)" },
	{ "question": "侵す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to invade; to raid; to violate (airspace, etc.); to intrude; to trespass\nto infringe; to encroach\nto harm; to afflict; to affect" },
	{ "question": "侵入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "invasion; incursion; raid; aggression; intrusion; trespass; penetration" },
	{ "question": "侵害", "answers": [ "しんがい" ], "comment": "infringement; violation; trespass; impairment" },
	{ "question": "侵攻", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "invasion" },
	{ "question": "侵犯", "answers": [ "しんぱん" ], "comment": "violation; invasion; infringement; trespass" },
	{ "question": "侵略", "answers": [ "しんりゃく" ], "comment": "aggression; invasion; raid" },
	{ "question": "便", "answers": [ "びん" ], "comment": "flight (e.g. airline flight); trip (e.g. train trip); service\nmail; post; letter\nopportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "便り", "answers": [ "たより" ], "comment": "news; tidings; information; correspondence; letter" },
	{ "question": "便乗", "answers": [ "びんじょう" ], "comment": "taking advantage of a ride or an opportunity; taking a ship" },
	{ "question": "便利", "answers": [ "べんり" ], "comment": "convenient; handy; useful" },
	{ "question": "便利さ", "answers": [ "べんりさ" ], "comment": "convenience; handiness; usefulness" },
	{ "question": "便宜", "answers": [ "べんぎ" ], "comment": "convenience; accommodation; advantage; expedience" },
	{ "question": "便所", "answers": [ "べんじょ" ], "comment": "toilet; lavatory; rest room; latrine; comfort station" },
	{ "question": "便秘", "answers": [ "べんぴ" ], "comment": "constipation" },
	{ "question": "便箋", "answers": [ "びんせん" ], "comment": "writing paper; stationery" },
	{ "question": "係", "answers": [ "かかり" ], "comment": "charge; duty; person in charge; official; clerk\nconnection; linking" },
	{ "question": "係わる", "answers": [ "かかわる" ], "comment": "to be affected; to be influenced\nto be concerned with; to have to do with\nto stick to (opinions)" },
	{ "question": "係争", "answers": [ "けいそう" ], "comment": "contention; dispute; conflict; controversy" },
	{ "question": "係員", "answers": [ "かかりいん" ], "comment": "official (e.g. customs); clerk in charge" },
	{ "question": "係官", "answers": [ "かかりかん" ], "comment": "official in charge" },
	{ "question": "係長", "answers": [ "かかりちょう" ], "comment": "chief clerk" },
	{ "question": "促す", "answers": [ "うながす" ], "comment": "to urge; to press; to prompt; to suggest; to demand; to stimulate; to quicken; to incite; to invite (attention to)" },
	{ "question": "促成", "answers": [ "そくせい" ], "comment": "promotion of growth" },
	{ "question": "促進", "answers": [ "そくしん" ], "comment": "promotion; acceleration; encouragement; facilitation; spurring on" },
	{ "question": "俄雨", "answers": [ "にわかあめ" ], "comment": "rain shower" },
	{ "question": "俊足", "answers": [ "しゅんそく" ], "comment": "fast runner\nswift horse; fleet steed\ntalented person; brilliant person" },
	{ "question": "俎板", "answers": [ "まないた" ], "comment": "chopping board" },
	{ "question": "俗語", "answers": [ "ぞくご" ], "comment": "colloquialism; colloquial language; slang" },
	{ "question": "保する", "answers": [ "ほする" ], "comment": "to guarantee" },
	{ "question": "保つ", "answers": [ "たもつ" ], "comment": "to keep; to preserve; to hold; to retain; to maintain; to support; to sustain; to last; to endure; to keep well (food); to wear well; to be durable" },
	{ "question": "保健", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "health preservation; hygiene; sanitation" },
	{ "question": "保健婦", "answers": [ "ほけんふ" ], "comment": "district health nurse; public health nurse" },
	{ "question": "保健所", "answers": [ "ほけんしょ", "ほけんじょ" ], "comment": "health care center; health care centre" },
	{ "question": "保全", "answers": [ "ほぜん" ], "comment": "preservation; integrity; conservation; maintenance" },
	{ "question": "保存", "answers": [ "ほぞん" ], "comment": "preservation; conservation; storage; saving (e.g. to disk); maintenance" },
	{ "question": "保守", "answers": [ "ほしゅ" ], "comment": "maintenance\nconservatism; conservativeness; conservation" },
	{ "question": "保守党", "answers": [ "ほしゅとう" ], "comment": "Conservative Party (UK, Canada, Japan)" },
	{ "question": "保守的", "answers": [ "ほしゅてき" ], "comment": "conservative" },
	{ "question": "保安", "answers": [ "ほあん" ], "comment": "peace preservation; security\nsafety" },
	{ "question": "保持", "answers": [ "ほじ" ], "comment": "retention; maintenance; preservation" },
	{ "question": "保有", "answers": [ "ほゆう" ], "comment": "possession; retention; maintenance" },
	{ "question": "保母", "answers": [ "ほぼ" ], "comment": "day-care worker in a kindergarten, nursery school, etc." },
	{ "question": "保温", "answers": [ "ほおん" ], "comment": "retaining warmth; keeping heat in; heat insulation" },
	{ "question": "保留", "answers": [ "ほりゅう" ], "comment": "reserve; putting on hold; deferment\nhold (e.g. telephone button); pending" },
	{ "question": "保管", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "charge; custody; safekeeping; deposit; storage" },
	{ "question": "保育", "answers": [ "ほいく" ], "comment": "nursing; nurturing; rearing; lactation; suckling" },
	{ "question": "保育園", "answers": [ "ほいくえん" ], "comment": "nursery school; day nursery; preschool" },
	{ "question": "保育所", "answers": [ "ほいくじょ", "ほいくしょ" ], "comment": "nursery school; nursery" },
	{ "question": "保証", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "guarantee; security; assurance; pledge; warranty" },
	{ "question": "保証人", "answers": [ "ほしょうにん" ], "comment": "guarantor; bondsman" },
	{ "question": "保証付き", "answers": [ "ほしょうつき" ], "comment": "guaranteed; certified; warranty included" },
	{ "question": "保証金", "answers": [ "ほしょうきん" ], "comment": "deposit (esp. on renting a house); security money; bond payment; guarantee" },
	{ "question": "保護", "answers": [ "ほうご", "ほご" ], "comment": "care; protection; shelter; safeguard; guardianship; favor; favour; patronage" },
	{ "question": "保護者", "answers": [ "ほごしゃ" ], "comment": "guardian; protector; patron; parent" },
	{ "question": "保釈", "answers": [ "ほしゃく" ], "comment": "bail; releasing on bail" },
	{ "question": "保険", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "insurance; guarantee" },
	{ "question": "保険金", "answers": [ "ほけんきん" ], "comment": "insurance payout; insurance money" },
	{ "question": "保障", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "guarantee; security; assurance; pledge; warranty" },
	{ "question": "保革", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "conservatism and progressivism; conservatives and reformists" },
	{ "question": "保養", "answers": [ "ほよう" ], "comment": "health preservation; recuperation; recreation" },
	{ "question": "保養所", "answers": [ "ほようしょ", "ほようじょ" ], "comment": "sanatorium; rest home" },
	{ "question": "信", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "honesty; fidelity\ntrust; reliance\n(religious) faith\ncounter for received messages" },
	{ "question": "信じる", "answers": [ "しんじる" ], "comment": "to believe; to believe in; to place trust in; to confide in; to have faith in" },
	{ "question": "信ずる", "answers": [ "しんずる" ], "comment": "to believe; to believe in; to place trust in; to confide in; to have faith in" },
	{ "question": "信仰", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(religious) faith; belief; creed" },
	{ "question": "信任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "trust; confidence; credence" },
	{ "question": "信号", "answers": [ "しんごう" ], "comment": "signal; signalling; signaling\ntraffic light; traffic signal" },
	{ "question": "信号機", "answers": [ "しんごうき" ], "comment": "traffic light\nsignalling mechanism; semaphore (apparatus)" },
	{ "question": "信徒", "answers": [ "しんと" ], "comment": "layman; believer; adherent; follower; laity" },
	{ "question": "信念", "answers": [ "しんねん" ], "comment": "belief; faith; conviction" },
	{ "question": "信条", "answers": [ "しんじょう" ], "comment": "creed; belief; conviction; article of faith" },
	{ "question": "信用", "answers": [ "しんよう" ], "comment": "confidence; dependence; credit; faith; reliance; belief; credence; trust" },
	{ "question": "信用組合", "answers": [ "しんようくみあい" ], "comment": "credit association" },
	{ "question": "信用金庫", "answers": [ "しんようきんこ" ], "comment": "credit union" },
	{ "question": "信義", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "faith; fidelity; loyalty" },
	{ "question": "信者", "answers": [ "しんじゃ" ], "comment": "believer; adherent; devotee" },
	{ "question": "信託", "answers": [ "しんたく" ], "comment": "trust; entrusting" },
	{ "question": "信販会社", "answers": [ "しんぱんがいしゃ" ], "comment": "credit company" },
	{ "question": "信金", "answers": [ "しんきん" ], "comment": "credit union (guild)" },
	{ "question": "信頼", "answers": [ "しんらい" ], "comment": "reliance; trust; faith; confidence" },
	{ "question": "信頼性", "answers": [ "しんらいせい" ], "comment": "credibility; authenticity; confidence; reliability" },
	{ "question": "修める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to study; to complete (a course); to cultivate; to master\nto order (one's life)\nto repair (a fault one has committed)" },
	{ "question": "修了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "completion (of a course)" },
	{ "question": "修士", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "master's (academic degree)" },
	{ "question": "修士課程", "answers": [ "しゅうしかてい" ], "comment": "master's course" },
	{ "question": "修学旅行", "answers": [ "しゅうがくりょこう" ], "comment": "excursion; field trip; school trip" },
	{ "question": "修復", "answers": [ "しゅふく", "しゅうふく" ], "comment": "restoration; repair; mending" },
	{ "question": "修業", "answers": [ "しゅうぎょう", "しゅぎょう" ], "comment": "pursuit of knowledge; studying; learning; training; completing a course" },
	{ "question": "修正", "answers": [ "しゅうせい" ], "comment": "amendment; correction; revision; modification; alteration; retouching; update; fix" },
	{ "question": "修理", "answers": [ "しゅり", "すり", "しゅうり" ], "comment": "repairing; mending; servicing" },
	{ "question": "修繕", "answers": [ "しゅうぜん" ], "comment": "repair; mending" },
	{ "question": "修行", "answers": [ "しゅぎょう" ], "comment": "ascetic practices\ntraining; practice; discipline; study" },
	{ "question": "修道", "answers": [ "しゅうどう" ], "comment": "learning; studying the fine arts" },
	{ "question": "修道院", "answers": [ "しゅうどういん" ], "comment": "monastery; convent; cloister; abbey" },
	{ "question": "俳人", "answers": [ "はいじん" ], "comment": "haiku poet" },
	{ "question": "俳優", "answers": [ "はいゆう" ], "comment": "actor; actress; player; performer" },
	{ "question": "俳句", "answers": [ "はいく" ], "comment": "haiku; 17-mora poem, usu. in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 morae" },
	{ "question": "俵", "answers": [ "たわら", "ひょう" ], "comment": "straw bag; bale; sack\ncounter for sacks; counter for bales; counter for bags" },
	{ "question": "俺", "answers": [ "おれ" ], "comment": "I; me" },
	{ "question": "倉", "answers": [ "くら" ], "comment": "warehouse; storehouse; cellar; magazine; granary; godown; depository; treasury; elevator" },
	{ "question": "倉庫", "answers": [ "そうこ" ], "comment": "storehouse; warehouse; godown" },
	{ "question": "倉敷", "answers": [ "くらしき" ], "comment": "storage charges" },
	{ "question": "個", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "counter for articles\ncounter for military units\nindividual" },
	{ "question": "個々", "answers": [ "ここ" ], "comment": "individual; one by one; separate" },
	{ "question": "個々人", "answers": [ "ここじん" ], "comment": "an individual; individual people" },
	{ "question": "個人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "individual; private person; personal; private" },
	{ "question": "個人差", "answers": [ "こじんさ" ], "comment": "individual differences; personal equation" },
	{ "question": "個人的", "answers": [ "こじんてき" ], "comment": "personal; individual; private" },
	{ "question": "個体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "individual; specimen" },
	{ "question": "個別", "answers": [ "こべつ" ], "comment": "particular case; discrete; individual; separate" },
	{ "question": "個室", "answers": [ "こしつ" ], "comment": "private room; one's own room\n(toilet) stall" },
	{ "question": "個展", "answers": [ "こてん" ], "comment": "solo exhibition; one-man exhibition; one-woman exhibition" },
	{ "question": "個性", "answers": [ "こせい" ], "comment": "individuality; personality; idiosyncrasy" },
	{ "question": "個所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "passage; place; point; part" },
	{ "question": "倍", "answers": [ "ばい" ], "comment": "twice; double\ntimes; -fold" },
	{ "question": "倍増", "answers": [ "ばいぞう" ], "comment": "double" },
	{ "question": "倍率", "answers": [ "ばいりつ" ], "comment": "magnification; leverage; amplification; scaling factor; scale factor\nacceptance rate; pass rate (of an exam, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "倒さ", "answers": [ "さかさ" ], "comment": "reverse; inversion; upside down" },
	{ "question": "倒す", "answers": [ "たおす" ], "comment": "to throw down; to bring down; to blow down; to fell; to knock down; to set (something) down on its side; to turn (something) on its side\nto kill; to defeat; to beat\nto overthrow; to trip up; to ruin\nto leave unpaid; to cheat" },
	{ "question": "倒れ", "answers": [ "たおれ" ], "comment": "bad debt\ncollapse (esp. pref.)" },
	{ "question": "倒れる", "answers": [ "たおれる" ], "comment": "to fall; to collapse; to drop; to fall senseless\nto be forced to bed (by illness, etc.)\nto die\nto go bankrupt; to be ruined; to have a bad debt\nto be defeated (in a game)\nto fall (of governments, dictators, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "倒産", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "(corporate) bankruptcy; insolvency; commercial failure; failed business" },
	{ "question": "倒置", "answers": [ "とうち" ], "comment": "turning upside down; placing nonessentials before essentials" },
	{ "question": "倒閣", "answers": [ "とうかく" ], "comment": "overthrow of government" },
	{ "question": "候補", "answers": [ "こうほ" ], "comment": "candidate; contender; prospect; pick; choice; list\ncandidacy; candidature; nomination" },
	{ "question": "借り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "borrowing; debt; loan" },
	{ "question": "借りる", "answers": [ "かりる" ], "comment": "to borrow; to have a loan\nto rent; to hire" },
	{ "question": "借り入れ", "answers": [ "かりいれ" ], "comment": "debt" },
	{ "question": "借入金", "answers": [ "かりいれきん" ], "comment": "loan; loan payable; debt" },
	{ "question": "借地", "answers": [ "しゃくち" ], "comment": "leased land" },
	{ "question": "借家", "answers": [ "かりいえ", "しゃっか", "かりや", "しゃくや" ], "comment": "house for rent; rented house; renting a house" },
	{ "question": "借款", "answers": [ "しゃっかん" ], "comment": "(international) loan" },
	{ "question": "借金", "answers": [ "しゃっきん" ], "comment": "debt; loan; liabilities; borrowing money" },
	{ "question": "値", "answers": [ "ね", "あたい" ], "comment": "price; cost\nvalue; worth; merit\nvalue; count; number\nvariable (computer programming, programing)" },
	{ "question": "値する", "answers": [ "あたいする" ], "comment": "to be worth; to deserve; to merit" },
	{ "question": "値上がり", "answers": [ "ねあがり" ], "comment": "price advance; increase in value" },
	{ "question": "値上げ", "answers": [ "ねあげ" ], "comment": "price hike; mark-up" },
	{ "question": "値下がり", "answers": [ "ねさがり" ], "comment": "price decline; fall in price" },
	{ "question": "値下げ", "answers": [ "ねさげ" ], "comment": "cut in price" },
	{ "question": "値切る", "answers": [ "ねぎる" ], "comment": "to drive a bargain; to beat down the price; to haggle" },
	{ "question": "値引き", "answers": [ "ねびき" ], "comment": "price reduction; discount" },
	{ "question": "値打ち", "answers": [ "ねうち" ], "comment": "value; worth; price; dignity" },
	{ "question": "値段", "answers": [ "ねだん" ], "comment": "price; cost" },
	{ "question": "倫理", "answers": [ "りんり" ], "comment": "ethics; morals" },
	{ "question": "倫理的", "answers": [ "りんりてき" ], "comment": "ethical" },
	{ "question": "倹約", "answers": [ "けんやく" ], "comment": "thrift; economy; frugality" },
	{ "question": "偉人", "answers": [ "いじん" ], "comment": "great man" },
	{ "question": "偉大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "greatness" },
	{ "question": "偉業", "answers": [ "いぎょう" ], "comment": "great enterprise; exploits" },
	{ "question": "偏り", "answers": [ "かたより" ], "comment": "deviation; inclination; offset; bias; prejudice\npolarization; polarisation" },
	{ "question": "偏る", "answers": [ "かたよる" ], "comment": "to be one-sided; to incline; to be partial; to be prejudiced; to lean; to be biased; to be biassed" },
	{ "question": "偏差値", "answers": [ "へんさち" ], "comment": "deviation value (usu. scaled to mean of 50, standard deviation of 10, and often used for academic grades); deviation; T-score; standard score" },
	{ "question": "偏見", "answers": [ "へんけん" ], "comment": "prejudice; narrow view" },
	{ "question": "偏重", "answers": [ "へんちょう" ], "comment": "preponderance; making too much of; overestimation; overemphasis; attaching too much importance to" },
	{ "question": "停学", "answers": [ "ていがく" ], "comment": "suspension from school" },
	{ "question": "停戦", "answers": [ "ていせん" ], "comment": "armistice; ceasefire" },
	{ "question": "停止", "answers": [ "ちょうじ", "ていし" ], "comment": "suspension; interruption; stoppage; ban; standstill; halt; hang-up; deadlock; stalemate; abeyance\nsuspension of music, dance, etc. as a sign of mourning for a prominent person" },
	{ "question": "停泊", "answers": [ "ていはく" ], "comment": "anchorage; moorings" },
	{ "question": "停滞", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "stagnation; tie-up; congestion; retention; accumulation; falling into arrears" },
	{ "question": "停留所", "answers": [ "ていりゅうじょ" ], "comment": "bus stop; tram stop; stop; station" },
	{ "question": "停車", "answers": [ "ていしゃ" ], "comment": "stopping (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "停電", "answers": [ "ていでん" ], "comment": "power outage; electricity outage; blackout; failure of electricity supply" },
	{ "question": "健やか", "answers": [ "すこやか" ], "comment": "vigorous; healthy; sound" },
	{ "question": "健保", "answers": [ "けんぽ" ], "comment": "health insurance" },
	{ "question": "健全", "answers": [ "けんぜん" ], "comment": "healthy; sound; wholesome" },
	{ "question": "健在", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "in good health; well; going strong" },
	{ "question": "健常者", "answers": [ "けんじょうしゃ" ], "comment": "(physically) non-handicapped person; healthy person" },
	{ "question": "健康", "answers": [ "けんこう" ], "comment": "health; sound; wholesome" },
	{ "question": "健康保険", "answers": [ "けんこうほけん" ], "comment": "health insurance" },
	{ "question": "健康食品", "answers": [ "けんこうしょくひん" ], "comment": "health foods" },
	{ "question": "健気", "answers": [ "けなげ" ], "comment": "admirable; commendable; praiseworthy; laudable; brave; heroic; noble; courageous" },
	{ "question": "健診", "answers": [ "けんしん" ], "comment": "physical examination; medical examination; health checkup; health screening" },
	{ "question": "健闘", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "fighting bravely; strenuous efforts" },
	{ "question": "側", "answers": [ "がわ", "かわ" ], "comment": "side (of something, or taking someone's side); part\n(watch) case" },
	{ "question": "側近", "answers": [ "そっきん" ], "comment": "close associate; close aide; brains-truster" },
	{ "question": "側面", "answers": [ "そくめん" ], "comment": "side; flank; aspect; dimension; profile; sidelight; lateral" },
	{ "question": "偵察", "answers": [ "ていさつ" ], "comment": "scout out; reconnaissance" },
	{ "question": "偶像", "answers": [ "ぐうぞう" ], "comment": "image; idol; statue" },
	{ "question": "偶数", "answers": [ "ぐうすう" ], "comment": "even number" },
	{ "question": "偶然", "answers": [ "ぐうぜん" ], "comment": "coincidence; chance; accident; fortuity\nby chance; unexpectedly\ncontingency (philosophy)" },
	{ "question": "偶発", "answers": [ "ぐうはつ" ], "comment": "sudden outbreak; accidental; incidental" },
	{ "question": "偽", "answers": [ "にせ" ], "comment": "imitation; fake; phony; counterfeit; forged; bogus; sham\npseudo-" },
	{ "question": "偽物", "answers": [ "ぎぶつ", "にせもの" ], "comment": "spurious article; forgery; counterfeit; imitation; sham" },
	{ "question": "偽装", "answers": [ "ぎそう" ], "comment": "camouflage; disguise\npretense; feigning; masquerade" },
	{ "question": "偽証", "answers": [ "ぎしょう" ], "comment": "false evidence; perjury; false testimony" },
	{ "question": "偽造", "answers": [ "ぎぞう" ], "comment": "forgery; falsification; fabrication; counterfeiting" },
	{ "question": "傍聴", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "hearing; listening; attendance; auditing" },
	{ "question": "傍観", "answers": [ "ぼうかん" ], "comment": "looking on; remaining a spectator" },
	{ "question": "傑作", "answers": [ "けっさく" ], "comment": "masterpiece; best work\namusing blunder; funny mistake; boner" },
	{ "question": "傘", "answers": [ "かさ" ], "comment": "umbrella; parasol\nsomething shaped like an umbrella or a conical hat; shade (of a lamp); mushroom cap; pileus" },
	{ "question": "傘下", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "affiliated with; under jurisdiction of; under the umbrella" },
	{ "question": "備え", "answers": [ "そなえ" ], "comment": "preparation; provision; guarding" },
	{ "question": "備える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install\nto have ready; to prepare for\nto possess (all that is needed); to be endowed with; to be armed with\nto be born with; to have since birth" },
	{ "question": "備え付ける", "answers": [ "そなえつける" ], "comment": "to provide; to furnish; to equip; to install" },
	{ "question": "備わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "to be furnished with; to be provided with; to be equipped with\nto be possessed of; to be endowed with; to be gifted with\nto be among; to be one of" },
	{ "question": "備考", "answers": [ "びこう" ], "comment": "note (for reference); remarks; N.B." },
	{ "question": "備蓄", "answers": [ "びちく" ], "comment": "stockpile; reserves; storing; stocking up; laying in (supplies)" },
	{ "question": "催し", "answers": [ "もよおし" ], "comment": "event; festivities; function; social gathering; auspices; opening; holding (a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "催す", "answers": [ "もよおす" ], "comment": "to hold (a meeting); to give (a dinner); to show signs of\nto feel (sensation, emotion, call of nature, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "催促", "answers": [ "さいそく" ], "comment": "pressing; demanding; urging; demand; request; claim" },
	{ "question": "催涙", "answers": [ "さいるい" ], "comment": "lacrimator; dacryagogue; tear-inducing agent" },
	{ "question": "債", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "debt; loan" },
	{ "question": "債券", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "bond; debenture" },
	{ "question": "債務", "answers": [ "さいむ" ], "comment": "debt; liabilities; obligation to a person or party (usu. legal or contractual)" },
	{ "question": "債権", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "credit; claim" },
	{ "question": "傷", "answers": [ "きず" ], "comment": "wound; injury; cut; gash; bruise; scratch; scrape; scar\nchip; crack; scratch; nick\nflaw; defect; weakness; weak point\nstain (on one's reputation); disgrace; dishonor; dishonour\n(emotional) hurt; hurt feelings" },
	{ "question": "傷つく", "answers": [ "きずつく" ], "comment": "to be wounded; to get injured\nto get hurt feelings\nto get damaged; to get chipped; to get scratched" },
	{ "question": "傷む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to hurt; to ache; to feel a pain\nto be injured; to be spoiled (e.g. food); to be damaged" },
	{ "question": "傷める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket" },
	{ "question": "傷付ける", "answers": [ "きずつける" ], "comment": "to wound; to injure\nto hurt someone's feelings (pride, etc.)\nto damage; to chip; to scratch" },
	{ "question": "傷口", "answers": [ "きずぐち" ], "comment": "(opening of) a wound; (mouth of a) wound; cut" },
	{ "question": "傷害", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "wound; injury; accident; casualty\nassault; inflicting bodily injury" },
	{ "question": "傷者", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "wounded person; casualty; injured person" },
	{ "question": "傷跡", "answers": [ "きずあと", "しょうこん" ], "comment": "scar; cicatrix" },
	{ "question": "傾く", "answers": [ "かたむく" ], "comment": "to incline toward; to slant; to lurch; to heel over; to be disposed to; to trend toward; to be prone to\nto go down (sun); to wane; to sink; to decline" },
	{ "question": "傾ける", "answers": [ "かたむける" ], "comment": "to incline; to lean; to tip; to tilt; to slant; to bend; to list\nto devote oneself to; to concentrate on; to pour one's energy into\nto ruin; to squander; to empty\nto drink (alcohol)" },
	{ "question": "傾げる", "answers": [ "かたげる", "かしげる" ], "comment": "to lean; to incline; to tilt; to slant" },
	{ "question": "傾向", "answers": [ "けいこう" ], "comment": "tendency; trend; inclination" },
	{ "question": "傾斜", "answers": [ "けいしゃ" ], "comment": "inclination; slant; slope; bevel; list; dip; tilt; lean" },
	{ "question": "傾注", "answers": [ "けいちゅう" ], "comment": "devotion; concentration" },
	{ "question": "働かせる", "answers": [ "はたらかせる" ], "comment": "to put someone to work; to make someone work\nto use; to apply; to exert; to exercise (restraint, one's imagination, one's brain, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "働き", "answers": [ "はたらき" ], "comment": "work; labor; labour\nachievement; performance; ability; talent\nsalary; income; earnings\naction; activity; workings; function; operation; movement; motion\nconjugation; inflection" },
	{ "question": "働きかける", "answers": [ "はたらきかける" ], "comment": "to work on someone; to influence; to exert influence on; to seek action from; to appeal to\nto begin to work" },
	{ "question": "働き掛ける", "answers": [ "はたらきかける" ], "comment": "to work on someone; to influence; to exert influence on; to seek action from; to appeal to\nto begin to work" },
	{ "question": "働き盛り", "answers": [ "はたらきざかり" ], "comment": "prime of one's working life" },
	{ "question": "働く", "answers": [ "はたらく" ], "comment": "to work; to labor; to labour\nto function; to operate; to be effective; to work (i.e. ... works); to come into play\nto commit (e.g. a crime); to perpetrate; to do; to act; to practise; to practice\nto be conjugated" },
	{ "question": "像", "answers": [ "ぞう" ], "comment": "image; figure; statue; picture; portrait\nfigure; form; shape; appearance\nimage" },
	{ "question": "僕", "answers": [ "ぼく" ], "comment": "I; me\nyou\nmanservant" },
	{ "question": "僕たち", "answers": [ "ぼくたち" ], "comment": "we" },
	{ "question": "僕ら", "answers": [ "ぼくら" ], "comment": "we" },
	{ "question": "僧", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "monk; priest" },
	{ "question": "僧侶", "answers": [ "そうりょ" ], "comment": "priest; monk" },
	{ "question": "僻み", "answers": [ "ひがみ" ], "comment": "prejudice; bias; warped view; jealousy; inferiority complex" },
	{ "question": "儀", "answers": [ "ぎ" ], "comment": "ceremony\nmatter; affair\nwith regard to (used after a person's name, a personal pronoun, etc. in epistolary style); as for; as concerns" },
	{ "question": "儀式", "answers": [ "ぎしき" ], "comment": "ceremony; rite; ritual; service" },
	{ "question": "儀礼", "answers": [ "ぎれい" ], "comment": "etiquette; courtesy" },
	{ "question": "億", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "10^8; 100,000,000; hundred million" },
	{ "question": "儒教", "answers": [ "じゅきょう" ], "comment": "Confucianism" },
	{ "question": "償い", "answers": [ "つぐない" ], "comment": "recompense; indemnity; atonement" },
	{ "question": "償う", "answers": [ "つぐなう", "つぐのう" ], "comment": "to make up for; to compensate for; to indemnify; to recompense; to redeem (e.g. a fault); to atone for" },
	{ "question": "償却", "answers": [ "しょうきゃく" ], "comment": "repayment; redemption\ndepreciation\namortization; amortisation" },
	{ "question": "償還", "answers": [ "しょうかん" ], "comment": "repayment; redemption; amortization; amortisation" },
	{ "question": "優しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable" },
	{ "question": "優れる", "answers": [ "すぐれる" ], "comment": "to surpass; to outstrip; to excel" },
	{ "question": "優位", "answers": [ "ゆうい" ], "comment": "predominance; ascendancy; superiority" },
	{ "question": "優先", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "preference; priority; precedence" },
	{ "question": "優先的", "answers": [ "ゆうせんてき" ], "comment": "preferential" },
	{ "question": "優勝", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "overall victory; championship" },
	{ "question": "優勢", "answers": [ "ゆうせい" ], "comment": "superiority; superior power; predominance; preponderance" },
	{ "question": "優秀", "answers": [ "ゆうしゅう" ], "comment": "superiority; excellence" },
	{ "question": "優等生", "answers": [ "ゆうとうせい" ], "comment": "honor student; honours student" },
	{ "question": "優美", "answers": [ "ゆうび" ], "comment": "grace; refinement; elegance; daintiness" },
	{ "question": "優良", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "superior; excellent; fine" },
	{ "question": "優越感", "answers": [ "ゆうえつかん" ], "comment": "superiority complex; sense of superiority" },
	{ "question": "優遇", "answers": [ "ゆうぐう" ], "comment": "favorable treatment; favourable treatment; hospitality; warm reception; good treatment; hearty welcome" },
	{ "question": "優雅", "answers": [ "ゆうが" ], "comment": "elegance; grace; refinement" },
	{ "question": "儲かる", "answers": [ "もうかる" ], "comment": "to be profitable; to yield a profit" },
	{ "question": "儲け", "answers": [ "もうけ" ], "comment": "profit; earnings" },
	{ "question": "儲ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "to profit; to get; to earn; to gain\nto have (bear, beget) a child\nto have a stroke of luck" },
	{ "question": "元", "answers": [ "もと" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\n(somebody's) side; (somebody's) location\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\ncounter for blades of grass, tree trunks, etc., and for falcons (in falconry)\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip" },
	{ "question": "元凶", "answers": [ "げんきょう" ], "comment": "ringleader; main culprit\nmain cause; source" },
	{ "question": "元号", "answers": [ "げんごう" ], "comment": "era name" },
	{ "question": "元帥", "answers": [ "げんすい" ], "comment": "(field) marshal; (fleet) admiral; general of the army" },
	{ "question": "元年", "answers": [ "がんねん" ], "comment": "first year (of a specific reign)" },
	{ "question": "元日", "answers": [ "がんにち", "がんじつ" ], "comment": "New Year's Day" },
	{ "question": "元旦", "answers": [ "がんたん" ], "comment": "New Year's Day\nNew Year's morning; morning of New Year's Day" },
	{ "question": "元本", "answers": [ "げんぽん", "がんぽん" ], "comment": "principal (invest.); capital" },
	{ "question": "元来", "answers": [ "がんらい" ], "comment": "originally; primarily; essentially; logically; naturally" },
	{ "question": "元気", "answers": [ "げんき" ], "comment": "lively; full of spirit; energetic; vigorous; vital; spirited\nhealthy; well; fit; in good health" },
	{ "question": "元祖", "answers": [ "がんそ" ], "comment": "originator; founder; pioneer; inventor" },
	{ "question": "元禄", "answers": [ "げんろく" ], "comment": "Genroku era (1688.9.30-1704.3.13)" },
	{ "question": "元素", "answers": [ "げんそ" ], "comment": "chemical element" },
	{ "question": "元首", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "兄", "answers": [ "あに" ], "comment": "elder brother; older brother" },
	{ "question": "兄さん", "answers": [ "にいさん", "あにさん" ], "comment": "older brother; elder brother\nbrother (as older-brother figure in friendly and or work relationship)\n(vocative) young man; buddy; fella; laddie" },
	{ "question": "兄ちゃん", "answers": [ "あんちゃん" ], "comment": "(my) older brother\nsonny (with a nuance of suspicion); lad" },
	{ "question": "兄弟", "answers": [ "けいてい", "きょうだい" ], "comment": "siblings; brothers and sisters\nbrothers\nsiblings-in-law; brothers-in-law; sisters-in-law\nmate; friend" },
	{ "question": "兄貴", "answers": [ "あにき" ], "comment": "elder brother\none's senior\nolder man; man older than oneself" },
	{ "question": "充てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "to assign; to set aside" },
	{ "question": "充実", "answers": [ "じゅうじつ" ], "comment": "fullness; completion; perfection; substantiality\nenhancement; improvement; enrichment; upgrading\nreplenishment; repletion" },
	{ "question": "充当", "answers": [ "じゅうとう" ], "comment": "allocation; appropriation" },
	{ "question": "充満", "answers": [ "じゅうまん" ], "comment": "being filled with; being full of; permeation" },
	{ "question": "充足", "answers": [ "じゅうそく" ], "comment": "sufficiency" },
	{ "question": "充電", "answers": [ "じゅうでん" ], "comment": "charging (electrically)\nelectrification" },
	{ "question": "兆", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "10^12; 1,000,000,000,000; trillion\nsign; omen; indication; portent" },
	{ "question": "兆し", "answers": [ "きざし" ], "comment": "signs; omen; symptoms" },
	{ "question": "兆候", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "sign; indication; omen; symptom" },
	{ "question": "先", "answers": [ "さき" ], "comment": "previous; prior; former; first; earlier; some time ago; preceding\npoint (e.g. pencil); tip; end; nozzle\nhead (of a line); front\nahead; the other side\nthe future; hereafter\ndestination\nthe other party" },
	{ "question": "先々", "answers": [ "さきざき" ], "comment": "distant future; inevitable future\nplaces one goes to" },
	{ "question": "先だって", "answers": [ "せんだって", "さきだって" ], "comment": "recently; the other day" },
	{ "question": "先に", "answers": [ "さきに" ], "comment": "before; earlier than; first; ahead; beyond; away; previously; recently" },
	{ "question": "先ほど", "answers": [ "さきほど" ], "comment": "some time ago; not long ago; just now" },
	{ "question": "先人", "answers": [ "せんじん" ], "comment": "predecessor; pioneer; ancestor" },
	{ "question": "先代", "answers": [ "せんだい" ], "comment": "family predecessor; previous age; previous generation" },
	{ "question": "先住", "answers": [ "せんじゅう" ], "comment": "previous priest or resident" },
	{ "question": "先例", "answers": [ "せんれい" ], "comment": "precedent" },
	{ "question": "先入観", "answers": [ "せんにゅうかん" ], "comment": "preconception; prejudice; preoccupation; preconceived notion" },
	{ "question": "先制", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "head start; initiative; preemption" },
	{ "question": "先取", "answers": [ "せんしゅ" ], "comment": "earning the first (runs); preoccupation" },
	{ "question": "先取り", "answers": [ "さきどり" ], "comment": "receiving in advance; taking before others\nprefetch\nanticipatory completion; finishing another person's sentence in anticipation of what likely to be said next" },
	{ "question": "先天的", "answers": [ "せんてんてき" ], "comment": "inborn; innate; inherent; congenital; hereditary\na priori" },
	{ "question": "先安", "answers": [ "さきやす" ], "comment": "lower future quotations" },
	{ "question": "先導", "answers": [ "せんどう" ], "comment": "guidance; leadership" },
	{ "question": "先手", "answers": [ "せんて" ], "comment": "first move (in go, shogi, etc.); moving first; person with the first move\nforestalling; (seizing the) initiative" },
	{ "question": "先方", "answers": [ "せんぽう", "さきかた" ], "comment": "companion; other party (side); he; she; they\ndestination\nperson in front" },
	{ "question": "先日", "answers": [ "せんじつ" ], "comment": "the other day; a few days ago" },
	{ "question": "先月", "answers": [ "せんげつ" ], "comment": "last month" },
	{ "question": "先決", "answers": [ "せんけつ" ], "comment": "previous decision; predetermination; deciding in advance; first priority" },
	{ "question": "先物", "answers": [ "さきもの" ], "comment": "futures" },
	{ "question": "先生", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "teacher; master; doctor\nwith names of teachers, etc. as an honorific\nprevious existence" },
	{ "question": "先発", "answers": [ "せんぱつ" ], "comment": "starting in advance; starting first; going first; going ahead\nstarting (in team sports)" },
	{ "question": "先着", "answers": [ "せんちゃく" ], "comment": "arriving first" },
	{ "question": "先祖", "answers": [ "せんぞ" ], "comment": "ancestor" },
	{ "question": "先程", "answers": [ "さきほど" ], "comment": "some time ago; not long ago; just now" },
	{ "question": "先端", "answers": [ "せんたん" ], "comment": "pointed end; tip; fine point; spearhead; cusp; vanguard; advanced; leading edge; apex (of a curve)" },
	{ "question": "先行", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "preceding; going first; leading; going ahead; taking priority" },
	{ "question": "先行き", "answers": [ "さきゆき", "さきいき" ], "comment": "the future; future prospects" },
	{ "question": "先見", "answers": [ "せんけん" ], "comment": "foresight; anticipation" },
	{ "question": "先輩", "answers": [ "せんぱい" ], "comment": "senior (at work or school); superior; elder; older graduate; progenitor; old-timer" },
	{ "question": "先送り", "answers": [ "さきおくり" ], "comment": "postpone" },
	{ "question": "先週", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "last week; the week before" },
	{ "question": "先進", "answers": [ "せんしん" ], "comment": "seniority; advance; leadership" },
	{ "question": "先進国", "answers": [ "せんしんこく" ], "comment": "advanced (developed) country; advanced nations" },
	{ "question": "先遣", "answers": [ "せんけん" ], "comment": "sending ahead" },
	{ "question": "先陣", "answers": [ "せんじん" ], "comment": "vanguard; advance guard" },
	{ "question": "先頃", "answers": [ "せんころ", "さきごろ" ], "comment": "recently; the other day" },
	{ "question": "先頭", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "head; lead; vanguard; first" },
	{ "question": "先駆", "answers": [ "せんく" ], "comment": "forerunner; pioneer; precursor\nherald\noutrider; pilot car" },
	{ "question": "先駆け", "answers": [ "さきがけ" ], "comment": "charging ahead of others; the first to charge; pioneer; forerunner; harbinger" },
	{ "question": "先駆ける", "answers": [ "さきがける" ], "comment": "to be the first" },
	{ "question": "光", "answers": [ "ひかり" ], "comment": "light\nillumination; ray; beam; gleam; glow\nhappiness; hope\ninfluence; power\nvision; eyesight" },
	{ "question": "光る", "answers": [ "ひかる" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to be bright" },
	{ "question": "光学", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "optics" },
	{ "question": "光学式文字認識", "answers": [ "こうがくしきもじにんしき" ], "comment": "optical character recognition; OCR" },
	{ "question": "光明", "answers": [ "こうみょう", "こうめい" ], "comment": "bright light\nhope; bright future\nlight emanating from a buddha or bodhisattva, symbolizing their wisdom and compassion" },
	{ "question": "光景", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "scene; spectacle; sight; view" },
	{ "question": "光栄", "answers": [ "こうえい" ], "comment": "honour; honor; glory; privilege" },
	{ "question": "光沢", "answers": [ "こうたく" ], "comment": "brilliance; polish; lustre; luster; glossy finish (of photographs)" },
	{ "question": "光熱費", "answers": [ "こうねつひ" ], "comment": "cost of fuel and lighting; cost of heat and electricity; energy bill; utility cost" },
	{ "question": "光線", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "beam; light ray" },
	{ "question": "克己", "answers": [ "こっき" ], "comment": "self denial; self control" },
	{ "question": "克明", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "detailed; elaborate; faithful (copy); accurate\nscrupulous; diligent; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "克服", "answers": [ "こくふく" ], "comment": "conquest (of a difficulty, illness, handicap, etc.); overcoming; bringing under control; subjugation; victory over" },
	{ "question": "免疫", "answers": [ "めんえき" ], "comment": "immunity; immunization; immunisation\nbeing hardened (to); being unaffected (by); being accustomed (to)" },
	{ "question": "免税", "answers": [ "めんぜい" ], "comment": "tax exemption; duty exemption" },
	{ "question": "免職", "answers": [ "めんしょく" ], "comment": "dismissal; sacking; discharge" },
	{ "question": "免許", "answers": [ "めんきょ" ], "comment": "license; permit; licence; certificate" },
	{ "question": "免許証", "answers": [ "めんきょしょう" ], "comment": "licence; license; permit; certificate (of qualification)" },
	{ "question": "免責", "answers": [ "めんせき" ], "comment": "exemption from responsibility; disclaimer" },
	{ "question": "免除", "answers": [ "めんじょ" ], "comment": "exemption; exoneration; discharge" },
	{ "question": "児童", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "children; juvenile" },
	{ "question": "党", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "party (political)\nfaction; -ite" },
	{ "question": "党内", "answers": [ "とうない" ], "comment": "party-internal" },
	{ "question": "党利", "answers": [ "とうり" ], "comment": "party interests" },
	{ "question": "党務", "answers": [ "とうむ" ], "comment": "party business" },
	{ "question": "党勢", "answers": [ "とうせい" ], "comment": "strength of a party" },
	{ "question": "党員", "answers": [ "とういん" ], "comment": "party member" },
	{ "question": "党派", "answers": [ "とうは" ], "comment": "faction" },
	{ "question": "党略", "answers": [ "とうりゃく" ], "comment": "party politics (tactics)" },
	{ "question": "党籍", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "party register; membership in a party" },
	{ "question": "党議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "party council; party conference" },
	{ "question": "党首", "answers": [ "とうしゅ" ], "comment": "party leader" },
	{ "question": "兜", "answers": [ "かぶと" ], "comment": "helmet (of armor, armour); headpiece" },
	{ "question": "入り", "answers": [ "いり" ], "comment": "entering\nsetting (of the sun)\ncontaining; content; audience\nincome\nbeginning" },
	{ "question": "入り口", "answers": [ "はいりくち", "いりくち", "いりぐち", "はいりぐち" ], "comment": "entrance; entry; gate; approach; mouth" },
	{ "question": "入り込み", "answers": [ "いりごみ" ], "comment": "coming in together; unreserved seats for the public" },
	{ "question": "入り込む", "answers": [ "はいりこむ", "いりこむ" ], "comment": "to go into; to come into; to penetrate; to get in; to step in (a house)\nto become complicated" },
	{ "question": "入る", "answers": [ "はいる", "いる" ], "comment": "to get in; to go in; to come in; to flow into; to set; to set in /\n to enter; to go into\nto break into\nto join; to enroll\nto contain; to hold; to accommodate\nto have (an income of)\nto get; to receive; to score" },
	{ "question": "入れる", "answers": [ "いれる" ], "comment": "to put in; to let in; to take in; to bring in; to insert; to set (a jewel, etc.); to ink in (e.g. a tattoo)\nto admit; to accept; to employ; to hire\nto accept; to comply; to grant; to adopt (a policy, etc.); to take (advice, etc.); to listen to; to pay attention to\nto include\nto pay (one's rent, etc.)\nto cast (a vote)\nto make (tea, coffee, etc.)\nto turn on (a switch, etc.)\nto send (a fax); to call" },
	{ "question": "入れ墨", "answers": [ "げい", "ぶんしん", "いれずみ", "しせい" ], "comment": "tattoo" },
	{ "question": "入れ替え", "answers": [ "いれかえ" ], "comment": "replacement; substitution; change\nshunting (rail); switching" },
	{ "question": "入れ歯", "answers": [ "いれば" ], "comment": "false tooth; denture" },
	{ "question": "入れ物", "answers": [ "いれもの" ], "comment": "container; case; receptacle\n(euph. for) coffin; casket" },
	{ "question": "入党", "answers": [ "にゅうとう" ], "comment": "joining a political party" },
	{ "question": "入力", "answers": [ "にゅうりょく" ], "comment": "input; (data) entry" },
	{ "question": "入口", "answers": [ "はいりくち", "いりくち", "いりぐち", "はいりぐち" ], "comment": "entrance; entry; gate; approach; mouth" },
	{ "question": "入団", "answers": [ "にゅうだん" ], "comment": "enrollment; enrolment" },
	{ "question": "入国", "answers": [ "にゅうこく" ], "comment": "entry to a country" },
	{ "question": "入国管理局", "answers": [ "にゅうこくかんりきょく" ], "comment": "Immigration Bureau; Immigration Office" },
	{ "question": "入園", "answers": [ "にゅうえん" ], "comment": "enrollment in kindergarten; enrolment in kindergarten\nentering a park, garden, zoo, etc." },
	{ "question": "入場", "answers": [ "にゅうじょう" ], "comment": "entrance; admission; entering" },
	{ "question": "入場券", "answers": [ "にゅうじょうけん" ], "comment": "ticket of admission; platform ticket" },
	{ "question": "入学", "answers": [ "にゅうがく" ], "comment": "entry to school or university; matriculation; enrolment (in university, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "入学試験", "answers": [ "にゅうがくしけん" ], "comment": "entrance examination" },
	{ "question": "入室", "answers": [ "にゅうしつ", "にっしつ" ], "comment": "entering a room\nstudying under a Buddhist teacher" },
	{ "question": "入居", "answers": [ "にゅうきょ" ], "comment": "moving into (house)" },
	{ "question": "入幕", "answers": [ "にゅうまく" ], "comment": "advancing to the first grade" },
	{ "question": "入念", "answers": [ "にゅうねん" ], "comment": "careful; elaborate; scrupulous" },
	{ "question": "入所", "answers": [ "にゅうしょ" ], "comment": "admission (e.g. to a training institution, research establishment, social welfare facility, etc.); entrance\nimprisonment; internment; confinement" },
	{ "question": "入手", "answers": [ "にゅうしゅ" ], "comment": "acquisition; obtaining; coming to hand" },
	{ "question": "入札", "answers": [ "にゅうさつ" ], "comment": "bid; bidding" },
	{ "question": "入梅", "answers": [ "つゆいり", "にゅうばい" ], "comment": "entering the rainy season; beginning of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "入植", "answers": [ "にゅうしょく" ], "comment": "settlement; immigration" },
	{ "question": "入浴", "answers": [ "にゅうよく" ], "comment": "bathing\nto bathe; to take a bath; to enter a bath" },
	{ "question": "入港", "answers": [ "にゅうこう" ], "comment": "entry into port" },
	{ "question": "入社", "answers": [ "にゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "joining a company; getting a job with a company; entering a company" },
	{ "question": "入籍", "answers": [ "にゅうせき" ], "comment": "entry in family register" },
	{ "question": "入荷", "answers": [ "にゅうか" ], "comment": "arrival of goods; goods received" },
	{ "question": "入試", "answers": [ "にゅうし" ], "comment": "entrance examination" },
	{ "question": "入賞", "answers": [ "にゅうしょう" ], "comment": "winning a prize or place (in a contest)" },
	{ "question": "入選", "answers": [ "にゅうせん" ], "comment": "chosen (in a competition)" },
	{ "question": "入金", "answers": [ "にゅうきん" ], "comment": "deposit; payment; money received; money due" },
	{ "question": "入門", "answers": [ "にゅうもん" ], "comment": "entering an institution; beginning training\nprimer; manual; introduction (to)" },
	{ "question": "入閣", "answers": [ "にゅうかく" ], "comment": "joining the cabinet" },
	{ "question": "入院", "answers": [ "にゅういん" ], "comment": "hospitalization; hospitalisation" },
	{ "question": "入館料", "answers": [ "にゅうかんりょう" ], "comment": "admission fee" },
	{ "question": "全", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "all; whole; entire; complete; overall\npan-; omni-; toti-" },
	{ "question": "全うする", "answers": [ "まっとうする" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to fulfill; to carry out" },
	{ "question": "全世界", "answers": [ "ぜんせかい" ], "comment": "the whole world" },
	{ "question": "全人", "answers": [ "ぜんじん" ], "comment": "saint; person well-balanced morally and intellectually" },
	{ "question": "全会", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "whole assembly" },
	{ "question": "全体", "answers": [ "ぜんたい" ], "comment": "whole; entirety; whatever (is the matter)" },
	{ "question": "全体主義", "answers": [ "ぜんたいしゅぎ" ], "comment": "totalitarianism" },
	{ "question": "全力", "answers": [ "ぜんりょく" ], "comment": "all one's power; whole energy" },
	{ "question": "全勝", "answers": [ "ぜんしょう" ], "comment": "complete victory\nwinning a tournament with no losses" },
	{ "question": "全員", "answers": [ "ぜんいん" ], "comment": "all members (unanimity); all hands; the whole crew; everyone; everybody" },
	{ "question": "全国", "answers": [ "ぜんこく" ], "comment": "countrywide; nationwide; whole country; national" },
	{ "question": "全土", "answers": [ "ぜんど" ], "comment": "whole nation; whole land; whole country" },
	{ "question": "全域", "answers": [ "ぜんいき" ], "comment": "the whole area" },
	{ "question": "全学", "answers": [ "ぜんがく" ], "comment": "whole college" },
	{ "question": "全容", "answers": [ "ぜんよう" ], "comment": "full portrait; whole aspect; full story" },
	{ "question": "全廃", "answers": [ "ぜんぱい" ], "comment": "total abolition; full phase-out; total repeal" },
	{ "question": "全快", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "complete recovery of health" },
	{ "question": "全文", "answers": [ "ぜんぶん" ], "comment": "whole passage; full text; whole sentence; full paragraph" },
	{ "question": "全日", "answers": [ "ぜんじつ" ], "comment": "all days" },
	{ "question": "全日制", "answers": [ "ぜんにちせい" ], "comment": "the full-day (school system)" },
	{ "question": "全曲", "answers": [ "ぜんきょく" ], "comment": "all compositions; the entire composition" },
	{ "question": "全校", "answers": [ "ぜんこう" ], "comment": "the whole school" },
	{ "question": "全権", "answers": [ "ぜんけん" ], "comment": "plenipotentiary powers; full authority" },
	{ "question": "全治", "answers": [ "ぜんじ", "ぜんち" ], "comment": "complete recovery; healing" },
	{ "question": "全滅", "answers": [ "ぜんめつ" ], "comment": "annihilation; total destruction; complete destruction; crushing defeat" },
	{ "question": "全点", "answers": [ "ぜんてん" ], "comment": "all items; all parts; all points" },
	{ "question": "全然", "answers": [ "ぜんぜん" ], "comment": "not at all (with neg. verb)\nwholly; entirely; completely" },
	{ "question": "全盛", "answers": [ "ぜんせい" ], "comment": "height of prosperity" },
	{ "question": "全社", "answers": [ "ぜんしゃ" ], "comment": "whole company; all the companies" },
	{ "question": "全米", "answers": [ "ぜんべい" ], "comment": "all-America; pan-American; all of America" },
	{ "question": "全線", "answers": [ "ぜんせん" ], "comment": "the whole line; all lines; the whole ship" },
	{ "question": "全般", "answers": [ "ぜんぱん" ], "comment": "(the) whole; universal; wholly; general; as a whole" },
	{ "question": "全身", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "whole (body); full-length (e.g. portrait)\nsystemic" },
	{ "question": "全速力", "answers": [ "ぜんそくりょく" ], "comment": "full speed" },
	{ "question": "全部", "answers": [ "ぜんぶ" ], "comment": "all; entire; whole; altogether" },
	{ "question": "全量", "answers": [ "ぜんりょう" ], "comment": "the whole quantity" },
	{ "question": "全長", "answers": [ "ぜんちょう" ], "comment": "over-all length; span" },
	{ "question": "全集", "answers": [ "ぜんしゅう" ], "comment": "complete works" },
	{ "question": "全面", "answers": [ "ぜんめん" ], "comment": "whole surface; entire" },
	{ "question": "全面的", "answers": [ "ぜんめんてき" ], "comment": "all-out; general; over-all; complete; extensive; full-scale" },
	{ "question": "全額", "answers": [ "ぜんがく" ], "comment": "total; full amount; sum" },
	{ "question": "八", "answers": [ "や", "はち" ], "comment": "eight" },
	{ "question": "八つ", "answers": [ "やっつ", "やつ" ], "comment": "eight" },
	{ "question": "八つ当たり", "answers": [ "やつあたり" ], "comment": "outburst of anger; venting one's anger" },
	{ "question": "八丁", "answers": [ "はっちょう" ], "comment": "skillfulness" },
	{ "question": "八分音符", "answers": [ "はちぶおんぷ" ], "comment": "8th note; eighth note; quaver" },
	{ "question": "八十", "answers": [ "はちじゅう" ], "comment": "eighty" },
	{ "question": "八千代", "answers": [ "やちよ" ], "comment": "eternity; thousands of years" },
	{ "question": "八幡", "answers": [ "はちまん" ], "comment": "Hachiman (God of War)\nHachiman shrine\ncertainly" },
	{ "question": "八方", "answers": [ "はっぽう" ], "comment": "all sides; the four cardinal directions and the four ordinal directions\nlarge hanging lantern" },
	{ "question": "八日", "answers": [ "ようか" ], "comment": "the eighth day of the month\neight days" },
	{ "question": "八月", "answers": [ "はちがつ" ], "comment": "August" },
	{ "question": "八百屋", "answers": [ "やおや" ], "comment": "greengrocer" },
	{ "question": "八重", "answers": [ "やえ" ], "comment": "multilayered; doubled" },
	{ "question": "公", "answers": [ "おおやけ" ], "comment": "public; open; formal; official; governmental" },
	{ "question": "公人", "answers": [ "こうじん" ], "comment": "public character" },
	{ "question": "公会堂", "answers": [ "こうかいどう" ], "comment": "town hall; public hall" },
	{ "question": "公使", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "envoy; diplomat below the rank of ambassador (e.g. deputy chief of mission, charge d'affaires); minister (of legation)" },
	{ "question": "公債", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "public debt; public bond or securities" },
	{ "question": "公共", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "public; community; public service; society; communal" },
	{ "question": "公共放送", "answers": [ "こうきょうほうそう" ], "comment": "public broadcasting (e.g. NHK, BBC)" },
	{ "question": "公共料金", "answers": [ "こうきょうりょうきん" ], "comment": "public utilities charge" },
	{ "question": "公判", "answers": [ "こうはん" ], "comment": "public hearing; trial" },
	{ "question": "公務", "answers": [ "こうむ" ], "comment": "official business; public business" },
	{ "question": "公務員", "answers": [ "こうむいん" ], "comment": "government worker; public servant; civil servant" },
	{ "question": "公募", "answers": [ "こうぼ" ], "comment": "public appeal (e.g. for contributions); public offering (of securities); public advertisement (of a post); open recruitment" },
	{ "question": "公取委", "answers": [ "こうとりい" ], "comment": "Fair Trade Commission" },
	{ "question": "公司", "answers": [ "こうし", "コンス" ], "comment": "company; firm (in China)" },
	{ "question": "公営", "answers": [ "こうえい" ], "comment": "public management" },
	{ "question": "公団", "answers": [ "こうだん" ], "comment": "public corporation\npublic housing" },
	{ "question": "公園", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(public) park" },
	{ "question": "公報", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "official bulletin; communique" },
	{ "question": "公子", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "young nobleman" },
	{ "question": "公安", "answers": [ "こうあん" ], "comment": "public safety; public welfare" },
	{ "question": "公安委員会", "answers": [ "こうあんいいんかい" ], "comment": "public safety commission" },
	{ "question": "公定", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "official (rate, price, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "公定歩合", "answers": [ "こうていぶあい" ], "comment": "official discount (bank) rate" },
	{ "question": "公害", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "pollution; public nuisance; contamination" },
	{ "question": "公布", "answers": [ "こうふ" ], "comment": "official proclamation; announcement; promulgation (e.g. of regulations)" },
	{ "question": "公平", "answers": [ "こうへい" ], "comment": "fairness; impartial; justice" },
	{ "question": "公庫", "answers": [ "こうこ" ], "comment": "finance corporation" },
	{ "question": "公式", "answers": [ "こうしき" ], "comment": "formal; official\nformula (e.g. mathematical)" },
	{ "question": "公式サイト", "answers": [ "こうしきサイト" ], "comment": "official website" },
	{ "question": "公式戦", "answers": [ "こうしきせん" ], "comment": "regular game; pennant race" },
	{ "question": "公文", "answers": [ "こうぶん" ], "comment": "official document; archives" },
	{ "question": "公文書", "answers": [ "こうぶんしょ" ], "comment": "official document; archives" },
	{ "question": "公明", "answers": [ "こうめい" ], "comment": "fairness; justice" },
	{ "question": "公明党", "answers": [ "こうめいとう" ], "comment": "New Komeito (Japanese political party); New Clean Government Party; Justice Party" },
	{ "question": "公有", "answers": [ "こうゆう" ], "comment": "public ownership" },
	{ "question": "公正", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "justice; fairness; impartiality" },
	{ "question": "公民", "answers": [ "こうみん" ], "comment": "citizen; freemen" },
	{ "question": "公民権", "answers": [ "こうみんけん" ], "comment": "civil rights; franchise; citizenship" },
	{ "question": "公民館", "answers": [ "こうみんかん" ], "comment": "public hall; community center; community centre" },
	{ "question": "公海", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "high seas; international waters" },
	{ "question": "公演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "public performance\nexhibition in a foreign country" },
	{ "question": "公然", "answers": [ "こうぜん" ], "comment": "open; public; official; overt" },
	{ "question": "公用", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "government business; official business\npublic; official; governmental" },
	{ "question": "公的", "answers": [ "こうてき" ], "comment": "public; official" },
	{ "question": "公益", "answers": [ "こうえき" ], "comment": "public interest; public benefit; public good" },
	{ "question": "公益法人", "answers": [ "こうえきほうじん" ], "comment": "public-service corporation; charitable corporation\njuridical (legal) person working for the public good" },
	{ "question": "公示", "answers": [ "こうし", "こうじ" ], "comment": "edict; public announcement" },
	{ "question": "公社", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "public corporation" },
	{ "question": "公社債", "answers": [ "こうしゃさい" ], "comment": "public bonds" },
	{ "question": "公私", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "public and private; official and personal; government and people" },
	{ "question": "公称", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "public name; announcing publicly\nnominal" },
	{ "question": "公立", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "public (institution)" },
	{ "question": "公算", "answers": [ "こうさん" ], "comment": "probability; likelihood" },
	{ "question": "公約", "answers": [ "こうやく" ], "comment": "public commitment; public promise; campaign pledge; official vow" },
	{ "question": "公聴会", "answers": [ "こうちょうかい" ], "comment": "public hearing" },
	{ "question": "公職", "answers": [ "こうしょく" ], "comment": "public office" },
	{ "question": "公舎", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "official residence" },
	{ "question": "公衆", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "the public; general public" },
	{ "question": "公衆衛生", "answers": [ "こうしゅうえいせい" ], "comment": "sanitation; public health" },
	{ "question": "公衆電話", "answers": [ "こうしゅうでんわ" ], "comment": "public telephone; pay phone" },
	{ "question": "公表", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "official announcement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "公言", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "declaration; profession" },
	{ "question": "公設", "answers": [ "こうせつ" ], "comment": "public (institution)" },
	{ "question": "公訴", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "accusation; prosecution" },
	{ "question": "公認", "answers": [ "こうにん" ], "comment": "official recognition; authorization; authorisation; licence; license; accreditation" },
	{ "question": "公認会計士", "answers": [ "こうにんかいけいし" ], "comment": "certified public accountant" },
	{ "question": "公論", "answers": [ "こうろん" ], "comment": "public opinion; unbiased criticism; unbiassed criticism" },
	{ "question": "公費", "answers": [ "こうひ" ], "comment": "public expense; public funds; public money; public expenditure" },
	{ "question": "公選", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "public election" },
	{ "question": "公邸", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "official residence" },
	{ "question": "公金", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "public funds" },
	{ "question": "公開", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "opening to the public; making available to the public; putting on display; exhibiting; showing (play, movie, etc.); holding (interview, etc.); open; public" },
	{ "question": "公館", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "official residence" },
	{ "question": "六", "answers": [ "む", "ろく", "むう" ], "comment": "six" },
	{ "question": "六つ", "answers": [ "むつ", "むっつ" ], "comment": "six" },
	{ "question": "六十", "answers": [ "ろくじゅう" ], "comment": "sixty" },
	{ "question": "六十四分音符", "answers": [ "ろくじゅうしぶおんぷ" ], "comment": "64th note; hemidemisemiquaver; semidemisemiquaver" },
	{ "question": "六日", "answers": [ "むいか" ], "comment": "sixth day of the month\nsix days" },
	{ "question": "六月", "answers": [ "ろくがつ" ], "comment": "June" },
	{ "question": "共々", "answers": [ "ともども" ], "comment": "together; in company" },
	{ "question": "共催", "answers": [ "きょうさい" ], "comment": "joint sponsorship" },
	{ "question": "共働き", "answers": [ "ともばたらき" ], "comment": "(husband and wife) both working; dual income" },
	{ "question": "共同", "answers": [ "きょうどう" ], "comment": "doing together (as equals); sharing; common (land, etc.); joint (statement, etc.); cooperation; co-operation; collaboration; association" },
	{ "question": "共同体", "answers": [ "きょうどうたい" ], "comment": "cooperative body; cooperative system; collective; community" },
	{ "question": "共和", "answers": [ "きょうわ" ], "comment": "republican; cooperative" },
	{ "question": "共和党", "answers": [ "きょうわとう" ], "comment": "Republican Party" },
	{ "question": "共和制", "answers": [ "きょうわせい" ], "comment": "republic; republicanism" },
	{ "question": "共和国", "answers": [ "きょうわこく" ], "comment": "republic; commonwealth" },
	{ "question": "共存", "answers": [ "きょうぞん", "きょうそん" ], "comment": "coexistence" },
	{ "question": "共学", "answers": [ "きょうがく" ], "comment": "coeducation" },
	{ "question": "共感", "answers": [ "きょうかん" ], "comment": "sympathy; empathy; response" },
	{ "question": "共有", "answers": [ "きょうゆう" ], "comment": "joint ownership; co-ownership; sharing" },
	{ "question": "共栄", "answers": [ "きょうえい" ], "comment": "mutual prosperity" },
	{ "question": "共済", "answers": [ "きょうさい" ], "comment": "mutual aid" },
	{ "question": "共演", "answers": [ "きょうえん" ], "comment": "appearing together; co-acting; co-starring" },
	{ "question": "共犯", "answers": [ "きょうはん" ], "comment": "complicity" },
	{ "question": "共生", "answers": [ "きょうせい", "ともいき" ], "comment": "symbiosis; paragenesis; union" },
	{ "question": "共産", "answers": [ "きょうさん" ], "comment": "communism\nCommunist Party" },
	{ "question": "共産主義", "answers": [ "きょうさんしゅぎ" ], "comment": "communism; collectivism" },
	{ "question": "共産党", "answers": [ "きょうさんとう" ], "comment": "Communist Party" },
	{ "question": "共用", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "common use; communal use; sharing" },
	{ "question": "共稼ぎ", "answers": [ "ともかせぎ" ], "comment": "working together; (husband and wife) earning a living together" },
	{ "question": "共立", "answers": [ "きょうりつ" ], "comment": "joint; common" },
	{ "question": "共著", "answers": [ "きょうちょ" ], "comment": "collaboration; co-authorship" },
	{ "question": "共謀", "answers": [ "きょうぼう" ], "comment": "conspiracy; collusion; complicity; being in cahoots" },
	{ "question": "共通", "answers": [ "きょうつう" ], "comment": "commonness; community\nto be common; to be shared\n-wide" },
	{ "question": "共通語", "answers": [ "きょうつうご" ], "comment": "common term\ncommon language; lingua franca; standard language" },
	{ "question": "共闘", "answers": [ "きょうとう" ], "comment": "joint struggle; common (united) front" },
	{ "question": "共鳴", "answers": [ "きょうめい" ], "comment": "resonance; sympathetic (sound); (being in) sympathy" },
	{ "question": "兵", "answers": [ "へい" ], "comment": "(common) soldier; rank and file\narmy; troops\nwarfare; strategy" },
	{ "question": "兵力", "answers": [ "へいりょく" ], "comment": "military force; force of arms; strength of an army" },
	{ "question": "兵員", "answers": [ "へいいん" ], "comment": "military strength; military personnel" },
	{ "question": "兵器", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "arms; weapons; ordnance" },
	{ "question": "兵士", "answers": [ "へいし" ], "comment": "soldier" },
	{ "question": "兵役", "answers": [ "へいえき" ], "comment": "military service; conscription" },
	{ "question": "兵舎", "answers": [ "へいしゃ" ], "comment": "barracks" },
	{ "question": "兵隊", "answers": [ "へいたい" ], "comment": "soldier; sailor" },
	{ "question": "具", "answers": [ "ぐ" ], "comment": "tool; means\ningredients (added to soup, rice, etc.)\ncounter for sets of armor, utensils, furniture, etc." },
	{ "question": "具わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "to be furnished with; to be provided with; to be equipped with\nto be possessed of; to be endowed with; to be gifted with\nto be among; to be one of" },
	{ "question": "具体", "answers": [ "ぐたい" ], "comment": "concrete; tangible; material" },
	{ "question": "具体化", "answers": [ "ぐたいか" ], "comment": "embodiment; materialization; actualization; realization; taking form; taking shape" },
	{ "question": "具体的", "answers": [ "ぐたいてき" ], "comment": "concrete; tangible; definite; specific" },
	{ "question": "具合", "answers": [ "ぐあい" ], "comment": "condition; state; manner; health" },
	{ "question": "具象", "answers": [ "ぐしょう" ], "comment": "embodying; expressing concretely" },
	{ "question": "典型", "answers": [ "てんけい" ], "comment": "type; pattern; model; epitome; exemplar; archetypal; representative" },
	{ "question": "典型的", "answers": [ "てんけいてき" ], "comment": "typical; prototypical; representative; stereotypical; model; ideal; archetypal; quintessential" },
	{ "question": "兼", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "cum (e.g. bedroom-cum-study); holding both roles (e.g. Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs); and; in addition; concurrently; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "兼ね備える", "answers": [ "かねそなえる" ], "comment": "to have both; to possess both; to combine with" },
	{ "question": "兼ね合い", "answers": [ "かねあい" ], "comment": "equilibrium; good balance; poise" },
	{ "question": "兼任", "answers": [ "けんにん" ], "comment": "concurrent post\nto hold two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "兼務", "answers": [ "けんむ" ], "comment": "holding two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "内", "answers": [ "ない" ], "comment": "inside; within" },
	{ "question": "内々", "answers": [ "うちうち", "ないない" ], "comment": "family circle; the inside; private; informal; secret; confidential" },
	{ "question": "内乱", "answers": [ "ないらん" ], "comment": "civil war; insurrection; rebellion; domestic conflict" },
	{ "question": "内側", "answers": [ "うちがわ" ], "comment": "inside; interior; inner part" },
	{ "question": "内務", "answers": [ "ないむ" ], "comment": "internal or domestic affairs" },
	{ "question": "内包", "answers": [ "ないほう" ], "comment": "connotation; comprehension; intension\ninclusion; containment within" },
	{ "question": "内向", "answers": [ "ないこう" ], "comment": "introvert" },
	{ "question": "内向的", "answers": [ "ないこうてき" ], "comment": "introvert" },
	{ "question": "内外", "answers": [ "うちそと", "ないがい" ], "comment": "inside and outside; domestic and foreign; approximately; interior and exterior" },
	{ "question": "内定", "answers": [ "ないてい" ], "comment": "unofficial offer (esp. job offer); tentative decision" },
	{ "question": "内実", "answers": [ "ないじつ" ], "comment": "the facts" },
	{ "question": "内容", "answers": [ "ないよう" ], "comment": "subject; contents; matter; substance; detail; import" },
	{ "question": "内幕", "answers": [ "ないまく", "うちまく" ], "comment": "lowdown; inside curtain; inside information; hidden circumstances; inside facts; inner workings; undisclosed circumstances" },
	{ "question": "内心", "answers": [ "ないしん" ], "comment": "inner thoughts; real intention; inmost heart; one's mind; at heart; deep down; on the inside\ninner center (centre)" },
	{ "question": "内情", "answers": [ "ないじょう" ], "comment": "internal conditions; true state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "内戦", "answers": [ "ないせん" ], "comment": "civil war" },
	{ "question": "内政", "answers": [ "ないせい" ], "comment": "domestic affairs; internal administration" },
	{ "question": "内気", "answers": [ "うちき" ], "comment": "bashfulness; shyness; reserve; timidity" },
	{ "question": "内海", "answers": [ "うちうみ", "ないかい" ], "comment": "inlet; bay; inland sea" },
	{ "question": "内申", "answers": [ "ないしん" ], "comment": "unofficial report; confidential report" },
	{ "question": "内示", "answers": [ "ないじ" ], "comment": "unofficial announcement" },
	{ "question": "内科", "answers": [ "ないか" ], "comment": "internal medicine, i.e. treatment by medical procedures rather than surgical procedures\ndepartment of internal medicine (hospital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "内緒", "answers": [ "ないしょ", "ないしょう" ], "comment": "secrecy; confidentiality; privacy; secret\none's circumstances (esp. fiscal)\ninner realization; personal enlightenment\nkitchen" },
	{ "question": "内線", "answers": [ "ないせん" ], "comment": "phone extension; indoor wiring; inner line" },
	{ "question": "内職", "answers": [ "ないしょく" ], "comment": "side job (at home); home industry; side line" },
	{ "question": "内臓", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "internal organs; intestines; viscera" },
	{ "question": "内蔵", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "internal (e.g. disk); built-in; equipped (with)" },
	{ "question": "内装", "answers": [ "ないそう" ], "comment": "interior design; interior; upholstery" },
	{ "question": "内規", "answers": [ "ないき" ], "comment": "private regulations; bylaws; internal rules; tradition" },
	{ "question": "内角", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "interior angle; internal angle\ninside corner" },
	{ "question": "内訳", "answers": [ "うちわけ" ], "comment": "itemization (of expenses); the items; breakdown; classification" },
	{ "question": "内輪", "answers": [ "うちわ" ], "comment": "moderate; private matter; family circle; the inside\nconservative\npigeon-toed" },
	{ "question": "内部", "answers": [ "ないぶ" ], "comment": "interior; inside; internal" },
	{ "question": "内野", "answers": [ "ないや" ], "comment": "infield; diamond" },
	{ "question": "内野手", "answers": [ "ないやしゅ" ], "comment": "infielder; baseman" },
	{ "question": "内閣", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "cabinet; (government) ministry" },
	{ "question": "内閣官房", "answers": [ "ないかくかんぼう" ], "comment": "Cabinet Secretariat" },
	{ "question": "内閣法制局", "answers": [ "ないかくほうせいきょく" ], "comment": "Cabinet Legislation Bureau" },
	{ "question": "内陸", "answers": [ "ないりく" ], "comment": "inland" },
	{ "question": "内需", "answers": [ "ないじゅ" ], "comment": "domestic demand" },
	{ "question": "内面", "answers": [ "ないめん" ], "comment": "inside; interior" },
	{ "question": "円", "answers": [ "えん" ], "comment": "yen; Japanese monetary unit\ncircle" },
	{ "question": "円い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "円み", "answers": [ "まるみ" ], "comment": "roundness; rotundity\nmellowness; maturity" },
	{ "question": "円卓", "answers": [ "えんたく" ], "comment": "round table" },
	{ "question": "円周", "answers": [ "えんしゅう" ], "comment": "circumference" },
	{ "question": "円安", "answers": [ "えんやす" ], "comment": "cheap yen" },
	{ "question": "円建て", "answers": [ "えんだて" ], "comment": "denominated in yen; yen-denominated; yen base" },
	{ "question": "円形", "answers": [ "えんけい", "まるがた" ], "comment": "round shape; circle\ncircular form" },
	{ "question": "円満", "answers": [ "えんまん" ], "comment": "perfection; harmony; peace; smoothness; completeness; satisfaction; integrity" },
	{ "question": "円滑", "answers": [ "えんかつ" ], "comment": "smooth; undisturbed; uninterrupted; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "円盤", "answers": [ "えんばん" ], "comment": "disk; discus; platter\nflying saucer\ndisc media (CD, DVD, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "円相場", "answers": [ "えんそうば" ], "comment": "yen exchange rate" },
	{ "question": "円筒", "answers": [ "えんとう" ], "comment": "cylinder" },
	{ "question": "円高", "answers": [ "えんだか" ], "comment": "appreciation of the yen; strong yen; strengthening of the yen; high-valued yen; exchange in favor of the yen (favour)" },
	{ "question": "冊", "answers": [ "さつ" ], "comment": "counter for books\nvolume" },
	{ "question": "冊子", "answers": [ "さっし" ], "comment": "book; booklet; story book; pamphlet; notebook" },
	{ "question": "再", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "re-; again; repeated; deutero-; deuto-; deuter-" },
	{ "question": "再び", "answers": [ "ふたたび" ], "comment": "again; once more; a second time" },
	{ "question": "再スタート", "answers": [ "さいスタート" ], "comment": "restarting" },
	{ "question": "再三", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "again and again; repeatedly" },
	{ "question": "再任", "answers": [ "さいにん" ], "comment": "reappointment" },
	{ "question": "再会", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "another meeting; meeting again; reunion" },
	{ "question": "再婚", "answers": [ "さいこん" ], "comment": "second marriage; remarriage" },
	{ "question": "再審", "answers": [ "さいしん" ], "comment": "retrial; reopening of a case\nreview; reexamination" },
	{ "question": "再度", "answers": [ "さいど" ], "comment": "twice; again; second time" },
	{ "question": "再建", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "rebuilding; reconstruction; rehabilitation\nprotoform reconstruction" },
	{ "question": "再来", "answers": [ "さいらい" ], "comment": "return; coming back\nsecond coming (e.g. of Christ); second advent; reincarnation" },
	{ "question": "再来年", "answers": [ "さらいねん" ], "comment": "year after next" },
	{ "question": "再来月", "answers": [ "さらいげつ" ], "comment": "month after next" },
	{ "question": "再来週", "answers": [ "さらいしゅう" ], "comment": "week after next" },
	{ "question": "再検討", "answers": [ "さいけんとう" ], "comment": "re-examination; review; reappraisal" },
	{ "question": "再演", "answers": [ "さいえん" ], "comment": "another showing (of a play)\nrecapitulation" },
	{ "question": "再燃", "answers": [ "さいねん" ], "comment": "recurrence; revival; resuscitation" },
	{ "question": "再現", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "reappearance; reproduction; return; revival" },
	{ "question": "再生", "answers": [ "さいせい" ], "comment": "resuscitation; regeneration; restoration to life\nreformation; rehabilitation\nplayback; regeneration (sound, etc.); view (of a video clip)\nreclamation; recovery\nrebirth; reincarnation" },
	{ "question": "再発", "answers": [ "さいはつ" ], "comment": "return; relapse; reoccurrence" },
	{ "question": "再編", "answers": [ "さいへん" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation; reshuffle" },
	{ "question": "再考", "answers": [ "さいこう" ], "comment": "reconsideration" },
	{ "question": "再販", "answers": [ "さいはん" ], "comment": "resale" },
	{ "question": "再起", "answers": [ "さいき" ], "comment": "comeback; recovery; restoration; rally; reflexive (in grammar)" },
	{ "question": "再選", "answers": [ "さいせん" ], "comment": "re-election" },
	{ "question": "再開", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "reopening; resumption; restarting" },
	{ "question": "再開発", "answers": [ "さいかいはつ" ], "comment": "redevelopment" },
	{ "question": "冒す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to brave; to risk; to face; to venture\nto harm; to afflict; to affect\nto desecrate; to profane\nto assume (someone else's surname); to take" },
	{ "question": "冒険", "answers": [ "ぼうけん" ], "comment": "risk; venture; adventure" },
	{ "question": "冒頭", "answers": [ "ぼうとう" ], "comment": "beginning; start; outset" },
	{ "question": "冗談", "answers": [ "じょうだん" ], "comment": "jest; joke; funny story" },
	{ "question": "写し", "answers": [ "うつし" ], "comment": "copy; duplicate; facsimile; transcript" },
	{ "question": "写す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to transcribe; to duplicate; to reproduce; to imitate; to trace\nto describe\nto film; to picture; to photograph" },
	{ "question": "写る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be photographed; to be projected" },
	{ "question": "写生", "answers": [ "しゃせい" ], "comment": "sketching; drawing from nature; portrayal; description" },
	{ "question": "写真", "answers": [ "しゃしん" ], "comment": "photograph; photo; picture; snapshot; snap\nmovie" },
	{ "question": "写真撮影", "answers": [ "しゃしんさつえい" ], "comment": "photography; taking photographs" },
	{ "question": "写真集", "answers": [ "しゃしんしゅう" ], "comment": "collection of photographs; photoalbum" },
	{ "question": "冠", "answers": [ "かん", "かむり", "かんむり", "かんぶり" ], "comment": "cap (esp. a traditional cap worn with sokutai or ikan clothing); crown; diadem; coronet\ntop kanji radical\nfirst verse of a haikai, etc.\nbest; peerless; first\nname; title; named sponsorship of a program, event, team, etc." },
	{ "question": "冠婚葬祭", "answers": [ "かんこんそうさい" ], "comment": "important ceremonial occasions in family relationships" },
	{ "question": "冬", "answers": [ "ふゆ" ], "comment": "winter" },
	{ "question": "冬休み", "answers": [ "ふゆやすみ" ], "comment": "winter vacation" },
	{ "question": "冬場", "answers": [ "ふゆば" ], "comment": "the winter season" },
	{ "question": "冬季", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "(season of) winter" },
	{ "question": "冬期", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "winter; wintertime; winter term" },
	{ "question": "冬眠", "answers": [ "とうみん" ], "comment": "hibernation; winter sleep" },
	{ "question": "冬至", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "winter solstice" },
	{ "question": "冴える", "answers": [ "さえる" ], "comment": "to be clear (of a sight, sound, colour, etc.); to be bright; to be vivid; to be crisp\nto be clear-headed; to be alert; to be on the ball; to be wide awake\nto look upbeat; to be perky; to be cheerful\nto master (a skill); to excel at; to cleanly execute\nto be satisfying\nto become frigid; to become intensely cold" },
	{ "question": "冷え", "answers": [ "ひえ" ], "comment": "chilliness; coldness" },
	{ "question": "冷える", "answers": [ "ひえる" ], "comment": "to grow cold (from room temperature, e.g. in refrigerator); to get chilly; to cool down" },
	{ "question": "冷え性", "answers": [ "ひえしょう" ], "comment": "sensitivity to cold" },
	{ "question": "冷え込む", "answers": [ "ひえこむ" ], "comment": "to get colder; to get chilled" },
	{ "question": "冷たい", "answers": [ "つめたい", "つべたい" ], "comment": "cold (to the touch); chilly; icy; freezing\ncoldhearted; unfeeling" },
	{ "question": "冷ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "to cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to let cool\nto dampen; to throw a damper on; to spoil" },
	{ "question": "冷める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "to become cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to come down (fever)\nto cool down (interest); to abate; to subside; to dampen" },
	{ "question": "冷やかす", "answers": [ "ひやかす" ], "comment": "to banter; to make fun of; to jeer at\nto cool; to refrigerate\nto window-shop; to look at without buying" },
	{ "question": "冷やす", "answers": [ "ひやす" ], "comment": "to cool (from room temperature); to chill; to refrigerate\nto calm down; to cool off; to regain one's composure; to relax\nto be frightened (at); to be scared (of)" },
	{ "question": "冷ややか", "answers": [ "ひややか" ], "comment": "cold; chilly; cool\nindifferent; cold-hearted; surly; curt; composed" },
	{ "question": "冷や汗", "answers": [ "ひやあせ", "れいかん" ], "comment": "cold sweat" },
	{ "question": "冷凍", "answers": [ "れいとう" ], "comment": "freezing; cold storage; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "冷凍庫", "answers": [ "れいとうこ" ], "comment": "freezer" },
	{ "question": "冷却", "answers": [ "れいきゃく" ], "comment": "cooling; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "冷夏", "answers": [ "れいか" ], "comment": "cool summer; cold summer; cooler-than-normal summer" },
	{ "question": "冷害", "answers": [ "れいがい" ], "comment": "cold-weather damage" },
	{ "question": "冷戦", "answers": [ "れいせん" ], "comment": "cold war" },
	{ "question": "冷房", "answers": [ "れいぼう" ], "comment": "cooling; air-conditioning" },
	{ "question": "冷暖房", "answers": [ "れいだんぼう" ], "comment": "air-conditioning; heating and cooling" },
	{ "question": "冷水", "answers": [ "れいすい" ], "comment": "cold water" },
	{ "question": "冷汗", "answers": [ "ひやあせ", "れいかん" ], "comment": "cold sweat" },
	{ "question": "冷淡", "answers": [ "れいたん" ], "comment": "coolness; indifference" },
	{ "question": "冷蔵", "answers": [ "れいぞう" ], "comment": "cold storage; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "冷蔵庫", "answers": [ "れいぞうこ" ], "comment": "refrigerator" },
	{ "question": "冷酷", "answers": [ "れいこく" ], "comment": "cruelty; coldheartedness; relentless; ruthless" },
	{ "question": "冷静", "answers": [ "れいせい" ], "comment": "calm; composure; coolness; serenity" },
	{ "question": "凄まじい", "answers": [ "すさまじい" ], "comment": "terrific; fierce; terrible; tremendous; dreadful; awful; amazing; absurd; cutthroat; intense" },
	{ "question": "凌ぐ", "answers": [ "しのぐ" ], "comment": "to endure; to keep out (e.g. rain); to stave off (e.g. starvation)\nto pull through; to get over; to survive\nto surpass; to outdo; to excel; to eclipse; to defy; to slight" },
	{ "question": "凍える", "answers": [ "こごえる" ], "comment": "to freeze (of one's body); to be frozen; to become numb (with cold); to be chilled" },
	{ "question": "凍る", "answers": [ "こおる" ], "comment": "to freeze; to be frozen over; to congeal" },
	{ "question": "凍結", "answers": [ "とうけつ" ], "comment": "freeze (e.g. program, food)" },
	{ "question": "凝った", "answers": [ "こった" ], "comment": "elaborate; exquisite; tasteful; refined; artistic" },
	{ "question": "凝る", "answers": [ "こる" ], "comment": "to grow stiff\nto be absorbed in; to be devoted to; to be a fanatic; to elaborate" },
	{ "question": "凝固", "answers": [ "ぎょうこ" ], "comment": "coagulation; freezing; solidification" },
	{ "question": "凝縮", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゅく" ], "comment": "condensation (of ideas, emotions, etc.)\ncondensation (of a vapour or gas)" },
	{ "question": "几帳面", "answers": [ "きちょうめん" ], "comment": "methodical; punctual; steady" },
	{ "question": "凡人", "answers": [ "ぼんじん", "ぼんにん" ], "comment": "ordinary person; average person; mediocre" },
	{ "question": "処分", "answers": [ "しょぶん" ], "comment": "disposal; dealing (with a problem); disposition; measure; procedure\npunishment\nputting down (e.g. diseased animal)" },
	{ "question": "処刑", "answers": [ "しょけい" ], "comment": "execution" },
	{ "question": "処女", "answers": [ "しょじょ" ], "comment": "virgin; maiden" },
	{ "question": "処理", "answers": [ "しょり" ], "comment": "processing; dealing with; treatment; disposition; disposal" },
	{ "question": "処置", "answers": [ "しょち" ], "comment": "measure; step; dealing with\nmedical treatment" },
	{ "question": "処罰", "answers": [ "しょばつ" ], "comment": "punishment" },
	{ "question": "処遇", "answers": [ "しょぐう" ], "comment": "treatment (of a person); dealing with" },
	{ "question": "凧", "answers": [ "いかのぼり", "はた", "たこ", "いか" ], "comment": "kite" },
	{ "question": "凶作", "answers": [ "きょうさく" ], "comment": "bad harvest; poor crop" },
	{ "question": "凶器", "answers": [ "きょうき" ], "comment": "dangerous weapon; lethal weapon; deadly weapon; murder weapon" },
	{ "question": "凶悪", "answers": [ "きょうあく" ], "comment": "atrocious; fiendish; brutal; villainous" },
	{ "question": "凸凹", "answers": [ "とつおう", "でこぼこ" ], "comment": "unevenness; roughness; ruggedness\ninequality" },
	{ "question": "凹み", "answers": [ "へこみ", "くぼみ" ], "comment": "hollow; cavity; dent; depression" },
	{ "question": "凹む", "answers": [ "へこむ" ], "comment": "to be dented; to be indented; to yield to; to give; to sink; to collapse; to cave in\nto be overwhelmed; to feel down; to be forced to yield; to be daunted; to be snubbed" },
	{ "question": "出かける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing); to leave; to depart; to start; to set out\nto be about to leave; to be just going out" },
	{ "question": "出す", "answers": [ "だす" ], "comment": "to take out; to get out\nto put out; to reveal; to show\nto submit (e.g. thesis); to turn in\nto publish; to make public\nto send (e.g. letter)\nto produce (a sound); to start (fire)\nto serve (food)\nto begin ...; to start to ...; to burst into ..." },
	{ "question": "出る", "answers": [ "でる" ], "comment": "to leave; to exit; to go out; to come out; to get out\nto leave (on a journey); to depart; to start out; to set out\nto move forward\nto come to; to get to; to lead to; to reach\nto appear; to come out; to emerge; to surface; to come forth; to turn up; to be found; to be detected; to be discovered; to be exposed; to show; to be exhibited; to be on display\nto appear (in print); to be published; to be announced; to be issued; to be listed; to come out\nto attend; to participate; to take part; to enter (an event); to play in; to perform\nto be stated; to be expressed; to come up; to be brought up; to be raised\nto sell\nto exceed; to go over\nto stick out; to protrude\nto break out; to occur; to start; to originate\nto be produced\nto come from; to be derived from\nto be given; to get; to receive; to be offered; to be provided; to be presented; to be submitted; to be handed in; to be turned in; to be paid\nto answer (phone, door, etc.); to get\nto assume (an attitude); to act; to behave\nto pick up (speed, etc.); to gain\nto flow (e.g. tears); to run; to bleed\nto graduate" },
	{ "question": "出世", "answers": [ "しゅっせ" ], "comment": "success in life; getting ahead; successful career; promotion; climbing the corporate ladder; eminence" },
	{ "question": "出会い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "meeting; rendezvous; encounter\nconfluence" },
	{ "question": "出会う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "to meet (by chance); to come across; to run across; to encounter; to happen upon\nto meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)\nto emerge and engage (an enemy)" },
	{ "question": "出入", "answers": [ "しゅつにゅう" ], "comment": "in and out; income and expenses; free associations; run of the house" },
	{ "question": "出入り", "answers": [ "ではいり", "でいり" ], "comment": "in and out; coming and going; free association; income and expenditure; debits and credit" },
	{ "question": "出入り口", "answers": [ "でいりぐち" ], "comment": "exit and entrance" },
	{ "question": "出入口", "answers": [ "でいりぐち" ], "comment": "exit and entrance" },
	{ "question": "出前", "answers": [ "でまえ" ], "comment": "catering; meal delivery service" },
	{ "question": "出力", "answers": [ "しゅつりょく" ], "comment": "output (electrical, signal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "出動", "answers": [ "しゅつどう" ], "comment": "sailing; marching; going out; dispatch" },
	{ "question": "出勤", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "attendance (at work); being at work; presence (in the office); going to work; reporting for work" },
	{ "question": "出口", "answers": [ "でぐち" ], "comment": "exit; gateway; way out; outlet; leak; vent" },
	{ "question": "出合い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "meeting; rendezvous; encounter\nconfluence" },
	{ "question": "出合う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "to meet (by chance); to come across; to run across; to encounter; to happen upon\nto meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)\nto emerge and engage (an enemy)" },
	{ "question": "出向", "answers": [ "しゅっこう" ], "comment": "secondment; temporary transfer\nproceeding; leaving for" },
	{ "question": "出向く", "answers": [ "でむく" ], "comment": "to go to; to proceed to; to leave for" },
	{ "question": "出品", "answers": [ "しゅっぴん" ], "comment": "exhibit; display; putting up for sale" },
	{ "question": "出国", "answers": [ "しゅっこく" ], "comment": "departure from a country" },
	{ "question": "出土", "answers": [ "しゅつど" ], "comment": "archeological excavation (archaeological)" },
	{ "question": "出場", "answers": [ "しゅつじょう" ], "comment": "(stage) appearance; performance\nparticipation (e.g. in a tournament)" },
	{ "question": "出塁", "answers": [ "しゅつるい" ], "comment": "on base" },
	{ "question": "出展", "answers": [ "しゅってん" ], "comment": "exhibit; display" },
	{ "question": "出席", "answers": [ "しゅっせき" ], "comment": "attendance; presence; appearance\nto attend; to be present; to appear" },
	{ "question": "出席者", "answers": [ "しゅっせきしゃ" ], "comment": "those present; attendance" },
	{ "question": "出店", "answers": [ "でみせ" ], "comment": "food stand; food stall\nbranch store" },
	{ "question": "出張", "answers": [ "しゅっちょう" ], "comment": "official tour; business trip" },
	{ "question": "出張所", "answers": [ "しゅっちょうじょ" ], "comment": "branch office; agency; sub-branch" },
	{ "question": "出所", "answers": [ "しゅっしょ", "でどこ", "でどころ" ], "comment": "origin; source; authority\nbirthplace\nrelease (discharge) from prison\nexit; point of departure\ntime to take action" },
	{ "question": "出掛ける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing); to leave; to depart; to start; to set out\nto be about to leave; to be just going out" },
	{ "question": "出撃", "answers": [ "しゅつげき" ], "comment": "sortie; sally" },
	{ "question": "出方", "answers": [ "でかた" ], "comment": "attitude; approach; move\ntheater usher; theatre usher" },
	{ "question": "出来", "answers": [ "でき", "しゅったい" ], "comment": "occurrence; happening; taking place /\n workmanship; craftsmanship; execution; finish\ngrades; results; score; record\nquality (e.g. of a crop)\ndealings; transactions" },
	{ "question": "出来上がり", "answers": [ "できあがり" ], "comment": "finish; completion; ready; made for; cut out" },
	{ "question": "出来上がる", "answers": [ "できあがる" ], "comment": "to be completed; to be finished; to be ready (e.g. to serve or eat)\nto be very drunk" },
	{ "question": "出来事", "answers": [ "できごと" ], "comment": "incident; affair; happening; event" },
	{ "question": "出来高", "answers": [ "できだか" ], "comment": "yield; crop; production; volume; piecework" },
	{ "question": "出欠", "answers": [ "しゅっけつ" ], "comment": "presence or absence; attendance (e.g. when taking a rollcall)" },
	{ "question": "出港", "answers": [ "しゅっこう" ], "comment": "departure; clearance (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "出演", "answers": [ "しゅつえん" ], "comment": "performance; stage appearance\nto act (in a play)" },
	{ "question": "出火", "answers": [ "しゅっか" ], "comment": "outbreak of fire" },
	{ "question": "出版", "answers": [ "しゅっぱん" ], "comment": "publication" },
	{ "question": "出版物", "answers": [ "しゅっぱんぶつ" ], "comment": "publication" },
	{ "question": "出版社", "answers": [ "しゅっぱんしゃ" ], "comment": "publisher; publishing house; publishing company" },
	{ "question": "出現", "answers": [ "しゅつげん" ], "comment": "appearance; arrival; make one's appearance" },
	{ "question": "出生", "answers": [ "しゅっせい", "しゅっしょう" ], "comment": "birth" },
	{ "question": "出産", "answers": [ "しゅっさん" ], "comment": "childbirth; (giving) birth; delivery; parturition; confinement\nproduction (of goods)" },
	{ "question": "出番", "answers": [ "でばん" ], "comment": "one's turn; one's shift\none's turn on stage; screen time; screentime" },
	{ "question": "出発", "answers": [ "しゅっぱつ" ], "comment": "departure" },
	{ "question": "出直し", "answers": [ "でなおし" ], "comment": "adjustment; touch up" },
	{ "question": "出稼ぎ", "answers": [ "でかせぎ" ], "comment": "working away from home" },
	{ "question": "出納", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "receipts and expenditure (disbursements)" },
	{ "question": "出荷", "answers": [ "しゅっか" ], "comment": "shipping; outgoing freight; forwarding" },
	{ "question": "出血", "answers": [ "しゅっけつ" ], "comment": "bleeding; haemorrhage; hemorrhage\nbleeding money; red ink; selling below cost" },
	{ "question": "出費", "answers": [ "しゅっぴ" ], "comment": "expenses; disbursements" },
	{ "question": "出資", "answers": [ "しゅっし" ], "comment": "investment; contribution; financing" },
	{ "question": "出走", "answers": [ "しゅっそう" ], "comment": "entry in a race" },
	{ "question": "出足", "answers": [ "であし" ], "comment": "turnout (of people)\nstart (e.g. race, campaign, term of office)\nconstant forward movement; initial charge; dash" },
	{ "question": "出身", "answers": [ "しゅっしん" ], "comment": "person's origin (e.g. city, country, parentage, school)" },
	{ "question": "出身者", "answers": [ "しゅっしんしゃ" ], "comment": "alumnus (alumnae); graduate; old boy (girl)\nformer member of an organization\nformer inhabitant (country, region, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "出迎え", "answers": [ "でむかえ" ], "comment": "meeting; reception" },
	{ "question": "出迎える", "answers": [ "でむかえる" ], "comment": "to meet; to greet" },
	{ "question": "出遅れる", "answers": [ "でおくれる" ], "comment": "to get a late start" },
	{ "question": "出金", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "withdrawal (of money); payment; contribution; investment; financing" },
	{ "question": "出陣", "answers": [ "しゅつじん" ], "comment": "departure for the front" },
	{ "question": "出頭", "answers": [ "しゅっとう" ], "comment": "appearance; presence; attendance\nsurrender (e.g. to the police); turning oneself in (e.g. to the police)" },
	{ "question": "出題", "answers": [ "しゅつだい" ], "comment": "setting a question (for an exam)\nsetting a theme (for composition of poetry)" },
	{ "question": "出願", "answers": [ "しゅつがん" ], "comment": "application" },
	{ "question": "出馬", "answers": [ "しゅつば" ], "comment": "running (for election); coming forward as a candidate\ngoing on horseback\ngoing in person\nletting out a horse; taking out a horse" },
	{ "question": "刀", "answers": [ "かたな", "とう" ], "comment": "(single-edged) sword; katana\ndagger; knife\nscalpel" },
	{ "question": "刃", "answers": [ "は", "やいば" ], "comment": "edge (of a knife or sword)\nprong (of an electrical plug)" },
	{ "question": "刃渡り", "answers": [ "はわたり" ], "comment": "length of a blade (sword, knife, etc.)\nwalking on the edge of a sword" },
	{ "question": "刃物", "answers": [ "はもの" ], "comment": "edged tool; cutlery" },
	{ "question": "分", "answers": [ "ぶん", "ふん" ], "comment": "minute\nfun (one tenth of a monme, 5.787 grains) /\n part; segment; share; ration\nrate\ndegree; one's lot; one's status; relation; duty; kind; lot\nin proportion to; just as much as" },
	{ "question": "分かち", "answers": [ "わかち" ], "comment": "distinction; differentiation; discrimination" },
	{ "question": "分かつ", "answers": [ "わかつ" ], "comment": "to divide; to separate\nto share; to distribute\nto distinguish" },
	{ "question": "分からず屋", "answers": [ "わからずや", "ぼつぶんぎょうかん" ], "comment": "obstinate person; blockhead" },
	{ "question": "分かり", "answers": [ "わかり" ], "comment": "understanding; comprehension" },
	{ "question": "分かれる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "to branch; to fork; to diverge\nto separate; to split; to divide\nto disperse; to scatter" },
	{ "question": "分かれ目", "answers": [ "わかれめ" ], "comment": "fork; junction; parting of the ways\nturning point" },
	{ "question": "分け", "answers": [ "わけ" ], "comment": "sharing; division\ndraw; tie" },
	{ "question": "分ける", "answers": [ "わける" ], "comment": "to divide (into); to split (into); to part; to separate; to divide up; to classify; to sort out; to divide out\nto share; to distribute; to deal out; to dish out\nto distinguish; to discriminate; to differentiate (between)\nto break up (a fight); to mediate\nto call a draw; to tie\nto push one's way through (a crowd)\nto sell" },
	{ "question": "分乗", "answers": [ "ぶんじょう" ], "comment": "riding separately" },
	{ "question": "分別", "answers": [ "ぶんべつ", "ふんべつ" ], "comment": "discernment; discretion; judgement; judgment; discrimination /\n separation (e.g. of rubbish when recycling); classification; discrimination; division; distinction" },
	{ "question": "分割", "answers": [ "ぶんかつ" ], "comment": "partition; division; separation; segmenting; splitting" },
	{ "question": "分化", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "specialization; specialisation; differentiation" },
	{ "question": "分子", "answers": [ "ぶんし" ], "comment": "numerator\nmolecule\nmember; element" },
	{ "question": "分岐", "answers": [ "ぶんき" ], "comment": "divergence (e.g. in a road); ramification\nforking; jump; multi-drop" },
	{ "question": "分岐点", "answers": [ "ぶんきてん" ], "comment": "junction; crossroads; division point; parting of ways" },
	{ "question": "分布", "answers": [ "ぶんぷ" ], "comment": "distribution; allocation" },
	{ "question": "分担", "answers": [ "ぶんたん" ], "comment": "apportionment; allotment; share" },
	{ "question": "分散", "answers": [ "ぶんさん" ], "comment": "dispersion; breakup; scattering; decentralization; decentralisation; distribution\nvariance\ndispersion" },
	{ "question": "分数", "answers": [ "ぶんすう" ], "comment": "fraction" },
	{ "question": "分析", "answers": [ "ぶんせき" ], "comment": "analysis" },
	{ "question": "分校", "answers": [ "ぶんこう" ], "comment": "branch school" },
	{ "question": "分業", "answers": [ "ぶんぎょう" ], "comment": "division of labor; division of labour; specialization; specialisation; assembly-line production" },
	{ "question": "分権", "answers": [ "ぶんけん" ], "comment": "decentralization of authority; decentralisation of authority" },
	{ "question": "分母", "answers": [ "ぶんぼ" ], "comment": "denominator" },
	{ "question": "分泌", "answers": [ "ぶんぴ", "ぶんぴつ" ], "comment": "secretion" },
	{ "question": "分科会", "answers": [ "ぶんかかい" ], "comment": "subcommittee; subworking group" },
	{ "question": "分立", "answers": [ "ぶんりつ" ], "comment": "segregation; separation; independence" },
	{ "question": "分裂", "answers": [ "ぶんれつ" ], "comment": "split; division; break up" },
	{ "question": "分解", "answers": [ "ぶんかい" ], "comment": "disassembly; dismantling; disaggregating; analysis; disintegrating; decomposing; degrading\nfactorization\ndecomposition; resolution\ndeblocking" },
	{ "question": "分譲", "answers": [ "ぶんじょう" ], "comment": "selling (real-estate) lots" },
	{ "question": "分身", "answers": [ "ぶんしん" ], "comment": "parturition; delivery; one's child; branch; offshoot; one's other self" },
	{ "question": "分配", "answers": [ "ぶんぱい" ], "comment": "division; splitting; sharing; distribution; dissemination; allocation" },
	{ "question": "分野", "answers": [ "ぶんや" ], "comment": "field; sphere; realm; division; branch" },
	{ "question": "分量", "answers": [ "ぶんりょう" ], "comment": "amount; quantity" },
	{ "question": "分間", "answers": [ "ふんかん" ], "comment": "minutes (period of)" },
	{ "question": "分離", "answers": [ "ぶんり" ], "comment": "separation; partition; detachment; segregation; isolation" },
	{ "question": "分類", "answers": [ "ぶんるい" ], "comment": "classification; categorization; sorting" },
	{ "question": "切ない", "answers": [ "せつない" ], "comment": "painful; heartrending; trying\noppressive; suffocating; miserable" },
	{ "question": "切らす", "answers": [ "きらす" ], "comment": "to be out of; to run out of; to be short of; to be out of stock" },
	{ "question": "切り下げ", "answers": [ "きりさげ" ], "comment": "devaluation (e.g. of currency); markdown; write-down; undercutting" },
	{ "question": "切り口", "answers": [ "きりくち" ], "comment": "cut end; section; opening; slit\npoint of view; (different) perspective; new approach" },
	{ "question": "切り抜き", "answers": [ "きりぬき" ], "comment": "clipping (of newspaper article, etc.); cutting; scrap (for a scrapbook)\ncut-out (picture, coloured paper, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "切り捨て", "answers": [ "きりすて" ], "comment": "cutting a person down (without a second thought); sacrificing; throwing to the wolves; treating as sword fodder\nomission; rounding down (e.g. fractions); truncation" },
	{ "question": "切り捨てる", "answers": [ "きりすてる" ], "comment": "to cut down; to slay\nto truncate; to round down; to round off\nto omit; to discard; to cast away" },
	{ "question": "切り替え", "answers": [ "きりかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion; replacement; switching (to); switchover" },
	{ "question": "切り替える", "answers": [ "きりかえる" ], "comment": "to change; to exchange; to convert; to renew; to throw a switch; to replace; to switch over" },
	{ "question": "切り札", "answers": [ "きりふだ" ], "comment": "trump card\nace up one's sleeve; secret weapon" },
	{ "question": "切る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "to cut; to cut through; to perform (surgery)\nto sever (connections, ties)\nto turn off (e.g. the light)\nto terminate (e.g. a conversation); to hang up (the phone); to disconnect\nto punch (a ticket); to tear off (a stub)\nto open (something sealed)\nto start\nto set (a limit); to do (something) in less or within a certain time; to issue (stamps, vouchers, etc.)\nto reduce; to decrease; to discount\nto shake off (water, etc.); to let drip-dry; to let drain\nto cross; to traverse\nto criticize sharply\nto act decisively; to do (something noticeable); to go first; to make (certain facial expressions, in kabuki)\nto turn (a vehicle)\nto curl (a ball); to bend; to cut\nto shuffle (cards)\nto dismiss; to sack; to let go; to expulse; to excommunicate\nto dig (a groove); to cut (a stencil, on a mimeograph)\nto trump\nto cut (the connection between two groups) (in go)\nto start a fire (with wood-wood friction or by striking a metal against stone)\nto draw (a shape) in the air (with a sword, etc.)\nto finish; to complete" },
	{ "question": "切れ", "answers": [ "きれ" ], "comment": "piece; slice; strip; scrap\ncloth\nsharpness\ncounter for scraps, pieces, etc." },
	{ "question": "切れ味", "answers": [ "きれあじ" ], "comment": "sharpness; cutting ability\nquickness (of wit); incisiveness; technical proficiency; skill\npeppiness (of a ball)" },
	{ "question": "切れ目", "answers": [ "きれめ" ], "comment": "break; pause; gap; end; rift; interruption; cut; section; notch; incision; end (of a task)" },
	{ "question": "切実", "answers": [ "せつじつ" ], "comment": "earnest; sincere; acute; keen; fervent\npressing; urgent; serious; severe\npertinent; appropriate" },
	{ "question": "切手", "answers": [ "きって" ], "comment": "stamp (postage); merchandise certificate" },
	{ "question": "切断", "answers": [ "せつだん", "さいだん" ], "comment": "cutting; severance; section; amputation; disconnection" },
	{ "question": "切望", "answers": [ "せつぼう" ], "comment": "longing for; earnest desire; desperate desire; hope; yearning; hankering" },
	{ "question": "切符", "answers": [ "きっぷ" ], "comment": "ticket" },
	{ "question": "刈り込む", "answers": [ "かりこむ" ], "comment": "to cut; to dress; to prune; to trim; to clip" },
	{ "question": "刈る", "answers": [ "かる" ], "comment": "to cut (hair); to mow (grass); to harvest; to clip; to shear; to reap; to trim; to prune" },
	{ "question": "刊行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "publication; issue" },
	{ "question": "刑", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "penalty; sentence; punishment" },
	{ "question": "刑事", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "(police) detective\ncriminal matter" },
	{ "question": "刑事事件", "answers": [ "けいじじけん" ], "comment": "criminal case" },
	{ "question": "刑事責任", "answers": [ "けいじせきにん" ], "comment": "criminal liability" },
	{ "question": "刑務所", "answers": [ "けいむしょ" ], "comment": "prison; penitentiary" },
	{ "question": "刑法", "answers": [ "けいほう" ], "comment": "criminal law; penal code" },
	{ "question": "刑罰", "answers": [ "けいばつ" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; penalty; punishment" },
	{ "question": "列", "answers": [ "れつ" ], "comment": "queue; line; row; column; sequence; string; train" },
	{ "question": "列島", "answers": [ "れっとう" ], "comment": "archipelago; chain of islands" },
	{ "question": "列挙", "answers": [ "れっきょ" ], "comment": "enumeration; list" },
	{ "question": "列車", "answers": [ "れっしゃ" ], "comment": "train (ordinary)" },
	{ "question": "初", "answers": [ "はつ", "うい" ], "comment": "first; new" },
	{ "question": "初めて", "answers": [ "はじめて" ], "comment": "for the first time\nonly after ... is it ...; only when ... do you ..." },
	{ "question": "初代", "answers": [ "しょだい" ], "comment": "first generation; founder" },
	{ "question": "初任給", "answers": [ "しょにんきゅう" ], "comment": "initial salary" },
	{ "question": "初出", "answers": [ "しょしゅつ" ], "comment": "first appearance" },
	{ "question": "初回", "answers": [ "しょかい" ], "comment": "first time; first innings; initial attempt\nfirst; initial" },
	{ "question": "初場所", "answers": [ "はつばしょ" ], "comment": "New Year's (January) tournament, held in Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "初売り", "answers": [ "はつうり" ], "comment": "first business conducted by retailers in the New Year" },
	{ "question": "初夏", "answers": [ "はつなつ", "しょか" ], "comment": "early summer\nfourth month of the lunar calendar" },
	{ "question": "初夢", "answers": [ "はつゆめ" ], "comment": "year's first dream" },
	{ "question": "初対面", "answers": [ "しょたいめん" ], "comment": "first meeting; first interview with" },
	{ "question": "初年", "answers": [ "しょねん" ], "comment": "first year; early years (of a reign or era)" },
	{ "question": "初心", "answers": [ "しょしん" ], "comment": "original intention; initial resolution" },
	{ "question": "初心者", "answers": [ "しょしんしゃ" ], "comment": "beginner" },
	{ "question": "初恋", "answers": [ "はつこい" ], "comment": "first love; puppy love" },
	{ "question": "初戦", "answers": [ "しょせん" ], "comment": "first match (in a series)" },
	{ "question": "初挑戦", "answers": [ "はつちょうせん" ], "comment": "first challenge; first try" },
	{ "question": "初日", "answers": [ "しょにち" ], "comment": "first or opening day" },
	{ "question": "初旬", "answers": [ "しょじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of the month" },
	{ "question": "初期", "answers": [ "しょき" ], "comment": "early (days); initial stage\ninitial" },
	{ "question": "初歩", "answers": [ "しょほ" ], "comment": "basics; rudiments; elements; ABCs of ..." },
	{ "question": "初演", "answers": [ "しょえん" ], "comment": "first performance" },
	{ "question": "初版", "answers": [ "しょはん" ], "comment": "first edition" },
	{ "question": "初球", "answers": [ "しょきゅう" ], "comment": "pitcher's first pitch (to batter)" },
	{ "question": "初級", "answers": [ "しょきゅう" ], "comment": "elementary level" },
	{ "question": "初老", "answers": [ "しょろう" ], "comment": "past middle-aged; aging; ageing; elderly\nage 40" },
	{ "question": "初舞台", "answers": [ "はつぶたい" ], "comment": "debut; initial stage appearance" },
	{ "question": "初詣", "answers": [ "はつもうで" ], "comment": "first shrine visit of New Year" },
	{ "question": "初詣で", "answers": [ "はつもうで" ], "comment": "first shrine visit of New Year" },
	{ "question": "初陣", "answers": [ "ういじん" ], "comment": "first campaign; one's first battle" },
	{ "question": "初雪", "answers": [ "はつゆき" ], "comment": "first snow (of season)" },
	{ "question": "初頭", "answers": [ "しょとう" ], "comment": "beginning (of a century, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "判", "answers": [ "ばん", "はん" ], "comment": "seal; stamp; monogram signature\njudgment; judgement\nsize (of paper or books)" },
	{ "question": "判事", "answers": [ "はんじ" ], "comment": "judge; judiciary" },
	{ "question": "判例", "answers": [ "はんれい" ], "comment": "(judicial) precedent" },
	{ "question": "判子", "answers": [ "はんこ" ], "comment": "seal (used for signature)" },
	{ "question": "判定", "answers": [ "はんてい" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; decision; adjudication; award; verdict; determination" },
	{ "question": "判断", "answers": [ "はんだん" ], "comment": "judgment; judgement; decision; conclusion; adjudication\ndivination\njudgement" },
	{ "question": "判明", "answers": [ "はんめい" ], "comment": "establishing; proving; ascertaining; identifying; confirming" },
	{ "question": "判決", "answers": [ "はんけつ" ], "comment": "judicial decision; judgement; judgment; sentence; decree" },
	{ "question": "別", "answers": [ "べつ" ], "comment": "distinction; difference; different; another; particular; separate; extra; exception" },
	{ "question": "別々", "answers": [ "べつべつ" ], "comment": "separately; individually" },
	{ "question": "別に", "answers": [ "べつに" ], "comment": "(not) particularly; (not) especially; (not) specially\nseparately; apart; additionally; extra" },
	{ "question": "別れ", "answers": [ "わかれ" ], "comment": "parting; separation; farewell; (lateral) branch; fork; offshoot; division; section" },
	{ "question": "別れる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "to part (usu. of people); to part from; to part with; to be apart from\nto separate (of a couple); to break up; to divorce\nto lose (e.g. one's mother); to be bereaved" },
	{ "question": "別人", "answers": [ "べつじん" ], "comment": "different person; someone else; changed man" },
	{ "question": "別個", "answers": [ "べっこ" ], "comment": "another; different; separate; discrete" },
	{ "question": "別冊", "answers": [ "べっさつ" ], "comment": "separate volume; extra issue; supplement; additional volume; supplementary volume" },
	{ "question": "別名", "answers": [ "べつみょう", "べつめい" ], "comment": "alias; pseudonym; pen name; nom de plume; different name; other name" },
	{ "question": "別問題", "answers": [ "べつもんだい" ], "comment": "different thing; another question; different case" },
	{ "question": "別室", "answers": [ "べっしつ" ], "comment": "separate room; another room\nspecial room\nconcubine (of a noble)" },
	{ "question": "別居", "answers": [ "べっきょ" ], "comment": "separation; living apart" },
	{ "question": "別荘", "answers": [ "べっそう" ], "comment": "holiday house; villa" },
	{ "question": "別表", "answers": [ "べっぴょう" ], "comment": "annexed (statistical) table" },
	{ "question": "別院", "answers": [ "べついん" ], "comment": "branch temple" },
	{ "question": "別館", "answers": [ "べっかん" ], "comment": "(hotel) annexe (annex)" },
	{ "question": "利", "answers": [ "り" ], "comment": "advantage; benefit; profit; interest" },
	{ "question": "利かせる", "answers": [ "きかせる" ], "comment": "to season (with salt, etc.); to bring out taste\nto use; to exercise; to display" },
	{ "question": "利き目", "answers": [ "ききめ" ], "comment": "effect; virtue; efficacy; impression" },
	{ "question": "利く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to be effective; to show effect\nto do its work; to carry out its function well\nto be possible to use" },
	{ "question": "利上げ", "answers": [ "りあげ" ], "comment": "increase in interest rates" },
	{ "question": "利下げ", "answers": [ "りさげ" ], "comment": "decrease in interest rates" },
	{ "question": "利便", "answers": [ "りべん" ], "comment": "convenience" },
	{ "question": "利口", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "clever; intelligent; wise; bright; sharp; sensible; smart; shrewd\nwell-behaved (of kids, animals, etc); obedient; good\ngood (with words)" },
	{ "question": "利回り", "answers": [ "りまわり" ], "comment": "interest; (investment) yield; profits" },
	{ "question": "利子", "answers": [ "りし" ], "comment": "interest (bank)" },
	{ "question": "利害", "answers": [ "りがい" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; interest" },
	{ "question": "利害関係", "answers": [ "りがいかんけい" ], "comment": "interests; stake" },
	{ "question": "利己主義", "answers": [ "りこしゅぎ" ], "comment": "egoism; selfishness" },
	{ "question": "利息", "answers": [ "りそく" ], "comment": "interest (bank)" },
	{ "question": "利払い", "answers": [ "りばらい" ], "comment": "interest payment" },
	{ "question": "利権", "answers": [ "りけん" ], "comment": "interest; rights; concession" },
	{ "question": "利潤", "answers": [ "りじゅん" ], "comment": "profit; returns" },
	{ "question": "利点", "answers": [ "りてん" ], "comment": "advantage; point in favor; point in favour" },
	{ "question": "利率", "answers": [ "りりつ" ], "comment": "interest rate" },
	{ "question": "利用", "answers": [ "りよう" ], "comment": "use; utilization; utilisation; application" },
	{ "question": "利用者", "answers": [ "りようしゃ" ], "comment": "user; end-user; consumer" },
	{ "question": "利益", "answers": [ "りやく", "りえき" ], "comment": "profit; gains\nbenefit; advantage; interest (of the public, etc.)\ngrace (of God, Buddha, etc.) (esp. as attained through rightful actions, prayer, adherence to one's faith, etc.); blessing; miracle" },
	{ "question": "到来", "answers": [ "とうらい" ], "comment": "arrival; coming (e.g. something awaited); advent" },
	{ "question": "到着", "answers": [ "とうちゃく" ], "comment": "arrival" },
	{ "question": "到達", "answers": [ "とうたつ" ], "comment": "reaching; attaining; arrival" },
	{ "question": "制", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "system; organization; organisation; imperial command; laws; regulation; control; government; suppression; restraint; holding back; establishment" },
	{ "question": "制する", "answers": [ "せいする" ], "comment": "to hold back (e.g. emotions); to rein in (e.g. a horse, unruly people); to bridle\nto get the better of\nto control; to command" },
	{ "question": "制作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "work (film, book)\nproduction; creation; turning (something) out; development" },
	{ "question": "制圧", "answers": [ "せいあつ" ], "comment": "gaining total control (of people or counties); suppression; oppression; control; mastery; ascendancy; supremacy" },
	{ "question": "制定", "answers": [ "せいてい" ], "comment": "enactment; establishment; creation" },
	{ "question": "制度", "answers": [ "せいど" ], "comment": "system; institution; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "制御", "answers": [ "せいぎょ" ], "comment": "control; governing; checking; suppression; repression; restraint; mastery; management" },
	{ "question": "制服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "uniform" },
	{ "question": "制止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "control; check; restraint; inhibition" },
	{ "question": "制球", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "(pitcher's) control" },
	{ "question": "制約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "limitation; restriction; condition; constraints" },
	{ "question": "制裁", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "restraint; sanctions; punishment" },
	{ "question": "制覇", "answers": [ "せいは" ], "comment": "conquest; domination; mastery" },
	{ "question": "制限", "answers": [ "せいげん" ], "comment": "restriction; restraint; limitation; limit" },
	{ "question": "刷る", "answers": [ "する" ], "comment": "to print\nto color or pattern fabric using a wooden mold" },
	{ "question": "刷新", "answers": [ "さっしん" ], "comment": "reform; renovation" },
	{ "question": "券", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "ticket; coupon; bond; certificate" },
	{ "question": "刺さる", "answers": [ "ささる" ], "comment": "to stick into (something with a sharp point); to prick; to pierce; to get stuck (in); to lodge (in)" },
	{ "question": "刺し", "answers": [ "さし" ], "comment": "grain thief; sharpened tube for testing rice in bags\nsashimi (sliced raw fish)\nstabbing; piercing; pricking" },
	{ "question": "刺し身", "answers": [ "さしみ" ], "comment": "sashimi (raw sliced fish, shellfish or crustaceans)" },
	{ "question": "刺す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to pierce; to stab; to prick; to stick; to thrust\nto sting; to bite\nto sew; to stitch; to embroider\nto pole (a boat)\nto catch (with a limed pole)\nto put (a runner) out; to pick off" },
	{ "question": "刺激", "answers": [ "しげき" ], "comment": "stimulus; impetus; incentive; encouragement; motivation; provocation; excitement; thrill" },
	{ "question": "刺繍", "answers": [ "ししゅう" ], "comment": "embroidery" },
	{ "question": "刺身", "answers": [ "さしみ" ], "comment": "sashimi (raw sliced fish, shellfish or crustaceans)" },
	{ "question": "刻", "answers": [ "こく" ], "comment": "archaic period of time (usu. a period of approx. two hours corresponding to one of the signs of the Chinese zodiac)\ncarving; engraving; cutting; mincing\nvictory\nstrictness; cruelty" },
	{ "question": "刻々", "answers": [ "こくこく", "こっこく" ], "comment": "moment by moment; hour by hour" },
	{ "question": "刻み", "answers": [ "きざみ" ], "comment": "shredded tobacco; notch; nick" },
	{ "question": "刻む", "answers": [ "きざむ" ], "comment": "to mince; to cut fine; to chop up; to hash; to shred\nto carve; to engrave; to chisel; to notch\nto tick away (time); to beat out (e.g. rhythm); to record the passing moments\nto etch (into one's mind); to remember distinctly\nto have tattooed\nto torment" },
	{ "question": "刻一刻", "answers": [ "こくいっこく" ], "comment": "moment by moment; hour by hour" },
	{ "question": "刻一刻と", "answers": [ "こくいっこくと" ], "comment": "moment by moment; hour by hour" },
	{ "question": "剃る", "answers": [ "する", "そる" ], "comment": "to shave" },
	{ "question": "削り節", "answers": [ "けずりぶし" ], "comment": "flaked bonito" },
	{ "question": "削る", "answers": [ "けずる" ], "comment": "to shave (wood or leather); to sharpen; to plane; to whittle; to pare; to scrape off\nto shave off (e.g. a budget, expenses, a salary, etc.); to curtail; to cut down\nto cross out; to reduce; to curtail; to remove; to erase; to delete" },
	{ "question": "削減", "answers": [ "さくげん" ], "comment": "cut; reduction; curtailment" },
	{ "question": "削除", "answers": [ "さくじょ" ], "comment": "deletion; elimination; erasure; striking out" },
	{ "question": "前", "answers": [ "まえ", "ぜん" ], "comment": "the last (i.e. immediately preceding) (e.g. \"the last mayor\"); previous; one-time; former\npre- (e.g. \"premodern\")\nbefore; earlier /\n ago; before (some event); previously; (minutes) to (the hour)\nin front (of); before (e.g. the house)\nhead (of a line); front (e.g. of a bus); fore part\nin the presence of\nhelping; portion\nprivates; private parts" },
	{ "question": "前々", "answers": [ "まえまえ" ], "comment": "beforehand; for a long time" },
	{ "question": "前もって", "answers": [ "まえもって" ], "comment": "in advance; beforehand; previously" },
	{ "question": "前代未聞", "answers": [ "ぜんだいみもん" ], "comment": "unheard-of; unprecedented; unparalleled in history (unparallelled); record-breaking" },
	{ "question": "前例", "answers": [ "ぜんれい" ], "comment": "precedent" },
	{ "question": "前倒し", "answers": [ "まえだおし" ], "comment": "moving forward (e.g. plans); acceleration (e.g. of payment schedule); front-loading" },
	{ "question": "前借り", "answers": [ "まえがり" ], "comment": "getting an advance (on one's salary)" },
	{ "question": "前兆", "answers": [ "ぜんちょう" ], "comment": "omen; portent; sign; premonition; harbinger" },
	{ "question": "前半", "answers": [ "ぜんはん", "ぜんぱん" ], "comment": "first half" },
	{ "question": "前半戦", "answers": [ "ぜんはんせん", "ぜんぱんせん" ], "comment": "first half of the game or match" },
	{ "question": "前向き", "answers": [ "まえむき" ], "comment": "facing forward; front-facing; forward-looking; positive; proactive" },
	{ "question": "前哨戦", "answers": [ "ぜんしょうせん" ], "comment": "skirmish; preliminary encounter; prefinals (in games)" },
	{ "question": "前回", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "previous time; last time; previous installment; previous instalment; previous session" },
	{ "question": "前売り", "answers": [ "まえうり" ], "comment": "advance sale; booking" },
	{ "question": "前売り券", "answers": [ "まえうりけん" ], "comment": "ticket sold in advance" },
	{ "question": "前夜", "answers": [ "ぜんや" ], "comment": "last night; the previous night\nnight before (Christmas, etc.); eve (of festival, major event, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "前夜祭", "answers": [ "ぜんやさい" ], "comment": "the eve (of festival) (e.g. Christmas Eve)" },
	{ "question": "前年", "answers": [ "ぜんねん" ], "comment": "the preceding year; the previous year; last year" },
	{ "question": "前年度", "answers": [ "ぜんねんど" ], "comment": "preceding fiscal year" },
	{ "question": "前後", "answers": [ "ぜんご" ], "comment": "front and rear; front and back; before and behind; back and forth\nbefore and after\norder; context\nconsequences\ninversion; reversion; getting out of order\nco-occurring\naround; about; approximately; nearly" },
	{ "question": "前払い", "answers": [ "まえばらい" ], "comment": "payment in advance; prepayment" },
	{ "question": "前提", "answers": [ "ぜんてい" ], "comment": "preamble; premise; reason; prerequisite; condition; assumption; hypothesis; given" },
	{ "question": "前文", "answers": [ "ぜんぶん" ], "comment": "preamble\nthe above statement" },
	{ "question": "前方", "answers": [ "ぜんぽう" ], "comment": "forward; frontward\nrectangular front" },
	{ "question": "前日", "answers": [ "まえび", "ぜんじつ" ], "comment": "previous day; day before; eve; prior day; preceding day" },
	{ "question": "前書き", "answers": [ "まえがき" ], "comment": "preface; preamble; prolog" },
	{ "question": "前期", "answers": [ "ぜんき" ], "comment": "first term; first half-year; preceding period; early period" },
	{ "question": "前略", "answers": [ "ぜんりゃく" ], "comment": "Forgive me for dispensing with the preliminaries, but I hasten to inform you that...\nomitting the beginning" },
	{ "question": "前線", "answers": [ "ぜんせん" ], "comment": "(weather) front\nfront line; forward area; action zone" },
	{ "question": "前置き", "answers": [ "まえおき" ], "comment": "preface; introduction" },
	{ "question": "前者", "answers": [ "ぜんしゃ" ], "comment": "the former" },
	{ "question": "前衛", "answers": [ "ぜんえい" ], "comment": "advance guard; vanguard\navant-garde (e.g. music)" },
	{ "question": "前触れ", "answers": [ "まえぶれ" ], "comment": "advance warning; previous notice; announcement\nherald; harbinger; forerunner; portent; omen" },
	{ "question": "前記", "answers": [ "ぜんき" ], "comment": "aforesaid; above-mentioned; said; above" },
	{ "question": "前身", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "antecedents; ancestor; previous position; previous existence; predecessor organization; predecessor organisation" },
	{ "question": "前途", "answers": [ "ぜんと" ], "comment": "future prospects; outlook; the journey ahead" },
	{ "question": "前週", "answers": [ "ぜんしゅう" ], "comment": "last week; the week before" },
	{ "question": "前進", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "advance; drive; progress" },
	{ "question": "前部", "answers": [ "ぜんぶ" ], "comment": "front part; fore; front" },
	{ "question": "前面", "answers": [ "ぜんめん" ], "comment": "front part; frontage; facade\ninitial pledge (e.g. election); opening slogan" },
	{ "question": "前頭", "answers": [ "まえがしら" ], "comment": "rank-and-file wrestlers in the highest division" },
	{ "question": "剣", "answers": [ "つるぎ", "けん" ], "comment": "sword (originally esp. a doubled-edged sword); sabre; saber; blade\nbayonet\nswordsmanship\nstinger; ovipositor; dart" },
	{ "question": "剣士", "answers": [ "けんし" ], "comment": "swordsman; swordswoman; fencer" },
	{ "question": "剣道", "answers": [ "けんどう" ], "comment": "kendo; swordmanship; fencing; way of the sword" },
	{ "question": "剥ぐ", "answers": [ "へぐ", "はぐ" ], "comment": "to tear off; to peel off; to rip off; to strip off; to skin; to flay; to bark; to disrobe\nto strip of (e.g. clothes, rank); to deprive of; to divest" },
	{ "question": "剥ける", "answers": [ "むける" ], "comment": "to peel off; to come off; to be taken off" },
	{ "question": "副", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "assistant; associate; vice-; sub-; deputy; substitute; auxiliary; supplementary; additional; collateral\nduplicate; copy\nadverb" },
	{ "question": "副作用", "answers": [ "ふくさよう" ], "comment": "side effect; adverse reaction" },
	{ "question": "副知事", "answers": [ "ふくちじ" ], "comment": "lieutenant governor" },
	{ "question": "副社長", "answers": [ "ふくしゃちょう" ], "comment": "executive vice-president" },
	{ "question": "副詞", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "adverb" },
	{ "question": "副賞", "answers": [ "ふくしょう" ], "comment": "extra prize" },
	{ "question": "副題", "answers": [ "ふくだい" ], "comment": "subtitle; subheading" },
	{ "question": "割", "answers": [ "わり" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; proportion; percentage\nprofit\nassignment\n10%; unit of ten percent\nmatch; schedule of matches\ndiluted with (of drinks); mixed with" },
	{ "question": "割く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to tear; to rip up\nto cut up; to cleave; to cut open (esp. the abdomen)\nto forcibly separate (e.g. two lovers)\nto spare (time, money, etc.); to use part of something\nto have a tattoo in the corner of one's eye" },
	{ "question": "割と", "answers": [ "わりと" ], "comment": "relatively; comparatively" },
	{ "question": "割に", "answers": [ "わりに" ], "comment": "comparatively; relatively; pretty; rather\nunexpectedly; unusually" },
	{ "question": "割り", "answers": [ "わり" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; proportion; percentage\nprofit\nassignment\n10%; unit of ten percent\nmatch; schedule of matches\ndiluted with (of drinks); mixed with" },
	{ "question": "割り出す", "answers": [ "わりだす" ], "comment": "to calculate; to compute; to infer" },
	{ "question": "割り切る", "answers": [ "わりきる" ], "comment": "to find a clear solution; to come to a clean decision; to give a clear explanation\nto divide" },
	{ "question": "割り引", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "割り引き", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "割り引く", "answers": [ "わりびく" ], "comment": "to discount" },
	{ "question": "割り当て", "answers": [ "かっとう", "わりあて" ], "comment": "allotment; assignment; allocation; quota; rationing\nallocation" },
	{ "question": "割り当てる", "answers": [ "わりあてる" ], "comment": "to assign; to allot; to allocate; to divide among; to distribute; to prorate; to apportion" },
	{ "question": "割り算", "answers": [ "わりざん" ], "comment": "division" },
	{ "question": "割り箸", "answers": [ "わりばし" ], "comment": "splittable (wood) chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "割り込み", "answers": [ "わりこみ" ], "comment": "queue jumping; breaking into a line; muscling in on; wedging oneself in; interruption; sharing a theater box (theatre)\ninterrupt" },
	{ "question": "割り込む", "answers": [ "わりこむ" ], "comment": "to cut in; to thrust oneself into; to wedge oneself in; to muscle in on; to interrupt; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "割る", "answers": [ "わる" ], "comment": "to divide\nto cut; to halve; to separate; to split; to rip\nto break; to crack; to smash\nto dilute\nto fall below\nto discount\nto step over (a line, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "割れる", "answers": [ "われる" ], "comment": "to break; to be smashed\nto split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn\nto be divided; to cleave\nto come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear" },
	{ "question": "割れ目", "answers": [ "われめ" ], "comment": "chasm; interstice; crevice; crack; cleft; split; rift; fissure\nvulva; slit; cunt; vagina; twat" },
	{ "question": "割出す", "answers": [ "わりだす" ], "comment": "to calculate; to compute; to infer" },
	{ "question": "割合", "answers": [ "わりあい" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; percentage; proportion\ncomparatively\ncontrary to expectations" },
	{ "question": "割合に", "answers": [ "わりあいに" ], "comment": "comparatively" },
	{ "question": "割安", "answers": [ "わりやす" ], "comment": "economical; comparatively cheap" },
	{ "question": "割引", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "割引き", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "割引く", "answers": [ "わりびく" ], "comment": "to discount" },
	{ "question": "割引債", "answers": [ "わりびきさい" ], "comment": "discount bond" },
	{ "question": "割当て", "answers": [ "かっとう", "わりあて" ], "comment": "allotment; assignment; allocation; quota; rationing\nallocation" },
	{ "question": "割当てる", "answers": [ "わりあてる" ], "comment": "to assign; to allot; to allocate; to divide among; to distribute; to prorate; to apportion" },
	{ "question": "割高", "answers": [ "わりだか" ], "comment": "comparatively high; fairly expensive" },
	{ "question": "創り出す", "answers": [ "つくりだす" ], "comment": "to manufacture; to produce; to raise (crops)\nto invent; to dream up; to create" },
	{ "question": "創る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "創作", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "production; literary creation; work" },
	{ "question": "創価学会", "answers": [ "そうかがっかい" ], "comment": "Soka Gakkai (lay organization, based on Nichiren Buddhism) (organisation)" },
	{ "question": "創出", "answers": [ "そうしゅつ" ], "comment": "creation; generation" },
	{ "question": "創刊", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "launching (e.g. newspaper); first issue" },
	{ "question": "創始", "answers": [ "そうし" ], "comment": "creation; founding; initiating" },
	{ "question": "創意", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "original idea; originality" },
	{ "question": "創業", "answers": [ "そうぎょう" ], "comment": "establishment (of a business, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "創立", "answers": [ "そうりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "創設", "answers": [ "そうせつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "創造", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "creation" },
	{ "question": "創造力", "answers": [ "そうぞうりょく" ], "comment": "creative power; creativity" },
	{ "question": "創造的", "answers": [ "そうぞうてき" ], "comment": "creative" },
	{ "question": "劇", "answers": [ "げき" ], "comment": "drama; play\npowerful drug" },
	{ "question": "劇作", "answers": [ "げきさく" ], "comment": "play writing" },
	{ "question": "劇団", "answers": [ "げきだん" ], "comment": "troupe; theatrical company" },
	{ "question": "劇場", "answers": [ "げきじょう" ], "comment": "theatre; theater; playhouse" },
	{ "question": "劇画", "answers": [ "げきが" ], "comment": "comic strip with dramatic story" },
	{ "question": "劇的", "answers": [ "げきてき" ], "comment": "dramatic; exciting; touching\nextreme" },
	{ "question": "力", "answers": [ "ちから", "りょく" ], "comment": "force; strength; might; vigour (vigor); energy\ncapability; ability; proficiency; capacity; faculty\nefficacy; effect\neffort; endeavours (endeavors); exertions\npower; authority; influence; good offices; agency\nsupport; help; aid; assistance\nstress; emphasis\nmeans; resources /\n strength; power; proficiency; ability" },
	{ "question": "力む", "answers": [ "りきむ" ], "comment": "to strain; to bear up; to exert one's strength\nto swagger; to bluff; to boast" },
	{ "question": "力一杯", "answers": [ "ちからいっぱい" ], "comment": "with might and main; with all one's strength" },
	{ "question": "力作", "answers": [ "りきさく" ], "comment": "tour de force; painstaking piece of work; achievement" },
	{ "question": "力士", "answers": [ "りきし" ], "comment": "sumo wrestler; rikishi\nstrong man" },
	{ "question": "力学", "answers": [ "りきがく" ], "comment": "mechanics; dynamics" },
	{ "question": "力強い", "answers": [ "ちからづよい" ], "comment": "powerful; strong; forceful; vigorous\nreassuring; encouraging" },
	{ "question": "力投", "answers": [ "りきとう" ], "comment": "powerful pitching" },
	{ "question": "力持ち", "answers": [ "ちからもち" ], "comment": "muscleman; strong man" },
	{ "question": "力点", "answers": [ "りきてん" ], "comment": "leverage; emphasis; importance" },
	{ "question": "力試し", "answers": [ "ちからだめし" ], "comment": "trial of strength; quiz" },
	{ "question": "力説", "answers": [ "りきせつ" ], "comment": "insistence; (major) emphasis; stress" },
	{ "question": "力量", "answers": [ "りきりょう" ], "comment": "ability; capacity; capability; talent\nphysical strength" },
	{ "question": "功労", "answers": [ "こうろう" ], "comment": "meritorious deed; services" },
	{ "question": "功績", "answers": [ "こうせき" ], "comment": "achievements; merit; meritorious service; meritorious deed" },
	{ "question": "加", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "addition; increase\nCanada" },
	{ "question": "加える", "answers": [ "くわえる" ], "comment": "to add; to add up; to sum up; to append; to annex\nto increase; to gather (e.g. speed); to pick up\nto include; to count in; to let join\nto inflict (damage); to deal; to give" },
	{ "question": "加わる", "answers": [ "くわわる" ], "comment": "to be added to; to be appended\nto join in (e.g. a group of friends); to participate\nto increase (e.g. heat); to gain in (e.g. influence); to grow; to gather (speed)\nto be applied (e.g. heat, pressure); to be exerted" },
	{ "question": "加入", "answers": [ "かにゅう" ], "comment": "becoming a member; joining; entry; admission; subscription; affiliation; adherence; signing" },
	{ "question": "加味", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavoring; flavouring\naddition; inclusion; taking into account" },
	{ "question": "加圧", "answers": [ "かあつ" ], "comment": "increasing pressure" },
	{ "question": "加害者", "answers": [ "かがいしゃ" ], "comment": "assailant; perpetrator; wrong-doer; aggressor" },
	{ "question": "加工", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "manufacturing; processing; treatment; machining" },
	{ "question": "加担", "answers": [ "かたん" ], "comment": "support; participation; assistance; complicity; conspiracy" },
	{ "question": "加減", "answers": [ "かげん" ], "comment": "degree; extent; just right amount of\ncondition; state of health\nadjustment; moderation\naddition and subtraction" },
	{ "question": "加点", "answers": [ "かてん" ], "comment": "addition of points; scoring" },
	{ "question": "加熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "heating; application of heat" },
	{ "question": "加盟", "answers": [ "かめい" ], "comment": "participation; affiliation" },
	{ "question": "加算", "answers": [ "かさん" ], "comment": "addition; adding; supplement" },
	{ "question": "加速", "answers": [ "かそく" ], "comment": "acceleration; speeding up" },
	{ "question": "加重", "answers": [ "かじゅう", "かちょう" ], "comment": "weighting (in averaging); aggravation" },
	{ "question": "劣る", "answers": [ "おとる" ], "comment": "to be inferior to; to be less good at; to fall behind" },
	{ "question": "劣勢", "answers": [ "れっせい" ], "comment": "inferiority (e.g. numerical); inferior position; disadvantage; unfavorable situation; unfavourable situation" },
	{ "question": "劣化", "answers": [ "れっか" ], "comment": "deterioration; degradation; drop in quality" },
	{ "question": "劣悪", "answers": [ "れつあく" ], "comment": "inferiority; coarseness" },
	{ "question": "劣等感", "answers": [ "れっとうかん" ], "comment": "inferiority complex" },
	{ "question": "助かる", "answers": [ "たすかる" ], "comment": "to be saved; to be rescued; to survive\nto escape harm; to be spared damage\nto be helped; to be saved trouble" },
	{ "question": "助け", "answers": [ "たすけ" ], "comment": "assistance; help; aid; support; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "助ける", "answers": [ "たすける" ], "comment": "to save; to rescue\nto help; to assist\nto aid; to contribute (financially)\nto facilitate; to stimulate" },
	{ "question": "助け合い", "answers": [ "たすけあい" ], "comment": "cooperation; mutual aid (help)" },
	{ "question": "助っ人", "answers": [ "すけっと" ], "comment": "helper; supporter; second; backer" },
	{ "question": "助役", "answers": [ "じょやく" ], "comment": "assistant official" },
	{ "question": "助成", "answers": [ "じょせい" ], "comment": "assisting; assistance; fostering; aiding" },
	{ "question": "助手", "answers": [ "すけて", "じょしゅ" ], "comment": "helper; helpmeet; assistant; tutor" },
	{ "question": "助教授", "answers": [ "じょきょうじゅ" ], "comment": "assistant professor; associate professor" },
	{ "question": "助演", "answers": [ "じょえん" ], "comment": "co-star" },
	{ "question": "助産婦", "answers": [ "じょさんぷ" ], "comment": "midwife" },
	{ "question": "助言", "answers": [ "じょげん", "じょごん" ], "comment": "advice; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "助詞", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "particle; postposition" },
	{ "question": "努めて", "answers": [ "つとめて" ], "comment": "as much as possible; as far as possible; to the best of one's ability; diligently" },
	{ "question": "努める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to endeavor (endeavour); to try; to strive; to make an effort; to exert oneself; to be diligent; to be committed (to doing something)" },
	{ "question": "努力", "answers": [ "どりょく" ], "comment": "great effort; exertion; endeavour; endeavor; effort" },
	{ "question": "励まし", "answers": [ "はげまし" ], "comment": "encouragement (as an abstract concept); stimulation" },
	{ "question": "励ます", "answers": [ "はげます" ], "comment": "to encourage; to cheer; to raise (the voice)" },
	{ "question": "励み", "answers": [ "はげみ" ], "comment": "(act of) encouragement; stimulus; incentive" },
	{ "question": "励む", "answers": [ "はげむ" ], "comment": "to strive; to endeavour; to endeavor; to make an effort; to be zealous" },
	{ "question": "労", "answers": [ "ろう" ], "comment": "labor; labour; toil; trouble; pains; work; effort; striving" },
	{ "question": "労作", "answers": [ "ろうさく" ], "comment": "toil; labor; labour; laborious task" },
	{ "question": "労使", "answers": [ "ろうし" ], "comment": "labour and management; labor and management" },
	{ "question": "労働", "answers": [ "ろうどう" ], "comment": "manual labor; manual labour; toil; work\nLabour Party" },
	{ "question": "労働党", "answers": [ "ろうどうとう" ], "comment": "Labour Party; Labor Party; worker's party" },
	{ "question": "労働基準法", "answers": [ "ろうどうきじゅんほう" ], "comment": "Labor Standards Act" },
	{ "question": "労働条件", "answers": [ "ろうどうじょうけん" ], "comment": "working conditions" },
	{ "question": "労働省", "answers": [ "ろうどうしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Labour (now Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare)" },
	{ "question": "労働組合", "answers": [ "ろうどうくみあい" ], "comment": "labor union; labour union; trade union" },
	{ "question": "労働者", "answers": [ "ろうどうしゃ" ], "comment": "employee; worker\nlaborer (labourer); blue-collar worker" },
	{ "question": "労働運動", "answers": [ "ろうどううんどう" ], "comment": "labour movement; labor movement" },
	{ "question": "労力", "answers": [ "ろうりょく" ], "comment": "labour; labor; effort; toil; trouble" },
	{ "question": "労務", "answers": [ "ろうむ" ], "comment": "labor; labour; work; service" },
	{ "question": "労災", "answers": [ "ろうさい" ], "comment": "work-related injury; work-related illness; work-related death; on-the-job accident\nworkers' compensation insurance" },
	{ "question": "労相", "answers": [ "ろうしょう" ], "comment": "Labor Minister" },
	{ "question": "労組", "answers": [ "ろうそ", "ろうくみ" ], "comment": "labor union; labour union; trade union" },
	{ "question": "労連", "answers": [ "ろうれん" ], "comment": "labour union; labor union" },
	{ "question": "効き目", "answers": [ "ききめ" ], "comment": "effect; virtue; efficacy; impression" },
	{ "question": "効く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to be effective; to show effect\nto do its work; to carry out its function well\nto be possible to use" },
	{ "question": "効力", "answers": [ "こうりょく" ], "comment": "effect; efficacy; validity; potency" },
	{ "question": "効果", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "effect; effectiveness; efficacy; result\neffects (e.g. sound effects, visual effects, special effects)" },
	{ "question": "効果的", "answers": [ "こうかてき" ], "comment": "effective; successful" },
	{ "question": "効率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "efficiency; efficacy; performance; utility factor" },
	{ "question": "効率的", "answers": [ "こうりつてき" ], "comment": "efficient" },
	{ "question": "効用", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "use; utility; effect; benefit" },
	{ "question": "効能", "answers": [ "こうのう" ], "comment": "effect; efficacy; virtue; benefit" },
	{ "question": "勃起", "answers": [ "ぼっき" ], "comment": "erection (usu. penis); standing erect; stiffening" },
	{ "question": "勅", "answers": [ "ちょく", "みことのり" ], "comment": "imperial decree; imperial edict" },
	{ "question": "勇ましい", "answers": [ "いさましい" ], "comment": "brave; valiant; gallant; courageous\nstirring; vigorous; rousing" },
	{ "question": "勇敢", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "brave; heroic; gallant" },
	{ "question": "勇気", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; valour; valor; nerve; boldness" },
	{ "question": "勇退", "answers": [ "ゆうたい" ], "comment": "bowing out; retiring voluntarily" },
	{ "question": "勉学", "answers": [ "べんがく" ], "comment": "study; pursuit of knowledge" },
	{ "question": "勉強", "answers": [ "べんきょう" ], "comment": "study\ndiligence\ndiscount; reduction" },
	{ "question": "動", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "motion; change; confusion" },
	{ "question": "動かす", "answers": [ "うごかす" ], "comment": "to move; to shift; to stir; to budge; to change position\nto inspire; to rouse; to move (e.g. feeling); to influence\nto change; to alter; to deny\nto operate; to set in motion; to get going\nto mobilize (e.g. troops); to mobilise; to deploy\nto manage (e.g. funds)" },
	{ "question": "動き", "answers": [ "うごき" ], "comment": "movement; move; motion\ntrend; development; change; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "動き出す", "answers": [ "うごきだす" ], "comment": "to come alive; to get going; to start to move" },
	{ "question": "動く", "answers": [ "うごく" ], "comment": "to move; to stir; to shift; to shake; to swing\nto operate; to run; to go; to work\nto be touched; to be influenced\nto change; to vary; to fluctuate; to waver\ncertain; factual\nto be transferred" },
	{ "question": "動じる", "answers": [ "どうじる" ], "comment": "to be perturbed; to be agitated" },
	{ "question": "動乱", "answers": [ "どうらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; agitation; commotion; upheaval; riot" },
	{ "question": "動作", "answers": [ "どうさ" ], "comment": "action; movements; motions; bearing; behaviour; behavior; execution; actuation; operation; manners" },
	{ "question": "動力", "answers": [ "どうりょく" ], "comment": "power; motive power; dynamic force\nthree-phase electricity" },
	{ "question": "動向", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "trend; tendency; movement; attitude" },
	{ "question": "動員", "answers": [ "どういん" ], "comment": "mobilization; mobilisation" },
	{ "question": "動態", "answers": [ "どうたい" ], "comment": "movement; dynamic state" },
	{ "question": "動揺", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "shaking; trembling; pitching; rolling; oscillation\ndisturbance; unrest; agitation; excitement; commotion; turmoil; discomposure; feeling shaken" },
	{ "question": "動植物", "answers": [ "どうしょくぶつ" ], "comment": "plants and animals; flora and fauna" },
	{ "question": "動機", "answers": [ "どうき" ], "comment": "motive; incentive\nmotif" },
	{ "question": "動物", "answers": [ "どうぶつ" ], "comment": "animal" },
	{ "question": "動物園", "answers": [ "どうぶつえん" ], "comment": "zoo; zoological gardens" },
	{ "question": "動画", "answers": [ "どうが" ], "comment": "video; movie; moving picture\nanimation; animated cartoon\nin-betweens (animation)" },
	{ "question": "動脈", "answers": [ "どうみゃく" ], "comment": "artery" },
	{ "question": "動脈硬化", "answers": [ "どうみゃくこうか" ], "comment": "arteriosclerosis; hardening of the arteries" },
	{ "question": "動詞", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "verb" },
	{ "question": "動議", "answers": [ "どうぎ" ], "comment": "motion (i.e. proposal to a committee, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "動静", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "state (of affairs); condition; developments; movements" },
	{ "question": "勘", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "perception; intuition; the sixth sense" },
	{ "question": "勘定", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "calculation; computation; counting; reckoning; count\nbill; check; account; payment (of a bill); settlement (of an account)\nconsideration; allowance" },
	{ "question": "勘案", "answers": [ "かんあん" ], "comment": "taking into consideration; giving consideration (to); thinking" },
	{ "question": "勘違い", "answers": [ "かんちがい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding; wrong guess" },
	{ "question": "務め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "service; duty; business; responsibility; task\nBuddhist religious services" },
	{ "question": "務める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "勝ち", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "win; victory" },
	{ "question": "勝ち星", "answers": [ "かちぼし" ], "comment": "(mark indicating) a win" },
	{ "question": "勝ち負け", "answers": [ "かちまけ" ], "comment": "victory or defeat" },
	{ "question": "勝ち越し", "answers": [ "かちこし" ], "comment": "having more wins than losses; taking the lead" },
	{ "question": "勝ち越す", "answers": [ "かちこす" ], "comment": "to have more wins than losses; to lead someone (by no. of matches)\nto take the lead over an opponent (in points)" },
	{ "question": "勝つ", "answers": [ "かつ" ], "comment": "to win; to gain victory" },
	{ "question": "勝る", "answers": [ "まさる" ], "comment": "to excel; to surpass; to exceed; to have an edge; to be superior; to outrival\nto outweigh; to preponderate" },
	{ "question": "勝利", "answers": [ "しょうり" ], "comment": "victory; triumph; conquest; success; win" },
	{ "question": "勝因", "answers": [ "しょういん" ], "comment": "cause of victory" },
	{ "question": "勝手", "answers": [ "かって" ], "comment": "one's own convenience; one's way; selfish\nsurroundings; environment; way of doing things\nconvenience; ease of use\nfinancial circumstances; living; livelihood\nkitchen\nright hand (in archery); hand that pulls the bowstring\nunauthorised (e.g. phone app, WWW site); unofficial" },
	{ "question": "勝手気まま", "answers": [ "かってきまま" ], "comment": "self-willed; (doing or saying things) to suit one's own convenience; oblivious to the convenience of others" },
	{ "question": "勝敗", "answers": [ "しょうはい" ], "comment": "victory or defeat; issue (of battle); outcome" },
	{ "question": "勝率", "answers": [ "しょうりつ" ], "comment": "winning percentage" },
	{ "question": "勝者", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "winner; victor" },
	{ "question": "勝訴", "answers": [ "しょうそ" ], "comment": "winning a lawsuit" },
	{ "question": "勝負", "answers": [ "しょうぶ" ], "comment": "victory or defeat; match; contest; game; bout" },
	{ "question": "募る", "answers": [ "つのる" ], "comment": "to grow violent; to become stronger; to become worse\nto invite contributions, etc.; to solicit help, participation, etc.; to recruit (e.g. soldiers)" },
	{ "question": "募金", "answers": [ "ぼきん" ], "comment": "fund-raising; collection of funds" },
	{ "question": "募集", "answers": [ "ぼしゅう" ], "comment": "recruiting; selection; taking applications\nraising; collection; subscription; soliciting (e.g. donations)\nflotation (shares, loans, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "勢い", "answers": [ "いきおい" ], "comment": "force; vigor; vigour; energy; spirit; life\ninfluence; authority; power; might\nimpetus; momentum; course (of events)\nnaturally; necessarily" },
	{ "question": "勢力", "answers": [ "せいりょく" ], "comment": "influence; power; might; strength; potency; force; energy" },
	{ "question": "勤め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "service; duty; business; responsibility; task\nBuddhist religious services" },
	{ "question": "勤める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "勤め先", "answers": [ "つとめさき" ], "comment": "place of work" },
	{ "question": "勤労", "answers": [ "きんろう" ], "comment": "labor; labour; exertion; diligent service" },
	{ "question": "勤労者", "answers": [ "きんろうしゃ" ], "comment": "worker" },
	{ "question": "勤勉", "answers": [ "きんべん" ], "comment": "diligent; industrious" },
	{ "question": "勤務", "answers": [ "きんむ" ], "comment": "service; duty; work" },
	{ "question": "勤続", "answers": [ "きんぞく" ], "comment": "continuous service" },
	{ "question": "勧め", "answers": [ "すすめ" ], "comment": "recommendation; advice; suggestion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "勧める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to recommend; to advise; to encourage; to offer (wine)" },
	{ "question": "勧告", "answers": [ "かんこく" ], "comment": "advice; counsel; remonstrance; recommendation" },
	{ "question": "勧奨", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "encouragement; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "勧誘", "answers": [ "かんゆう" ], "comment": "invitation; solicitation; canvassing; canvasing; inducement; persuasion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "勲章", "answers": [ "くんしょう" ], "comment": "decoration; order; medal" },
	{ "question": "勾配", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "slope; incline; gradient; grade; pitch\nslope (of a linear function)\ngradient (vector calculus)" },
	{ "question": "匂い", "answers": [ "におい" ], "comment": "odour; odor; scent; smell; stench\naura; whiff; smacks of ...; sense; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "匂う", "answers": [ "におう" ], "comment": "to be fragrant; to smell (good)\nto stink; to smell (bad)\nto glow; to be bright\nto smack of; to show hints of" },
	{ "question": "包み", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "bundle; package; parcel\ncounter for wrapped objects" },
	{ "question": "包み紙", "answers": [ "つつみがみ" ], "comment": "wrapping paper" },
	{ "question": "包み込む", "answers": [ "つつみこむ" ], "comment": "to wrap up" },
	{ "question": "包む", "answers": [ "つつむ" ], "comment": "to wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in\nto conceal; to hide; to be engulfed in; to be enveloped by" },
	{ "question": "包丁", "answers": [ "ほうちょう" ], "comment": "kitchen knife; carving knife\ncooking; food" },
	{ "question": "包囲", "answers": [ "ほうい" ], "comment": "siege; encirclement; envelopment; surrounding; besiegement" },
	{ "question": "包帯", "answers": [ "ほうたい" ], "comment": "bandage; dressing" },
	{ "question": "包括", "answers": [ "ほうかつ" ], "comment": "inclusion; complete coverage; comprehensiveness" },
	{ "question": "包装", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "packing; wrapping" },
	{ "question": "化ける", "answers": [ "ばける" ], "comment": "to take the form of (esp. in ref. to a spirit, fox, raccoon dog, etc.); to assume the shape of; to turn oneself into; to transform oneself into\nto disguise oneself as\nto change radically; to metamorphose\nto improve unexpectedly and dramatically (esp. of an actor, artist, rikishi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "化け物", "answers": [ "ばけもの" ], "comment": "goblin; apparition; monster; ghost; phantom; spectre; specter" },
	{ "question": "化合", "answers": [ "かごう" ], "comment": "chemical combination" },
	{ "question": "化合物", "answers": [ "かごうぶつ" ], "comment": "compound" },
	{ "question": "化学", "answers": [ "かがく", "ばけがく" ], "comment": "chemistry\nchemical company (e.g. Acme Chemical Co.)" },
	{ "question": "化学兵器", "answers": [ "かがくへいき" ], "comment": "chemical weapon" },
	{ "question": "化学肥料", "answers": [ "かがくひりょう" ], "comment": "chemical fertilizer; chemical fertiliser" },
	{ "question": "化成", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "change; transformation" },
	{ "question": "化石", "answers": [ "かせき" ], "comment": "fossil; petrifaction; fossilization; fossilisation" },
	{ "question": "化粧", "answers": [ "けしょう", "けわい" ], "comment": "make-up; makeup; cosmetics" },
	{ "question": "化繊", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "synthetic fibres; synthetic fibers" },
	{ "question": "北", "answers": [ "きた" ], "comment": "north\nthe North; northern territories\nNorth Korea\nnorth wind" },
	{ "question": "北アイルランド", "answers": [ "きたアイルランド" ], "comment": "Northern Ireland" },
	{ "question": "北上", "answers": [ "ほくじょう" ], "comment": "going north" },
	{ "question": "北京", "answers": [ "ペキン" ], "comment": "Beijing; Peking" },
	{ "question": "北側", "answers": [ "ほくそく", "きたがわ" ], "comment": "north side; north bank" },
	{ "question": "北口", "answers": [ "きたぐち" ], "comment": "north entrance" },
	{ "question": "北国", "answers": [ "ほっこく", "きたぐに" ], "comment": "northern provinces; northern countries" },
	{ "question": "北方", "answers": [ "ほっぽう" ], "comment": "northern (district); northward" },
	{ "question": "北朝鮮", "answers": [ "きたちょうせん" ], "comment": "North Korea" },
	{ "question": "北東", "answers": [ "きたひがし", "ほくとう" ], "comment": "northeast" },
	{ "question": "北極", "answers": [ "ほっきょく" ], "comment": "North Pole\nthe Arctic" },
	{ "question": "北極圏", "answers": [ "ほっきょくけん" ], "comment": "Arctic Circle; the Arctic" },
	{ "question": "北欧", "answers": [ "ほくおう" ], "comment": "Northern Europe; land of the Norsemen; Scandinavia" },
	{ "question": "北海", "answers": [ "ほっかい" ], "comment": "northern sea; North Sea" },
	{ "question": "北海道", "answers": [ "ほっかいどう" ], "comment": "Hokkaido (island, prefectural-level administrative unit)" },
	{ "question": "北海道開発庁長官", "answers": [ "ほっかいどうかいはつちょうちょうかん" ], "comment": "Director General of Hokkaido Development Agency" },
	{ "question": "北端", "answers": [ "ほくたん" ], "comment": "northern extremity" },
	{ "question": "北緯", "answers": [ "ほくい" ], "comment": "north latitude" },
	{ "question": "北西", "answers": [ "ほくせい" ], "comment": "northwest" },
	{ "question": "北部", "answers": [ "ほくぶ" ], "comment": "northern part; the north (of a region)" },
	{ "question": "北陸", "answers": [ "ほくりく" ], "comment": "region west of Tokyo on Japan Sea side of Japan" },
	{ "question": "北風", "answers": [ "きたかぜ", "ほくふう" ], "comment": "north wind" },
	{ "question": "匹", "answers": [ "ひき", "き" ], "comment": "counter for small animals\ncounter for rolls of cloth (two han in size)\ncounter for horses\nroll of cloth" },
	{ "question": "匹敵", "answers": [ "ひってき" ], "comment": "to be a match for; to rival; to equal; to compare with; to be equivalent to" },
	{ "question": "区", "answers": [ "く" ], "comment": "ward; district; section" },
	{ "question": "区内", "answers": [ "くない" ], "comment": "in the ward or borough" },
	{ "question": "区分", "answers": [ "くぶん" ], "comment": "division; section; demarcation; partition; segmentation; subdivision; (traffic) lane; compartment; classification; sorting" },
	{ "question": "区切り", "answers": [ "くぎり" ], "comment": "punctuation; pause; juncture\nend; (place to) stop" },
	{ "question": "区切る", "answers": [ "くぎる" ], "comment": "to demarcate; to delimit; to divide (an area); to mark off; to cut off\nto punctuate; to put an end to (e.g. a sentence); to insert pauses or breaks (e.g. when reading aloud)" },
	{ "question": "区別", "answers": [ "くべつ" ], "comment": "distinction; differentiation; classification" },
	{ "question": "区域", "answers": [ "くいき" ], "comment": "limits; boundary; domain; zone; sphere; territory\narea (e.g. in programming languages)" },
	{ "question": "区役所", "answers": [ "くやくしょ" ], "comment": "ward office; council (regional)" },
	{ "question": "区民", "answers": [ "くみん" ], "comment": "ward residents" },
	{ "question": "区画", "answers": [ "くかく" ], "comment": "division; section; compartment; boundary; area; block" },
	{ "question": "区立", "answers": [ "くりつ" ], "comment": "established by the ward" },
	{ "question": "区議", "answers": [ "くぎ" ], "comment": "ward assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "区長", "answers": [ "くちょう" ], "comment": "head of a ward; mayor of a ward; chief administrator of a ward" },
	{ "question": "区間", "answers": [ "くかん" ], "comment": "section (of track, etc.); segment; dimension\ninterval" },
	{ "question": "医", "answers": [ "い" ], "comment": "medicine; the healing art; healing; curing; doctor" },
	{ "question": "医大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "medical university; medical school; med school" },
	{ "question": "医学", "answers": [ "いがく" ], "comment": "medical science; medicine" },
	{ "question": "医局", "answers": [ "いきょく" ], "comment": "medical office; dispensary" },
	{ "question": "医師", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "doctor; physician" },
	{ "question": "医師会", "answers": [ "いしかい" ], "comment": "medical association" },
	{ "question": "医療", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "medical care; medical treatment" },
	{ "question": "医科", "answers": [ "いか" ], "comment": "medical science; medical department" },
	{ "question": "医科学", "answers": [ "いかがく" ], "comment": "medical college" },
	{ "question": "医者", "answers": [ "いしゃ" ], "comment": "(medical) doctor; physician" },
	{ "question": "医薬", "answers": [ "いやく" ], "comment": "medicine\nPharmaceutical and Food Safety Bureau" },
	{ "question": "医薬品", "answers": [ "いやくひん" ], "comment": "medical and pharmaceutical products; medicinal supplies; drugs; pharmaceuticals; medicine" },
	{ "question": "医長", "answers": [ "いちょう" ], "comment": "medical director; chief physician" },
	{ "question": "医院", "answers": [ "いいん" ], "comment": "doctor's office (surgery); clinic; dispensary" },
	{ "question": "匿名", "answers": [ "とくめい" ], "comment": "anonymity; using an assumed name" },
	{ "question": "十", "answers": [ "とお", "と", "じゅう" ], "comment": "ten" },
	{ "question": "十一月", "answers": [ "じゅういちがつ" ], "comment": "November" },
	{ "question": "十七", "answers": [ "じゅうしち", "じゅうなな" ], "comment": "17; seventeen" },
	{ "question": "十万", "answers": [ "じゅうまん" ], "comment": "100,000; hundred thousand" },
	{ "question": "十三", "answers": [ "じゅうさん" ], "comment": "13; thirteen" },
	{ "question": "十両", "answers": [ "じゅうりょう" ], "comment": "second highest division; wrestlers of the second highest division" },
	{ "question": "十九", "answers": [ "じゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "19; nineteen" },
	{ "question": "十二", "answers": [ "じゅうに" ], "comment": "12; twelve" },
	{ "question": "十二分", "answers": [ "じゅうにぶん" ], "comment": "more than enough; more than ample; exhaustive" },
	{ "question": "十二月", "answers": [ "じゅうにがつ" ], "comment": "December" },
	{ "question": "十五", "answers": [ "じゅうご" ], "comment": "15; fifteen" },
	{ "question": "十代", "answers": [ "じゅうだい" ], "comment": "the teens (10-19); teenage\nthe tenth generation" },
	{ "question": "十億", "answers": [ "じゅうおく" ], "comment": "1,000,000,000; billion" },
	{ "question": "十八", "answers": [ "じゅうはち" ], "comment": "18; eighteen" },
	{ "question": "十八番", "answers": [ "じゅうはちばん", "おはこ" ], "comment": "one's favourite party trick (favorite); one's specialty; one's forte\nNo. 18; eighteenth\nrepertoire of 18 kabuki plays" },
	{ "question": "十六", "answers": [ "じゅうろく" ], "comment": "16; sixteen" },
	{ "question": "十分", "answers": [ "じゅうぶん" ], "comment": "plenty; enough; sufficient; satisfactory; adequate\ndivision into ten\nperfectly; thoroughly; fully; in full" },
	{ "question": "十四", "answers": [ "じゅうし", "じゅうよん" ], "comment": "14; fourteen" },
	{ "question": "十字", "answers": [ "じゅうじ" ], "comment": "cross; crossed; cruciform" },
	{ "question": "十字架", "answers": [ "じゅうじか" ], "comment": "cross; the Cross (of Christ)" },
	{ "question": "十字路", "answers": [ "じゅうじろ" ], "comment": "crossroads" },
	{ "question": "十日", "answers": [ "とおか" ], "comment": "the tenth day of the month\nten days" },
	{ "question": "十月", "answers": [ "じゅうがつ" ], "comment": "October" },
	{ "question": "千", "answers": [ "せん", "ち" ], "comment": "1,000; thousand" },
	{ "question": "千九百年代", "answers": [ "せんきゅうひゃくねんだい" ], "comment": "the 1900s" },
	{ "question": "千代", "answers": [ "ちよ", "せんだい" ], "comment": "thousand years\nvery long period; forever" },
	{ "question": "千円札", "answers": [ "せんえんさつ" ], "comment": "1,000 yen bill" },
	{ "question": "千島", "answers": [ "ちしま" ], "comment": "Kurile Islands" },
	{ "question": "千島列島", "answers": [ "ちしまれっとう" ], "comment": "Kurile Islands" },
	{ "question": "千秋楽", "answers": [ "せんしゅうらく" ], "comment": "concluding festivities; concluding program; concluding programme\nfinal day of a tournament" },
	{ "question": "千里", "answers": [ "せんり" ], "comment": "1000 ri; (a) long distance" },
	{ "question": "午", "answers": [ "うま" ], "comment": "seventh sign of Chinese zodiac (The Horse, 11am-1pm, south, May)" },
	{ "question": "午前", "answers": [ "ごぜん" ], "comment": "morning; a.m." },
	{ "question": "午前中", "answers": [ "ごぜんちゅう" ], "comment": "in the morning; during the morning" },
	{ "question": "午後", "answers": [ "ごご" ], "comment": "afternoon; p.m." },
	{ "question": "半", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "half; semi-\nhalf-past\nodd number\nunit of land area (595.8 m^2)" },
	{ "question": "半々", "answers": [ "はんはん" ], "comment": "half and half; fifty-fifty" },
	{ "question": "半ば", "answers": [ "なかば" ], "comment": "middle; half; semi; halfway; partly" },
	{ "question": "半値", "answers": [ "はんね" ], "comment": "half price" },
	{ "question": "半分", "answers": [ "はんぶん" ], "comment": "half" },
	{ "question": "半導体", "answers": [ "はんどうたい" ], "comment": "semiconductor; solid-state" },
	{ "question": "半島", "answers": [ "はんとう" ], "comment": "peninsula" },
	{ "question": "半年", "answers": [ "はんねん", "はんとし" ], "comment": "half year" },
	{ "question": "半径", "answers": [ "はんけい" ], "comment": "radius" },
	{ "question": "半数", "answers": [ "はんすう" ], "comment": "half the number\nhaploid" },
	{ "question": "半日", "answers": [ "はんじつ", "はんにち" ], "comment": "half day" },
	{ "question": "半月", "answers": [ "はんげつ", "はんつき" ], "comment": "half-moon\nhalf month\nsemicircle" },
	{ "question": "半期", "answers": [ "はんき" ], "comment": "half-term; half-time; half period" },
	{ "question": "半減", "answers": [ "はんげん" ], "comment": "reduction by half; halve" },
	{ "question": "半生", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "half a lifetime" },
	{ "question": "半端", "answers": [ "はんぱ" ], "comment": "remnant; fragment; incomplete set; incompleteness\nfraction; odd sum\nhalfway; half-hearted; perfunctory\nirresponsible; foolish" },
	{ "question": "半袖", "answers": [ "はんそで" ], "comment": "short sleeves" },
	{ "question": "半身", "answers": [ "はんしん" ], "comment": "half the body; half length" },
	{ "question": "半面", "answers": [ "はんめん" ], "comment": "half the face; one side; half; the other side; the reverse; the contrary" },
	{ "question": "半額", "answers": [ "はんがく" ], "comment": "half; half amount; half price; half fare" },
	{ "question": "卑しい", "answers": [ "いやしい" ], "comment": "lowborn; humble; lowly\nvulgar; coarse; crude; mean; base; vile\nshabby\ngreedy; gluttonous; avaricious" },
	{ "question": "卑劣", "answers": [ "ひれつ" ], "comment": "mean; foul play; cowardly; base" },
	{ "question": "卑怯", "answers": [ "ひきょう" ], "comment": "cowardice; meanness; unfairness" },
	{ "question": "卒業", "answers": [ "そつぎょう" ], "comment": "graduation; completion (e.g. of a course)\noutgrowing something; moving on" },
	{ "question": "卓", "answers": [ "たく", "しょく" ], "comment": "table; desk\ncounter for tables, desks, etc.\noffering table before an altar (sometimes used in tea ceremony)\ntabletop incense burner" },
	{ "question": "卓球", "answers": [ "たっきゅう" ], "comment": "table tennis; ping-pong" },
	{ "question": "卓越", "answers": [ "たくえつ" ], "comment": "preeminence; excellence; superiority; transcendence" },
	{ "question": "協会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "association; society; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "協力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "cooperation; collaboration" },
	{ "question": "協同", "answers": [ "きょうどう" ], "comment": "doing together (as equals); sharing; common (land, etc.); joint (statement, etc.); cooperation; co-operation; collaboration; association" },
	{ "question": "協同組合", "answers": [ "きょうどうくみあい" ], "comment": "cooperative; association; partnership" },
	{ "question": "協和", "answers": [ "きょうわ" ], "comment": "concord; harmony; concert" },
	{ "question": "協奏曲", "answers": [ "きょうそうきょく" ], "comment": "concerto" },
	{ "question": "協定", "answers": [ "きょうてい" ], "comment": "arrangement; pact; agreement" },
	{ "question": "協調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "cooperation; conciliation; harmony; coordination" },
	{ "question": "協議", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "conference; consultation; discussion; negotiation" },
	{ "question": "協賛", "answers": [ "きょうさん" ], "comment": "support; mutual aid; cooperation; approval; authorization; authorisation" },
	{ "question": "南", "answers": [ "みなみ" ], "comment": "south" },
	{ "question": "南アフリカ", "answers": [ "みなみアフリカ" ], "comment": "South Africa" },
	{ "question": "南側", "answers": [ "みなみがわ", "なんそく" ], "comment": "south side" },
	{ "question": "南北", "answers": [ "なんぼく" ], "comment": "north and south; north to south\nSouth Korea and North Korea" },
	{ "question": "南北問題", "answers": [ "なんぼくもんだい" ], "comment": "North-South problem" },
	{ "question": "南口", "answers": [ "みなみぐち" ], "comment": "south entrance" },
	{ "question": "南国", "answers": [ "なんごく", "なんこく" ], "comment": "southern countries" },
	{ "question": "南方", "answers": [ "なんぽう" ], "comment": "south; southern; southward" },
	{ "question": "南東", "answers": [ "みなみひがし", "なんとう" ], "comment": "southeast" },
	{ "question": "南極", "answers": [ "なんきょく" ], "comment": "South Pole\nthe Antarctic; Antarctica" },
	{ "question": "南氷洋", "answers": [ "なんぴょうよう", "なんひょうよう" ], "comment": "Antarctic Ocean" },
	{ "question": "南海", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "southern sea" },
	{ "question": "南米", "answers": [ "なんべい" ], "comment": "South America" },
	{ "question": "南西", "answers": [ "なんせい", "みなみにし" ], "comment": "southwest" },
	{ "question": "南部", "answers": [ "なんぶ" ], "comment": "southern part; the south (of a region)" },
	{ "question": "単", "answers": [ "ひとえ" ], "comment": "one layer; single; onefold" },
	{ "question": "単なる", "answers": [ "たんなる" ], "comment": "mere; simple; sheer" },
	{ "question": "単に", "answers": [ "たんに" ], "comment": "simply; merely; only; solely" },
	{ "question": "単一", "answers": [ "たんいつ" ], "comment": "single; simple; sole; individual; unitary" },
	{ "question": "単位", "answers": [ "たんい" ], "comment": "unit; denomination\ncredit (in school)" },
	{ "question": "単価", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "unit price; unit cost" },
	{ "question": "単数", "answers": [ "たんすう" ], "comment": "singular number" },
	{ "question": "単独", "answers": [ "たんどく" ], "comment": "sole; single; solo\nindependence; singleness; singularity" },
	{ "question": "単産", "answers": [ "たんさん" ], "comment": "(single-industry) industrial union" },
	{ "question": "単純", "answers": [ "たんじゅん" ], "comment": "simplicity; simple; uncomplicated" },
	{ "question": "単行本", "answers": [ "たんこうぼん" ], "comment": "special book; separate volume; book of lectures" },
	{ "question": "単語", "answers": [ "たんご" ], "comment": "word; vocabulary; (usually) single-character word" },
	{ "question": "単調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "monotony; monotone; dullness\nmonotone; monotonic" },
	{ "question": "単身", "answers": [ "たんしん" ], "comment": "alone; unaided; away from home" },
	{ "question": "単身赴任", "answers": [ "たんしんふにん" ], "comment": "job transfer away from one's home; taking up a new post leaving one's family behind" },
	{ "question": "博", "answers": [ "はく", "ばく" ], "comment": "doctor; PhD\nexposition; fair; exhibition" },
	{ "question": "博士", "answers": [ "はかせ", "はくし" ], "comment": "doctorate; PhD; Dr (as a title)\nexpert; learned person" },
	{ "question": "博学", "answers": [ "はくがく" ], "comment": "erudition; extensive learning" },
	{ "question": "博愛", "answers": [ "はくあい" ], "comment": "charity; benevolence; philanthropy; (love for) humanity; fraternity; brotherhood; brotherly love; love of fellow man" },
	{ "question": "博物", "answers": [ "はくぶつ" ], "comment": "natural history\nwide learning; broad area of learning" },
	{ "question": "博物館", "answers": [ "はくぶつかん" ], "comment": "museum" },
	{ "question": "博覧会", "answers": [ "はくらんかい" ], "comment": "fair; exhibition; exposition" },
	{ "question": "占い", "answers": [ "うらない" ], "comment": "fortune-telling; divination" },
	{ "question": "占う", "answers": [ "うらなう" ], "comment": "to tell someone's fortune; to forecast; to predict; to divine" },
	{ "question": "占める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to occupy; to hold\nto account for; to make up; to take up" },
	{ "question": "占拠", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "occupation (e.g. of territory); exclusive possession" },
	{ "question": "占領", "answers": [ "せんりょう" ], "comment": "occupying; having (an area) all to oneself\nmilitary occupation; possession; capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "印刷", "answers": [ "いんさつ" ], "comment": "printing" },
	{ "question": "印紙", "answers": [ "いんし" ], "comment": "(revenue) stamp" },
	{ "question": "印象", "answers": [ "いんしょう" ], "comment": "impression" },
	{ "question": "印象付ける", "answers": [ "いんしょうづける" ], "comment": "to impress (someone)" },
	{ "question": "印象的", "answers": [ "いんしょうてき" ], "comment": "impressive" },
	{ "question": "印鑑", "answers": [ "いんかん" ], "comment": "stamp; seal" },
	{ "question": "危うい", "answers": [ "あやうい" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow" },
	{ "question": "危うく", "answers": [ "あやうく" ], "comment": "barely; narrowly\nalmost; nearly" },
	{ "question": "危ない", "answers": [ "あぶない" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow\nlook out!; watch out!" },
	{ "question": "危ぶむ", "answers": [ "あやぶむ" ], "comment": "to fear; to have misgivings; to be doubtful; to mistrust" },
	{ "question": "危害", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "injury; harm; danger" },
	{ "question": "危惧", "answers": [ "きぐ" ], "comment": "apprehensions; misgivings; uneasiness; anxiety; fear" },
	{ "question": "危機", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "crisis; danger; risk" },
	{ "question": "危篤", "answers": [ "きとく" ], "comment": "critical condition; being on the verge of death" },
	{ "question": "危険", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "danger; peril; hazard\nrisk" },
	{ "question": "即する", "answers": [ "そくする" ], "comment": "to conform to; to agree with; to be adapted to; to be based on" },
	{ "question": "即位", "answers": [ "そくい" ], "comment": "enthronement" },
	{ "question": "即刻", "answers": [ "そっこく" ], "comment": "immediately; at once; instantly" },
	{ "question": "即効", "answers": [ "そっこう" ], "comment": "immediate effect; instant effect" },
	{ "question": "即売", "answers": [ "そくばい" ], "comment": "sale on the spot" },
	{ "question": "即席", "answers": [ "そくせき" ], "comment": "extempore; impromptu; improvised; ad-lib; off-the-cuff; instant" },
	{ "question": "即座", "answers": [ "そくざ" ], "comment": "immediate; right there on the spot; impromptu; instant; instantaneous" },
	{ "question": "即座に", "answers": [ "そくざに" ], "comment": "immediately; right away; on the spot" },
	{ "question": "即戦力", "answers": [ "そくせんりょく" ], "comment": "ready fire-power; battle-ready forces; immediate asset (to a team or firm); someone who can be an immediately effective player or worker" },
	{ "question": "即日", "answers": [ "そくじつ" ], "comment": "same day" },
	{ "question": "即時", "answers": [ "そくじ" ], "comment": "prompt; immediate; in real time" },
	{ "question": "即死", "answers": [ "そくし" ], "comment": "instant death" },
	{ "question": "即興", "answers": [ "そっきょう" ], "comment": "improvisation; impromptu; off the cuff; without a score" },
	{ "question": "卵", "answers": [ "たまご" ], "comment": "eggs; egg; spawn; roe\nhen egg\n(an expert) in the making\nbeginning; origin; infancy" },
	{ "question": "卵子", "answers": [ "らんし" ], "comment": "ovum; ovule; egg cell" },
	{ "question": "卵巣", "answers": [ "らんそう" ], "comment": "ovary" },
	{ "question": "卵形", "answers": [ "らんけい", "たまごがた" ], "comment": "oval; egg-shaped" },
	{ "question": "卸", "answers": [ "おろし" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "卸す", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to sell wholesale\nto grate (e.g. vegetables)\nto cut up fish" },
	{ "question": "卸売", "answers": [ "おろしうり" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "卸売り", "answers": [ "おろしうり" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "卸売市場", "answers": [ "おろしうりしじょう" ], "comment": "wholesale market" },
	{ "question": "卸売物価", "answers": [ "おろしうりぶっか" ], "comment": "wholesale price" },
	{ "question": "卿", "answers": [ "きょう", "けい" ], "comment": "lord; sir\nstate minister (i.e. under the ritsuryo system)\nyou (in reference to someone of lower status)" },
	{ "question": "厄介", "answers": [ "やっかい" ], "comment": "trouble; burden; nuisance; bother; worry\ncare; dependence; support; kindness; obligation; staying (with a person)" },
	{ "question": "厘", "answers": [ "りん" ], "comment": "one-hundredth; 0.3 mm (one-hundredth of a sun); 0.1 percent (one-hundredth of a wari); 0.0375 grams (one-hundredth of a monme)\nold monetary unit (0.001 yen)" },
	{ "question": "厚い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "thick; deep; heavy\nkind; cordial; hospitable; warm; faithful\nserious (of an illness)\nabundant" },
	{ "question": "厚かましい", "answers": [ "あつかましい" ], "comment": "impudent; shameless; brazen" },
	{ "question": "厚さ", "answers": [ "あつさ" ], "comment": "thickness" },
	{ "question": "厚み", "answers": [ "あつみ" ], "comment": "thickness; profound" },
	{ "question": "厚意", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "kindness; favor; favour" },
	{ "question": "厚生", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "welfare; public welfare; social welfare\n(former) Ministry of Health and Welfare" },
	{ "question": "厚生年金", "answers": [ "こうせいねんきん" ], "comment": "welfare pension" },
	{ "question": "厚生省", "answers": [ "こうせいしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Health and Welfare (now Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare)" },
	{ "question": "厚相", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "Welfare Minister" },
	{ "question": "厚着", "answers": [ "あつぎ" ], "comment": "wearing thick clothes; dressing warmly" },
	{ "question": "原", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "field; plain; prairie; tundra; moor; wilderness" },
	{ "question": "原っぱ", "answers": [ "はらっぱ" ], "comment": "open field; empty lot; plain" },
	{ "question": "原人", "answers": [ "げんじん" ], "comment": "primitive man" },
	{ "question": "原作", "answers": [ "げんさく" ], "comment": "original work" },
	{ "question": "原価", "answers": [ "げんか" ], "comment": "cost price" },
	{ "question": "原則", "answers": [ "げんそく" ], "comment": "principle; general rule" },
	{ "question": "原動力", "answers": [ "げんどうりょく" ], "comment": "motive power; driving force" },
	{ "question": "原告", "answers": [ "げんこく" ], "comment": "plaintiff; accuser; prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "原因", "answers": [ "げんいん" ], "comment": "cause; origin; source" },
	{ "question": "原型", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "prototype; model; pattern; archetypal" },
	{ "question": "原始", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "origin; primeval" },
	{ "question": "原子", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "atom" },
	{ "question": "原子力", "answers": [ "げんしりょく" ], "comment": "atomic energy; nuclear power" },
	{ "question": "原子核", "answers": [ "げんしかく" ], "comment": "nucleus (atomic)" },
	{ "question": "原子炉", "answers": [ "げんしろ" ], "comment": "atomic reactor; nuclear reactor" },
	{ "question": "原形", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "original form; base form" },
	{ "question": "原文", "answers": [ "げんぶん" ], "comment": "the text; original" },
	{ "question": "原料", "answers": [ "げんりょう" ], "comment": "raw materials" },
	{ "question": "原書", "answers": [ "げんしょ" ], "comment": "original document (not a copy or adaptation); book in its original language (esp. a European language)" },
	{ "question": "原本", "answers": [ "げんぽん" ], "comment": "the original; original copy; script" },
	{ "question": "原材料", "answers": [ "げんざいりょう" ], "comment": "raw materials" },
	{ "question": "原案", "answers": [ "げんあん" ], "comment": "original plan; original bill; motion; draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "原水爆", "answers": [ "げんすいばく" ], "comment": "atomic and hydrogen bombs; nuclear and thermonuclear bombs" },
	{ "question": "原油", "answers": [ "げんゆ" ], "comment": "crude oil" },
	{ "question": "原潜", "answers": [ "げんせん" ], "comment": "nuclear submarine" },
	{ "question": "原点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "origin (coordinates); starting point" },
	{ "question": "原爆", "answers": [ "げんばく" ], "comment": "atomic bomb; A-bomb" },
	{ "question": "原理", "answers": [ "げんり" ], "comment": "principle; theory; fundamental truth" },
	{ "question": "原生", "answers": [ "げんせい" ], "comment": "primeval; primordial; primitive; pristine" },
	{ "question": "原産", "answers": [ "げんさん" ], "comment": "place of origin; habitat" },
	{ "question": "原産地", "answers": [ "げんさんち" ], "comment": "place of origin; home; habitat" },
	{ "question": "原画", "answers": [ "げんが" ], "comment": "original picture\nkey frame; key animation" },
	{ "question": "原発", "answers": [ "げんぱつ" ], "comment": "nuclear power plant; nuclear power generation\nprimary (e.g. primary immunodeficiency syndrome)" },
	{ "question": "原稿", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "manuscript; copy" },
	{ "question": "原稿用紙", "answers": [ "げんこうようし" ], "comment": "Japanese writing paper (lined with a square grid, one square per character)" },
	{ "question": "原義", "answers": [ "げんぎ" ], "comment": "original meaning" },
	{ "question": "原資", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "capital; principal" },
	{ "question": "原野", "answers": [ "げんや" ], "comment": "waste land; wilderness; moor; field; plain" },
	{ "question": "厨房", "answers": [ "ちゅうぼう" ], "comment": "kitchen; galley\n(Internet) troll" },
	{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "solemn (ceremony, atmosphere, etc.); austere; grave; majestic; dignified; stately; impressive" },
	{ "question": "厳しい", "answers": [ "きびしい" ], "comment": "severe; strict; rigid; unsparing; relentless\nintense (e.g. cold); harsh; tough" },
	{ "question": "厳しさ", "answers": [ "きびしさ" ], "comment": "severity; strictness; intensity" },
	{ "question": "厳守", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "strict observance; adherence; scrupulous compliance" },
	{ "question": "厳密", "answers": [ "げんみつ" ], "comment": "strict; close" },
	{ "question": "厳格", "answers": [ "げんかく" ], "comment": "severe; rigid; stern; strictness; rigor; rigour; austerity" },
	{ "question": "厳粛", "answers": [ "げんしゅく" ], "comment": "gravity; solemnity; severity; seriousness; dignity; rigor; rigour; austerity" },
	{ "question": "厳重", "answers": [ "げんじゅう" ], "comment": "strict; rigour; rigor; severe; firm; strong; secure" },
	{ "question": "去る", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "to leave; to go away\nto pass; to elapse\nto be distant\nto send away; to drive off; to divorce\n... completely\nlast ... (e.g. \"last April\")" },
	{ "question": "去就", "answers": [ "きょしゅう" ], "comment": "(one's) course of action; (one's) position; (one's) attitude" },
	{ "question": "去年", "answers": [ "きょねん" ], "comment": "last year" },
	{ "question": "参与", "answers": [ "さんよ" ], "comment": "participation; taking part\nconsultant; councillor; adviser" },
	{ "question": "参事", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "secretary; councillor; councilor" },
	{ "question": "参事官", "answers": [ "さんじかん" ], "comment": "councillor; councilor" },
	{ "question": "参入", "answers": [ "さんにゅう" ], "comment": "entering (the marketplace); introducing (something) to the market; access\nvisiting a high-class or noble individual" },
	{ "question": "参列", "answers": [ "さんれつ" ], "comment": "attendance; participation; presence" },
	{ "question": "参加", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "participation" },
	{ "question": "参加者", "answers": [ "さんかしゃ" ], "comment": "participant; entrant" },
	{ "question": "参戦", "answers": [ "さんせん" ], "comment": "participation in a war; going to war\ntaking part in a competition or contest" },
	{ "question": "参拝", "answers": [ "さんぱい" ], "comment": "visit to a shrine or temple; paying homage at a shrine or temple" },
	{ "question": "参政権", "answers": [ "さんせいけん" ], "comment": "suffrage; franchise" },
	{ "question": "参照", "answers": [ "さんしょう" ], "comment": "reference; bibliographical reference; consultation; browsing (e.g. when selecting a file to upload on a computer); checking out" },
	{ "question": "参画", "answers": [ "さんかく" ], "comment": "taking part in planning" },
	{ "question": "参考", "answers": [ "さんこう" ], "comment": "reference; consultation" },
	{ "question": "参考書", "answers": [ "さんこうしょ" ], "comment": "reference book" },
	{ "question": "参観", "answers": [ "さんかん" ], "comment": "visit; inspection" },
	{ "question": "参謀", "answers": [ "さんぼう" ], "comment": "staff officer; military staff\nadviser; counselor; counsellor" },
	{ "question": "参議院", "answers": [ "さんぎいん" ], "comment": "House of Councillors" },
	{ "question": "参道", "answers": [ "さんどう" ], "comment": "road approaching a shrine" },
	{ "question": "参院", "answers": [ "さんいん" ], "comment": "House of Councillors" },
	{ "question": "及び", "answers": [ "および" ], "comment": "and; as well as" },
	{ "question": "及ぶ", "answers": [ "およぶ" ], "comment": "to reach; to amount to; to befall; to happen to; to extend\nto be up to the task; to come up to\nto compare with; to be a match (for)\nto commit (a crime)\nto require (to do) (usu. used in the negative)" },
	{ "question": "及ぼす", "answers": [ "およぼす" ], "comment": "to exert; to cause; to exercise" },
	{ "question": "友", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "friend; companion; comrade; pal" },
	{ "question": "友人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "friend" },
	{ "question": "友好", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "friendship" },
	{ "question": "友情", "answers": [ "ゆうじょう" ], "comment": "friendship; fellowship; camaraderie" },
	{ "question": "友愛", "answers": [ "ゆうあい" ], "comment": "fraternity; friendship" },
	{ "question": "友達", "answers": [ "ともだち" ], "comment": "friend; companion" },
	{ "question": "双", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "pair" },
	{ "question": "双子", "answers": [ "そうし", "ふたご" ], "comment": "twins; twin" },
	{ "question": "双方", "answers": [ "そうほう" ], "comment": "two way; both parties; mutual; both" },
	{ "question": "双葉", "answers": [ "ふたば" ], "comment": "bud; sprout" },
	{ "question": "反", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "anti-\nantithesis\nfanqie; traditional Chinese spelling system in which two characters are used: the first one for the onset, the second one for rhyme and tone" },
	{ "question": "反す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "to return (something); to restore; to put back\nto turn over; to turn upside down; to overturn\nto pay back; to retaliate; to reciprocate\nto repeat ...; to do ... back" },
	{ "question": "反する", "answers": [ "はんする" ], "comment": "to be contrary to; to be inconsistent with; to contradict\nto act contrary to (rules or guidelines); to violate; to transgress\nto oppose; to rebel; to revolt" },
	{ "question": "反る", "answers": [ "かえる", "そる" ], "comment": "to warp; to be warped; to curve; to be curved; to be arched; to bend; to be bent\nto bend backward (body or body part, e.g. fingers) /\n to return; to come back; to go back\nto turn over\n(after the -masu stem of a verb) (to become) extremely; (to become) completely" },
	{ "question": "反乱", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "insurrection; mutiny; rebellion; revolt; uprising" },
	{ "question": "反体制", "answers": [ "はんたいせい" ], "comment": "anti-establishment" },
	{ "question": "反作用", "answers": [ "はんさよう" ], "comment": "reaction" },
	{ "question": "反共", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "anticommunist" },
	{ "question": "反則", "answers": [ "はんそく" ], "comment": "foul play (sport); breaking the rules; infringement; irregularity" },
	{ "question": "反動", "answers": [ "はんどう" ], "comment": "reaction; recoil; kick; backlash" },
	{ "question": "反対", "answers": [ "はんたい" ], "comment": "opposition; resistance; antagonism; hostility; objection; dissension\nreverse; opposite; vice versa; contrast" },
	{ "question": "反射", "answers": [ "はんしゃ" ], "comment": "reflection; reverberation\nreflex; reflexes" },
	{ "question": "反射的", "answers": [ "はんしゃてき" ], "comment": "reflexive; reflecting" },
	{ "question": "反応", "answers": [ "はんおう", "はんのう" ], "comment": "reaction; response" },
	{ "question": "反感", "answers": [ "はんかん" ], "comment": "antipathy; antagonism; animosity; revulsion; ill feeling" },
	{ "question": "反戦", "answers": [ "はんせん" ], "comment": "anti-war" },
	{ "question": "反抗", "answers": [ "はんこう" ], "comment": "opposition; resistance; insubordination; defiance; hostility; rebellion" },
	{ "question": "反撃", "answers": [ "はんげき" ], "comment": "counterattack; counteroffensive; counterblow" },
	{ "question": "反旗", "answers": [ "はんき" ], "comment": "standard of revolt; banner of revolution" },
	{ "question": "反日", "answers": [ "はんにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "反映", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "reflection (light, image, situation, attitude, etc.); reflecting\ninfluence; application (e.g. of an update)" },
	{ "question": "反発", "answers": [ "はんぱつ" ], "comment": "opposition; rebellion; revolt; resistance; backlash; refusal\nrebounding; recoiling; repulsion\nrally (e.g. in stock prices); recovery" },
	{ "question": "反省", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "reflection; reconsideration; introspection; meditation; contemplation\nregret; repentance; remorse; being sorry" },
	{ "question": "反米", "answers": [ "はんべい" ], "comment": "anti-American" },
	{ "question": "反落", "answers": [ "はんらく" ], "comment": "reactionary fall (e.g. in stock prices)" },
	{ "question": "反論", "answers": [ "はんろん" ], "comment": "objection; refutation; rebuttal" },
	{ "question": "反転", "answers": [ "はんてん" ], "comment": "rolling over\nturning around; turning from side to side; inversion; reversal\ntonal inversion; (making a) negative image" },
	{ "question": "反逆", "answers": [ "はんぎゃく" ], "comment": "treason; treachery; mutiny; rebellion; insurrection" },
	{ "question": "反面", "answers": [ "はんめん" ], "comment": "on the other hand; opposite side; reverse" },
	{ "question": "反響", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "echo; reverberation\nrepercussion; reaction; response; influence" },
	{ "question": "収まり", "answers": [ "おさまり" ], "comment": "conclusion; end; settlement" },
	{ "question": "収まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "収める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "収入", "answers": [ "しゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "income; receipts; revenue" },
	{ "question": "収容", "answers": [ "しゅうよう" ], "comment": "accommodation; reception; housing\nseating\ncustody (e.g. awaiting deportation); internment\nadmission; hospitalization\nentering (e.g. in dictionary)" },
	{ "question": "収容所", "answers": [ "しゅうようじょ" ], "comment": "internment camp; detention facility; POW camp; refugee camp" },
	{ "question": "収拾", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "control; bringing under control; settling (a matter); putting in order" },
	{ "question": "収支", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "income and expenditure" },
	{ "question": "収用", "answers": [ "しゅうよう" ], "comment": "expropriation; seizure" },
	{ "question": "収益", "answers": [ "しゅうえき" ], "comment": "earnings; proceeds; returns; revenue" },
	{ "question": "収穫", "answers": [ "しゅうかく" ], "comment": "harvest; crop; ingathering\nfruits (of one's labors); results" },
	{ "question": "収納", "answers": [ "しゅうのう" ], "comment": "storage; putting or stowing away\nreceipt (of funds, payment, etc.)\nharvesting" },
	{ "question": "収縮", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅく" ], "comment": "deflation; contraction; shrinking; constriction" },
	{ "question": "収賄", "answers": [ "しゅうわい" ], "comment": "accepting bribes; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "収量", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "yield; size of harvest" },
	{ "question": "収録", "answers": [ "しゅうろく" ], "comment": "compilation; editing\nrecording" },
	{ "question": "収集", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "gathering up; collection; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "叔母", "answers": [ "はくぼ", "おば", "しゅくぼ" ], "comment": "aunt" },
	{ "question": "叔父", "answers": [ "はくふ", "しゅくふ", "おじ" ], "comment": "uncle" },
	{ "question": "取っ手", "answers": [ "はしゅ", "とって" ], "comment": "handle; grip; knob" },
	{ "question": "取りまとめる", "answers": [ "とりまとめる" ], "comment": "to collect; to gather; to compile; to assemble\nto arrange; to settle" },
	{ "question": "取り上げる", "answers": [ "とりあげる" ], "comment": "to pick up; to take up\nto adopt; to feature; to accept; to listen to\nto take away; to confiscate; to deprive; to disqualify\nto deliver (a child)" },
	{ "question": "取り下げ", "answers": [ "とりさげ" ], "comment": "withdrawal" },
	{ "question": "取り入れる", "answers": [ "とりいれる" ], "comment": "to harvest; to reap\nto take in; to gather in\nto adopt (e.g. idea); to accept (e.g. advice); to introduce; to borrow (e.g. word)" },
	{ "question": "取り出す", "answers": [ "とりだす" ], "comment": "to take out; to produce; to pick out\nto fetch; to retrieve" },
	{ "question": "取り口", "answers": [ "とりくち" ], "comment": "technique; techniques" },
	{ "question": "取り囲む", "answers": [ "とりかこむ" ], "comment": "to surround; to crowd around" },
	{ "question": "取り壊し", "answers": [ "とりこわし" ], "comment": "demolition; pulling down; destruction; dismantling" },
	{ "question": "取り外す", "answers": [ "とりはずす" ], "comment": "to dismantle; to demount; to take something away; to detach" },
	{ "question": "取り寄せる", "answers": [ "とりよせる" ], "comment": "to order; to send away for\nto pull something closer" },
	{ "question": "取り巻く", "answers": [ "とりまく" ], "comment": "to surround; to circle; to enclose" },
	{ "question": "取り戻す", "answers": [ "とりもどす" ], "comment": "to take back; to regain; to get back; to recover" },
	{ "question": "取り扱", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service; handling; management" },
	{ "question": "取り扱い", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service; handling; management" },
	{ "question": "取り扱う", "answers": [ "とりあつかう" ], "comment": "to handle; to operate (a machine, etc.); to use\nto deal with (an issue); to manage\nto treat (someone); to deal with (someone)\nto deal in; to carry; to sell" },
	{ "question": "取り掛かる", "answers": [ "とりかかる" ], "comment": "to begin; to set about; to start" },
	{ "question": "取り替える", "answers": [ "とりかえる" ], "comment": "to exchange; to replace" },
	{ "question": "取り柄", "answers": [ "とりえ" ], "comment": "worth; redeeming feature; merit; gain; profit" },
	{ "question": "取り次ぐ", "answers": [ "とりつぐ" ], "comment": "to act as an agent for; to intermediate\nto announce (someone's arrival); to answer (the door, the phone); to receive (a guest at reception); to usher in (a guest)\nto convey (a message)" },
	{ "question": "取り残す", "answers": [ "とりのこす" ], "comment": "to leave behind" },
	{ "question": "取り決め", "answers": [ "とりきめ" ], "comment": "decision; agreement" },
	{ "question": "取り決める", "answers": [ "とりきめる" ], "comment": "to agree; to decide upon; to enter into (a contract)" },
	{ "question": "取り消し", "answers": [ "とりけし" ], "comment": "cancellation; withdrawal; abolition; revocation; cancel; CAN" },
	{ "question": "取り消す", "answers": [ "とりけす" ], "comment": "to cancel; to withdraw; to retract; to take back (words, etc.); to revoke" },
	{ "question": "取り立て", "answers": [ "とりたて" ], "comment": "collection (of a debt)\npatronage; promotion\nfresh (e.g. freshly picked)" },
	{ "question": "取り組み", "answers": [ "とりくみ" ], "comment": "bout (in sports, etc.); match\neffort; initiative; dealing with; grappling with; wrestling with" },
	{ "question": "取り組む", "answers": [ "とっくむ", "とりくむ" ], "comment": "to tackle; to wrestle with; to engage in a bout; to come to grips with; to make effort; to strive for; to deal with" },
	{ "question": "取り締まり", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "control; management; supervision" },
	{ "question": "取り締まる", "answers": [ "とりしまる" ], "comment": "to manage; to control; to supervise; to crack down on" },
	{ "question": "取り締り", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "control; management; supervision" },
	{ "question": "取り計らい", "answers": [ "とりはからい" ], "comment": "arrangement" },
	{ "question": "取り調べ", "answers": [ "とりしらべ" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. by police or prosecutors); examination; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "取り込み", "answers": [ "とりこみ" ], "comment": "taking in; bringing in\ncapturing (e.g. customers); attracting; winning over; pleasing\nconfusion; bustle; misfortune; disorder\nimporting (e.g. data); capturing (e.g. image)" },
	{ "question": "取り込む", "answers": [ "とりこむ" ], "comment": "to take in; to bring in; to adopt (e.g. behaviour); to introduce\nto capture (e.g. image); to import\nto win over; to please; to curry favour with; to flatter\nto defraud of; to swindle; to embezzle\nto be busy; to be in confusion; to have trouble" },
	{ "question": "取り返す", "answers": [ "とりかえす" ], "comment": "to regain; to recover; to get back" },
	{ "question": "取り除く", "answers": [ "とりのぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to deinstall; to take away; to set apart" },
	{ "question": "取る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take; to pick up; to harvest; to earn; to win; to choose\nto steal\nto eat; to have (a meal)\nto remove (one's glasses, etc.)\nto compete (in sumo, cards, etc.); to play" },
	{ "question": "取れる", "answers": [ "とれる" ], "comment": "to come off; to be removed\n(of pain, a fever, etc.) to disappear\nto be caught; to be harvested\nto be interpreted (as); to be taken as\n(of balance, etc.) to be attained\nto be obtainable" },
	{ "question": "取上げる", "answers": [ "とりあげる" ], "comment": "to pick up; to take up\nto adopt; to feature; to accept; to listen to\nto take away; to confiscate; to deprive; to disqualify\nto deliver (a child)" },
	{ "question": "取引", "answers": [ "とりひき" ], "comment": "transactions; dealings; business" },
	{ "question": "取得", "answers": [ "しゅとく" ], "comment": "acquisition; obtaining; gaining possession; purchase" },
	{ "question": "取扱", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service; handling; management" },
	{ "question": "取扱い", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service; handling; management" },
	{ "question": "取扱注意", "answers": [ "とりあつかいちゅうい" ], "comment": "handling warning" },
	{ "question": "取材", "answers": [ "しゅざい" ], "comment": "news coverage; collecting data (e.g. for an article); covering (something for media)\ninterview" },
	{ "question": "取次", "answers": [ "とりつぎ" ], "comment": "agency; commission; distributor; intermediation\nreception (of guests)\nconveyance (of messages)" },
	{ "question": "取水", "answers": [ "しゅすい" ], "comment": "drawing water from river or lake; water intake" },
	{ "question": "取決め", "answers": [ "とりきめ" ], "comment": "decision; agreement" },
	{ "question": "取消し", "answers": [ "とりけし" ], "comment": "cancellation; withdrawal; abolition; revocation; cancel; CAN" },
	{ "question": "取締まり", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "control; management; supervision" },
	{ "question": "取締り", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "control; management; supervision" },
	{ "question": "取締役", "answers": [ "とりしまりやく" ], "comment": "company director; board member" },
	{ "question": "取締役会", "answers": [ "とりしまりやくかい" ], "comment": "board of directors\nboard of directors' meeting" },
	{ "question": "取締法", "answers": [ "とりしまりほう" ], "comment": "control law" },
	{ "question": "取調べ", "answers": [ "とりしらべ" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. by police or prosecutors); examination; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "受かる", "answers": [ "うかる" ], "comment": "to pass (examination)" },
	{ "question": "受け付け", "answers": [ "うけつけ" ], "comment": "reception (desk); information desk\nreceipt; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受け付ける", "answers": [ "うけつける" ], "comment": "to accept; to receive (an application); to take up\nto withstand; to tolerate; to bear" },
	{ "question": "受け入れ", "answers": [ "うけいれ" ], "comment": "receiving; acceptance; reception" },
	{ "question": "受け入れる", "answers": [ "うけいれる" ], "comment": "to accept; to receive; to agree" },
	{ "question": "受け取", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受け取り", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受け取る", "answers": [ "うけとる" ], "comment": "to receive; to get; to accept\nto take; to interpret; to understand" },
	{ "question": "受け持ち", "answers": [ "うけもち" ], "comment": "charge (of something); matter in one's charge" },
	{ "question": "受け持つ", "answers": [ "うけもつ" ], "comment": "to take (be in) charge of" },
	{ "question": "受け止める", "answers": [ "うけとめる" ], "comment": "to catch; to stop the blow\nto react to; to take (advice, etc.); to accept; to come to grips with" },
	{ "question": "受け渡し", "answers": [ "うけわたし" ], "comment": "delivery" },
	{ "question": "受け皿", "answers": [ "うけざら" ], "comment": "saucer\nperson (group, institution, etc.) to take over a position or matter; receptacle (e.g. of funds); receiver" },
	{ "question": "受け継ぐ", "answers": [ "うけつぐ" ], "comment": "to inherit; to succeed; to take over" },
	{ "question": "受け身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "the defensive\npassive attitude; passivity; passiveness\nthe passive; passive voice\nukemi (the art of falling safely)" },
	{ "question": "受付", "answers": [ "うけつけ" ], "comment": "reception (desk); information desk\nreceipt; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受付中", "answers": [ "うけつけちゅう" ], "comment": "currently accepting (applications, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "受信", "answers": [ "じゅしん" ], "comment": "reception (e.g. radio); receipt (e.g. email message)" },
	{ "question": "受信機", "answers": [ "じゅしんき" ], "comment": "(television, radio, etc.) receiver" },
	{ "question": "受像", "answers": [ "じゅぞう" ], "comment": "(television) reception" },
	{ "question": "受刑", "answers": [ "じゅけい" ], "comment": "punishment" },
	{ "question": "受動的", "answers": [ "じゅどうてき" ], "comment": "passive" },
	{ "question": "受取", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受取り", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受取人", "answers": [ "うけとりにん" ], "comment": "recipient" },
	{ "question": "受容", "answers": [ "じゅよう" ], "comment": "reception" },
	{ "question": "受注", "answers": [ "じゅちゅう" ], "comment": "accepting an order; receiving an order; orders received" },
	{ "question": "受理", "answers": [ "じゅり" ], "comment": "acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受益", "answers": [ "じゅえき" ], "comment": "benefitting by; benefiting by" },
	{ "question": "受章", "answers": [ "じゅしょう" ], "comment": "reception of a decoration; reception of an order" },
	{ "question": "受精", "answers": [ "じゅせい" ], "comment": "fertilization; fertilisation; impregnation; pollination" },
	{ "question": "受精卵", "answers": [ "じゅせいらん" ], "comment": "fertilized eggs; fertilised eggs" },
	{ "question": "受給", "answers": [ "じゅきゅう" ], "comment": "receiving payments (pension, ration)" },
	{ "question": "受託", "answers": [ "じゅたく" ], "comment": "being entrusted with; taking charge of" },
	{ "question": "受診", "answers": [ "じゅしん" ], "comment": "having a medical exam; seeing a doctor" },
	{ "question": "受話器", "answers": [ "じゅわき" ], "comment": "(telephone) receiver" },
	{ "question": "受諾", "answers": [ "じゅだく" ], "comment": "acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受講", "answers": [ "じゅこう" ], "comment": "taking (attending) lectures" },
	{ "question": "受賞", "answers": [ "じゅしょう" ], "comment": "winning (a prize)" },
	{ "question": "受身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "the defensive\npassive attitude; passivity; passiveness\nthe passive; passive voice\nukemi (the art of falling safely)" },
	{ "question": "受難", "answers": [ "じゅなん" ], "comment": "suffering; agony; passion" },
	{ "question": "受領", "answers": [ "じゅりょう" ], "comment": "receipt (of letter); acknowledgement; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受験", "answers": [ "じゅけん" ], "comment": "taking an examination (esp. school and university entrance)" },
	{ "question": "叙勲", "answers": [ "じょくん" ], "comment": "conferring of decorations" },
	{ "question": "叙情", "answers": [ "じょじょう" ], "comment": "lyricism; description or expression of one's feelings" },
	{ "question": "口", "answers": [ "くち" ], "comment": "mouth\nopening; hole; gap; orifice\nmouth (of a bottle); spout; nozzle; mouthpiece\ngate; door; entrance; exit\nspeaking; speech; talk (i.e. gossip)\ntaste; palate\nmouth (to feed)\nopening (i.e. vacancy); available position\ninvitation; summons\nkind; sort; type\nopening (i.e. beginning)\ncounter for mouthfuls, shares (of money), and swords" },
	{ "question": "口々", "answers": [ "くちぐち" ], "comment": "each entrance; every mouth" },
	{ "question": "口々に", "answers": [ "くちぐちに" ], "comment": "severally; unanimously" },
	{ "question": "口喧嘩", "answers": [ "くちげんか" ], "comment": "quarrel; dispute; argument" },
	{ "question": "口ごもる", "answers": [ "くちごもる" ], "comment": "to hesitate to say; to mumble; to hem and haw; to falter" },
	{ "question": "口ぶり", "answers": [ "くちぶり" ], "comment": "way of speaking\nintimation" },
	{ "question": "口コミ", "answers": [ "くちコミ" ], "comment": "word of mouth\ncomment on an Internet forum or web page" },
	{ "question": "口上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "vocal message; speech; statement\nprologue at the start of a kabuki performance" },
	{ "question": "口先", "answers": [ "くちさき" ], "comment": "lip service; mere words; professions\nlips; mouth; snout; proboscis" },
	{ "question": "口出し", "answers": [ "くちだし" ], "comment": "interference; meddling; butting in" },
	{ "question": "口利き", "answers": [ "くちきき" ], "comment": "mediation; good offices; intervention; mediator; middleman\ninfluential person; person of influence\neloquence; eloquent person\nway of speaking" },
	{ "question": "口実", "answers": [ "こうじつ" ], "comment": "excuse; pretext" },
	{ "question": "口座", "answers": [ "こうざ" ], "comment": "account (e.g. bank)" },
	{ "question": "口座番号", "answers": [ "こうざばんごう" ], "comment": "account number (bank, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "口径", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "aperture; bore; calibre; caliber" },
	{ "question": "口数", "answers": [ "くちかず", "くちすう" ], "comment": "number of words a person speaks\nnumber of dependents (words, shares, accounts)" },
	{ "question": "口止め", "answers": [ "くちどめ" ], "comment": "forbidding to speak; muzzling (a person); bribing into secrecy\nhush money" },
	{ "question": "口火", "answers": [ "くちび" ], "comment": "fuse; pilot light\ncause (of a war, argument, revolt, etc.); origin; trigger" },
	{ "question": "口癖", "answers": [ "くちぐせ" ], "comment": "way of saying; favorite phrase; favourite phrase" },
	{ "question": "口笛", "answers": [ "くちぶえ" ], "comment": "whistle (sound made with the lips)" },
	{ "question": "口答え", "answers": [ "くちごたえ" ], "comment": "retort; back talk" },
	{ "question": "口紅", "answers": [ "くちべに" ], "comment": "lipstick" },
	{ "question": "口語", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "spoken language; colloquial speech\nliterary style based on (modern) spoken language" },
	{ "question": "口調", "answers": [ "くちょう" ], "comment": "tone (e.g. of voice, etc.); (verbal) expression" },
	{ "question": "口論", "answers": [ "こうろん" ], "comment": "dispute; quarrel; argument" },
	{ "question": "口頭", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "oral; verbal; parol" },
	{ "question": "口頭弁論", "answers": [ "こうとうべんろん" ], "comment": "oral proceedings; oral pleadings" },
	{ "question": "古", "answers": [ "いにしえ" ], "comment": "antiquity; ancient times" },
	{ "question": "古い", "answers": [ "ふるい" ], "comment": "old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article" },
	{ "question": "古今", "answers": [ "ここん" ], "comment": "ancient and modern times; all ages; past and present" },
	{ "question": "古代", "answers": [ "こだい" ], "comment": "ancient times" },
	{ "question": "古典", "answers": [ "こてん" ], "comment": "old book; classics; classic" },
	{ "question": "古典的", "answers": [ "こてんてき" ], "comment": "classical; classic" },
	{ "question": "古参", "answers": [ "こさん" ], "comment": "seniority; long service" },
	{ "question": "古墳", "answers": [ "こふん" ], "comment": "ancient burial mound; barrow; tumulus" },
	{ "question": "古巣", "answers": [ "ふるす" ], "comment": "old haunts; former homes" },
	{ "question": "古文書", "answers": [ "こもんじょ", "こぶんしょ" ], "comment": "ancient document; archives; ancient manuscript; paleograph\ndocument addressed to someone in particular (jargon used in paleography)" },
	{ "question": "古書", "answers": [ "こしょ" ], "comment": "old book; rare book\nsecondhand book; used book" },
	{ "question": "古本", "answers": [ "ふるほん", "こほん", "ふるぼん" ], "comment": "secondhand book\nancient book; antiquarian books" },
	{ "question": "古来", "answers": [ "こらい" ], "comment": "from time immemorial; ancient; time-honoured; time-honored" },
	{ "question": "古着", "answers": [ "ふるぎ" ], "comment": "old clothes; secondhand clothing" },
	{ "question": "古紙", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "used paper; paper for recycling" },
	{ "question": "古都", "answers": [ "こと" ], "comment": "ancient city; former capital" },
	{ "question": "句", "answers": [ "く" ], "comment": "section (i.e. of text); sentence; passage; paragraph\nphrase\nverse (of 5 or 7 mora in Japanese poetry; of 4, 5, or 7 characters in Chinese poetry)\nhaiku; first 17 morae of a renga, etc.\nmaxim; saying; idiom; expression" },
	{ "question": "句読点", "answers": [ "くとうてん" ], "comment": "punctuation mark; punctuation marks" },
	{ "question": "句集", "answers": [ "くしゅう" ], "comment": "collection of haiku poems" },
	{ "question": "叩き", "answers": [ "たたき" ], "comment": "mince (minced meat or fish)\nseared skipjack tuna\nrobbery; extortion\nhard-packed dirt (clay, gravel, etc.) floor; concrete floor\nwhipping; lashing; bashing; beating; flaming" },
	{ "question": "叩く", "answers": [ "たたく" ], "comment": "to strike; to clap; to knock; to beat; to tap; to pat\nto play drums\nto abuse; to flame (e.g. on the Internet); to insult\nto consult; to sound out\nto brag; to talk big\nto call; to invoke (e.g. a function)" },
	{ "question": "叫び", "answers": [ "さけび" ], "comment": "shout; scream; outcry" },
	{ "question": "叫び声", "answers": [ "さけびごえ" ], "comment": "shout; yell; scream" },
	{ "question": "叫ぶ", "answers": [ "さけぶ" ], "comment": "to shout; to cry; to scream; to shriek; to yell; to exclaim\nto clamor (for or against); to clamour (for or against)" },
	{ "question": "召し上がる", "answers": [ "めしあがる" ], "comment": "to eat; to drink" },
	{ "question": "召集", "answers": [ "しょうしゅう" ], "comment": "convening; calling together (e.g. parliament)" },
	{ "question": "可", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "passable; acceptable; tolerable; fair" },
	{ "question": "可否", "answers": [ "かひ" ], "comment": "propriety; right and wrong; advisability; possibility\npro and con; ayes and noes" },
	{ "question": "可愛がる", "answers": [ "かわいがる" ], "comment": "to love; to be affectionate; to favor; to favour; to be partial to\nto torment; to tease; to be rough with" },
	{ "question": "可愛らしい", "answers": [ "かわいらしい" ], "comment": "lovely; sweet" },
	{ "question": "可決", "answers": [ "かけつ" ], "comment": "approval; adoption (e.g. motion, bill); passage" },
	{ "question": "可燃物", "answers": [ "かねんぶつ" ], "comment": "combustibles; inflammables; flammables; burnables" },
	{ "question": "可能", "answers": [ "かのう" ], "comment": "potential; possible; practicable; feasible" },
	{ "question": "可能にする", "answers": [ "かのうにする" ], "comment": "to allow; to enable; to make possible; to make feasible; to permit" },
	{ "question": "可能性", "answers": [ "かのうせい" ], "comment": "potentiality; likelihood; possibility; availability" },
	{ "question": "可能性が高い", "answers": [ "かのうせいがたかい" ], "comment": "very likely; very probable" },
	{ "question": "台", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "stand; rack; table; bench; podium; pedestal; platform; stage\nsupport; holder; rack\ncounter for machines, incl. vehicles\nsetting (e.g. in jewellery)\nlevel (e.g. price level); range (e.g. after physical units); period (of time, e.g. a decade of one's life)\nelevated area\nviewing platform\ndish tray\nmeal\ntall building; tower" },
	{ "question": "台地", "answers": [ "だいち" ], "comment": "plateau; tableland; eminence" },
	{ "question": "台帳", "answers": [ "だいちょう" ], "comment": "account book; ledger; register" },
	{ "question": "台所", "answers": [ "だいどこ", "だいどころ" ], "comment": "kitchen\nfinancial situation" },
	{ "question": "台本", "answers": [ "だいほん" ], "comment": "script; libretto; scenario" },
	{ "question": "台湾", "answers": [ "たいわん" ], "comment": "Taiwan" },
	{ "question": "台無し", "answers": [ "だいなし" ], "comment": "mess; spoiled; spoilt; (come to) nothing; ruin" },
	{ "question": "台車", "answers": [ "だいしゃ" ], "comment": "platform truck; hand truck; trolley; dolly; cart\n(railway) truck; bogie; flatcar; wagon; waggon" },
	{ "question": "台頭", "answers": [ "たいとう" ], "comment": "rise (e.g. of a movement); emergence; rearing one's head; gaining prominence; coming to the fore; gaining power; gathering strength" },
	{ "question": "台風", "answers": [ "たいふう" ], "comment": "typhoon; hurricane" },
	{ "question": "史", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "history" },
	{ "question": "史上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "in history; ever; historical" },
	{ "question": "史学", "answers": [ "しがく" ], "comment": "study of history" },
	{ "question": "史実", "answers": [ "しじつ" ], "comment": "historical fact" },
	{ "question": "史家", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "historian" },
	{ "question": "史料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "historical records; archives" },
	{ "question": "史跡", "answers": [ "しせき" ], "comment": "historic landmark; historic site; historic remains" },
	{ "question": "右", "answers": [ "みぎ" ], "comment": "right; right hand side\nafore-mentioned (esp. in vertical Japanese writing); foregoing; forgoing; above" },
	{ "question": "右中間", "answers": [ "うちゅうかん" ], "comment": "between right and center fielders (centre)" },
	{ "question": "右側", "answers": [ "うそく", "みぎがわ" ], "comment": "right side; right hand" },
	{ "question": "右手", "answers": [ "みぎて" ], "comment": "right hand\nright-hand side; right-hand direction; (on) the right" },
	{ "question": "右派", "answers": [ "うは" ], "comment": "right wing" },
	{ "question": "右翼", "answers": [ "うよく" ], "comment": "right-wing (politics)\nextreme right-wing group\nright wing (bird, plane, etc.)\nright field; right flank; right wing\nright fielder\nhigh rank; high grade; A-student" },
	{ "question": "右腕", "answers": [ "みぎうで", "うわん" ], "comment": "right arm\nright-hand man; right hand; right-hand person\nright-handed pitcher" },
	{ "question": "叶える", "answers": [ "かなえる" ], "comment": "to grant (request, wish); to answer (prayer)\nto fulfill (conditions); to meet (requirements)" },
	{ "question": "号", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "number; edition; make; model; issue; part of that group\nsobriquet; pen-name\nsuffix attached to names of ships, trains, airplanes, etc." },
	{ "question": "号令", "answers": [ "ごうれい" ], "comment": "order; command" },
	{ "question": "号車", "answers": [ "ごうしゃ" ], "comment": "classifier for naming train cars" },
	{ "question": "司る", "answers": [ "つかさどる" ], "comment": "to rule; to govern; to administer" },
	{ "question": "司令", "answers": [ "しれい" ], "comment": "command; control; commander" },
	{ "question": "司令官", "answers": [ "しれいかん" ], "comment": "commandant; commanding officer; general" },
	{ "question": "司令部", "answers": [ "しれいぶ" ], "comment": "headquarters" },
	{ "question": "司会", "answers": [ "しかい" ], "comment": "leading a meeting; presiding over a meeting; officiating at a ceremony; chairmanship\nchairman; presenter; host; moderator; master of ceremonies" },
	{ "question": "司会者", "answers": [ "しかいしゃ" ], "comment": "chairman; moderator; toastmaster; master of ceremonies; chairperson; host (of a TV show, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "司法", "answers": [ "しほう" ], "comment": "administration of justice" },
	{ "question": "司法裁判", "answers": [ "しほうさいばん" ], "comment": "judicial trial" },
	{ "question": "各", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "each; every; all" },
	{ "question": "各々", "answers": [ "おのおの" ], "comment": "each\nyou (plural)" },
	{ "question": "各位", "answers": [ "かくい" ], "comment": "everyone; each and every one (of you); ladies and gentlemen" },
	{ "question": "各各", "answers": [ "おのおの" ], "comment": "each\nyou (plural)" },
	{ "question": "各国", "answers": [ "かくこく", "かっこく" ], "comment": "each nation\nmany nations; many countries" },
	{ "question": "各地", "answers": [ "かくち" ], "comment": "every place; various places" },
	{ "question": "各種", "answers": [ "かくしゅ" ], "comment": "every kind; all sorts" },
	{ "question": "各自", "answers": [ "かくじ" ], "comment": "each (person); everyone; individual; respective" },
	{ "question": "合", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "0.18039 litres (liters)\n0.3306 metres square (meters)\none-tenth of the way from the base to the summit of a mountain\nconjunction\ncounter for covered containers\ncounter for matches, battles, etc." },
	{ "question": "合う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "to come together; to merge; to unite; to meet\nto fit; to match; to suit; to agree with; to be correct\nto be profitable; to be equitable\nto do ... to each other; to do ... together" },
	{ "question": "合わす", "answers": [ "あわす" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "合わせる", "answers": [ "あわせる" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "合作", "answers": [ "がっさく" ], "comment": "collaboration; joint work" },
	{ "question": "合併", "answers": [ "がっぺい" ], "comment": "combination; union; amalgamation; consolidation; merger; coalition; fusion; annexation; affiliation; incorporation" },
	{ "question": "合併症", "answers": [ "がっぺいしょう" ], "comment": "complications (in an illness)" },
	{ "question": "合力", "answers": [ "ごうりょく", "こうりょく", "ごうりき" ], "comment": "resultant force\nassistance; help\ndonation; alms; almsgiving" },
	{ "question": "合同", "answers": [ "ごうどう" ], "comment": "combination; union; incorporation; amalgamation; fusion\ncongruence" },
	{ "question": "合否", "answers": [ "ごうひ" ], "comment": "success or failure; result" },
	{ "question": "合唱", "answers": [ "がっしょう" ], "comment": "chorus; singing in a chorus" },
	{ "question": "合唱団", "answers": [ "がっしょうだん" ], "comment": "chorus group; choir" },
	{ "question": "合図", "answers": [ "あいず" ], "comment": "sign; signal" },
	{ "question": "合奏", "answers": [ "がっそう" ], "comment": "ensemble (e.g. orchestra, chamber group, etc.); concert" },
	{ "question": "合宿", "answers": [ "がっしゅく" ], "comment": "lodging together; training camp; boarding house" },
	{ "question": "合弁", "answers": [ "ごうべん" ], "comment": "joint management; pool" },
	{ "question": "合意", "answers": [ "ごうい" ], "comment": "agreement; consent; mutual understanding; accord; consensus" },
	{ "question": "合憲", "answers": [ "ごうけん" ], "comment": "constitutionality" },
	{ "question": "合成", "answers": [ "ごうせい" ], "comment": "composition; synthesis\ncomposite; compound; synthetic; mixed; combined\n(function) composition" },
	{ "question": "合成洗剤", "answers": [ "ごうせいせんざい" ], "comment": "synthetic detergent" },
	{ "question": "合戦", "answers": [ "かっせん" ], "comment": "battle; fight; fighting; engagement; contest" },
	{ "question": "合板", "answers": [ "ごうはん", "ごうばん" ], "comment": "veneer board; plywood\njoint publication" },
	{ "question": "合格", "answers": [ "ごうかく" ], "comment": "success; passing (e.g. exam); eligibility" },
	{ "question": "合法", "answers": [ "ごうほう" ], "comment": "legal; lawful; legality" },
	{ "question": "合法的", "answers": [ "ごうほうてき" ], "comment": "legal; lawful; legitimate; law-abiding; in order" },
	{ "question": "合理", "answers": [ "ごうり" ], "comment": "rationality" },
	{ "question": "合理化", "answers": [ "ごうりか" ], "comment": "rationalization; rationalisation; rationalize; rationalise" },
	{ "question": "合理的", "answers": [ "ごうりてき" ], "comment": "rational; reasonable; logical" },
	{ "question": "合繊", "answers": [ "ごうせん" ], "comment": "synthetic fiber; synthetic fibre" },
	{ "question": "合致", "answers": [ "がっち" ], "comment": "agreement; concurrence; conformance; compliance" },
	{ "question": "合言葉", "answers": [ "あいことば" ], "comment": "password; watchword\nmotto; slogan" },
	{ "question": "合計", "answers": [ "ごうけい" ], "comment": "sum total; total amount" },
	{ "question": "合議", "answers": [ "ごうぎ" ], "comment": "consultation; conference" },
	{ "question": "合金", "answers": [ "ごうきん" ], "comment": "alloy" },
	{ "question": "合間", "answers": [ "あいま" ], "comment": "interval; break; pause; spare moment" },
	{ "question": "吉祥天", "answers": [ "きっしょうてん", "きちじょうてん" ], "comment": "Sri-mahadevi (consort of Vaisravana in Buddhism, based on Lakshmi, the consort of Vishnu in Hinduism)" },
	{ "question": "吊る", "answers": [ "つる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend (something from something); to be hanged (by the neck)\nto hoist an opponent off of his feet by his loincloth" },
	{ "question": "吊るす", "answers": [ "つるす" ], "comment": "to hang; to hang up" },
	{ "question": "同", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "the same; the said; ibid." },
	{ "question": "同じ", "answers": [ "おんなじ", "おなじ" ], "comment": "same; identical; equal; uniform; equivalent; similar; common (origin); changeless; alike\n(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway; anyhow; in either case" },
	{ "question": "同じく", "answers": [ "おなじく" ], "comment": "similarly; same (idea); same (name)" },
	{ "question": "同一", "answers": [ "どういつ" ], "comment": "identical; same; one and the same; equal\nfair; equal treatment; without discrimination" },
	{ "question": "同上", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "same as above; ditto; ibid." },
	{ "question": "同乗", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "riding together; riding with" },
	{ "question": "同人", "answers": [ "どうじん", "どうにん" ], "comment": "same person\nsaid person; the person in question\ncoterie; clique; fraternity; kindred spirits; comrade; colleague\ndōjin; doujin; Japanese fans or hobbyists who produce their owns magazines, manga, software, etc." },
	{ "question": "同伴", "answers": [ "どうはん" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go with\ncompany; companion" },
	{ "question": "同僚", "answers": [ "どうりょう" ], "comment": "coworker; co-worker; colleague; associate" },
	{ "question": "同党", "answers": [ "どうとう" ], "comment": "the same political party" },
	{ "question": "同列", "answers": [ "どうれつ" ], "comment": "same rank or file; company; attendance" },
	{ "question": "同化", "answers": [ "どうか" ], "comment": "assimilation; absorption\nanabolism\nadaptation" },
	{ "question": "同名", "answers": [ "どうめい", "どうみょう" ], "comment": "same name\nhomonym" },
	{ "question": "同国", "answers": [ "どうこく" ], "comment": "the same country; the same province; the said country" },
	{ "question": "同地", "answers": [ "どうち" ], "comment": "the same place; that place" },
	{ "question": "同士", "answers": [ "どうし", "どし" ], "comment": "fellow; mutual; companion; comrade" },
	{ "question": "同夜", "answers": [ "どうや" ], "comment": "the same night; that night" },
	{ "question": "同好", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "similar tastes" },
	{ "question": "同姓", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "same surname" },
	{ "question": "同室", "answers": [ "どうしつ" ], "comment": "the same room" },
	{ "question": "同封", "answers": [ "どうふう" ], "comment": "enclosing (e.g. with a letter)" },
	{ "question": "同局", "answers": [ "どうきょく" ], "comment": "the said bureau; the same bureau" },
	{ "question": "同居", "answers": [ "どうきょ" ], "comment": "coexistence; living together" },
	{ "question": "同市", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "same city" },
	{ "question": "同席", "answers": [ "どうせき" ], "comment": "presence; sitting with; being with" },
	{ "question": "同年", "answers": [ "どうねん" ], "comment": "that year; same year; same age" },
	{ "question": "同店", "answers": [ "どうてん" ], "comment": "the same store; the same shop" },
	{ "question": "同志", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "like-mindedness; (being of the) same mind; shared sentiment\ncomrade; fellow; kindred soul" },
	{ "question": "同性", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "same sex" },
	{ "question": "同性愛", "answers": [ "どうせいあい" ], "comment": "homosexual love" },
	{ "question": "同情", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "sympathy; compassion; feeling pity for" },
	{ "question": "同意", "answers": [ "どうい" ], "comment": "agreement; consent; same opinion; approval\nsame meaning" },
	{ "question": "同感", "answers": [ "どうかん" ], "comment": "agreement; same opinion; same feeling; sympathy; concurrence" },
	{ "question": "同数", "answers": [ "どうすう" ], "comment": "same number" },
	{ "question": "同日", "answers": [ "どうじつ" ], "comment": "the same day" },
	{ "question": "同時", "answers": [ "どうじ" ], "comment": "simultaneous; concurrent; same time; synchronous; together" },
	{ "question": "同時に", "answers": [ "どうじに" ], "comment": "coincident with; while; simultaneously" },
	{ "question": "同時代", "answers": [ "どうじだい" ], "comment": "the same age; same period" },
	{ "question": "同月", "answers": [ "どうげつ" ], "comment": "the same month" },
	{ "question": "同期", "answers": [ "どうき" ], "comment": "same period; corresponding period\nsame year (of graduation, entering a company, etc.); contemporary; classmate\nsynchronization; synchronism" },
	{ "question": "同校", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "same school" },
	{ "question": "同棲", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "cohabitation (usu. of a romantically involved couple); living together" },
	{ "question": "同業", "answers": [ "どうぎょう" ], "comment": "same trade; same business" },
	{ "question": "同様", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "identical; equal to; same (kind); like; similarity" },
	{ "question": "同氏", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "the said person; he; she; same person" },
	{ "question": "同点", "answers": [ "どうてん" ], "comment": "deadlock; tie; draw" },
	{ "question": "同然", "answers": [ "どうぜん" ], "comment": "similar to; same; right; proper; just; natural" },
	{ "question": "同率", "answers": [ "どうりつ" ], "comment": "the same ratio or percentage" },
	{ "question": "同町", "answers": [ "どうちょう" ], "comment": "the same town; that town" },
	{ "question": "同病", "answers": [ "どうびょう" ], "comment": "the same sickness" },
	{ "question": "同盟", "answers": [ "どうめい" ], "comment": "alliance; union; league" },
	{ "question": "同省", "answers": [ "どうしょう" ], "comment": "the said ministry; the same ministry" },
	{ "question": "同県", "answers": [ "どうけん" ], "comment": "the same prefecture" },
	{ "question": "同社", "answers": [ "どうしゃ" ], "comment": "the same firm" },
	{ "question": "同種", "answers": [ "どうしゅ" ], "comment": "same kind (race); homogeneousness" },
	{ "question": "同窓", "answers": [ "どうそう" ], "comment": "the same school" },
	{ "question": "同窓会", "answers": [ "どうそうかい" ], "comment": "graduate's association; alumni meeting; class reunion" },
	{ "question": "同等", "answers": [ "どうとう" ], "comment": "equality; equal; same rights; same rank; equivalence" },
	{ "question": "同級", "answers": [ "どうきゅう" ], "comment": "the same grade; same class" },
	{ "question": "同級生", "answers": [ "どうきゅうせい" ], "comment": "classmate" },
	{ "question": "同胞", "answers": [ "はらから", "どうぼう", "どうほう" ], "comment": "brethren; brothers; fellow countrymen; fellowman; compatriot" },
	{ "question": "同船", "answers": [ "どうせん" ], "comment": "the same ship; taking the same ship" },
	{ "question": "同行", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "accompanying; travelling together; traveling together\nsame bank" },
	{ "question": "同調", "answers": [ "どうちょう" ], "comment": "sympathy; agreement with; alignment; conformity; tuning" },
	{ "question": "同郷", "answers": [ "どうきょう" ], "comment": "same village; same town; same province" },
	{ "question": "同音", "answers": [ "どうおん" ], "comment": "homophony; same pronunciation; same sound\nunison; same pitch\n(in) one voice; (speaking in) unison" },
	{ "question": "同類", "answers": [ "どうるい" ], "comment": "the same kind; accomplice; partner" },
	{ "question": "名", "answers": [ "な" ], "comment": "name; given name\ntitle\nfame; renown; reputation\npretext; pretense; justification; appearance" },
	{ "question": "名乗り", "answers": [ "なのり" ], "comment": "giving one's name (or rank, etc.); self-introduction\nname readings of kanji" },
	{ "question": "名乗り出る", "answers": [ "なのりでる" ], "comment": "to introduce oneself; to announce oneself (e.g. as the person sought); to come forward (e.g. as a witness, with a claim, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "名乗る", "answers": [ "なのる" ], "comment": "to give one's name (as); to introduce oneself (as)\nto claim to be; to call oneself; to wear the title of\nto reveal oneself (as); to admit to being\nto adopt as one's name; to take (a name)\nto call out the goods one is selling" },
	{ "question": "名人", "answers": [ "めいじん" ], "comment": "master; expert" },
	{ "question": "名付ける", "answers": [ "なづける" ], "comment": "to name; to call; to christen; to term" },
	{ "question": "名作", "answers": [ "めいさく" ], "comment": "masterpiece" },
	{ "question": "名優", "answers": [ "めいゆう" ], "comment": "great or famous actor; star" },
	{ "question": "名刺", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "business card" },
	{ "question": "名前", "answers": [ "なまえ" ], "comment": "name; full name\ngiven name; first name" },
	{ "question": "名声", "answers": [ "めいせい" ], "comment": "fame; reputation; renown" },
	{ "question": "名字", "answers": [ "みょうじ" ], "comment": "surname; family name" },
	{ "question": "名実", "answers": [ "めいじつ" ], "comment": "in name and in reality; nominally and virtually; form and contents" },
	{ "question": "名所", "answers": [ "などころ", "めいしょ" ], "comment": "famous place\nname of a part (of an instrument, etc.)\nname and address" },
	{ "question": "名手", "answers": [ "めいしゅ" ], "comment": "master; expert\nexpert board game player (chess, go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "名指し", "answers": [ "なざし" ], "comment": "nomination; calling names" },
	{ "question": "名曲", "answers": [ "めいきょく" ], "comment": "famous music" },
	{ "question": "名月", "answers": [ "めいげつ" ], "comment": "harvest moon\nbright moon; full moon" },
	{ "question": "名札", "answers": [ "なふだ" ], "comment": "name plate; name tag; label" },
	{ "question": "名案", "answers": [ "めいあん" ], "comment": "good idea" },
	{ "question": "名残", "answers": [ "なごり" ], "comment": "remains; traces; vestiges; relics\n(the sorrow of) parting\nend" },
	{ "question": "名残惜しい", "answers": [ "なごりおしい" ], "comment": "reluctant (to part)" },
	{ "question": "名物", "answers": [ "めいぶつ" ], "comment": "famous product; special product; speciality; specialty" },
	{ "question": "名画", "answers": [ "めいが" ], "comment": "famous picture; masterpiece\nfilm classic" },
	{ "question": "名目", "answers": [ "みょうもく", "めいもく" ], "comment": "name; title; appellation; (something) nominal\n(under the) pretext (of); pretense" },
	{ "question": "名称", "answers": [ "めいしょう" ], "comment": "name; title" },
	{ "question": "名簿", "answers": [ "めいぼ" ], "comment": "register of names; list of names; roll; register" },
	{ "question": "名義", "answers": [ "めいぎ" ], "comment": "name\nin the name of" },
	{ "question": "名著", "answers": [ "めいちょ" ], "comment": "famous book; masterpiece (literary work)" },
	{ "question": "名詞", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "noun" },
	{ "question": "名誉", "answers": [ "めいよ" ], "comment": "honor; honour; credit; prestige" },
	{ "question": "名門", "answers": [ "めいもん" ], "comment": "noted family; noble family\nprestigious school, organization, business, etc." },
	{ "question": "名高い", "answers": [ "なだかい" ], "comment": "famous; celebrated; well-known" },
	{ "question": "吐き気", "answers": [ "はきけ" ], "comment": "nausea; sickness in the stomach" },
	{ "question": "吐く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto emit; to send forth; to breathe out\nto give (an opinion); to make (a comment); to express; to tell\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "吐露", "answers": [ "とろ" ], "comment": "expressing one's mind; speaking out" },
	{ "question": "向い", "answers": [ "むかい" ], "comment": "facing; opposite; across the street; other side" },
	{ "question": "向かい", "answers": [ "むかい" ], "comment": "facing; opposite; across the street; other side" },
	{ "question": "向かう", "answers": [ "むかう" ], "comment": "to face\nto go towards; to head towards" },
	{ "question": "向かって左", "answers": [ "むかってひだり" ], "comment": "on the left as one faces (it)" },
	{ "question": "向き", "answers": [ "むき" ], "comment": "direction; orientation; aspect; exposure\nsuited to; suitable for; designed for\ntendency; inclination\nnature (of a request or desire)\nperson" },
	{ "question": "向く", "answers": [ "むく" ], "comment": "to face\nto turn toward\nto be suited to; to be fit for" },
	{ "question": "向け", "answers": [ "むけ" ], "comment": "intended for ...; oriented towards ...; aimed at ..." },
	{ "question": "向ける", "answers": [ "むける" ], "comment": "to turn towards; to point" },
	{ "question": "向こう", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "opposite side; other side; opposite direction\nover there; that way; far away; beyond\nthe other party; the other person\nfuture (starting now)" },
	{ "question": "向こう側", "answers": [ "むこうがわ" ], "comment": "other side; opposite side; other party" },
	{ "question": "向上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "elevation; rise; improvement; advancement; progress" },
	{ "question": "君", "answers": [ "きみ", "くん" ], "comment": "you; buddy; pal\nmonarch; ruler; sovereign; (one's) master /\n Mr (junior); master; boy" },
	{ "question": "君が代", "answers": [ "きみがよ" ], "comment": "Imperial reign\ntitle of Japanese national anthem" },
	{ "question": "君たち", "answers": [ "きみたち" ], "comment": "you (plural); all of you; you all" },
	{ "question": "君主", "answers": [ "くんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; monarch; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "君子", "answers": [ "くんし" ], "comment": "man of virtue; person of high rank; wise man" },
	{ "question": "君臨", "answers": [ "くんりん" ], "comment": "reigning; controlling\nto reign; to dictate; to control" },
	{ "question": "吟味", "answers": [ "ぎんみ" ], "comment": "close examination; careful selection; testing; scrutiny\nexamination of criminal charges\nreciting and appreciating traditional poetry" },
	{ "question": "吠える", "answers": [ "ほえる" ], "comment": "to bark; to bay; to howl; to bellow; to roar; to cry" },
	{ "question": "否", "answers": [ "ひ", "いや", "いな" ], "comment": "no; the noes" },
	{ "question": "否定", "answers": [ "ひてい" ], "comment": "negation; denial; repudiation; disavowal\nNOT operation" },
	{ "question": "否決", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "rejection; negation; voting down" },
	{ "question": "否認", "answers": [ "ひにん" ], "comment": "denial; negation; repudiation; disapproval" },
	{ "question": "含み", "answers": [ "ふくみ" ], "comment": "implication; hidden meaning; latitude; atmosphere; tone; sentiment; inclusion" },
	{ "question": "含む", "answers": [ "ふくむ", "くくむ" ], "comment": "to contain; to comprise; to have; to hold; to include; to embrace\nto hold in the mouth\nto bear in mind; to understand; to harbor (grudge, etc.); to harbour\nto express (emotion, etc.); to imply" },
	{ "question": "含める", "answers": [ "ふくめる" ], "comment": "to include (in a group or scope)\nto instruct; to make one understand\nto include (a nuance); to put in (an implication)\nto put in (someone's) mouth\nto permeate with flavor" },
	{ "question": "含有", "answers": [ "がんゆう" ], "comment": "contain; include" },
	{ "question": "吸い殻", "answers": [ "すいがら" ], "comment": "cigarette end; cigarette butt; tobacco ashes" },
	{ "question": "吸い込む", "answers": [ "すいこむ" ], "comment": "to inhale; to breathe in; to suck up; to imbibe\nto absorb; to soak up" },
	{ "question": "吸う", "answers": [ "すう" ], "comment": "to smoke; to breathe in; to inhale\nto suck; to sip; to slurp\nto absorb; to soak up\nto kiss" },
	{ "question": "吸収", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "absorption; suction; attraction" },
	{ "question": "吸血鬼", "answers": [ "きゅうけつき" ], "comment": "vampire; bloodsucker" },
	{ "question": "吹き出す", "answers": [ "ふきだす" ], "comment": "to spout out; to spurt out; to gush out; to jet out\nto sprout; to bud\nto burst into laughter\nto blow (smoke, etc.)\nto send out shoots (of a tree)" },
	{ "question": "吹き出物", "answers": [ "ふきでもの" ], "comment": "pimple; acne; boil; rash" },
	{ "question": "吹き溜まり", "answers": [ "ふきだまり" ], "comment": "drift of snow or leaves\nhangout for drifters" },
	{ "question": "吹き込む", "answers": [ "ふきこむ" ], "comment": "to blow into; to breathe into\nto inspire; to indoctrinate\nto record (music, video, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "吹く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "to blow (e.g. wind); to play a wind instrument\nto emit; to spout\nto whistle\nto laugh; to burst into laughter\nto smelt; to mint\nto brag; to talk big" },
	{ "question": "吹雪", "answers": [ "ふぶき" ], "comment": "snow storm; blizzard" },
	{ "question": "呆れる", "answers": [ "あきれる" ], "comment": "to be amazed; to be shocked; to be astonished; to be astounded; to be disgusted; to be exasperated" },
	{ "question": "呉服", "answers": [ "ごふく" ], "comment": "cloth (for Japanese clothes); textile; drapery; dry goods; piece goods\nsilk fabrics" },
	{ "question": "告げる", "answers": [ "つげる" ], "comment": "to tell; to inform; to announce\nto indicate; to signal; to mark" },
	{ "question": "告別", "answers": [ "こくべつ" ], "comment": "farewell; leave-taking" },
	{ "question": "告発", "answers": [ "こくはつ" ], "comment": "indictment; prosecution; complaint" },
	{ "question": "告白", "answers": [ "こくはく" ], "comment": "confession; acknowledgement; acknowledgment\nprofession of love\nconfession of sins (e.g. the confessional)" },
	{ "question": "告知", "answers": [ "こくち" ], "comment": "notice; announcement" },
	{ "question": "告示", "answers": [ "こくじ" ], "comment": "notice; bulletin" },
	{ "question": "告訴", "answers": [ "こくそ" ], "comment": "accusation; complaint; charge; legal action" },
	{ "question": "周り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "circumference; girth\nsurroundings; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity" },
	{ "question": "周到", "answers": [ "しゅうとう" ], "comment": "scrupulous; meticulous; careful" },
	{ "question": "周囲", "answers": [ "しゅうい" ], "comment": "surroundings; environs\ncircumference" },
	{ "question": "周年", "answers": [ "しゅうねん" ], "comment": "whole year; anniversary" },
	{ "question": "周期", "answers": [ "しゅうき" ], "comment": "cycle; period" },
	{ "question": "周波数", "answers": [ "しゅうはすう" ], "comment": "frequency (esp. of waveforms)" },
	{ "question": "周知", "answers": [ "しゅうち" ], "comment": "common knowledge; being well-known; making (something) well-known" },
	{ "question": "周辺", "answers": [ "しゅうへん" ], "comment": "circumference; outskirts; environs; around; in the area of; in the vicinity of\n(computer) peripheral" },
	{ "question": "呪い", "answers": [ "のろい" ], "comment": "curse; spell; malediction" },
	{ "question": "呪う", "answers": [ "のろう" ], "comment": "to curse; to put a curse on; to detest intensely" },
	{ "question": "味", "answers": [ "あじ" ], "comment": "flavor; flavour; taste\ncharm; style\nexperience\nsmart; clever; witty; strange" },
	{ "question": "味の素", "answers": [ "あじのもと" ], "comment": "Ajinomoto; brand name of monosodium glutamate (MSG)" },
	{ "question": "味わい", "answers": [ "あじわい" ], "comment": "flavour; flavor\nmeaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "味わう", "answers": [ "あじわう" ], "comment": "to taste; to savor; to savour; to relish\nto appreciate; to enjoy; to relish; to digest\nto taste; to experience; to undergo; to endure" },
	{ "question": "味付け", "answers": [ "あじつけ" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "味噌", "answers": [ "みそ" ], "comment": "miso; fermented condiment usu. made from soybeans\ninnards (from crabs, shrimps, etc.) resembling miso\nkey (main) point; good part (of something)\nweakling; weak person" },
	{ "question": "味噌汁", "answers": [ "みそしる" ], "comment": "miso soup" },
	{ "question": "味方", "answers": [ "みかた" ], "comment": "friend; ally; supporter" },
	{ "question": "味気ない", "answers": [ "あじけない", "あじきない" ], "comment": "wearisome; insipid; dull; irksome; wretched; vain" },
	{ "question": "味覚", "answers": [ "みかく" ], "comment": "taste; palate; sense of taste" },
	{ "question": "呼びかけ", "answers": [ "よびかけ" ], "comment": "call; appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼びかける", "answers": [ "よびかける" ], "comment": "to call out to; to hail; to address\nto appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼び出し", "answers": [ "よびだし" ], "comment": "call; summons; paging; curtain call\nusher who calls the names of wrestlers, sweeps the ring, etc.\ntelephone number at which a person without a telephone can be reached\nbox-shaped area containing clean water for rinsing oneself (in an Edo-period bathhouse)\nhigh-ranking prostitute in the Yoshiwara district (Edo period)\nunlicensed prostitute in the Fukagawa red-light district (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "呼び出す", "answers": [ "よびだす" ], "comment": "to summon; to call (e.g. phone); to convene; to decoy; to lure\nto invoke (e.g. subroutine); to call; to open (e.g. a file)" },
	{ "question": "呼び名", "answers": [ "よびな" ], "comment": "given name; popular name; mnemonic name" },
	{ "question": "呼び捨て", "answers": [ "よびすて" ], "comment": "addressing someone without an honorific such as \"san\"" },
	{ "question": "呼び掛け", "answers": [ "よびかけ" ], "comment": "call; appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼び掛ける", "answers": [ "よびかける" ], "comment": "to call out to; to hail; to address\nto appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼び水", "answers": [ "よびみず" ], "comment": "pump-priming; rousing; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "呼ぶ", "answers": [ "よぶ" ], "comment": "to call out (to); to call; to invoke\nto summon (a doctor, etc.)\nto invite\nto designate; to name; to brand\nto garner (support, etc.); to gather\nto take as one's wife" },
	{ "question": "呼吸", "answers": [ "こきゅう" ], "comment": "breathing; respiration\nknack; trick; secret (of doing something)\nharmony; balance; synchronization; accord\nshort interval; short pause" },
	{ "question": "呼吸器", "answers": [ "こきゅうき" ], "comment": "respiratory organs" },
	{ "question": "呼応", "answers": [ "こおう" ], "comment": "hailing each other\nacting in concert\nagreement; concord" },
	{ "question": "呼称", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "naming; giving a name; designation; denomination\nnominal" },
	{ "question": "命", "answers": [ "いのち" ], "comment": "life; life force\nlifetime; lifespan\nmost important thing; foundation; core\npaired tattoos of the \"life\" kanji on the upper arms of a man and woman (indicating unwavering love)\nfate; destiny; karma" },
	{ "question": "命じる", "answers": [ "めいじる" ], "comment": "to order; to command; to appoint" },
	{ "question": "命ずる", "answers": [ "めいずる" ], "comment": "to command; to appoint" },
	{ "question": "命中", "answers": [ "めいちゅう" ], "comment": "a hit; hitting something that was aimed at" },
	{ "question": "命令", "answers": [ "めいれい" ], "comment": "order; command; decree; directive\n(software) instruction; statement" },
	{ "question": "命名", "answers": [ "めいめい" ], "comment": "naming; christening" },
	{ "question": "命日", "answers": [ "めいにち" ], "comment": "death anniversary" },
	{ "question": "命運", "answers": [ "めいうん" ], "comment": "fate; doom" },
	{ "question": "命題", "answers": [ "めいだい" ], "comment": "proposition; thesis; notion; theory\nproblem; issue; challenge" },
	{ "question": "和", "answers": [ "わ" ], "comment": "sum\nharmony; peace\nJapan; Japanese-style" },
	{ "question": "和む", "answers": [ "なごむ" ], "comment": "to be softened; to calm down" },
	{ "question": "和やか", "answers": [ "なごやか" ], "comment": "mild; calm; gentle; quiet; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "和らぐ", "answers": [ "やわらぐ" ], "comment": "to soften; to calm down; to be mitigated" },
	{ "question": "和らげる", "answers": [ "やわらげる" ], "comment": "to soften; to moderate; to relieve" },
	{ "question": "和室", "answers": [ "わしつ" ], "comment": "Japanese-style room" },
	{ "question": "和平", "answers": [ "わへい" ], "comment": "peace" },
	{ "question": "和式", "answers": [ "わしき" ], "comment": "Japanese style" },
	{ "question": "和服", "answers": [ "わふく" ], "comment": "Japanese clothes" },
	{ "question": "和歌", "answers": [ "わか" ], "comment": "waka; classic Japanese poem, esp. a tanka, often 31 morae" },
	{ "question": "和牛", "answers": [ "わぎゅう" ], "comment": "Wagyu beef; Japanese beef" },
	{ "question": "和紙", "answers": [ "わし" ], "comment": "washi; Japanese paper" },
	{ "question": "和英", "answers": [ "わえい" ], "comment": "Japanese-English" },
	{ "question": "和菓子", "answers": [ "わがし" ], "comment": "wagashi; traditional Japanese confectionery" },
	{ "question": "和解", "answers": [ "わかい", "わげ" ], "comment": "reconciliation; amicable settlement; accommodation; compromise; mediation; rapprochement\ncourt-mediated settlement\ntranslation of a foreign language into Japanese" },
	{ "question": "和語", "answers": [ "わご" ], "comment": "native Japanese words (especially as opposed to Chinese and other foreign loanwords)" },
	{ "question": "和議", "answers": [ "わぎ" ], "comment": "peace conference; peace negotiations" },
	{ "question": "和風", "answers": [ "わふう" ], "comment": "Japanese style\nlight wind; moderate breeze" },
	{ "question": "和食", "answers": [ "わしょく" ], "comment": "Japanese food; Japanese-style meal; Japanese cuisine" },
	{ "question": "咬む", "answers": [ "かむ" ], "comment": "to bite; to chew; to gnaw\nto crash against (e.g. of waves); to break onto (shore)\nto engage (of cogs, zippers, etc.); to mesh; to fit together\nto be involved in\nto fumble one's words (during a play, broadcast, etc.); to falter with one's words\nto strongly confute; to argue down; to rebuke; to scold harshly" },
	{ "question": "咲く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to bloom" },
	{ "question": "咳", "answers": [ "しわぶき", "せき" ], "comment": "cough; coughing; tussis" },
	{ "question": "哀れ", "answers": [ "あわれ" ], "comment": "pity; sorrow; grief; misery; compassion; pathos\npitiable; pitiful; pathetic; miserable\nalack; alas" },
	{ "question": "哀れむ", "answers": [ "あわれむ" ], "comment": "to commiserate; to pity; to have mercy on; to sympathize with; to sympathise with\nto enjoy the beauty of; to appreciate (e.g. the moon, flowers)" },
	{ "question": "哀悼", "answers": [ "あいとう" ], "comment": "condolence; regret; tribute; sorrow; sympathy; lament" },
	{ "question": "哀愁", "answers": [ "あいしゅう" ], "comment": "pathos; sorrow; grief" },
	{ "question": "品", "answers": [ "ひん", "しな" ], "comment": "elegance; grace; refinement; class; dignity\narticle; item\ncounter for items (of food, etc.); counter for dishes or courses (at a restaurant)" },
	{ "question": "品位", "answers": [ "ひんい" ], "comment": "dignity; grace; nobility\ngrade; quality; fineness; carat; karat" },
	{ "question": "品切れ", "answers": [ "しなぎれ" ], "comment": "out of stock; sold out" },
	{ "question": "品名", "answers": [ "ひんめい" ], "comment": "name of product" },
	{ "question": "品性", "answers": [ "ひんせい" ], "comment": "character" },
	{ "question": "品格", "answers": [ "ひんかく" ], "comment": "dignity; quality of character" },
	{ "question": "品物", "answers": [ "しなもの" ], "comment": "goods; article; thing" },
	{ "question": "品目", "answers": [ "ひんもく", "しなめ" ], "comment": "item; commodity; list of articles" },
	{ "question": "品種", "answers": [ "ひんしゅ" ], "comment": "kind (of goods); brand\n(taxonomical) form\nbreed; cultivar" },
	{ "question": "品詞", "answers": [ "ひんし" ], "comment": "part of speech" },
	{ "question": "品質", "answers": [ "ひんしつ" ], "comment": "(material) quality" },
	{ "question": "員", "answers": [ "いん" ], "comment": "member" },
	{ "question": "員数", "answers": [ "いんず", "いんずう" ], "comment": "numbers of members (things, people)" },
	{ "question": "哲学", "answers": [ "てつがく" ], "comment": "philosophy" },
	{ "question": "唄", "answers": [ "うた" ], "comment": "song\nclassical Japanese poetry (esp. tanka)\nmodern poetry" },
	{ "question": "唄う", "answers": [ "うたう" ], "comment": "to sing\nto sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.); to compose a poem; to recite a poem" },
	{ "question": "唇", "answers": [ "くちびる" ], "comment": "lips" },
	{ "question": "唐突", "answers": [ "とうとつ" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden" },
	{ "question": "唐辛子", "answers": [ "とんがらし", "とうがらし", "ばんしょう" ], "comment": "capsicum (Capsicum annuum, esp. the cultivated chili peppers); chili pepper (chile, chilli); cayenne; red pepper\nshichimi pepper" },
	{ "question": "唯一", "answers": [ "ゆいいつ", "ゆいつ" ], "comment": "only; sole; unique" },
	{ "question": "唱える", "answers": [ "となえる" ], "comment": "to recite; to chant\nto cry; to yell; to shout\nto advocate; to advance; to preach; to insist" },
	{ "question": "唸る", "answers": [ "うなる" ], "comment": "to groan; to moan\nto roar; to howl; to growl\nto hum (e.g. engine, wires in wind); to buzz; to sough; low, dull sound\nto ooh and aah (in admiration)\nto sing in a strong, low voice (esp. traditional chant or recitation)" },
	{ "question": "唾", "answers": [ "つばき", "つば", "つわき" ], "comment": "saliva; spit; sputum" },
	{ "question": "商", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "quotient\ndealing; dealer; store\nsecond degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nShang (dynasty of China)" },
	{ "question": "商い", "answers": [ "あきない" ], "comment": "trade; business; trading; dealing" },
	{ "question": "商事", "answers": [ "しょうじ" ], "comment": "commercial affairs" },
	{ "question": "商人", "answers": [ "あきうど", "あきゅうど", "あきんど", "あきびと", "しょうにん" ], "comment": "trader; shopkeeper; merchant" },
	{ "question": "商会", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "firm; company" },
	{ "question": "商務", "answers": [ "しょうむ" ], "comment": "commercial affairs" },
	{ "question": "商品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "commodity; article of commerce; goods; stock; merchandise" },
	{ "question": "商品券", "answers": [ "しょうひんけん" ], "comment": "gift certificate" },
	{ "question": "商売", "answers": [ "しょうばい" ], "comment": "trade; business; commerce; transaction; occupation" },
	{ "question": "商学", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "commercial science" },
	{ "question": "商工", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "commerce and industry" },
	{ "question": "商工会議所", "answers": [ "しょうこうかいぎしょ" ], "comment": "Chamber of Commerce and Industry" },
	{ "question": "商店", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "shop; small store; business; firm" },
	{ "question": "商戦", "answers": [ "しょうせん" ], "comment": "sales war" },
	{ "question": "商業", "answers": [ "しょうぎょう" ], "comment": "commerce; trade; business" },
	{ "question": "商標", "answers": [ "しょうひょう" ], "comment": "trademark" },
	{ "question": "商法", "answers": [ "しょうほう" ], "comment": "business practice; business method; commerce\ncommercial law" },
	{ "question": "商用", "answers": [ "しょうよう" ], "comment": "on business; for business; business purpose" },
	{ "question": "商社", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "trading company; firm" },
	{ "question": "商談", "answers": [ "しょうだん" ], "comment": "business discussion; negotiation" },
	{ "question": "問", "answers": [ "もん" ], "comment": "counter for questions" },
	{ "question": "問い", "answers": [ "とい" ], "comment": "question; query" },
	{ "question": "問い合わせ", "answers": [ "といあわせ" ], "comment": "enquiry; inquiry; query; interrogation; ENQ" },
	{ "question": "問い合わせる", "answers": [ "といあわせる" ], "comment": "to enquire; to inquire; to seek information" },
	{ "question": "問う", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "to ask; to inquire\nto charge (e.g. with a crime); to accuse\nwithout regard to; to not matter\nto call into question; to doubt; to question" },
	{ "question": "問屋", "answers": [ "とんや", "といや" ], "comment": "wholesale store" },
	{ "question": "問答", "answers": [ "もんどう" ], "comment": "questions and answers; dialogue" },
	{ "question": "問責", "answers": [ "もんせき" ], "comment": "blame; censure; reproof; reprimand; rebuke" },
	{ "question": "問題", "answers": [ "もんだい" ], "comment": "question (e.g. on a test); problem\nproblem (e.g. societal, political); question; issue; subject (e.g. of research); case; matter\nquestion (i.e. doubt)\npublic discussion; controversy\ntrouble; problem; inconvenience; difficulty" },
	{ "question": "問題意識", "answers": [ "もんだいいしき" ], "comment": "awareness of the issues; (having a) critical mind; concerns" },
	{ "question": "問題点", "answers": [ "もんだいてん" ], "comment": "the problem (at issue); the point at issue; problematic issue; problem" },
	{ "question": "啓発", "answers": [ "けいはつ" ], "comment": "enlightenment; development; edification; public awareness; illumination; education; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "啓蒙", "answers": [ "けいもう" ], "comment": "enlightenment; instruction" },
	{ "question": "善", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "good; goodness; right; virtue" },
	{ "question": "善し悪し", "answers": [ "よしわるし", "よしあし" ], "comment": "right or wrong; good or bad; merits or demerits; quality; suitability" },
	{ "question": "善悪", "answers": [ "ぜんあく" ], "comment": "good and evil" },
	{ "question": "善意", "answers": [ "ぜんい" ], "comment": "virtuous mind\ngood intentions; good will\npositive mindset\nbona fides; good faith" },
	{ "question": "善戦", "answers": [ "ぜんせん" ], "comment": "fighting a good fight; putting up a good fight; fighting bravely" },
	{ "question": "善隣", "answers": [ "ぜんりん" ], "comment": "good neighbour; good neighbor" },
	{ "question": "喚問", "answers": [ "かんもん" ], "comment": "summons" },
	{ "question": "喚起", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "arousal; excitation; awakening; evocation" },
	{ "question": "喜ばしい", "answers": [ "よろこばしい" ], "comment": "delightful; joyous; happy" },
	{ "question": "喜ばす", "answers": [ "よろこばす" ], "comment": "to delight; to give pleasure" },
	{ "question": "喜び", "answers": [ "よろこび" ], "comment": "joy; delight; rapture; pleasure; gratification; rejoicing; congratulations; felicitations" },
	{ "question": "喜ぶ", "answers": [ "よろこぶ" ], "comment": "to be delighted; to be glad; to be pleased\nto congratulate\nto gratefully accept" },
	{ "question": "喜んで", "answers": [ "よろこんで" ], "comment": "with pleasure ..." },
	{ "question": "喜劇", "answers": [ "きげき" ], "comment": "comedy; funny show" },
	{ "question": "喧嘩", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "quarrel; brawl; fight; squabble; scuffle; argument" },
	{ "question": "喪主", "answers": [ "もしゅ" ], "comment": "chief mourner" },
	{ "question": "喪失", "answers": [ "そうしつ" ], "comment": "loss; forfeit" },
	{ "question": "喫する", "answers": [ "きっする" ], "comment": "to eat; to drink; to smoke; to take\nto suffer (e.g. defeat); to receive a blow" },
	{ "question": "喫煙", "answers": [ "きつえん" ], "comment": "smoking" },
	{ "question": "喫茶", "answers": [ "きっさ" ], "comment": "tea drinking\nteahouse; tearoom; coffee lounge; coffee shop; (rather formal) cafe" },
	{ "question": "喫茶店", "answers": [ "きっさてん", "きっちゃてん" ], "comment": "coffee shop; tearoom; coffee lounge; coffeehouse; cafe" },
	{ "question": "営み", "answers": [ "いとなみ" ], "comment": "activity; action; performance; execution; occupation; business; work; sexual intercourse; sex" },
	{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "to run (a business); to operate; to conduct; to practice (law, medicine, etc.)\nto carry out; to perform; to lead (a life)\nto hold (a Buddhist or Shinto ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "営利", "answers": [ "えいり" ], "comment": "money-making; commercialized; commercialised" },
	{ "question": "営団", "answers": [ "えいだん" ], "comment": "corporation; foundation" },
	{ "question": "営業", "answers": [ "えいぎょう" ], "comment": "business; trade; sales; operations" },
	{ "question": "営業所", "answers": [ "えいぎょうしょ" ], "comment": "business office; place of business" },
	{ "question": "営農", "answers": [ "えいのう" ], "comment": "farming; agriculture" },
	{ "question": "嗅ぐ", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "to sniff; to smell" },
	{ "question": "嘆き", "answers": [ "なげき" ], "comment": "grief; lamentation" },
	{ "question": "嘆く", "answers": [ "なげく" ], "comment": "to lament; to grieve; to regret\nto deplore" },
	{ "question": "嘘", "answers": [ "うそ" ], "comment": "lie; fib; falsehood; untruth\nmistake; error\nunwise move; bad decision\nNo way!; Unbelievable!; Really?!" },
	{ "question": "嘘つき", "answers": [ "うそつき", "ウソつき" ], "comment": "liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness); fibber" },
	{ "question": "嘱託", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "commission; charge (person with); entrusting with\npart-time (employee)" },
	{ "question": "嘲る", "answers": [ "あざける" ], "comment": "to scoff; to laugh at; to make fun of; to ridicule; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "噂", "answers": [ "うわさ" ], "comment": "rumour; rumor; report; hearsay; gossip; common talk" },
	{ "question": "噛み付く", "answers": [ "かみつく" ], "comment": "to bite (at); to snap at; to snarl at" },
	{ "question": "噛む", "answers": [ "かむ" ], "comment": "to bite; to chew; to gnaw\nto crash against (e.g. of waves); to break onto (shore)\nto engage (of cogs, zippers, etc.); to mesh; to fit together\nto be involved in\nto fumble one's words (during a play, broadcast, etc.); to falter with one's words\nto strongly confute; to argue down; to rebuke; to scold harshly" },
	{ "question": "器", "answers": [ "うつわ" ], "comment": "bowl; vessel; container\nability; capacity; calibre; caliber" },
	{ "question": "器具", "answers": [ "きぐ" ], "comment": "utensil; apparatus; implement; device; gadget" },
	{ "question": "器官", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "organ (of body, plant, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "器材", "answers": [ "きざい" ], "comment": "tools and materials; equipment and materials" },
	{ "question": "器械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "machine; mechanism\ninstrument; appliance; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "器物", "answers": [ "うつわもの", "きぶつ" ], "comment": "container; receptacle\nutensil; implement; furniture\ncalibre; talent; ability\npersonal property" },
	{ "question": "器用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "skilful; skillfull; adroit; dexterous; dextrous; deft; nimble; handy\nclever; shrewd; ingenious" },
	{ "question": "噴き出す", "answers": [ "ふきだす" ], "comment": "to spout out; to spurt out; to gush out; to jet out\nto sprout; to bud\nto burst into laughter\nto blow (smoke, etc.)\nto send out shoots (of a tree)" },
	{ "question": "噴出", "answers": [ "ふんしゅつ" ], "comment": "spewing; gushing; spouting; eruption; effusion" },
	{ "question": "噴射", "answers": [ "ふんしゃ" ], "comment": "jet; spray; injection; jet propulsion" },
	{ "question": "噴水", "answers": [ "ふんすい" ], "comment": "water fountain" },
	{ "question": "噴火", "answers": [ "ふんか" ], "comment": "eruption" },
	{ "question": "噴煙", "answers": [ "ふんえん" ], "comment": "(eruption of) smoke" },
	{ "question": "囚人", "answers": [ "しゅうじん", "めしゅうど", "めしうど" ], "comment": "prisoner" },
	{ "question": "四", "answers": [ "よん", "し", "よ" ], "comment": "four" },
	{ "question": "四つ", "answers": [ "よつ", "よっつ" ], "comment": "four" },
	{ "question": "四つ角", "answers": [ "よつかど" ], "comment": "four corners; crossroads" },
	{ "question": "四十", "answers": [ "よんじゅう", "しじゅう" ], "comment": "forty" },
	{ "question": "四千", "answers": [ "よんせん" ], "comment": "four thousand" },
	{ "question": "四半期", "answers": [ "しはんき" ], "comment": "quarter (of a year)" },
	{ "question": "四季", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "four seasons" },
	{ "question": "四捨五入", "answers": [ "ししゃごにゅう" ], "comment": "rounding (fractions); rounding half up" },
	{ "question": "四方", "answers": [ "よも", "よほう", "しほう" ], "comment": "the four cardinal directions; north, east, south and west; all directions\nsurroundings\nmany countries; the whole world\nall around; here and there\nsquare; quadrilateral; four-sided figure\nfour sides (of a square)" },
	{ "question": "四日", "answers": [ "よっか" ], "comment": "fourth day of the month\nfour days" },
	{ "question": "四月", "answers": [ "しがつ" ], "comment": "April" },
	{ "question": "四本", "answers": [ "よんほん" ], "comment": "four (long cylindrical things)" },
	{ "question": "四死球", "answers": [ "ししきゅう" ], "comment": "bases on balls and pitches striking the batsmen" },
	{ "question": "四球", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "four balls; base on balls; a walk" },
	{ "question": "四畳半", "answers": [ "よじょうはん" ], "comment": "four and a half tatami mats; four-and-a-half-mat room\nsmall room esp. for assignations" },
	{ "question": "四百", "answers": [ "よんひゃく" ], "comment": "four hundred" },
	{ "question": "四角", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "square" },
	{ "question": "四角い", "answers": [ "しかくい" ], "comment": "square; rectangular" },
	{ "question": "四輪車", "answers": [ "よんりんしゃ" ], "comment": "automobile; car" },
	{ "question": "四重奏", "answers": [ "しじゅうそう" ], "comment": "instrumental quartet" },
	{ "question": "回", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "counter for occurrences\na time; an instance\ninning (baseball); round; game\nepisode; chapter; instalment\nHui (people)\nIslam" },
	{ "question": "回し", "answers": [ "まわし" ], "comment": "mawashi; belt; loincloth\nmantle; cape\ngang rape" },
	{ "question": "回す", "answers": [ "まわす" ], "comment": "to turn; to rotate; to gyrate\nto circulate; to send around\nto surround\nto put something to a new use (e.g. leftovers)\n... around (e.g. to chase someone around)\nto dial (e.g. telephone number)\nto invest\nto gang-rape" },
	{ "question": "回り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "rotation\nmaking the rounds\nspreading\neffect; efficacy\nby way of; via\nround; turn\nsize\n12-year period; 12-year age difference" },
	{ "question": "回り道", "answers": [ "まわりみち" ], "comment": "detour; diversion" },
	{ "question": "回る", "answers": [ "まわる" ], "comment": "to turn; to revolve\nto visit several places\nto function well\nto pass a certain time" },
	{ "question": "回収", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "collection; recovery; withdrawal; retrieval" },
	{ "question": "回帰", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "return (to); revolution; recurrence; recursion; comeback; revival\nregression" },
	{ "question": "回廊", "answers": [ "かいろう" ], "comment": "corridor; gallery; hallway; cloister (i.e. covered walk typically circling a building or garden, esp. in a palace or place of worship)" },
	{ "question": "回復", "answers": [ "かいふく" ], "comment": "restoration; rehabilitation; recovery; return; replevin; improvement\nrecovery (from an illness); recuperation; convalescence" },
	{ "question": "回忌", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "death anniversary" },
	{ "question": "回想", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "reflection; reminiscence" },
	{ "question": "回戦", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "counter for numbering the rounds in a tournament\nfight with ... rounds (e.g. boxing)" },
	{ "question": "回数", "answers": [ "かいすう" ], "comment": "number of times; frequency; count" },
	{ "question": "回数券", "answers": [ "かいすうけん" ], "comment": "book of tickets" },
	{ "question": "回生", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "resurrection; resuscitation; regeneration\nuniversity student in ... year" },
	{ "question": "回答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "reply; answer" },
	{ "question": "回線", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "circuit; line" },
	{ "question": "回路", "answers": [ "かいろ" ], "comment": "circuit (electric)\ncycle (e.g. Krebs cycle)" },
	{ "question": "回転", "answers": [ "かいてん" ], "comment": "rotation (usu. around something); revolution; turning" },
	{ "question": "回避", "answers": [ "かいひ" ], "comment": "evasion; avoidance" },
	{ "question": "回顧", "answers": [ "かいこ" ], "comment": "recollecting; reminiscing; looking back; retrospection; review" },
	{ "question": "因子", "answers": [ "いんし" ], "comment": "factor; divisor; element" },
	{ "question": "因果", "answers": [ "いんが" ], "comment": "cause and effect; karma; fate" },
	{ "question": "因縁", "answers": [ "いんえん", "いんねん" ], "comment": "fate; destiny\nconnection; tie; bond; origin\npretext; justification\nhetu and prataya (direct causes and indirect conditions, which underlie the actions of all things)" },
	{ "question": "団体", "answers": [ "だんたい" ], "comment": "organization; organisation; association" },
	{ "question": "団員", "answers": [ "だんいん" ], "comment": "group member" },
	{ "question": "団地", "answers": [ "だんち" ], "comment": "multi-unit apartments; apartment complex" },
	{ "question": "団塊", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "mass; lump\nbaby boom generation (of 1947-1949); babyboomer (born between 1947-1949)" },
	{ "question": "団結", "answers": [ "だんけつ" ], "comment": "unity; union; combination; teaming up" },
	{ "question": "団長", "answers": [ "だんちょう" ], "comment": "leader of a delegation (body, party)" },
	{ "question": "困り果てる", "answers": [ "こまりはてる" ], "comment": "to be greatly perplexed; to be greatly embarrassed" },
	{ "question": "困る", "answers": [ "こまる" ], "comment": "to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped" },
	{ "question": "困惑", "answers": [ "こんわく" ], "comment": "bewilderment; perplexity; embarrassment; discomfiture; bafflement" },
	{ "question": "困難", "answers": [ "こんなん" ], "comment": "difficulty; hardship; trouble; distress" },
	{ "question": "囲い", "answers": [ "かこい" ], "comment": "enclosure; paling; storage\ncastle; strong defensive position" },
	{ "question": "囲う", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "to enclose; to surround; to encircle; to fence; to wall in\nto shelter (e.g. a criminal); to shield; to hide; to protect\nto keep (e.g. a mistress)\nto store (vegetables, fruit, etc.); to preserve\nto protect" },
	{ "question": "囲み", "answers": [ "かこみ" ], "comment": "enclosure; box\nsiege" },
	{ "question": "囲む", "answers": [ "かこむ" ], "comment": "to surround; to encircle; to enclose; to fence; to wall in\nto besiege; to lay siege to\nto play (go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "囲碁", "answers": [ "いご" ], "comment": "go; board game of capturing territory" },
	{ "question": "図", "answers": [ "ず" ], "comment": "drawing; picture; diagram; figure; illustration; chart; graph\nsight; scene" },
	{ "question": "図々しい", "answers": [ "ずうずうしい" ], "comment": "impudent; shameless" },
	{ "question": "図る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to plan; to attempt; to devise\nto plot; to conspire; to scheme\nto aim for; to strive for; to work towards; to seek\nto deceive; to trick; to take in" },
	{ "question": "図式", "answers": [ "ずしき" ], "comment": "diagram; graph; schema" },
	{ "question": "図形", "answers": [ "ずけい" ], "comment": "figure; shape; graphic" },
	{ "question": "図書", "answers": [ "としょ" ], "comment": "books" },
	{ "question": "図書室", "answers": [ "としょしつ" ], "comment": "library room" },
	{ "question": "図書館", "answers": [ "としょかん" ], "comment": "library" },
	{ "question": "図柄", "answers": [ "ずがら" ], "comment": "design; pattern" },
	{ "question": "図版", "answers": [ "ずはん" ], "comment": "plate; illustration; figure" },
	{ "question": "図示", "answers": [ "ずし" ], "comment": "illustration; showing in graphic form or by diagram" },
	{ "question": "図表", "answers": [ "ずひょう" ], "comment": "chart; diagram; graph; figure" },
	{ "question": "図解", "answers": [ "ずかい" ], "comment": "schematic; schema; illustration; explanatory diagram" },
	{ "question": "図鑑", "answers": [ "ずかん" ], "comment": "pictorial book; picture book; illustrated reference book; identification manual; field guide" },
	{ "question": "図面", "answers": [ "ずめん" ], "comment": "drawing; diagram; plans; blueprint" },
	{ "question": "固い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "hard; solid; tough\nstiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing)\nstrong; firm (not viscous or easily moved)\nsafe; steady; honest; steadfast\nobstinate; stubborn\nbookish; formal; stuffy" },
	{ "question": "固さ", "answers": [ "かたさ" ], "comment": "firmness; hardness; stiffness; honesty" },
	{ "question": "固まる", "answers": [ "かたまる" ], "comment": "to harden; to solidify\nto become firm; to become certain\nto gather (together); to assemble; to huddle together" },
	{ "question": "固め", "answers": [ "かため" ], "comment": "hardening; fortifying\npledge; vow\ndefense; defence; guarding" },
	{ "question": "固める", "answers": [ "かためる" ], "comment": "to harden; to freeze; to strengthen; to solidify; to make (a fist); to tramp down (snow, dirt)\nto put together; to collect; to gather; to consolidate\nto make secure; to stabilize; to settle down; to strengthen (belief, resolution, etc.); to establish (evidence)\nto fortify; to reinforce; to support\nto wear for a specific purpose (armor, coat, etc.)\nto swear; to resolutely vow; to sincerely promise\nto tie tightly; to fasten\nto hold a bow fully drawn" },
	{ "question": "固体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "solid (body); solid matter; solid-state" },
	{ "question": "固執", "answers": [ "こしつ", "こしゅう" ], "comment": "adherence (e.g. to ideas, beliefs, a pet theory) (negative nuance); persistence; insistence; stubbornness" },
	{ "question": "固定", "answers": [ "こてい" ], "comment": "fixation; fixing (e.g. salary, capital)\nfixed handle" },
	{ "question": "固定費", "answers": [ "こていひ" ], "comment": "fixed cost" },
	{ "question": "固定資産", "answers": [ "こていしさん" ], "comment": "fixed assets" },
	{ "question": "固形", "answers": [ "こけい" ], "comment": "solid (body)" },
	{ "question": "固有", "answers": [ "こゆう" ], "comment": "characteristic; traditional; peculiar; inherent; native; eigen-" },
	{ "question": "国", "answers": [ "くに" ], "comment": "country; state\nregion\nnational government; central government\nhome (i.e. hometown, home country)\nprovince (of Japan)\nland; earth" },
	{ "question": "国々", "answers": [ "くにぐに" ], "comment": "countries" },
	{ "question": "国交", "answers": [ "こっこう" ], "comment": "diplomatic relations" },
	{ "question": "国人", "answers": [ "こくじん", "こくにん", "くにゅうど", "くにうど", "くにびと" ], "comment": "indigenous person; inhabitant of a country\nlocal; native\nlocal lords and samurai\ndaimyo who did not leave his domains to meet the shogun in Kyoto (during the Muromachi period)" },
	{ "question": "国会", "answers": [ "こっかい" ], "comment": "National Diet; legislative assembly of Japan (1947-)\nImperial Diet; legislative assembly of Japan (1889-1947)\nlegislative assembly; parliament; congress" },
	{ "question": "国会議事堂", "answers": [ "こっかいぎじどう" ], "comment": "national parliament or congress building (e.g. National Diet Building (Japan), United States Capitol (USA), Houses of Parliament (UK), etc.)" },
	{ "question": "国会議員", "answers": [ "こっかいぎいん" ], "comment": "member of National Diet; Diet member; member of parliament; MP" },
	{ "question": "国体", "answers": [ "こくたい" ], "comment": "national polity\nNational Athletic Meet" },
	{ "question": "国債", "answers": [ "こくさい" ], "comment": "national debt; national securities; government bonds; government securities" },
	{ "question": "国内", "answers": [ "こくない", "こくだい" ], "comment": "internal; domestic" },
	{ "question": "国内旅行", "answers": [ "こくないりょこう" ], "comment": "domestic travel" },
	{ "question": "国分寺", "answers": [ "こくぶんじ" ], "comment": "(Nara Era) state-supported provincial temples" },
	{ "question": "国力", "answers": [ "こくりょく" ], "comment": "national power" },
	{ "question": "国務", "answers": [ "こくむ" ], "comment": "affairs of state" },
	{ "question": "国務省", "answers": [ "こくむしょう" ], "comment": "State Department" },
	{ "question": "国務長官", "answers": [ "こくむちょうかん" ], "comment": "Secretary of State" },
	{ "question": "国勢", "answers": [ "こくせい" ], "comment": "state (condition, strength) of a country" },
	{ "question": "国勢調査", "answers": [ "こくせいちょうさ" ], "comment": "(national) census" },
	{ "question": "国名", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "country name" },
	{ "question": "国営", "answers": [ "こくえい" ], "comment": "government management; state management" },
	{ "question": "国土", "answers": [ "こくど" ], "comment": "country; territory; domain; realm" },
	{ "question": "国土庁", "answers": [ "こくどちょう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) National Land Agency" },
	{ "question": "国境", "answers": [ "こっきょう", "くにざかい" ], "comment": "national border; provincial border" },
	{ "question": "国士", "answers": [ "こくし" ], "comment": "distinguished citizen; patriot" },
	{ "question": "国外", "answers": [ "こくがい" ], "comment": "outside the country" },
	{ "question": "国大", "answers": [ "こくだい" ], "comment": "national university" },
	{ "question": "国学", "answers": [ "こくがく" ], "comment": "study of (ancient) Japanese literature and culture\nprovincial school (under Japan's ritsuryo system and pre-Sui Chinese law)" },
	{ "question": "国宝", "answers": [ "こくほう" ], "comment": "national treasure" },
	{ "question": "国家", "answers": [ "こっか" ], "comment": "state; country; nation" },
	{ "question": "国家公務員", "answers": [ "こっかこうむいん" ], "comment": "government official" },
	{ "question": "国家試験", "answers": [ "こっかしけん" ], "comment": "state examination" },
	{ "question": "国対", "answers": [ "こくたい" ], "comment": "Committee of the National Diet" },
	{ "question": "国庫", "answers": [ "こっこ" ], "comment": "national treasury" },
	{ "question": "国情", "answers": [ "こくじょう" ], "comment": "conditions of a country" },
	{ "question": "国技", "answers": [ "こくぎ" ], "comment": "national sport (e.g. sumo)" },
	{ "question": "国政", "answers": [ "こくせい" ], "comment": "national politics; political situation; statecraft; body politic" },
	{ "question": "国文学", "answers": [ "こくぶんがく" ], "comment": "Japanese literature" },
	{ "question": "国旗", "answers": [ "こっき" ], "comment": "national flag" },
	{ "question": "国是", "answers": [ "こくぜ" ], "comment": "national policy" },
	{ "question": "国有", "answers": [ "こくゆう" ], "comment": "national ownership" },
	{ "question": "国柄", "answers": [ "くにがら" ], "comment": "national character; regional character" },
	{ "question": "国権", "answers": [ "こっけん" ], "comment": "power of the state; national sovereignty; sovereign rights" },
	{ "question": "国歌", "answers": [ "こっか" ], "comment": "national anthem" },
	{ "question": "国民", "answers": [ "こくみん" ], "comment": "nation; nationality; people; citizen" },
	{ "question": "国民健康保険", "answers": [ "こくみんけんこうほけん" ], "comment": "national health insurance" },
	{ "question": "国民年金", "answers": [ "こくみんねんきん" ], "comment": "national pension; government pension system" },
	{ "question": "国民性", "answers": [ "こくみんせい" ], "comment": "national traits or character; nationality" },
	{ "question": "国民投票", "answers": [ "こくみんとうひょう" ], "comment": "national referendum" },
	{ "question": "国民的", "answers": [ "こくみんてき" ], "comment": "national" },
	{ "question": "国民総生産", "answers": [ "こくみんそうせいさん" ], "comment": "gross national product; GNP" },
	{ "question": "国王", "answers": [ "こくおう" ], "comment": "king" },
	{ "question": "国産", "answers": [ "こくさん" ], "comment": "domestic; domestically-produced; produced within a country" },
	{ "question": "国益", "answers": [ "こくえき" ], "comment": "national interest" },
	{ "question": "国税", "answers": [ "こくぜい" ], "comment": "national tax" },
	{ "question": "国税局", "answers": [ "こくぜいきょく" ], "comment": "revenue office; taxation bureau" },
	{ "question": "国税庁", "answers": [ "こくぜいちょう" ], "comment": "National Tax Agency (Japan); Internal Revenue Service (USA); IRS" },
	{ "question": "国立", "answers": [ "こくりつ" ], "comment": "national" },
	{ "question": "国立劇場", "answers": [ "こくりつげきじょう" ], "comment": "National Theater" },
	{ "question": "国立博物館", "answers": [ "こくりつはくぶつかん" ], "comment": "national museum" },
	{ "question": "国策", "answers": [ "こくさく" ], "comment": "national policy" },
	{ "question": "国籍", "answers": [ "こくせき" ], "comment": "nationality; citizenship\nnationality (ship, airplane, etc.); registration; flag" },
	{ "question": "国語", "answers": [ "こくご" ], "comment": "national language\nJapanese language (often as a school subject in Japan)\nnative Japanese words (as opposed to loanwords)" },
	{ "question": "国語辞典", "answers": [ "こくごじてん" ], "comment": "Japanese-language dictionary" },
	{ "question": "国論", "answers": [ "こくろん" ], "comment": "public opinion" },
	{ "question": "国費", "answers": [ "こくひ" ], "comment": "national expenditures" },
	{ "question": "国賓", "answers": [ "こくひん" ], "comment": "state guest" },
	{ "question": "国軍", "answers": [ "こくぐん" ], "comment": "national armed forces" },
	{ "question": "国連", "answers": [ "こくれん" ], "comment": "United Nations; UN" },
	{ "question": "国道", "answers": [ "こくどう" ], "comment": "national highway" },
	{ "question": "国鉄", "answers": [ "こくてつ" ], "comment": "national railway (esp. former Japan National Railways)" },
	{ "question": "国防", "answers": [ "こくぼう" ], "comment": "national defence; national defense" },
	{ "question": "国際", "answers": [ "こくさい" ], "comment": "international" },
	{ "question": "国際人", "answers": [ "こくさいじん" ], "comment": "internationally-minded person; cosmopolitan; citizen of the world\ninternational celebrity" },
	{ "question": "国際化", "answers": [ "こくさいか" ], "comment": "internationalization; internationalisation; i18n (in IT)" },
	{ "question": "国際協力事業団", "answers": [ "こくさいきょうりょくじぎょうだん" ], "comment": "Japan International Cooperation Agency (1974); JICA" },
	{ "question": "国際法", "answers": [ "こくさいほう" ], "comment": "international laws" },
	{ "question": "国際的", "answers": [ "こくさいてき" ], "comment": "international" },
	{ "question": "国際連合", "answers": [ "こくさいれんごう" ], "comment": "United Nations" },
	{ "question": "圏内", "answers": [ "けんない" ], "comment": "(being) within range (radio, commuting, etc.); (being) within the sphere (e.g. of influence)" },
	{ "question": "園", "answers": [ "えん", "その" ], "comment": "garden (esp. man-made); orchard; park; plantation\nplace; location" },
	{ "question": "園児", "answers": [ "えんじ" ], "comment": "kindergarten pupil; kindergartener" },
	{ "question": "園内", "answers": [ "えんない" ], "comment": "inside the garden (park)" },
	{ "question": "園芸", "answers": [ "えんげい" ], "comment": "horticulture; gardening" },
	{ "question": "園長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "head of a garden; kindergarten principal; nursery school principal; park director (botanical garden); zoo director (zoological garden); head of a plantation" },
	{ "question": "土", "answers": [ "つし", "つち" ], "comment": "earth; soil; dirt; clay; mud\nthe earth (historically, esp. as opposed to the heavens); the ground; the land\nlow-quality torinoko-gami (containing mud)\n(period of) refraining from construction in the direction of the god of the earth (in Onmyōdō)" },
	{ "question": "土俵", "answers": [ "どひょう" ], "comment": "(wrestling) ring\nforum (e.g. for discussion)\nsandbag; gabion" },
	{ "question": "土俵際", "answers": [ "どひょうぎわ" ], "comment": "edge of the ring\nverge; brink; critical moment; last moment" },
	{ "question": "土台", "answers": [ "どだい" ], "comment": "foundation; base; basis\nfrom the beginning; from the outset; by nature" },
	{ "question": "土器", "answers": [ "かわらけ", "どき" ], "comment": "earthenware\nunglazed (bisque-fired) earthenware" },
	{ "question": "土地", "answers": [ "とち" ], "comment": "plot of land; lot; soil\nlocality; region; place" },
	{ "question": "土地柄", "answers": [ "とちがら" ], "comment": "nature of the locality; character of a place; local colour; local color" },
	{ "question": "土壇場", "answers": [ "どたんば" ], "comment": "last moment; eleventh hour\nplatform made of dirt used to perform executions (decapitations) in the Edo period" },
	{ "question": "土壌", "answers": [ "どじょう" ], "comment": "soil\nbreeding ground; fertile ground (for); foundation (for the development of ...)" },
	{ "question": "土建屋", "answers": [ "どけんや" ], "comment": "general (civil engineering and construction) contractor" },
	{ "question": "土手", "answers": [ "どて" ], "comment": "embankment; bank\nbeef sinew stewed in miso and mirin" },
	{ "question": "土日", "answers": [ "どにち" ], "comment": "weekend; Saturday and Sunday" },
	{ "question": "土星", "answers": [ "どせい" ], "comment": "Saturn (planet)" },
	{ "question": "土曜", "answers": [ "どよう" ], "comment": "Saturday" },
	{ "question": "土曜日", "answers": [ "どようび" ], "comment": "Saturday" },
	{ "question": "土木", "answers": [ "どぼく" ], "comment": "engineering works; civil engineering; public works" },
	{ "question": "土産", "answers": [ "みやげ" ], "comment": "present; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "土石", "answers": [ "どせき" ], "comment": "earth and stones" },
	{ "question": "土砂", "answers": [ "どしゃ" ], "comment": "sediment; earth and sand" },
	{ "question": "土足", "answers": [ "どそく" ], "comment": "shod feet\nmuddy feet; dirty feet" },
	{ "question": "土間", "answers": [ "どま" ], "comment": "dirt floor; room with dirt floor\npit (theater seating); parterre" },
	{ "question": "圧倒", "answers": [ "あっとう" ], "comment": "overwhelm; overpower; overwhelming" },
	{ "question": "圧倒的", "answers": [ "あっとうてき" ], "comment": "overwhelming" },
	{ "question": "圧力", "answers": [ "あつりょく" ], "comment": "pressure; stress\ncoercion; arm-twisting" },
	{ "question": "圧勝", "answers": [ "あっしょう" ], "comment": "complete victory" },
	{ "question": "圧巻", "answers": [ "あっかん" ], "comment": "highlight; best part\nstunning; incredible; superb" },
	{ "question": "圧縮", "answers": [ "あっしゅく" ], "comment": "compression; condensation; constriction; compaction" },
	{ "question": "圧迫", "answers": [ "あっぱく" ], "comment": "pressure\noppression; suppression" },
	{ "question": "在りし日", "answers": [ "ありしひ" ], "comment": "past days; bygone days; days of yore; the olden days\nwhile still alive; during one's lifetime" },
	{ "question": "在京", "answers": [ "ざいきょう" ], "comment": "being in the capital (i.e. Tokyo, or formerly Kyoto)" },
	{ "question": "在任", "answers": [ "ざいにん" ], "comment": "being in office" },
	{ "question": "在住", "answers": [ "ざいじゅう" ], "comment": "residing; living; dwelling" },
	{ "question": "在外", "answers": [ "ざいがい" ], "comment": "overseas; abroad" },
	{ "question": "在外公館", "answers": [ "ざいがいこうかん" ], "comment": "diplomatic mission; government establishments overseas" },
	{ "question": "在学", "answers": [ "ざいがく" ], "comment": "(enrolled) in school" },
	{ "question": "在宅", "answers": [ "ざいたく" ], "comment": "being in; being at home" },
	{ "question": "在庫", "answers": [ "ざいこ" ], "comment": "inventory; stock; stockpile" },
	{ "question": "在日", "answers": [ "ざいにち" ], "comment": "in Japan\nKorean living in Japan\n(foreign) person living or staying in Japan" },
	{ "question": "在来", "answers": [ "ざいらい" ], "comment": "pre-existing; already there; conventional" },
	{ "question": "在留", "answers": [ "ざいりゅう" ], "comment": "residing (esp. abroad); staying; living" },
	{ "question": "在籍", "answers": [ "ざいせき" ], "comment": "enrollment; enrolment" },
	{ "question": "在米", "answers": [ "ざいべい" ], "comment": "being in the USA" },
	{ "question": "在職", "answers": [ "ざいしょく" ], "comment": "being in office" },
	{ "question": "在野", "answers": [ "ざいや" ], "comment": "out of office; out of power; in opposition\nunaffiliated (e.g. researcher, scientist); in private practice" },
	{ "question": "地", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "earth; ground; land; soil\nplace\nterritory\nbottom (of a package, book, etc.)\nearth (one of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "地上", "answers": [ "ちじょう" ], "comment": "above ground; surface\nearth; world" },
	{ "question": "地下", "answers": [ "ちか" ], "comment": "basement; cellar; underground place\nunderground; below ground\nsecret; under cover\nunderground (railway); subway; metro" },
	{ "question": "地下室", "answers": [ "ちかしつ" ], "comment": "cellar; basement" },
	{ "question": "地下水", "answers": [ "ちかすい" ], "comment": "underground water" },
	{ "question": "地下道", "answers": [ "ちかどう" ], "comment": "subterranean tunnel" },
	{ "question": "地下鉄", "answers": [ "ちかてつ" ], "comment": "underground train; subway" },
	{ "question": "地中", "answers": [ "ちちゅう" ], "comment": "underground; subterranean" },
	{ "question": "地中海", "answers": [ "ちちゅうかい" ], "comment": "Mediterranean Sea" },
	{ "question": "地主", "answers": [ "じぬし" ], "comment": "landlord; landowner" },
	{ "question": "地位", "answers": [ "ちい" ], "comment": "(social) position; status" },
	{ "question": "地価", "answers": [ "ちか" ], "comment": "the price of land" },
	{ "question": "地元", "answers": [ "じもと" ], "comment": "home area; home town\nlocal" },
	{ "question": "地力", "answers": [ "じりき" ], "comment": "one's own potential; real ability; one's own strength" },
	{ "question": "地区", "answers": [ "ちく" ], "comment": "district; section; sector" },
	{ "question": "地合い", "answers": [ "じあい" ], "comment": "texture (cloth, fabric, paper)\nmarket tone; undertone\nbalance between the position of white and black stones (in go)" },
	{ "question": "地名", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "place name" },
	{ "question": "地味", "answers": [ "じみ" ], "comment": "plain; simple; subdued; sober" },
	{ "question": "地図", "answers": [ "ちず" ], "comment": "map" },
	{ "question": "地域", "answers": [ "ちいき" ], "comment": "area; region" },
	{ "question": "地域社会", "answers": [ "ちいきしゃかい" ], "comment": "regional community" },
	{ "question": "地層", "answers": [ "ちそう" ], "comment": "stratum; geological formation; layer; bed (coal, gravel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "地帯", "answers": [ "ちたい" ], "comment": "area; zone; belt (of land)" },
	{ "question": "地平線", "answers": [ "ちへいせん" ], "comment": "horizon (related to land)" },
	{ "question": "地形", "answers": [ "ちけい", "じぎょう" ], "comment": "terrain; geographical features; topography" },
	{ "question": "地方", "answers": [ "ちほう" ], "comment": "district; region; area; locality\nthe country; countryside; the provinces; rural area" },
	{ "question": "地方公共団体", "answers": [ "ちほうこうきょうだんたい" ], "comment": "local public body" },
	{ "question": "地方公務員", "answers": [ "ちほうこうむいん" ], "comment": "local government employee" },
	{ "question": "地方分権", "answers": [ "ちほうぶんけん" ], "comment": "decentralization of power; decentralisation of power" },
	{ "question": "地方税", "answers": [ "ちほうぜい" ], "comment": "local tax; council tax" },
	{ "question": "地方自治", "answers": [ "ちほうじち" ], "comment": "local (governmental) autonomy" },
	{ "question": "地方自治体", "answers": [ "ちほうじちたい" ], "comment": "local authority; local government; locality; local self-governing body; municipality" },
	{ "question": "地方行政", "answers": [ "ちほうぎょうせい" ], "comment": "local administration" },
	{ "question": "地方議会", "answers": [ "ちほうぎかい" ], "comment": "local assembly" },
	{ "question": "地検", "answers": [ "ちけん" ], "comment": "District Public Prosecutor's Office" },
	{ "question": "地殻変動", "answers": [ "ちかくへんどう" ], "comment": "change in earth's crust" },
	{ "question": "地点", "answers": [ "ちてん" ], "comment": "site; point on a map; spot" },
	{ "question": "地獄", "answers": [ "じごく" ], "comment": "hell" },
	{ "question": "地球", "answers": [ "ちきゅう" ], "comment": "the earth; the globe" },
	{ "question": "地球上", "answers": [ "ちきゅうじょう" ], "comment": "on the earth" },
	{ "question": "地理", "answers": [ "ちり" ], "comment": "geography" },
	{ "question": "地理情報システム", "answers": [ "ちりじょうほうシステム" ], "comment": "geographic information system; GIS" },
	{ "question": "地盤", "answers": [ "じばん", "ちばん" ], "comment": "ground; crust (earth); bed (gravel, river, etc.)\nfoundation (building, etc.); base\nconstituency; power base; support (electoral); footing; foothold" },
	{ "question": "地蔵", "answers": [ "じぞう" ], "comment": "Kshitigarbha (bodhisattva who looks over children, travellers and the underworld) (travelers); Ksitigarbha; Jizo" },
	{ "question": "地表", "answers": [ "ちひょう" ], "comment": "surface of the earth; ground surface" },
	{ "question": "地裁", "answers": [ "ちさい" ], "comment": "district court" },
	{ "question": "地質", "answers": [ "ちしつ" ], "comment": "geological features" },
	{ "question": "地道", "answers": [ "じみち" ], "comment": "steady; honest; sober; straightforward" },
	{ "question": "地雷", "answers": [ "じらい" ], "comment": "land mine; booby trap\ntopic that sets one off (esp. based on previous experience); sensitive topic; taboo topic" },
	{ "question": "地震", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "earthquake" },
	{ "question": "地面", "answers": [ "じめん" ], "comment": "ground; earth's surface" },
	{ "question": "坂", "answers": [ "さか" ], "comment": "slope; hill" },
	{ "question": "坂道", "answers": [ "さかみち" ], "comment": "hill road" },
	{ "question": "均一", "answers": [ "きんいつ", "きんいち" ], "comment": "uniformity; equality" },
	{ "question": "均整", "answers": [ "きんせい" ], "comment": "symmetry; balance; proportion; uniformity" },
	{ "question": "均斉", "answers": [ "きんせい" ], "comment": "symmetry; balance; proportion; uniformity" },
	{ "question": "均等", "answers": [ "きんとう" ], "comment": "equality; uniformity; evenness" },
	{ "question": "均衡", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "equilibrium; balance" },
	{ "question": "坊さん", "answers": [ "ぼうさん" ], "comment": "Buddhist priest; monk\nboy" },
	{ "question": "坊ちゃん", "answers": [ "ぼっちゃん" ], "comment": "son (of others)\nyoung master\ngreen young man from a well-to-do family" },
	{ "question": "坊っちゃん", "answers": [ "ぼっちゃん" ], "comment": "son (of others)\nyoung master\ngreen young man from a well-to-do family" },
	{ "question": "坊主", "answers": [ "ぼうず" ], "comment": "Buddhist priest; bonze\nclose-cropped hair; crew cut; person with a shorn head\nboy; sonny; lad\nnot catching anything (in fishing)" },
	{ "question": "坪", "answers": [ "つぼ" ], "comment": "unit of land measurement; 3.95 square yards; 3.31 square meters" },
	{ "question": "垂らす", "answers": [ "たらす" ], "comment": "to dribble; to spill\nto suspend; to hang down; to slouch; to dangle" },
	{ "question": "垂れる", "answers": [ "たれる" ], "comment": "to hang; to droop; to dangle; to sag; to lower; to pull down\nto leave behind (at death); to give; to confer\nto drip; to ooze; to trickle; to drop" },
	{ "question": "垂れ幕", "answers": [ "たれまく" ], "comment": "hanging banner; hanging screen; curtain" },
	{ "question": "垂直", "answers": [ "すいちょく" ], "comment": "vertical\nperpendicular" },
	{ "question": "型", "answers": [ "がた", "かた" ], "comment": "model; type (e.g. of machine, goods, etc.)\ntype; style; pattern\nmold (mould); template; model\nkata (standard form of a movement, posture, etc. in martial arts, sport, etc.)\nform (i.e. customary procedure)\nsize (i.e. clothing, shoes)\n(taxonomical) form" },
	{ "question": "型式", "answers": [ "かたしき", "けいしき" ], "comment": "model (e.g. of a vehicle); type" },
	{ "question": "垢", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "dirt; filth; grime\naccount (e.g. online service)" },
	{ "question": "垣", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "fence; hedge; barrier; wall; railing" },
	{ "question": "垣根", "answers": [ "かきね" ], "comment": "hedge; fence" },
	{ "question": "埋まる", "answers": [ "うまる", "うずまる" ], "comment": "to be buried; to be covered; to be surrounded\nto overflow; to be crowded; to be filled\nto be repaid (e.g. debt); to be replenished" },
	{ "question": "埋める", "answers": [ "うめる", "うずめる" ], "comment": "to cover; to bury (e.g. one's face in hands); to submerge\nto fill (completely); to stuff; to pack; to cram; to fill up /\n to bury (e.g. in the ground)\nto fill up (e.g. audience fills a hall); to cause to be packed\nto plug (a gap); to stop (a gap); to bridge (a difference, a gap); to fill (a seat, a vacant position); to fill out\nto make up for (a loss, shortage, etc.); to make amends; to compensate for\nto put cold water (in a bath)\nto cover; to scatter something over" },
	{ "question": "埋め立て", "answers": [ "うめたて" ], "comment": "land reclamation" },
	{ "question": "埋め立て地", "answers": [ "うめたてち" ], "comment": "reclaimed land" },
	{ "question": "埋葬", "answers": [ "まいそう" ], "comment": "burial" },
	{ "question": "埋蔵", "answers": [ "まいぞう" ], "comment": "burying in the ground\nhaving underground deposits" },
	{ "question": "城", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "castle" },
	{ "question": "城内", "answers": [ "じょうない" ], "comment": "inside of a castle\narea surrounded by castle walls" },
	{ "question": "域内", "answers": [ "いきない" ], "comment": "inside the area" },
	{ "question": "域外", "answers": [ "いきがい" ], "comment": "outside the area" },
	{ "question": "執る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take (trouble); to attend (to business); to command (army)" },
	{ "question": "執務", "answers": [ "しつむ" ], "comment": "performance of one's official duties" },
	{ "question": "執念", "answers": [ "しゅうねん" ], "comment": "tenacity; persistence; obsession; implacability" },
	{ "question": "執着", "answers": [ "しゅうじゃく", "しゅうちゃく" ], "comment": "attachment; adhesion; tenacity; fixation; obsession" },
	{ "question": "執筆", "answers": [ "しっぴつ" ], "comment": "writing (e.g. as a profession)" },
	{ "question": "執行", "answers": [ "しぎょう", "しっこう", "しゅぎょう", "しゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "execution; carrying out; performance; enforcement; exercise; service\nlead monk performing various tasks in a temple" },
	{ "question": "執行委員", "answers": [ "しっこういいん" ], "comment": "executive committee" },
	{ "question": "執行猶予", "answers": [ "しっこうゆうよ" ], "comment": "stay of execution; suspended sentence" },
	{ "question": "執行部", "answers": [ "しっこうぶ" ], "comment": "executive; executives" },
	{ "question": "培養", "answers": [ "ばいよう" ], "comment": "cultivation; nurture; culture" },
	{ "question": "基づく", "answers": [ "もとづく" ], "comment": "to be grounded on; to be based on; to be due to; to originate from" },
	{ "question": "基地", "answers": [ "きち" ], "comment": "base (military, expedition, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "基幹", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "mainstay; nucleus; key" },
	{ "question": "基本", "answers": [ "きほん" ], "comment": "foundation; basis; standard" },
	{ "question": "基本料金", "answers": [ "きほんりょうきん" ], "comment": "basic rate (i.e. excluding optional service fees, usage charges, etc.); basic charge; base cost; base price" },
	{ "question": "基本的", "answers": [ "きほんてき" ], "comment": "fundamental; standard; basic" },
	{ "question": "基準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; basis; criterion; norm; reference; datum" },
	{ "question": "基準法", "answers": [ "きじゅんほう" ], "comment": "basic law" },
	{ "question": "基盤", "answers": [ "きばん" ], "comment": "foundation; basis; base; footing; infrastructure\nbedrock\nsubstrate (circuit board)" },
	{ "question": "基礎", "answers": [ "きそ" ], "comment": "foundation; basis" },
	{ "question": "基調", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "basic tone; underlying tone; basic theme; basis; keynote\ntrend\nkeynote" },
	{ "question": "基軸", "answers": [ "きじく" ], "comment": "key; yardstick; criterion; standard" },
	{ "question": "基金", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "fund; foundation" },
	{ "question": "堀", "answers": [ "ほり" ], "comment": "moat; fosse\ncanal; ditch" },
	{ "question": "堀川", "answers": [ "ほりかわ" ], "comment": "canal" },
	{ "question": "堀江", "answers": [ "ほりえ" ], "comment": "canal" },
	{ "question": "堂", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "temple; shrine; chapel\nhall\nsuffix attached to the names of some businesses, stores, etc.\n(arch) front room" },
	{ "question": "堂々", "answers": [ "どうどう" ], "comment": "magnificent; grand; impressive; dignified; majestic; imposing; stately\nfair; square; open; unashamed; brazen\ngrandly; boldly; confidently\nfairly; squarely; unreservedly; brazenly" },
	{ "question": "堅い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "hard; solid; tough\nstiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing)\nstrong; firm (not viscous or easily moved)\nsafe; steady; honest; steadfast\nobstinate; stubborn\nbookish; formal; stuffy" },
	{ "question": "堅さ", "answers": [ "かたさ" ], "comment": "firmness; hardness; stiffness; honesty" },
	{ "question": "堅実", "answers": [ "けんじつ" ], "comment": "steady; sound; reliable; solid" },
	{ "question": "堅持", "answers": [ "けんじ" ], "comment": "holding on to; sticking to" },
	{ "question": "堅調", "answers": [ "けんちょう" ], "comment": "bullish; firm (market)" },
	{ "question": "堆積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "accumulation; pile; heap\nsedimentation" },
	{ "question": "堕落", "answers": [ "だらく" ], "comment": "depravity; corruption; degradation" },
	{ "question": "堤", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "bank; embankment; dike" },
	{ "question": "堤防", "answers": [ "ていぼう" ], "comment": "bank; weir; embankment; levee" },
	{ "question": "堪える", "answers": [ "たえる", "こらえる", "こたえる" ], "comment": "to bear; to stand; to endure; to put up with\nto support; to withstand; to resist; to brave\nto be fit for; to be equal to" },
	{ "question": "堪能", "answers": [ "たんのう" ], "comment": "proficient; skillful\nenjoying; satisfaction; satiation; having one's fill (of)" },
	{ "question": "堰", "answers": [ "いせき", "せき" ], "comment": "dam; weir; barrier; sluice" },
	{ "question": "報", "answers": [ "ほう" ], "comment": "information; news; report" },
	{ "question": "報いる", "answers": [ "むくいる" ], "comment": "to reward; to recompense; to repay\nto retaliate; to get revenge" },
	{ "question": "報う", "answers": [ "むくう" ], "comment": "to reward; to recompense; to repay" },
	{ "question": "報じる", "answers": [ "ほうじる" ], "comment": "to inform; to report" },
	{ "question": "報告", "answers": [ "ほうこく" ], "comment": "report; information" },
	{ "question": "報告書", "answers": [ "ほうこくしょ" ], "comment": "(written) report" },
	{ "question": "報奨金", "answers": [ "ほうしょうきん" ], "comment": "cash bonus; reward; bounty" },
	{ "question": "報復", "answers": [ "ほうふく" ], "comment": "retaliation; revenge; reprisal; retribution\nretorsion; retortion" },
	{ "question": "報道", "answers": [ "ほうどう" ], "comment": "information; report; journalism; news\nto report" },
	{ "question": "報道機関", "answers": [ "ほうどうきかん" ], "comment": "information media; press; news organs" },
	{ "question": "報道陣", "answers": [ "ほうどうじん" ], "comment": "press corps" },
	{ "question": "報酬", "answers": [ "ほうしゅう" ], "comment": "remuneration; recompense; reward; toll" },
	{ "question": "場", "answers": [ "ば" ], "comment": "place; spot; space\nfield; discipline; sphere; realm\noccasion; situation\nscene (of a play, movie, etc.)\nsession (of the stock market)\narea in which cards are laid out (in a card game)\nround (i.e. east, south, etc.)\nfield\nfield (gestalt psychology)" },
	{ "question": "場内", "answers": [ "じょうない" ], "comment": "in-house; (on) the grounds; (in) the premises; hall; theatre; theater" },
	{ "question": "場合", "answers": [ "ばあい" ], "comment": "case; situation" },
	{ "question": "場外", "answers": [ "じょうがい" ], "comment": "outside the hall (or stadium, market, etc.); off the grounds; off the premises; off-track" },
	{ "question": "場所", "answers": [ "ばしょ" ], "comment": "place; location; spot; position\nroom; space\nbasho; wrestling tournament" },
	{ "question": "場違い", "answers": [ "ばちがい" ], "comment": "out-of-place; inappropriate; sticking out like a sore thumb" },
	{ "question": "場面", "answers": [ "ばめん" ], "comment": "scene; setting (e.g. of novel)" },
	{ "question": "塀", "answers": [ "へい" ], "comment": "wall\nfence" },
	{ "question": "塁", "answers": [ "るい" ], "comment": "base; bag; sack\nfortress; stronghold" },
	{ "question": "塊", "answers": [ "かたまり" ], "comment": "lump; mass; bundle; clump; clod; cluster\ngroup; crowd\nembodiment (of an idea, quality, feeling etc.); personification" },
	{ "question": "塔", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "tower; steeple; spire\nstupa; pagoda; dagoba" },
	{ "question": "塗り替える", "answers": [ "ぬりかえる" ], "comment": "to repaint; to paint again\nto break (a record); to rewrite; to remake" },
	{ "question": "塗る", "answers": [ "ぬる" ], "comment": "to paint; to plaster; to lacquer; to varnish; to spread; to smear; to put up (wallpaper)" },
	{ "question": "塗料", "answers": [ "とりょう" ], "comment": "paints; painting material" },
	{ "question": "塗装", "answers": [ "とそう" ], "comment": "coating; painting" },
	{ "question": "塚", "answers": [ "つか" ], "comment": "mound; heap; hillock\nburial mound; tomb; tumulus; barrow" },
	{ "question": "塞ぐ", "answers": [ "ふさぐ" ], "comment": "to stop up; to close up; to block (up); to plug up; to shut up; to cover (ears, eyes, etc.); to close (eyes, mouth)\nto stand in the way; to obstruct\nto occupy; to fill up; to take up\nto perform one's role; to do one's duty\nto feel depressed; to mope" },
	{ "question": "塩", "answers": [ "えん", "しお" ], "comment": "salt (i.e. sodium chloride); common salt; table salt\nsalt (e.g. sodium chloride, calcium sulfate, etc.)\nhardship; toil; trouble\nsaltiness" },
	{ "question": "塩分", "answers": [ "えんぶん" ], "comment": "salt; salt content" },
	{ "question": "塩化", "answers": [ "えんか" ], "comment": "chloride" },
	{ "question": "塩味", "answers": [ "しおあじ" ], "comment": "salty taste; saltiness" },
	{ "question": "塩基", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "base" },
	{ "question": "塩梅", "answers": [ "あんばい" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavour; flavor\ncondition; state; situation\narrangement; assignment; adjustment" },
	{ "question": "塩水", "answers": [ "しおみず", "えんすい" ], "comment": "salt water; brine" },
	{ "question": "塩田", "answers": [ "えんでん" ], "comment": "saltpan; field for drying salt" },
	{ "question": "塩素", "answers": [ "えんそ" ], "comment": "chlorine (Cl)" },
	{ "question": "塩辛い", "answers": [ "しおからい", "からい" ], "comment": "salty (taste); briny" },
	{ "question": "塵", "answers": [ "ちり" ], "comment": "dust; dirt" },
	{ "question": "塾", "answers": [ "じゅく" ], "comment": "coaching school; cramming school; juku" },
	{ "question": "塾長", "answers": [ "じゅくちょう" ], "comment": "principal of a private school" },
	{ "question": "境", "answers": [ "さかい", "きょう" ], "comment": "border; boundary\nturning point; watershed\narea; region; spot; space; environment\npsychological state; mental state\ncognitive object; something perceptible by the sense organs or mind" },
	{ "question": "境内", "answers": [ "けいだい" ], "comment": "grounds (esp. of shrines and temples); compound; churchyard; precincts" },
	{ "question": "境地", "answers": [ "きょうち" ], "comment": "state (of mind); mental state; emotional condition\nfield (of activity)\none's lot; circumstance; situation in life\nplace; region; area; land" },
	{ "question": "境界", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "boundary" },
	{ "question": "境遇", "answers": [ "きょうぐう" ], "comment": "environment; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "墓", "answers": [ "はか" ], "comment": "gravesite; tomb" },
	{ "question": "墓参", "answers": [ "ぼさん", "はかまいり" ], "comment": "visit to a grave" },
	{ "question": "墓参り", "answers": [ "はかまいり" ], "comment": "visit to a grave" },
	{ "question": "墓地", "answers": [ "はかち", "ぼち" ], "comment": "cemetery; graveyard" },
	{ "question": "墓石", "answers": [ "はかいし", "ぼせき" ], "comment": "tombstone; gravestone" },
	{ "question": "増える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "増す", "answers": [ "ます" ], "comment": "to increase; to grow" },
	{ "question": "増やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "to increase; to add to; to augment" },
	{ "question": "増加", "answers": [ "ぞうか" ], "comment": "increase; rise; growth; addition; increment" },
	{ "question": "増収", "answers": [ "ぞうしゅう" ], "comment": "increase in yield" },
	{ "question": "増員", "answers": [ "ぞういん" ], "comment": "increase the number of personnel" },
	{ "question": "増大", "answers": [ "ぞうだい" ], "comment": "enlargement; increase" },
	{ "question": "増強", "answers": [ "ぞうきょう" ], "comment": "augment; reinforce; increase" },
	{ "question": "増殖", "answers": [ "ぞうしょく" ], "comment": "increase; multiplication; propagation; proliferation" },
	{ "question": "増水", "answers": [ "ぞうすい" ], "comment": "rising water (of river, lake, etc.); swelling water; increased water; high water" },
	{ "question": "増減", "answers": [ "ぞうげん" ], "comment": "increase and decrease; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "増産", "answers": [ "ぞうさん" ], "comment": "production increase" },
	{ "question": "増発", "answers": [ "ぞうはつ" ], "comment": "increase the number of trains in operation; increase bond issues" },
	{ "question": "増益", "answers": [ "ぞうえき" ], "comment": "increased (profit)" },
	{ "question": "増税", "answers": [ "ぞうぜい" ], "comment": "tax increase" },
	{ "question": "増設", "answers": [ "ぞうせつ" ], "comment": "extension; expansion; adding (equipment, facilities, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "増資", "answers": [ "ぞうし" ], "comment": "increase of capital" },
	{ "question": "増進", "answers": [ "ぞうしん" ], "comment": "promoting; increase; advance" },
	{ "question": "増額", "answers": [ "ぞうがく" ], "comment": "increased amount" },
	{ "question": "墜落", "answers": [ "ついらく" ], "comment": "falling; crashing" },
	{ "question": "墨", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "sumi; India ink; Chinese ink; ink stick; ink-cake\nsquid ink; octopus ink\ncarpenter's inking string" },
	{ "question": "墨付き", "answers": [ "すみつき" ], "comment": "handwriting; autograph; authorization; authorisation\ncertificate; certified document; paper with signature of the shogun or lord" },
	{ "question": "壁", "answers": [ "かべ", "へき" ], "comment": "wall; partition\nbarrier; obstacle\nChinese \"Wall\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "壁画", "answers": [ "へきが" ], "comment": "fresco; mural; wall painting" },
	{ "question": "壁面", "answers": [ "へきめん" ], "comment": "surface of a wall" },
	{ "question": "壇", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "platform; podium; rostrum\nmandala" },
	{ "question": "壇上", "answers": [ "だんじょう" ], "comment": "on a stage; on a platform; on an altar" },
	{ "question": "壊す", "answers": [ "こわす" ], "comment": "to break; to destroy; to demolish\nto wreck; to ruin; to spoil; to damage\nto break (a bill, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "壊れる", "answers": [ "こわれる" ], "comment": "to be broken; to break\nto fall through; to come to nothing" },
	{ "question": "壊滅", "answers": [ "かいめつ" ], "comment": "destruction; annihilation; devastation; catastrophe" },
	{ "question": "壕", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "moat; fosse; trench; ditch\nunderground air-raid shelter; dugout" },
	{ "question": "士官", "answers": [ "しかん" ], "comment": "officer" },
	{ "question": "士気", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "morale (of troops, team, etc.); esprit de corps" },
	{ "question": "壮大", "answers": [ "そうだい" ], "comment": "magnificent; grand; majestic; splendid" },
	{ "question": "壮年", "answers": [ "そうねん" ], "comment": "prime of life" },
	{ "question": "壮行", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "rousing" },
	{ "question": "声", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "voice" },
	{ "question": "声援", "answers": [ "せいえん" ], "comment": "encouragement; cheering; support" },
	{ "question": "声明", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "declaration; statement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "声楽", "answers": [ "せいがく" ], "comment": "vocal music" },
	{ "question": "声高", "answers": [ "こわだか" ], "comment": "with a loud voice" },
	{ "question": "売り", "answers": [ "うり" ], "comment": "sale; selling\nselling point; gimmick\nseller; vendor" },
	{ "question": "売り上げ", "answers": [ "うりあげ" ], "comment": "amount sold; sales; proceeds; takings; turnover" },
	{ "question": "売り出し", "answers": [ "うりだし" ], "comment": "(bargain) sale" },
	{ "question": "売り出す", "answers": [ "うりだす" ], "comment": "to put on the market; to put out for sale; to put on sale; to begin selling; to market\nto become popular" },
	{ "question": "売り切れ", "answers": [ "うりきれ" ], "comment": "sold-out" },
	{ "question": "売り切れる", "answers": [ "うりきれる" ], "comment": "to be sold out" },
	{ "question": "売り場", "answers": [ "うりば" ], "comment": "place where things are sold; point of sale; POS; sales floor; counter (in shop)\nfavorable time to sell; good time to sell" },
	{ "question": "売り手", "answers": [ "うりて" ], "comment": "seller; vendor" },
	{ "question": "売り物", "answers": [ "うりもの" ], "comment": "article for sale; goods for sale; offering; For Sale (on a sign)\nspecialty; selling point" },
	{ "question": "売り込み", "answers": [ "うりこみ" ], "comment": "sales promotion; hard selling" },
	{ "question": "売り込む", "answers": [ "うりこむ" ], "comment": "to build a market for; to promote (a product); to sell; to become well known\nto promote oneself; to sell oneself\nto sell heavily" },
	{ "question": "売る", "answers": [ "うる" ], "comment": "to sell" },
	{ "question": "売れる", "answers": [ "うれる" ], "comment": "to sell (well)\nto be well known; to be popular; to be famous" },
	{ "question": "売れ行き", "answers": [ "うれゆき" ], "comment": "sales; demand" },
	{ "question": "売上", "answers": [ "うりあげ" ], "comment": "amount sold; sales; proceeds; takings; turnover" },
	{ "question": "売上金", "answers": [ "うりあげきん" ], "comment": "proceeds" },
	{ "question": "売上高", "answers": [ "うりあげだか" ], "comment": "sales; amount sold; proceeds" },
	{ "question": "売却", "answers": [ "ばいきゃく" ], "comment": "selling off; disposal by sale; sale" },
	{ "question": "売店", "answers": [ "ばいてん" ], "comment": "shop; stand" },
	{ "question": "売春", "answers": [ "ばいしゅん" ], "comment": "prostitution" },
	{ "question": "売春婦", "answers": [ "ばいしゅんぷ", "ばいしゅんふ" ], "comment": "prostitute" },
	{ "question": "売買", "answers": [ "ばいばい" ], "comment": "trade; buying and selling; trafficking (e.g. of humans, arms, drugs); dealing" },
	{ "question": "変", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "strange; odd; peculiar; weird; curious; queer; eccentric; funny; suspicious; fishy\nunexpected\nchange\nincident; disturbance; disaster; accident\nflat" },
	{ "question": "変える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to change; to alter; to transform; to convert; to turn; to vary\nto reform; to revise; to amend" },
	{ "question": "変わった", "answers": [ "かわった" ], "comment": "another; different; various; particular; unusual; novel; peculiar" },
	{ "question": "変わらない", "answers": [ "かわらない" ], "comment": "constant; invariant" },
	{ "question": "変わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "change; alteration\nunusual state or event; accident; abnormality\ndifference; distinction" },
	{ "question": "変わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to change; to be transformed; to be altered; to vary\nto move to\nto be different; to be uncommon; to be unusual" },
	{ "question": "変則", "answers": [ "へんそく" ], "comment": "irregularity" },
	{ "question": "変動", "answers": [ "へんどう" ], "comment": "change; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "変化", "answers": [ "へんか" ], "comment": "change; variation; alteration; mutation; transition; transformation; transfiguration; metamorphosis\nvariety; diversity\ninflection; declension; conjugation\nsidestepping" },
	{ "question": "変化球", "answers": [ "へんかきゅう" ], "comment": "breaking ball (pitch); curve ball; screwball" },
	{ "question": "変容", "answers": [ "へんよう" ], "comment": "change in appearance; transformation" },
	{ "question": "変形", "answers": [ "へんけい" ], "comment": "transformation; variation; metamorphosis; modification; deformation; variety; deformity; monster" },
	{ "question": "変換", "answers": [ "へんかん" ], "comment": "change; conversion; transformation; translation" },
	{ "question": "変更", "answers": [ "へんこう" ], "comment": "change; modification; alteration; revision; amendment" },
	{ "question": "変更届", "answers": [ "へんこうとどけ" ], "comment": "notification of change; alteration report; registration of modification" },
	{ "question": "変移", "answers": [ "へんい" ], "comment": "change; alteration; transmutation; mutation" },
	{ "question": "変貌", "answers": [ "へんぼう" ], "comment": "transfiguration; transformation; change of appearance" },
	{ "question": "変質", "answers": [ "へんしつ" ], "comment": "alteration (of character or essence); change in quality; transformation; deterioration; degeneration; transmutation" },
	{ "question": "変身", "answers": [ "へんしん" ], "comment": "metamorphosis; disguise; transformation; shapeshifting; morphing" },
	{ "question": "変造", "answers": [ "へんぞう" ], "comment": "alteration; defacement; debasement; falsification; forgery" },
	{ "question": "変遷", "answers": [ "へんせん" ], "comment": "change; transition; vicissitudes" },
	{ "question": "変革", "answers": [ "へんかく" ], "comment": "change; transformation; innovation; reform; revolution; revolutionizing; upheaval\nReformation" },
	{ "question": "夏", "answers": [ "なつ" ], "comment": "summer" },
	{ "question": "夏ばて", "answers": [ "なつばて", "なつバテ" ], "comment": "suffering from summer heat; summer heat fatigue" },
	{ "question": "夏休み", "answers": [ "なつやすみ" ], "comment": "summer vacation; summer holiday" },
	{ "question": "夏場", "answers": [ "なつば" ], "comment": "summertime" },
	{ "question": "夏場所", "answers": [ "なつばしょ" ], "comment": "summer (May) tournament, held in Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "夏季", "answers": [ "なつき", "かき" ], "comment": "summer season" },
	{ "question": "夏時間", "answers": [ "なつじかん" ], "comment": "daylight saving time; summer time" },
	{ "question": "夏期", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "summer term (e.g. school); summer period" },
	{ "question": "夏至", "answers": [ "げし" ], "comment": "summer solstice" },
	{ "question": "夕", "answers": [ "ゆう", "ゆうべ", "さくや" ], "comment": "evening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "夕べ", "answers": [ "ゆう", "ゆうべ", "さくや" ], "comment": "evening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "夕刊", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "evening paper" },
	{ "question": "夕刻", "answers": [ "ゆうこく" ], "comment": "evening; evening hour" },
	{ "question": "夕方", "answers": [ "ゆうがた" ], "comment": "evening; dusk" },
	{ "question": "夕日", "answers": [ "ゆうひ", "せきじつ", "せきよう" ], "comment": "evening sun; setting sun" },
	{ "question": "夕暮れ", "answers": [ "ゆうぐれ" ], "comment": "evening; dusk; twilight" },
	{ "question": "夕焼け", "answers": [ "ゆうやけ" ], "comment": "evening glow; red sunset; afterglow (of sunset)" },
	{ "question": "夕立", "answers": [ "ゆうだち" ], "comment": "(sudden) evening shower (rain)" },
	{ "question": "夕食", "answers": [ "ゆうしょく" ], "comment": "evening meal; dinner" },
	{ "question": "夕飯", "answers": [ "ゆうめし", "ゆうはん" ], "comment": "evening meal" },
	{ "question": "外", "answers": [ "がい", "そと" ], "comment": "outside; exterior\nopen air\nother place /\n outside of; not covered by" },
	{ "question": "外す", "answers": [ "はずす" ], "comment": "to unfasten; to undo\nto remove; to take off; to deinstall\nto leave; to step out; to slip away\nto miss (a target)" },
	{ "question": "外に", "answers": [ "ほかに" ], "comment": "in addition; besides" },
	{ "question": "外れ", "answers": [ "はずれ" ], "comment": "end; verge; extremity; tip; outskirts\nmiss; failure" },
	{ "question": "外れる", "answers": [ "はずれる" ], "comment": "to be disconnected; to get out of place; to be off; to be out (e.g. of gear)" },
	{ "question": "外交", "answers": [ "がいこう" ], "comment": "diplomacy\nselling (e.g. door-to-door); canvassing" },
	{ "question": "外交官", "answers": [ "がいこうかん" ], "comment": "diplomat" },
	{ "question": "外人", "answers": [ "がいじん" ], "comment": "foreigner (esp. one of European ancestry); gaijin\noutsider" },
	{ "question": "外付", "answers": [ "そとづけ" ], "comment": "external (hard drive, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外付け", "answers": [ "そとづけ" ], "comment": "external (hard drive, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外信", "answers": [ "がいしん" ], "comment": "external communication" },
	{ "question": "外側", "answers": [ "そとがわ", "がいそく" ], "comment": "exterior; outside; outer; external; lateral" },
	{ "question": "外傷", "answers": [ "がいしょう" ], "comment": "external wound; (physical) trauma" },
	{ "question": "外出", "answers": [ "がいしゅつ" ], "comment": "going out; outing; leaving (one's home, office, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外務", "answers": [ "がいむ" ], "comment": "foreign affairs" },
	{ "question": "外務省", "answers": [ "がいむしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs" },
	{ "question": "外国", "answers": [ "がいこく" ], "comment": "foreign country" },
	{ "question": "外国人", "answers": [ "がいこくじん" ], "comment": "foreigner; foreign citizen; foreign national; alien; non-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "外国語", "answers": [ "がいこくご" ], "comment": "foreign language" },
	{ "question": "外圧", "answers": [ "がいあつ" ], "comment": "external pressure" },
	{ "question": "外壁", "answers": [ "がいへき", "そとかべ" ], "comment": "outer wall" },
	{ "question": "外来", "answers": [ "がいらい" ], "comment": "foreign; imported\noutpatient; outpatient care; outpatient clinic; outpatient ward" },
	{ "question": "外来語", "answers": [ "がいらいご" ], "comment": "borrowed word; foreign origin word" },
	{ "question": "外気", "answers": [ "がいき" ], "comment": "open air" },
	{ "question": "外洋", "answers": [ "がいよう" ], "comment": "open sea; ocean" },
	{ "question": "外相", "answers": [ "がいしょう" ], "comment": "Foreign Minister" },
	{ "question": "外科", "answers": [ "げか" ], "comment": "surgery\ndepartment of surgery (hospital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外科医", "answers": [ "げかい" ], "comment": "surgeon" },
	{ "question": "外苑", "answers": [ "がいえん" ], "comment": "outer garden" },
	{ "question": "外見", "answers": [ "そとみ", "がいけん" ], "comment": "outward appearance" },
	{ "question": "外観", "answers": [ "がいかん" ], "comment": "appearance; exterior; facade" },
	{ "question": "外角", "answers": [ "がいかく" ], "comment": "external angle; exterior angle\noutside corner" },
	{ "question": "外貨", "answers": [ "がいか" ], "comment": "foreign currency; foreign money; foreign exchange\nforeign goods; imported goods" },
	{ "question": "外資", "answers": [ "がいし" ], "comment": "foreign capital (e.g. in a company); foreign investment" },
	{ "question": "外車", "answers": [ "がいしゃ" ], "comment": "foreign automobile" },
	{ "question": "外遊", "answers": [ "がいゆう" ], "comment": "foreign travel" },
	{ "question": "外部", "answers": [ "がいぶ" ], "comment": "the outside\nexternal" },
	{ "question": "外郭団体", "answers": [ "がいかくだんたい" ], "comment": "auxiliary organization (organisation); extra-departmental body; fringe organization" },
	{ "question": "外野", "answers": [ "がいや" ], "comment": "outfield\noutfielder\noutfield bleachers\nthird party; outsider" },
	{ "question": "外野手", "answers": [ "がいやしゅ" ], "comment": "outfielder" },
	{ "question": "外需", "answers": [ "がいじゅ" ], "comment": "foreign demand" },
	{ "question": "外面", "answers": [ "がいめん", "そとづら", "げめん" ], "comment": "outer surface; outward appearance; outside; exterior\noutside; outer; outward; exterior; external" },
	{ "question": "外食", "answers": [ "がいしょく" ], "comment": "eating out" },
	{ "question": "多", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "multi-" },
	{ "question": "多い", "answers": [ "おおい" ], "comment": "many; numerous; a lot\nlarge quantity; large amount\nfrequent; common" },
	{ "question": "多く", "answers": [ "おおく" ], "comment": "many; much; largely; abundantly; mostly" },
	{ "question": "多め", "answers": [ "おおめ" ], "comment": "somewhat larger quantity; larger portion" },
	{ "question": "多分", "answers": [ "たぶん" ], "comment": "perhaps; probably\ngenerous; many; much; great" },
	{ "question": "多大", "answers": [ "ただい" ], "comment": "great (quantity, amount, etc.); huge; enormous; serious" },
	{ "question": "多少", "answers": [ "たしょう" ], "comment": "more or less; somewhat; a little; a few; some\namount; quantity" },
	{ "question": "多岐", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "digression; many divergences" },
	{ "question": "多彩", "answers": [ "たさい" ], "comment": "variegated; varicoloured; varicolored; multi-coloured; multi-colored; diverse" },
	{ "question": "多忙", "answers": [ "たぼう" ], "comment": "busy; pressure of work" },
	{ "question": "多数", "answers": [ "たすう" ], "comment": "large number; many\nmajority" },
	{ "question": "多数決", "answers": [ "たすうけつ" ], "comment": "majority rule" },
	{ "question": "多様", "answers": [ "たよう" ], "comment": "diverse; varied" },
	{ "question": "多様化", "answers": [ "たようか" ], "comment": "diversification" },
	{ "question": "多様性", "answers": [ "たようせい" ], "comment": "diversity; variety" },
	{ "question": "多湿", "answers": [ "たしつ" ], "comment": "high humidity" },
	{ "question": "多発", "answers": [ "たはつ" ], "comment": "repeated occurrence" },
	{ "question": "多目的", "answers": [ "たもくてき" ], "comment": "multipurpose" },
	{ "question": "多角", "answers": [ "たかく" ], "comment": "many-sided; versatile; polygonal; diversified" },
	{ "question": "多角的", "answers": [ "たかくてき" ], "comment": "multilateral; many-sided; diversified" },
	{ "question": "多重", "answers": [ "たじゅう" ], "comment": "multiple; multiplex" },
	{ "question": "多量", "answers": [ "たりょう" ], "comment": "large quantity" },
	{ "question": "多難", "answers": [ "たなん" ], "comment": "full of troubles, difficulties" },
	{ "question": "多面", "answers": [ "ためん" ], "comment": "many-sided; multifaceted" },
	{ "question": "多額", "answers": [ "たがく" ], "comment": "large amount of money" },
	{ "question": "夜", "answers": [ "よる", "よ" ], "comment": "evening; night" },
	{ "question": "夜中", "answers": [ "よなか" ], "comment": "middle of the night; dead of night" },
	{ "question": "夜具", "answers": [ "やぐ" ], "comment": "bedding; bedclothes" },
	{ "question": "夜勤", "answers": [ "やきん" ], "comment": "night shift" },
	{ "question": "夜学", "answers": [ "やがく" ], "comment": "evening course; night-school" },
	{ "question": "夜明け", "answers": [ "よあけ" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak" },
	{ "question": "夜景", "answers": [ "やけい" ], "comment": "night view; night skyline; nightscape" },
	{ "question": "夜更かし", "answers": [ "よふかし" ], "comment": "staying up late; keeping late hours; sitting up late at night; nighthawk" },
	{ "question": "夜更け", "answers": [ "よふけ" ], "comment": "late at night; small hours of the morning" },
	{ "question": "夜空", "answers": [ "よぞら" ], "comment": "night sky" },
	{ "question": "夜間", "answers": [ "やかん" ], "comment": "at night; nighttime" },
	{ "question": "夢", "answers": [ "ゆめ" ], "comment": "dream" },
	{ "question": "夢中", "answers": [ "むちゅう" ], "comment": "daze; (in a) trance; ecstasy; delirium; engrossment; within a (deep) dream" },
	{ "question": "夢想", "answers": [ "むそう" ], "comment": "dream; vision; reverie" },
	{ "question": "大々的", "answers": [ "だいだいてき" ], "comment": "great; grand; extensive; large-scale" },
	{ "question": "大いに", "answers": [ "おおいに" ], "comment": "very; much; greatly; a lot of" },
	{ "question": "大きい", "answers": [ "おおきい" ], "comment": "big; large; great; loud" },
	{ "question": "大きさ", "answers": [ "おおきさ" ], "comment": "size; dimensions; volume" },
	{ "question": "大きな", "answers": [ "おおきな" ], "comment": "big; large; great" },
	{ "question": "大げさ", "answers": [ "おおげさ" ], "comment": "grandiose; exaggerated" },
	{ "question": "大さじ", "answers": [ "おおさじ" ], "comment": "tablespoon" },
	{ "question": "大ざっぱ", "answers": [ "おおざっぱ" ], "comment": "rough (as in not precise); broad; sketchy" },
	{ "question": "大した", "answers": [ "たいした" ], "comment": "considerable; great; important; significant; a big deal" },
	{ "question": "大まか", "answers": [ "おおまか" ], "comment": "rough (e.g. sketch, approximation); broad; general; loose\ngenerous; openhanded" },
	{ "question": "大丈夫", "answers": [ "だいじょぶ", "だいじょうぶ" ], "comment": "safe; all right; alright; OK; okay; sure\ncertainly; surely; undoubtedly\ngreat man; fine figure of a man" },
	{ "question": "大事", "answers": [ "おおごと", "だいじ" ], "comment": "important; valuable; serious matter\nsafe (Tochigi dialect); OK" },
	{ "question": "大事件", "answers": [ "だいじけん" ], "comment": "major incident; major event" },
	{ "question": "大人", "answers": [ "だいにん", "おとな" ], "comment": "adult" },
	{ "question": "大仏", "answers": [ "だいぶつ" ], "comment": "large statue of Buddha (trad. at least 4.8m high)" },
	{ "question": "大企業", "answers": [ "だいきぎょう" ], "comment": "large company; enterprise" },
	{ "question": "大会", "answers": [ "たいかい" ], "comment": "convention; tournament; mass meeting; rally" },
	{ "question": "大佐", "answers": [ "たいさ" ], "comment": "colonel; (navy) captain" },
	{ "question": "大作", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "epic" },
	{ "question": "大使", "answers": [ "たいし" ], "comment": "ambassador" },
	{ "question": "大使館", "answers": [ "たいしかん" ], "comment": "embassy" },
	{ "question": "大便", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "feces; excrement; shit" },
	{ "question": "大切", "answers": [ "たいせつ" ], "comment": "important; necessary; indispensable\nbeloved; precious; dear; cherished; valuable\ncareful" },
	{ "question": "大別", "answers": [ "たいべつ" ], "comment": "general classification" },
	{ "question": "大前提", "answers": [ "だいぜんてい" ], "comment": "major premise; principle" },
	{ "question": "大動脈", "answers": [ "だいどうみゃく" ], "comment": "aorta\nimportant traffic route" },
	{ "question": "大勝", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "great victory; crushing victory" },
	{ "question": "大募集", "answers": [ "だいぼしゅう" ], "comment": "mass recruitment" },
	{ "question": "大勢", "answers": [ "おおぜい", "たいせい", "たいぜい" ], "comment": "crowd of people; great number of people\nin great numbers /\n general trend; current thought" },
	{ "question": "大半", "answers": [ "たいはん" ], "comment": "majority; more than half; most (of)\nmostly; largely; mainly; predominately; nearly" },
	{ "question": "大卒", "answers": [ "だいそつ" ], "comment": "university graduate" },
	{ "question": "大口", "answers": [ "おおぐち", "おおくち" ], "comment": "big mouth\nboastful speech; tall talk\nlarge amount; large sum" },
	{ "question": "大台", "answers": [ "おおだい" ], "comment": "(major) mark; level; barrier\n100-yen unit (stock market)" },
	{ "question": "大同", "answers": [ "だいどう" ], "comment": "largely the same\nDaidou era (806.5.18-810.9.19)" },
	{ "question": "大名", "answers": [ "だいみょう" ], "comment": "daimyo (Japanese feudal lord); daimio" },
	{ "question": "大和", "answers": [ "やまと" ], "comment": "Yamato; ancient province corresponding to modern-day Nara Prefecture\n(ancient) Japan\nJapanese" },
	{ "question": "大商い", "answers": [ "おおあきない" ], "comment": "heavy turnover (trading)" },
	{ "question": "大喜び", "answers": [ "おおよろこび" ], "comment": "great joy" },
	{ "question": "大回転", "answers": [ "だいかいてん" ], "comment": "the giant slalom" },
	{ "question": "大国", "answers": [ "たいこく" ], "comment": "large country; major powers" },
	{ "question": "大地", "answers": [ "だいち" ], "comment": "ground; earth; the solid earth; the (vast) land" },
	{ "question": "大型", "answers": [ "おおがた" ], "comment": "large; large-sized; large-scale; big" },
	{ "question": "大声", "answers": [ "たいせい", "おおごえ" ], "comment": "loud voice" },
	{ "question": "大変", "answers": [ "たいへん" ], "comment": "very; greatly\nimmense; enormous; great\nserious; grave; dreadful; terrible\ndifficult; hard\nmajor incident; disaster" },
	{ "question": "大多数", "answers": [ "だいたすう" ], "comment": "great majority" },
	{ "question": "大好き", "answers": [ "だいすき" ], "comment": "loveable; very likeable; like very much" },
	{ "question": "大嫌い", "answers": [ "だいきらい" ], "comment": "detestable; abhorrent; loathsome" },
	{ "question": "大学", "answers": [ "だいがく" ], "comment": "post-secondary education institution, incl. university, college, etc.\nformer central university of Kyoto (established under the ritsuryo system for the training of government administrators)\nthe Great Learning (one of the Four Books)" },
	{ "question": "大学生", "answers": [ "だいがくせい" ], "comment": "university student; college student" },
	{ "question": "大学進学", "answers": [ "だいがくしんがく" ], "comment": "continuing one's education into university" },
	{ "question": "大学院", "answers": [ "だいがくいん" ], "comment": "graduate school" },
	{ "question": "大家", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "master; expert; authority; leading figure\nmansion; large house\nrich family; distinguished family" },
	{ "question": "大家族", "answers": [ "だいかぞく" ], "comment": "extended family; large family" },
	{ "question": "大将", "answers": [ "だいしょう", "たいしょう" ], "comment": "general; admiral\nhead; chief; leader; boss; kingpin\nold chap; mate; boss; chief; man\nathlete who competes in the last match of a team competition (kendo, judo, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "大尉", "answers": [ "だいい", "たいい" ], "comment": "captain (Army, U.S. Marine Corps, USAF); lieutenant (Navy); flight lieutenant (RAF, RAAF, RNZAF, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "大小", "answers": [ "だいしょう" ], "comment": "sizes (various); large and small\ndaisho (matched pair of long and short swords)\nlarge and small drums\nlong months and short months\nsic bo (Macau dice game); tai sai; dai siu; big and small" },
	{ "question": "大屋", "answers": [ "おおや" ], "comment": "landlord; landlady" },
	{ "question": "大山", "answers": [ "たいざん" ], "comment": "great mountain" },
	{ "question": "大工", "answers": [ "だいく" ], "comment": "carpenter" },
	{ "question": "大差", "answers": [ "たいさ" ], "comment": "great difference" },
	{ "question": "大師", "answers": [ "だいし" ], "comment": "great teacher (i.e. a buddha, bodhisattva or high monk, esp. Kobo Daishi)" },
	{ "question": "大幅", "answers": [ "おおはば" ], "comment": "big; large; drastic; substantial\nfull-width cloth (approx. 72 cm wide for traditional Japanese clothing; approx. 140 cm wide for Western clothing)" },
	{ "question": "大店", "answers": [ "おおだな" ], "comment": "large store" },
	{ "question": "大当たり", "answers": [ "おおあたり" ], "comment": "big hit; big prize; bumper crop; striking it rich; right on the mark; bonanza; bull's eye; bullseye" },
	{ "question": "大役", "answers": [ "たいやく" ], "comment": "important task; important role; great duty; important mission\nmajor part (e.g. in a movie)" },
	{ "question": "大急ぎ", "answers": [ "おおいそぎ" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "大成", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "completion; accomplishment; attainment of greatness or success" },
	{ "question": "大戦", "answers": [ "たいせん" ], "comment": "great war; great battle" },
	{ "question": "大手", "answers": [ "おおて" ], "comment": "major company; big company\nfront castle gate\nforce attacking the front of a castle" },
	{ "question": "大掛かり", "answers": [ "おおがかり" ], "comment": "large-scale" },
	{ "question": "大敗", "answers": [ "たいはい" ], "comment": "crushing defeat" },
	{ "question": "大文字", "answers": [ "だいもんじ", "おおもじ" ], "comment": "upper case letters; large characters; capital letter\nthe (kanji) character \"dai\" meaning \"big\"\nhuge character \"dai\" formed by fires lit on the side of a mountain in Kyoto on 16 Aug each year" },
	{ "question": "大方", "answers": [ "おおかた" ], "comment": "large part; greater part; majority\npeople in general; general public; public at large\nmostly; for the most part; almost; nearly\nprobably; maybe; perhaps" },
	{ "question": "大時代", "answers": [ "おおじだい" ], "comment": "old-fashioned; antiquated; anachronistic" },
	{ "question": "大晦日", "answers": [ "おおみそか" ], "comment": "New Year's Eve; December 31st" },
	{ "question": "大木", "answers": [ "たいぼく" ], "comment": "large tree" },
	{ "question": "大根", "answers": [ "だいこん", "だいこ" ], "comment": "daikon (variety of large white Oriental radish, Raphanus sativus var. longipinnatus)\nham actor" },
	{ "question": "大概", "answers": [ "たいがい" ], "comment": "in general; almost all\nmainly; mostly; most likely\nmoderately; suitably" },
	{ "question": "大正", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "Taisho era (1912.7.30-1926.12.25)" },
	{ "question": "大気", "answers": [ "たいき" ], "comment": "atmosphere" },
	{ "question": "大水", "answers": [ "おおみず" ], "comment": "flood" },
	{ "question": "大河", "answers": [ "たいが" ], "comment": "large river" },
	{ "question": "大洋", "answers": [ "たいよう" ], "comment": "ocean" },
	{ "question": "大火", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "large fire" },
	{ "question": "大物", "answers": [ "おおもの" ], "comment": "important person; big-shot; bigwig\nbig game (animal, fish); big thing; valuable thing" },
	{ "question": "大理石", "answers": [ "だいりせき" ], "comment": "marble" },
	{ "question": "大病", "answers": [ "たいびょう" ], "comment": "serious illness; dangerous disease" },
	{ "question": "大盛り", "answers": [ "おおもり" ], "comment": "large serving" },
	{ "question": "大相撲", "answers": [ "おおずもう" ], "comment": "professional sumo wrestling" },
	{ "question": "大砲", "answers": [ "たいほう" ], "comment": "gun; cannon; artillery" },
	{ "question": "大破", "answers": [ "たいは" ], "comment": "serious damage; drubbing" },
	{ "question": "大社", "answers": [ "たいしゃ", "おおやしろ" ], "comment": "grand shrine; famous shrine\nIzumo Grand Shrine" },
	{ "question": "大空", "answers": [ "おおぞら" ], "comment": "heavens; firmament; sky" },
	{ "question": "大筋", "answers": [ "おおすじ" ], "comment": "outline; summary" },
	{ "question": "大統領", "answers": [ "だいとうりょう" ], "comment": "president; chief executive" },
	{ "question": "大綱", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "fundamental principles; outline; general features" },
	{ "question": "大義", "answers": [ "たいぎ" ], "comment": "great cause; moral law; justice" },
	{ "question": "大義名分", "answers": [ "たいぎめいぶん" ], "comment": "a just cause" },
	{ "question": "大胆", "answers": [ "だいたん" ], "comment": "bold; daring; audacious" },
	{ "question": "大脳", "answers": [ "だいのう" ], "comment": "cerebrum" },
	{ "question": "大腸", "answers": [ "だいちょう" ], "comment": "large intestine; large bowel; colon" },
	{ "question": "大腸菌", "answers": [ "だいちょうきん" ], "comment": "Escherichia coli (E. coli)\ncolon bacterium" },
	{ "question": "大臣", "answers": [ "だいじん" ], "comment": "cabinet minister" },
	{ "question": "大自然", "answers": [ "だいしぜん" ], "comment": "nature; Mother Nature" },
	{ "question": "大船", "answers": [ "おおふね", "たいせん", "おおぶね" ], "comment": "large boat" },
	{ "question": "大蔵", "answers": [ "おおくら" ], "comment": "Ministry of Finance" },
	{ "question": "大蔵省", "answers": [ "おおくらしょう" ], "comment": "(former) Ministry of Finance (1869-2001)\nMinistry of the Treasury (under the ritsuryo system)" },
	{ "question": "大衆", "answers": [ "たいしゅう" ], "comment": "general public; the masses" },
	{ "question": "大西洋", "answers": [ "たいせいよう" ], "comment": "Atlantic Ocean" },
	{ "question": "大規模", "answers": [ "だいきぼ" ], "comment": "large-scale" },
	{ "question": "大詰め", "answers": [ "おおづめ" ], "comment": "final scene; the end; finale" },
	{ "question": "大豆", "answers": [ "だいず" ], "comment": "soya bean (Glycine max); soybean; soy" },
	{ "question": "大賞", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "big prize; first prize" },
	{ "question": "大通り", "answers": [ "おおどおり" ], "comment": "main street" },
	{ "question": "大道", "answers": [ "たいどう", "だいどう" ], "comment": "main street; avenue" },
	{ "question": "大部分", "answers": [ "だいぶぶん" ], "comment": "most part; greater part; majority" },
	{ "question": "大野", "answers": [ "おおの" ], "comment": "large field" },
	{ "question": "大量", "answers": [ "たいりょう" ], "comment": "large quantity; massive (quantity); mass (e.g. mass production, mass transit, mass destruction)" },
	{ "question": "大金", "answers": [ "おおがね", "たいきん" ], "comment": "large amount of money; great cost" },
	{ "question": "大関", "answers": [ "おおぜき" ], "comment": "ōzeki (second highest rank in sumo)" },
	{ "question": "大陸", "answers": [ "たいりく" ], "comment": "continent\ncontinental Asia (esp. mainland China)\ncontinental Europe" },
	{ "question": "大隊", "answers": [ "だいたい" ], "comment": "battalion" },
	{ "question": "大雑把", "answers": [ "おおざっぱ" ], "comment": "rough (as in not precise); broad; sketchy" },
	{ "question": "大雨", "answers": [ "おおあめ" ], "comment": "heavy rain" },
	{ "question": "大雪", "answers": [ "たいせつ", "おおゆき" ], "comment": "heavy snow\n\"major snow\" solar term (approx. Dec. 7)" },
	{ "question": "大震災", "answers": [ "だいしんさい" ], "comment": "great earthquake (disaster)\nGreat Kanto earthquake of 1923" },
	{ "question": "大騒ぎ", "answers": [ "おおさわぎ" ], "comment": "clamour; clamor; uproar; tumult; furore; furor" },
	{ "question": "大麦", "answers": [ "おおむぎ" ], "comment": "barley (Hordeum vulgare)" },
	{ "question": "大麻", "answers": [ "おおあさ", "たいま" ], "comment": "hemp\ncannabis; marijuana; pot; hashish\nShinto paper offerings" },
	{ "question": "大黒柱", "answers": [ "だいこくばしら" ], "comment": "central pillar (of a building)\nmainstay (e.g. of an economy); backbone (e.g. of a family); provider; main man" },
	{ "question": "天", "answers": [ "あま", "てん", "あめ" ], "comment": "sky\nheaven\nsvarga (heaven-like realm visited as a stage of death and rebirth)\ndeva (divine being of Buddhism)" },
	{ "question": "天の川", "answers": [ "あまのがわ" ], "comment": "Milky Way; luminous band corresponding to the plane of the galaxy" },
	{ "question": "天の河", "answers": [ "あまのがわ" ], "comment": "Milky Way; luminous band corresponding to the plane of the galaxy" },
	{ "question": "天ぷら", "answers": [ "てんぷら" ], "comment": "tempura; deep-fried fish and vegetables in a light batter" },
	{ "question": "天下", "answers": [ "てんげ", "てんか", "てんが" ], "comment": "the whole world\nthe whole country\nsociety; the public\nsupremacy over a nation; government of a country; the ruling power\nhaving one's own way; doing as one pleases\npeerless; incomparable; superlative; world-famous\nshogun (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "天下り", "answers": [ "あまくだり" ], "comment": "retiring high-ranking government officials taking a lucrative job in a private or semi-private corporation\ncommand (from superior to inferior, government to private sector, etc.); order; imposition\ndescent from heaven" },
	{ "question": "天井", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "ceiling; ceiling price" },
	{ "question": "天体", "answers": [ "てんたい" ], "comment": "heavenly body; celestial body; astronomical object" },
	{ "question": "天使", "answers": [ "てんし" ], "comment": "angel" },
	{ "question": "天候", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "weather" },
	{ "question": "天国", "answers": [ "てんごく" ], "comment": "paradise; heaven; Kingdom of Heaven" },
	{ "question": "天地", "answers": [ "てんち", "あめつち" ], "comment": "heaven and earth; the universe; nature; top and bottom; realm; sphere; world\ntop and bottom\ngods of heaven and earth" },
	{ "question": "天才", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "genius; prodigy; natural gift" },
	{ "question": "天文", "answers": [ "てんもん" ], "comment": "astronomy" },
	{ "question": "天文台", "answers": [ "てんもんだい" ], "comment": "astronomical observatory" },
	{ "question": "天文学", "answers": [ "てんもんがく" ], "comment": "astronomy" },
	{ "question": "天気", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "weather; the elements\nfair weather; fine weather" },
	{ "question": "天気予報", "answers": [ "てんきよほう" ], "comment": "weather forecast; weather report" },
	{ "question": "天満宮", "answers": [ "てんまんぐう" ], "comment": "Tenmangu shrine (shrine dedicated to Sugawara no Michizane's spirit)" },
	{ "question": "天災", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "natural calamity; disaster" },
	{ "question": "天然", "answers": [ "てんねん" ], "comment": "nature; spontaneity\nnatural airhead" },
	{ "question": "天然ガス", "answers": [ "てんねんガス" ], "comment": "natural gas" },
	{ "question": "天然記念物", "answers": [ "てんねんきねんぶつ" ], "comment": "natural monument\nprotected species (animal, habitat, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "天王星", "answers": [ "てんのうせい", "てんおうせい" ], "comment": "Uranus (planet)" },
	{ "question": "天理", "answers": [ "てんり" ], "comment": "natural laws; rule of heaven" },
	{ "question": "天皇", "answers": [ "すめろぎ", "てんのう", "すめらぎ" ], "comment": "Emperor of Japan" },
	{ "question": "天皇制", "answers": [ "てんのうせい" ], "comment": "the Emperor System" },
	{ "question": "天皇陛下", "answers": [ "てんのうへいか" ], "comment": "His Majesty the Emperor" },
	{ "question": "天神", "answers": [ "てんじん" ], "comment": "heavenly god; heavenly gods\nspirit of Sugawara no Michizane\nTenmangu shrine (dedicated to Michizane's spirit)\npit of a dried plum; dried plum\ntenjin hairstyle\nprostitute of the second-highest class (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "太い", "answers": [ "ふとい" ], "comment": "fat; thick\ndeep (of a voice)\ndaring; shameless; brazen\nlucky (billiards)" },
	{ "question": "太っ腹", "answers": [ "ふとっぱら" ], "comment": "generous; magnanimous; big-hearted; broad-minded" },
	{ "question": "太もも", "answers": [ "ふともも" ], "comment": "thigh\nbuttocks; arse; ass; butt" },
	{ "question": "太り肉", "answers": [ "ふとりじし" ], "comment": "corpulent; fat; chubby" },
	{ "question": "太る", "answers": [ "ふとる" ], "comment": "to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight" },
	{ "question": "太子", "answers": [ "たいし" ], "comment": "Crown Prince\nShotoku Taishi" },
	{ "question": "太平洋", "answers": [ "たいへいよう" ], "comment": "Pacific Ocean" },
	{ "question": "太平洋戦争", "answers": [ "たいへいようせんそう" ], "comment": "Pacific War (1941-1945)" },
	{ "question": "太陽", "answers": [ "たいよう" ], "comment": "sun; solar" },
	{ "question": "太陽系", "answers": [ "たいようけい" ], "comment": "solar system" },
	{ "question": "太陽電池", "answers": [ "たいようでんち" ], "comment": "solar cell" },
	{ "question": "太鼓", "answers": [ "たいこ" ], "comment": "drum" },
	{ "question": "夫", "answers": [ "おっと" ], "comment": "husband" },
	{ "question": "夫人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "wife; Mrs; madam\nwife of a nobleman (aristocrat, etc.)\nconsort of the emperor" },
	{ "question": "夫妻", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "man and wife; married couple" },
	{ "question": "夫婦", "answers": [ "めおと", "みょうと", "ふうふ" ], "comment": "married couple; spouses; husband and wife; couple; pair\nhis and hers; pair of objects, one larger (for man), one smaller (for woman)" },
	{ "question": "失う", "answers": [ "うしなう" ], "comment": "to lose; to part with" },
	{ "question": "失恋", "answers": [ "しつれん" ], "comment": "disappointed love; broken heart; unrequited love; being lovelorn" },
	{ "question": "失態", "answers": [ "しったい" ], "comment": "mismanagement; fault; error; failure; disgrace; discredit" },
	{ "question": "失敗", "answers": [ "しっぱい" ], "comment": "failure; mistake; blunder" },
	{ "question": "失敗談", "answers": [ "しっぱいだん" ], "comment": "failure story; horror story" },
	{ "question": "失敬", "answers": [ "しっけい" ], "comment": "rudeness; saying good-bye; acting impolitely; stealing; impoliteness; disrespect; impertinence" },
	{ "question": "失明", "answers": [ "しつめい" ], "comment": "loss of eyesight; loss of vision; going blind; blindness" },
	{ "question": "失望", "answers": [ "しつぼう" ], "comment": "disappointment; despair" },
	{ "question": "失格", "answers": [ "しっかく" ], "comment": "disqualification; elimination; incapacity (legal)" },
	{ "question": "失業", "answers": [ "しつぎょう" ], "comment": "unemployment" },
	{ "question": "失点", "answers": [ "しってん" ], "comment": "losing points; lost points\nrun charged to the pitcher\nblunder; mistake; error" },
	{ "question": "失礼", "answers": [ "しつれい" ], "comment": "discourtesy; impoliteness\nExcuse me; Goodbye\nto leave\nto be rude" },
	{ "question": "失策", "answers": [ "しっさく" ], "comment": "blunder; slip; error" },
	{ "question": "失脚", "answers": [ "しっきゃく" ], "comment": "losing one's standing; being overthrown; falling" },
	{ "question": "失跡", "answers": [ "しっせき" ], "comment": "absconding; disappearance" },
	{ "question": "失速", "answers": [ "しっそく" ], "comment": "stall (in flying); stalling\nsuddenly losing momentum; downturn; slump; weakening; decline" },
	{ "question": "奇妙", "answers": [ "きみょう" ], "comment": "strange; queer; curious" },
	{ "question": "奇抜", "answers": [ "きばつ" ], "comment": "novel; original; striking; strange; eccentric; fantastic" },
	{ "question": "奇数", "answers": [ "きすう" ], "comment": "odd number" },
	{ "question": "奇異", "answers": [ "きい" ], "comment": "odd; strange; queer; peculiar" },
	{ "question": "奇襲", "answers": [ "きしゅう" ], "comment": "surprise attack" },
	{ "question": "奇跡", "answers": [ "きせき" ], "comment": "miracle; wonder; marvel" },
	{ "question": "奉仕", "answers": [ "ほうし" ], "comment": "service; ministry; attendance; church work\noffering goods at a reduced price; providing a service for free" },
	{ "question": "奉公", "answers": [ "ほうこう" ], "comment": "service; apprenticeship; public duty" },
	{ "question": "奉行", "answers": [ "ぶぎょう" ], "comment": "magistrate; shogunate administrator" },
	{ "question": "奏功", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "success; achievement; fruition" },
	{ "question": "奏者", "answers": [ "そうしゃ" ], "comment": "instrumentalist; player" },
	{ "question": "契機", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "契約", "answers": [ "けいやく" ], "comment": "contract; compact; agreement" },
	{ "question": "奔放", "answers": [ "ほんぽう" ], "comment": "wild; uninhibited; extravagant; rampant" },
	{ "question": "奥", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "inner part; inside; interior; depths (e.g. of a forest); back (of a house, drawer, etc.); bottom (e.g. of one's heart); recesses; heart" },
	{ "question": "奥さん", "answers": [ "おくさん" ], "comment": "wife; your wife; his wife; married lady; madam" },
	{ "question": "奥地", "answers": [ "おくち", "おうち" ], "comment": "interior; backwoods; hinterland; back regions" },
	{ "question": "奥山", "answers": [ "おくやま" ], "comment": "remote mountain; mountain recesses" },
	{ "question": "奥様", "answers": [ "おくさま" ], "comment": "wife; your wife; his wife; married lady; madam" },
	{ "question": "奥行", "answers": [ "おくゆき" ], "comment": "depth; length" },
	{ "question": "奥行き", "answers": [ "おくゆき" ], "comment": "depth; length" },
	{ "question": "奨励", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "encouragement; promotion; inducement; incitement; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "奨学", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "encouragement to study" },
	{ "question": "奨学金", "answers": [ "しょうがくきん" ], "comment": "scholarship; stipend; bursary\nstudent loan" },
	{ "question": "奪う", "answers": [ "うばう" ], "comment": "to snatch away; to dispossess; to steal" },
	{ "question": "奪三振", "answers": [ "だつさんしん" ], "comment": "striking a batter out" },
	{ "question": "奪取", "answers": [ "だっしゅ" ], "comment": "usurpation; taking back; dispossession" },
	{ "question": "奪回", "answers": [ "だっかい" ], "comment": "recovery; rescue; recapture" },
	{ "question": "奪還", "answers": [ "だっかん" ], "comment": "recovery; rescue; recapture" },
	{ "question": "奮う", "answers": [ "ふるう" ], "comment": "to muster (e.g. one's courage); to call forth; to rouse up\nto be enlivened; to be invigorated" },
	{ "question": "奮発", "answers": [ "ふんぱつ" ], "comment": "strenuous exertion; spurt\nsplurge" },
	{ "question": "奮起", "answers": [ "ふんき" ], "comment": "stirring; rousing oneself" },
	{ "question": "奮闘", "answers": [ "ふんとう" ], "comment": "hard struggle; strenuous effort" },
	{ "question": "女", "answers": [ "おんな" ], "comment": "female; woman; female sex\nfemale lover; girlfriend; mistress; (someone's) woman" },
	{ "question": "女のコ", "answers": [ "おんにゃのこ", "おんなのこ", "おんなのコ" ], "comment": "girl; daughter\nyoung woman" },
	{ "question": "女の人", "answers": [ "おんなのひと" ], "comment": "woman" },
	{ "question": "女の子", "answers": [ "おんにゃのこ", "おんなのこ", "おんなのコ" ], "comment": "girl; daughter\nyoung woman" },
	{ "question": "女らしい", "answers": [ "おんならしい" ], "comment": "womanly; ladylike; feminine" },
	{ "question": "女優", "answers": [ "じょゆう" ], "comment": "actress" },
	{ "question": "女児", "answers": [ "じょじ" ], "comment": "baby girl; primary schoolgirl" },
	{ "question": "女史", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "Ms (nuance of status); Miss; Madame\nhighbrow (woman); cerebral" },
	{ "question": "女子", "answers": [ "じょし", "おなご" ], "comment": "woman; girl" },
	{ "question": "女子大", "answers": [ "じょしだい" ], "comment": "women's college; women's university" },
	{ "question": "女学校", "answers": [ "じょがっこう" ], "comment": "girl's school" },
	{ "question": "女形", "answers": [ "おやま", "おんながた" ], "comment": "male actor in female kabuki roles" },
	{ "question": "女性", "answers": [ "じょせい", "にょしょう" ], "comment": "woman; female\nfeminine gender" },
	{ "question": "女性的", "answers": [ "じょせいてき" ], "comment": "feminine; effeminate" },
	{ "question": "女房", "answers": [ "にょうぼう", "にょうぼ" ], "comment": "wife (esp. one's own wife)\ncourt lady; female court attache; woman who served at the imperial palace\nwoman (esp. as a love interest)" },
	{ "question": "女流", "answers": [ "じょりゅう" ], "comment": "woman (writer, artist, aviator, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "女王", "answers": [ "じょおう" ], "comment": "queen" },
	{ "question": "女神", "answers": [ "めがみ", "じょしん" ], "comment": "goddess; female deity" },
	{ "question": "奴ら", "answers": [ "やつら" ], "comment": "they; those guys" },
	{ "question": "奴隷", "answers": [ "どれい" ], "comment": "slave; servant\nslavery" },
	{ "question": "好き", "answers": [ "すき" ], "comment": "liking; fondness; love" },
	{ "question": "好き好き", "answers": [ "すきずき" ], "comment": "matter of taste" },
	{ "question": "好き嫌い", "answers": [ "すききらい" ], "comment": "likes and dislikes; pickiness (about food); choosiness; fussiness; tastes; preferences" },
	{ "question": "好ましい", "answers": [ "このましい" ], "comment": "nice; likeable; desirable" },
	{ "question": "好み", "answers": [ "このみ" ], "comment": "liking; taste; choice" },
	{ "question": "好む", "answers": [ "このむ" ], "comment": "to like; to prefer" },
	{ "question": "好んで", "answers": [ "このんで" ], "comment": "by (from) choice; by (for) preference; of one's own accord; of one's (own) free will; on purpose; deliberately; intentionally" },
	{ "question": "好天", "answers": [ "こうてん" ], "comment": "fine weather" },
	{ "question": "好奇心", "answers": [ "こうきしん" ], "comment": "curiosity; inquisitiveness" },
	{ "question": "好守", "answers": [ "こうしゅ" ], "comment": "good fielding" },
	{ "question": "好意", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "good will; favor; favour; courtesy" },
	{ "question": "好感", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "good feeling; good will; favourable impression; favorable impression" },
	{ "question": "好成績", "answers": [ "こうせいせき" ], "comment": "good results" },
	{ "question": "好投", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "good (nice) pitching" },
	{ "question": "好景気", "answers": [ "こうけいき" ], "comment": "good times; boom; (wave of) prosperity" },
	{ "question": "好機", "answers": [ "こうき" ], "comment": "good opportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "好況", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "prosperous conditions; healthy economy" },
	{ "question": "好物", "answers": [ "こうぶつ" ], "comment": "favourite dish (favorite); favourite food" },
	{ "question": "好評", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "popularity; favorable reputation; favourable reputation" },
	{ "question": "好調", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "favourable; favorable; promising; satisfactory; in good shape" },
	{ "question": "好転", "answers": [ "こうてん" ], "comment": "changing for the better" },
	{ "question": "好都合", "answers": [ "こうつごう" ], "comment": "convenient; favorable; favourable; expedient; expedience" },
	{ "question": "如し", "answers": [ "ごとし" ], "comment": "like; as if; the same as" },
	{ "question": "如実", "answers": [ "にょじつ" ], "comment": "reality; actuality; actual conditions; true situation; faithful representation; vivid depiction\nultimate reality; absolute truth" },
	{ "question": "妃", "answers": [ "きさき", "ひ" ], "comment": "princess; consort" },
	{ "question": "妄信", "answers": [ "もうしん", "ぼうしん" ], "comment": "blind acceptance; blind belief; credulity" },
	{ "question": "妊娠", "answers": [ "にんしん" ], "comment": "conception; pregnancy" },
	{ "question": "妊婦", "answers": [ "にんぷ" ], "comment": "pregnant woman" },
	{ "question": "妖怪", "answers": [ "ようかい" ], "comment": "ghost; apparition; phantom; spectre; specter; demon; monster; goblin" },
	{ "question": "妖精", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "fairy; sprite; elf" },
	{ "question": "妙", "answers": [ "みょう" ], "comment": "strange; weird; odd; curious\nwonder; mystery; miracle; excellence\ncleverness; adroitness; knack; skill" },
	{ "question": "妥協", "answers": [ "だきょう" ], "comment": "compromise; giving in" },
	{ "question": "妥当", "answers": [ "だとう" ], "comment": "valid; proper; right; appropriate; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "妥結", "answers": [ "だけつ" ], "comment": "settlement; an agreement" },
	{ "question": "妨げ", "answers": [ "さまたげ" ], "comment": "obstruction; hindrance" },
	{ "question": "妨げる", "answers": [ "さまたげる" ], "comment": "to disturb; to prevent; to obstruct; to hinder" },
	{ "question": "妨害", "answers": [ "ぼうがい" ], "comment": "disturbance; obstruction; hindrance; jamming; interference" },
	{ "question": "妹", "answers": [ "いもうと" ], "comment": "younger sister" },
	{ "question": "妻子", "answers": [ "さいし", "つまこ" ], "comment": "wife and children\nwife" },
	{ "question": "姉", "answers": [ "あね" ], "comment": "older sister; elder sister" },
	{ "question": "姉さん", "answers": [ "あねさん", "ねえさん" ], "comment": "elder sister\n(vocative) young lady\nmiss (referring to a waitress, etc.)\nma'am (used by geisha to refer to their superiors)" },
	{ "question": "姉妹", "answers": [ "しまい" ], "comment": "sisters" },
	{ "question": "始まり", "answers": [ "はじまり" ], "comment": "origin; beginning" },
	{ "question": "始まる", "answers": [ "はじまる" ], "comment": "to begin; to start; to commence\nto happen (again); to begin (anew)\nto date (from); to originate (in)" },
	{ "question": "始める", "answers": [ "はじめる" ], "comment": "to start; to begin; to commence; to initiate; to originate\nto open (e.g. a store); to start up; to establish (business. etc.)\nto start ...; to begin to ..." },
	{ "question": "始末", "answers": [ "しまつ" ], "comment": "management; dealing with; settlement; cleaning up; disposal\ncourse of events; circumstances; particulars\nend result (usu. bad); outcome\neconomizing; economising; frugality; being thrifty" },
	{ "question": "始業", "answers": [ "しぎょう" ], "comment": "start of work; commencement; opening" },
	{ "question": "始発", "answers": [ "しはつ" ], "comment": "first departure (of the day: train, bus, etc.); first train; first bus\ndeparting one's home station (of a train, bus, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "始終", "answers": [ "しじゅう" ], "comment": "continuously; from beginning to end; from first to last" },
	{ "question": "姑", "answers": [ "しゅうとめ", "しうとめ", "しゅうと" ], "comment": "mother-in-law" },
	{ "question": "姓", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "surname; family name\nhereditary title (used in ancient Japan to denote rank and political standing)" },
	{ "question": "姓名", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "full name" },
	{ "question": "委ねる", "answers": [ "ゆだねる" ], "comment": "to entrust (a matter) to; to leave to\nto abandon oneself to (e.g. pleasure); to yield to (e.g. anger); to devote oneself to" },
	{ "question": "委任", "answers": [ "いにん" ], "comment": "charge; trust" },
	{ "question": "委員", "answers": [ "いいん" ], "comment": "committee member" },
	{ "question": "委員会", "answers": [ "いいんかい" ], "comment": "committee; commission; board; panel; committee meeting" },
	{ "question": "委員長", "answers": [ "いいんちょう" ], "comment": "committee chairman" },
	{ "question": "委嘱", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "entrusting (with)" },
	{ "question": "委託", "answers": [ "いたく" ], "comment": "entrusting (something to a person); consignment (of goods); putting in someone's charge; trust; commission" },
	{ "question": "姪", "answers": [ "めい" ], "comment": "niece" },
	{ "question": "姫", "answers": [ "ひめ" ], "comment": "young lady of noble birth; princess (esp. in Western contexts, tales, etc.)\ngirl\nsmall; cute; lesser (in names of species)\nprostitute" },
	{ "question": "姿", "answers": [ "すがた" ], "comment": "figure; form; shape\nappearance; dress; guise\nstate; condition; picture; image\nform (of a waka)\ndressed in ...; wearing ..." },
	{ "question": "姿勢", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "attitude; posture; stance; approach; carriage (of the body)" },
	{ "question": "威信", "answers": [ "いしん" ], "comment": "prestige; dignity" },
	{ "question": "威力", "answers": [ "いりょく" ], "comment": "power; might; authority; influence" },
	{ "question": "威勢", "answers": [ "いせい" ], "comment": "power; might; authority; influence\nspirits; vigor; vigour; energy; boldness" },
	{ "question": "威嚇", "answers": [ "いかく" ], "comment": "menace; threat; intimidation\nto threaten; to intimidate" },
	{ "question": "威張る", "answers": [ "えばる", "いばる" ], "comment": "to put on airs; to act big; to throw one's weight about; to be overbearing; to be domineering; to be bossy; to be pushy; to be proud; to be haughty; to be arrogant; to swagger; to boast; to brag" },
	{ "question": "娘", "answers": [ "むすめ" ], "comment": "(my) daughter\ngirl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)" },
	{ "question": "娘婿", "answers": [ "むすめむこ" ], "comment": "son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "娯楽", "answers": [ "ごらく" ], "comment": "pleasure; amusement" },
	{ "question": "娼婦", "answers": [ "しょうふ" ], "comment": "prostitute; harlot" },
	{ "question": "婉曲", "answers": [ "えんきょく" ], "comment": "euphemistic; circumlocutory; roundabout; indirect" },
	{ "question": "婚姻", "answers": [ "こんいん" ], "comment": "marriage; matrimony" },
	{ "question": "婚約", "answers": [ "こんやく" ], "comment": "engagement; betrothal" },
	{ "question": "婚約者", "answers": [ "こんやくしゃ" ], "comment": "fiance; fiancee" },
	{ "question": "婦人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "woman; lady; adult female" },
	{ "question": "婦人科", "answers": [ "ふじんか" ], "comment": "gynecology department\ngynecology" },
	{ "question": "婦女", "answers": [ "ふじょ" ], "comment": "woman; womankind" },
	{ "question": "婦女暴行", "answers": [ "ふじょぼうこう" ], "comment": "rape" },
	{ "question": "婿", "answers": [ "むこ" ], "comment": "husband; groom\n(one's) son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "媒体", "answers": [ "ばいたい" ], "comment": "media; medium" },
	{ "question": "嫁", "answers": [ "よめ" ], "comment": "wife; bride\n(one's) daughter-in-law" },
	{ "question": "嫁ぐ", "answers": [ "とつぐ" ], "comment": "to marry (of a woman); to become a bride; to marry into (a family)\nto have sexual intercourse" },
	{ "question": "嫉妬", "answers": [ "しっと" ], "comment": "jealousy; envy" },
	{ "question": "嫌", "answers": [ "いや", "や" ], "comment": "disagreeable; detestable; unpleasant; reluctant" },
	{ "question": "嫌う", "answers": [ "きらう" ], "comment": "to hate; to dislike; to loathe" },
	{ "question": "嫌がらせ", "answers": [ "いやがらせ" ], "comment": "harassment; pestering" },
	{ "question": "嫌がる", "answers": [ "いやがる" ], "comment": "to hate; to dislike" },
	{ "question": "嫌悪", "answers": [ "けんお" ], "comment": "disgust; hate; repugnance" },
	{ "question": "嫌悪感", "answers": [ "けんおかん" ], "comment": "unpleasant feelings (e.g. hatred, disgust, revulsion, fear)" },
	{ "question": "嫌気", "answers": [ "いやけ", "けんき", "いやき" ], "comment": "dislike; disgust; disinclination; tired of" },
	{ "question": "嫌疑", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "suspicion" },
	{ "question": "嫡出", "answers": [ "てきしゅつ", "ちゃくしゅつ" ], "comment": "legitimate birth" },
	{ "question": "嬉しい", "answers": [ "うれしい" ], "comment": "happy; glad; pleasant" },
	{ "question": "嬢", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "unmarried woman\nMiss\n-ess; -ette" },
	{ "question": "子", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "child\nyoung (animal)\nyoung woman; young geisha\noffshoot\ninterest\nnew shares\nplayer who is not a dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)\nbird egg\n-er (often of young women)" },
	{ "question": "子ども", "answers": [ "こども" ], "comment": "child; children" },
	{ "question": "子どもたち", "answers": [ "こどもたち" ], "comment": "children" },
	{ "question": "子ども達", "answers": [ "こどもたち" ], "comment": "children" },
	{ "question": "子会社", "answers": [ "こがいしゃ" ], "comment": "subsidiary (company)" },
	{ "question": "子供", "answers": [ "こども" ], "comment": "child; children" },
	{ "question": "子供たち", "answers": [ "こどもたち" ], "comment": "children" },
	{ "question": "子供の頃", "answers": [ "こどものころ" ], "comment": "as a child; when one was a child; childhood" },
	{ "question": "子供達", "answers": [ "こどもたち" ], "comment": "children" },
	{ "question": "子女", "answers": [ "しじょ" ], "comment": "sons and daughters; male and female children; children\ngirl" },
	{ "question": "子孫", "answers": [ "しそん" ], "comment": "descendant; posterity; offspring" },
	{ "question": "子宮", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "womb; uterus" },
	{ "question": "子弟", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "young(er) people" },
	{ "question": "子役", "answers": [ "こやく" ], "comment": "dramatic role for child; child actor" },
	{ "question": "子息", "answers": [ "しそく" ], "comment": "son" },
	{ "question": "子牛", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "calf; small cow" },
	{ "question": "子猫", "answers": [ "こねこ" ], "comment": "kitten" },
	{ "question": "子羊", "answers": [ "こひつじ" ], "comment": "lamb" },
	{ "question": "字", "answers": [ "じ", "あざ" ], "comment": "section of village /\n character (i.e. kanji)\nhand-writing; penmanship\nthe ... word (i.e. \"the L word\" = \"love\")" },
	{ "question": "字幕", "answers": [ "じまく" ], "comment": "subtitles; captioning" },
	{ "question": "字引", "answers": [ "じびき" ], "comment": "dictionary" },
	{ "question": "字形", "answers": [ "じけい" ], "comment": "character style; character form" },
	{ "question": "字数", "answers": [ "じすう" ], "comment": "number of characters or letters" },
	{ "question": "字画", "answers": [ "じかく" ], "comment": "number of strokes in character" },
	{ "question": "字詰め", "answers": [ "じづめ" ], "comment": "character fill; number of characters" },
	{ "question": "存じる", "answers": [ "ぞんじる" ], "comment": "to think, feel, consider, know, etc." },
	{ "question": "存亡", "answers": [ "そんぼう" ], "comment": "life or death; existence; destiny" },
	{ "question": "存分", "answers": [ "ぞんぶん" ], "comment": "to one's heart's content; as much as one wants" },
	{ "question": "存在", "answers": [ "そんざい" ], "comment": "existence; being" },
	{ "question": "存廃", "answers": [ "そんぱい" ], "comment": "(whether to) continue or eliminate; existence" },
	{ "question": "存立", "answers": [ "そんりつ" ], "comment": "existence; subsistence" },
	{ "question": "存続", "answers": [ "そんぞく" ], "comment": "duration; continuance" },
	{ "question": "孝行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "filial piety" },
	{ "question": "季刊", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "quarterly (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "季節", "answers": [ "きせつ" ], "comment": "season" },
	{ "question": "季語", "answers": [ "きご" ], "comment": "seasonal word (in haiku)" },
	{ "question": "孤児", "answers": [ "こじ", "みなしご" ], "comment": "orphan" },
	{ "question": "孤児院", "answers": [ "こじいん" ], "comment": "orphanage" },
	{ "question": "孤独", "answers": [ "こどく" ], "comment": "solitude; loneliness; isolation" },
	{ "question": "孤立", "answers": [ "こりつ" ], "comment": "isolation; being alone; being friendless" },
	{ "question": "学", "answers": [ "がく" ], "comment": "-ology; -ics; study of ...\nlearning; scholarship; erudition; knowledge" },
	{ "question": "学ぶ", "answers": [ "まなぶ" ], "comment": "to study (in depth); to learn; to take lessons in" },
	{ "question": "学会", "answers": [ "がっかい" ], "comment": "scientific society; academic meeting; academic conference" },
	{ "question": "学会誌", "answers": [ "がっかいし" ], "comment": "academic journal" },
	{ "question": "学位", "answers": [ "がくい" ], "comment": "(university) degree; (academic) degree" },
	{ "question": "学内", "answers": [ "がくない" ], "comment": "within the school" },
	{ "question": "学割", "answers": [ "がくわり" ], "comment": "student discount" },
	{ "question": "学割り", "answers": [ "がくわり" ], "comment": "student discount" },
	{ "question": "学力", "answers": [ "がくりょく" ], "comment": "scholarly ability; scholarship; knowledge; literary ability" },
	{ "question": "学区", "answers": [ "がっく" ], "comment": "school district; school area" },
	{ "question": "学卒", "answers": [ "がくそつ" ], "comment": "college graduate" },
	{ "question": "学問", "answers": [ "がくもん" ], "comment": "scholarship; study; learning\ndiscipline; branch of learning; (a) science" },
	{ "question": "学園", "answers": [ "がくえん" ], "comment": "educational institution; school; academy; campus" },
	{ "question": "学士", "answers": [ "がくし" ], "comment": "university graduate; bachelor\nbachelor's degree" },
	{ "question": "学年", "answers": [ "がくねん" ], "comment": "academic year; school year\nyear in school; grade in school" },
	{ "question": "学徒", "answers": [ "がくと" ], "comment": "student; follower; students and pupils" },
	{ "question": "学期", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "school term; semester" },
	{ "question": "学校", "answers": [ "がっこう" ], "comment": "school" },
	{ "question": "学校名", "answers": [ "がっこうめい" ], "comment": "school's name" },
	{ "question": "学校法人", "answers": [ "がっこうほうじん" ], "comment": "(legally) incorporated educational institution" },
	{ "question": "学業", "answers": [ "がくぎょう" ], "comment": "studies; schoolwork; classwork" },
	{ "question": "学歴", "answers": [ "がくれき" ], "comment": "academic background" },
	{ "question": "学生", "answers": [ "がくせい" ], "comment": "student (esp. a university student)" },
	{ "question": "学界", "answers": [ "がっかい" ], "comment": "academic world; academia; academic circles; scientific world; learned circles" },
	{ "question": "学科", "answers": [ "がっか" ], "comment": "study subject; course of study\ndepartment (university, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "学童", "answers": [ "がくどう" ], "comment": "school child; pupil" },
	{ "question": "学級", "answers": [ "がっきゅう" ], "comment": "(school) class" },
	{ "question": "学習", "answers": [ "がくしゅう" ], "comment": "study; learning; tutorial" },
	{ "question": "学習指導要領", "answers": [ "がくしゅうしどうようりょう" ], "comment": "government course (curriculum) guidelines" },
	{ "question": "学者", "answers": [ "がくしゃ" ], "comment": "scholar" },
	{ "question": "学芸", "answers": [ "がくげい" ], "comment": "arts and sciences; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "学術", "answers": [ "がくじゅつ" ], "comment": "science; learning; scholarship; arts and sciences; academic pursuits" },
	{ "question": "学説", "answers": [ "がくせつ" ], "comment": "theory" },
	{ "question": "学識", "answers": [ "がくしき" ], "comment": "scholarship; scientific attainments" },
	{ "question": "学費", "answers": [ "がくひ" ], "comment": "tuition; school expenses" },
	{ "question": "学部", "answers": [ "がくぶ" ], "comment": "department of a university\nundergraduate (course, program, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "学長", "answers": [ "がくちょう" ], "comment": "university president" },
	{ "question": "学院", "answers": [ "がくいん" ], "comment": "institute; academy" },
	{ "question": "学際", "answers": [ "がくさい" ], "comment": "interdisciplinary" },
	{ "question": "孫", "answers": [ "まご" ], "comment": "grandchild" },
	{ "question": "宅", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "house; home; husband" },
	{ "question": "宅地", "answers": [ "たくち" ], "comment": "building lot; residential land" },
	{ "question": "宅配", "answers": [ "たくはい" ], "comment": "home delivery" },
	{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "universe; cosmos; space" },
	{ "question": "宇宙空間", "answers": [ "うちゅうくうかん" ], "comment": "outer space; void of space" },
	{ "question": "宇宙開発", "answers": [ "うちゅうかいはつ" ], "comment": "space development" },
	{ "question": "宇宙開発事業団", "answers": [ "うちゅうかいはつじぎょうだん" ], "comment": "National Space Development Agency; NASDA" },
	{ "question": "宇宙飛行士", "answers": [ "うちゅうひこうし" ], "comment": "astronaut" },
	{ "question": "守り", "answers": [ "まもり", "もり" ], "comment": "babysitting; babysitter\nprotecting; keeping; keeper /\n protection; defense; defence\nprovidence\namulet; charm; talisman" },
	{ "question": "守る", "answers": [ "まもる" ], "comment": "to protect; to guard; to defend\nto keep (i.e. a promise); to abide (by the rules); to observe; to obey; to follow" },
	{ "question": "守備", "answers": [ "しゅび" ], "comment": "defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "守勢", "answers": [ "しゅせい" ], "comment": "(being on the) defensive" },
	{ "question": "守衛", "answers": [ "しゅえい" ], "comment": "security guard; doorkeeper" },
	{ "question": "安い", "answers": [ "やすい" ], "comment": "cheap; inexpensive\ncalm; peaceful; quiet" },
	{ "question": "安っぽい", "answers": [ "やすっぽい" ], "comment": "cheap-looking; tawdry; insignificant" },
	{ "question": "安らか", "answers": [ "やすらか" ], "comment": "peaceful; tranquil; calm; restful" },
	{ "question": "安らぎ", "answers": [ "やすらぎ" ], "comment": "peace (of mind); tranquility; tranquillity; serenity" },
	{ "question": "安らぐ", "answers": [ "やすらぐ" ], "comment": "to feel at ease" },
	{ "question": "安上がり", "answers": [ "やすあがり" ], "comment": "cheap; economical" },
	{ "question": "安住", "answers": [ "あんじゅう" ], "comment": "living in peace; being content with one's present position" },
	{ "question": "安価", "answers": [ "あんか" ], "comment": "low price; cheapness" },
	{ "question": "安保", "answers": [ "あんぽ" ], "comment": "security (e.g. national security)\nUS-Japan Security Treaty\ncampaign against the Japan-U.S. Security Treaty (1959-60, 1970)" },
	{ "question": "安値", "answers": [ "やすね" ], "comment": "low price" },
	{ "question": "安全", "answers": [ "あんぜん" ], "comment": "safety\nsecurity" },
	{ "question": "安全保障", "answers": [ "あんぜんほしょう" ], "comment": "security guarantee (e.g. military security, network security, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "安否", "answers": [ "あんぴ" ], "comment": "safety; welfare; well-being" },
	{ "question": "安売り", "answers": [ "やすうり" ], "comment": "discount; bargain sale; selling cheaply" },
	{ "question": "安定", "answers": [ "あんてい" ], "comment": "stability; steadiness; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "安心", "answers": [ "あんしん" ], "comment": "relief; peace of mind" },
	{ "question": "安心感", "answers": [ "あんしんかん" ], "comment": "sense of security" },
	{ "question": "安打", "answers": [ "あんだ" ], "comment": "safe hit" },
	{ "question": "安易", "answers": [ "あんい" ], "comment": "easy; simple\neasy-going" },
	{ "question": "安楽死", "answers": [ "あんらくし" ], "comment": "euthanasia" },
	{ "question": "安泰", "answers": [ "あんたい" ], "comment": "peace; security; tranquility; tranquillity" },
	{ "question": "安物", "answers": [ "やすもの" ], "comment": "cheap article; poor quality article" },
	{ "question": "安眠", "answers": [ "あんみん" ], "comment": "quiet sleep" },
	{ "question": "安芸", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "former name of Hiroshima prefecture" },
	{ "question": "安静", "answers": [ "あんせい" ], "comment": "rest; quiet; repose" },
	{ "question": "完了", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "completion; conclusion\nperfect (tense, form, aspect)" },
	{ "question": "完全", "answers": [ "かんぜん" ], "comment": "perfection; completeness" },
	{ "question": "完全試合", "answers": [ "かんぜんしあい", "かんぜんじあい" ], "comment": "perfect game" },
	{ "question": "完売", "answers": [ "かんばい" ], "comment": "sold out" },
	{ "question": "完封", "answers": [ "かんぷう" ], "comment": "complete blockade (seal); baseball shutout" },
	{ "question": "完工", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "completion" },
	{ "question": "完成", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "complete; completion\nperfection; accomplishment" },
	{ "question": "完投", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "going the whole distance; pitching a whole game" },
	{ "question": "完敗", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "complete defeat; utter defeat; annihilation\nto be completely defeated; to be beaten hollow" },
	{ "question": "完治", "answers": [ "かんち", "かんじ" ], "comment": "complete recovery" },
	{ "question": "完璧", "answers": [ "かんぺき" ], "comment": "perfect; complete; flawless" },
	{ "question": "完結", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "conclusion; completion" },
	{ "question": "完走", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "finishing a race; reaching the goal; staying the course" },
	{ "question": "宗", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "sect" },
	{ "question": "宗教", "answers": [ "しゅうきょう" ], "comment": "religion; religious affiliation; belief; faith; creed\nreligious activity" },
	{ "question": "宗派", "answers": [ "しゅうは" ], "comment": "sect; denomination" },
	{ "question": "宗門", "answers": [ "しゅうもん" ], "comment": "doctrine; creed; sect" },
	{ "question": "官僚", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "bureaucrat; bureaucracy" },
	{ "question": "官公庁", "answers": [ "かんこうちょう" ], "comment": "government administration office" },
	{ "question": "官報", "answers": [ "かんぽう" ], "comment": "official daily gazette; official telegram" },
	{ "question": "官庁", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "government office; government agency; authorities" },
	{ "question": "官房", "answers": [ "かんぼう" ], "comment": "government secretariat" },
	{ "question": "官房長官", "answers": [ "かんぼうちょうかん" ], "comment": "Chief Cabinet Secretary" },
	{ "question": "官民", "answers": [ "かんみん" ], "comment": "government and people; government and private sector; public and private sector" },
	{ "question": "官界", "answers": [ "かんかい" ], "comment": "bureaucracy" },
	{ "question": "官邸", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "official residence (e.g. of the prime minister)" },
	{ "question": "宙", "answers": [ "ちゅう" ], "comment": "space; air; midair\n(from) memory; (by) heart" },
	{ "question": "定か", "answers": [ "さだか" ], "comment": "definite; sure" },
	{ "question": "定まる", "answers": [ "さだまる" ], "comment": "to become settled; to be fixed" },
	{ "question": "定める", "answers": [ "さだめる" ], "comment": "to decide; to establish; to determine" },
	{ "question": "定休", "answers": [ "ていきゅう" ], "comment": "regular holiday; fixed day off; regular closing day" },
	{ "question": "定休日", "answers": [ "ていきゅうび" ], "comment": "regular holiday; fixed day off; regular closing day" },
	{ "question": "定住", "answers": [ "ていじゅう" ], "comment": "settlement; permanent residency\nto settle down in; to reside in" },
	{ "question": "定例", "answers": [ "ていれい", "じょうれい" ], "comment": "regular; ordinary (e.g. session of parliament)\nestablished usage; precedent; regular practice" },
	{ "question": "定価", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "list price; regular price; established price" },
	{ "question": "定刻", "answers": [ "ていこく" ], "comment": "appointed time; timetable; schedule" },
	{ "question": "定員", "answers": [ "ていいん" ], "comment": "fixed number of regular personnel; staff quota; complement\ncapacity (of boat, hall, aeroplane, airplane, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "定型", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "fixed form; regular shape; stereotyped" },
	{ "question": "定年", "answers": [ "ていねん" ], "comment": "retirement age\nyears of service in a military rank before eligibility for promotion" },
	{ "question": "定形", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "fixed form; regular shape; stereotyped" },
	{ "question": "定数", "answers": [ "じょうすう", "ていすう" ], "comment": "fixed number; quorum (for an assembly)\nconstant; invariable\nliteral\nfate" },
	{ "question": "定時", "answers": [ "ていじ" ], "comment": "regular time; stated period" },
	{ "question": "定時制", "answers": [ "ていじせい" ], "comment": "part time (school system)" },
	{ "question": "定期", "answers": [ "ていき" ], "comment": "fixed period; fixed term\nregular; periodic; periodical\nfixed-term commutation pass\nfixed-term deposit\nfutures contracts" },
	{ "question": "定期便", "answers": [ "ていきびん" ], "comment": "regular service" },
	{ "question": "定期券", "answers": [ "ていきけん" ], "comment": "commuter pass; season ticket" },
	{ "question": "定期的", "answers": [ "ていきてき" ], "comment": "periodic; regular; routine" },
	{ "question": "定期購読", "answers": [ "ていきこうどく" ], "comment": "subscription (e.g. to a magazine)" },
	{ "question": "定期預金", "answers": [ "ていきよきん" ], "comment": "term deposit; (fixed) time deposit" },
	{ "question": "定率", "answers": [ "ていりつ" ], "comment": "fixed rate" },
	{ "question": "定番", "answers": [ "ていばん" ], "comment": "standard; routine; regular; basic; staple" },
	{ "question": "定着", "answers": [ "ていちゃく" ], "comment": "taking hold; getting attached; becoming established; becoming entrenched; establishing" },
	{ "question": "定義", "answers": [ "ていぎ" ], "comment": "definition" },
	{ "question": "定規", "answers": [ "じょうぎ" ], "comment": "(measuring) ruler" },
	{ "question": "定評", "answers": [ "ていひょう" ], "comment": "established opinion; established reputation; acknowledged authority; recognized scholar" },
	{ "question": "定説", "answers": [ "ていせつ" ], "comment": "established theory; accepted opinion; accepted explanation" },
	{ "question": "定量", "answers": [ "ていりょう" ], "comment": "fixed quantity" },
	{ "question": "定額", "answers": [ "ていがく" ], "comment": "ration; fixed amount" },
	{ "question": "定食", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "set meal; special (of the day)" },
	{ "question": "宛先", "answers": [ "あてさき" ], "comment": "address; destination" },
	{ "question": "宛名", "answers": [ "あてな" ], "comment": "(addressee's) name; (recipient's) name and address" },
	{ "question": "宝", "answers": [ "たから" ], "comment": "treasure" },
	{ "question": "宝くじ", "answers": [ "たからクジ", "たからくじ" ], "comment": "lottery" },
	{ "question": "宝庫", "answers": [ "ほうこ" ], "comment": "treasury; treasure house" },
	{ "question": "宝物", "answers": [ "たからもの", "ほうもつ" ], "comment": "treasure; treasured item; prized possession" },
	{ "question": "宝石", "answers": [ "ほうせき" ], "comment": "gem; jewel; precious stone" },
	{ "question": "宝飾", "answers": [ "ほうしょく" ], "comment": "jewels and ornaments; jewelry; jewellery" },
	{ "question": "実", "answers": [ "じち", "み", "じつ" ], "comment": "truth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; fidelity\ncontent; substance\n(good) result /\n fruit; nut\nseed\n(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc." },
	{ "question": "実に", "answers": [ "じつに", "まことに", "げに" ], "comment": "indeed; really; absolutely; truly; actually; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "実は", "answers": [ "じつは" ], "comment": "as a matter of fact; by the way; to tell you the truth; to be honest; frankly" },
	{ "question": "実り", "answers": [ "みのり" ], "comment": "ripening (of a crop)\ncrop; harvest" },
	{ "question": "実る", "answers": [ "みのる" ], "comment": "to bear fruit; to ripen" },
	{ "question": "実体", "answers": [ "じったい" ], "comment": "substance; entity; object" },
	{ "question": "実例", "answers": [ "じつれい" ], "comment": "example; illustration; precedent" },
	{ "question": "実像", "answers": [ "じつぞう" ], "comment": "real image\nreal form; real-life image; true picture; actual conditions; actual circumstances" },
	{ "question": "実兄", "answers": [ "じっけい" ], "comment": "one's own elder brother" },
	{ "question": "実刑", "answers": [ "じっけい" ], "comment": "jail sentence; gaol sentence\nimprisonment without a stay of execution" },
	{ "question": "実利", "answers": [ "じつり" ], "comment": "use; utility; profit; gain" },
	{ "question": "実力", "answers": [ "じつりょく" ], "comment": "(real) ability; true strength; merit; efficiency; competency\narms; force" },
	{ "question": "実力行使", "answers": [ "じつりょくこうし" ], "comment": "use of force" },
	{ "question": "実効", "answers": [ "じっこう" ], "comment": "practical effect; efficacy; efficiency" },
	{ "question": "実務", "answers": [ "じつむ" ], "comment": "practical business; practical work experience; practicum; practice" },
	{ "question": "実勢", "answers": [ "じっせい" ], "comment": "actual; real; true" },
	{ "question": "実名", "answers": [ "じつめい" ], "comment": "real name" },
	{ "question": "実在", "answers": [ "じつざい" ], "comment": "reality; existence" },
	{ "question": "実地", "answers": [ "じっち" ], "comment": "practice\nthe actual site" },
	{ "question": "実子", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "biological child; one's own child" },
	{ "question": "実家", "answers": [ "じっか" ], "comment": "(one's parents') home" },
	{ "question": "実弟", "answers": [ "じってい" ], "comment": "one's (biological) younger brother" },
	{ "question": "実弾", "answers": [ "じつだん" ], "comment": "live bullets; live ammunition; ball cartridge; money" },
	{ "question": "実情", "answers": [ "じつじょう" ], "comment": "real condition; actual circumstances; actual state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "実感", "answers": [ "じっかん" ], "comment": "real feeling; actual feeling\nto actually feel; to have a real feeling (that ...); to experience personally" },
	{ "question": "実態", "answers": [ "じったい" ], "comment": "true state; actual condition; reality" },
	{ "question": "実態調査", "answers": [ "じったいちょうさ" ], "comment": "factual investigation" },
	{ "question": "実戦", "answers": [ "じっせん" ], "comment": "combat; actual fighting" },
	{ "question": "実技", "answers": [ "じつぎ" ], "comment": "practical skill" },
	{ "question": "実数", "answers": [ "じっすう" ], "comment": "real number" },
	{ "question": "実施", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "enforcement; implementation; putting into practice; carrying out; operation; working (e.g. working parameters); enactment" },
	{ "question": "実業", "answers": [ "じつぎょう" ], "comment": "industry; business" },
	{ "question": "実業家", "answers": [ "じつぎょうか" ], "comment": "businessman; industrialist" },
	{ "question": "実権", "answers": [ "じっけん" ], "comment": "real power" },
	{ "question": "実況", "answers": [ "じっきょう" ], "comment": "actual state (of things); real state; actual condition; real condition; actual scene\nlive; on-the-scene\nreporting live; live coverage; live broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "実演", "answers": [ "じつえん" ], "comment": "demonstration; presentation\nstage show; performance" },
	{ "question": "実物", "answers": [ "じつぶつ" ], "comment": "real thing; original; actual" },
	{ "question": "実現", "answers": [ "じつげん" ], "comment": "implementation (e.g. of a system); materialization; materialisation; realization; realisation" },
	{ "question": "実用", "answers": [ "じつよう" ], "comment": "practical use; utility" },
	{ "question": "実用的", "answers": [ "じつようてき" ], "comment": "practical; useful; utilitarian; pragmatic" },
	{ "question": "実相", "answers": [ "じっそう" ], "comment": "reality; real state of affairs; true state of affairs\ntrue form of all things as they are; ultimate reality" },
	{ "question": "実績", "answers": [ "じっせき" ], "comment": "achievements; actual results; accomplishments; past results; track record" },
	{ "question": "実習", "answers": [ "じっしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training (esp. practical and hands-on); drill" },
	{ "question": "実行", "answers": [ "じっこう" ], "comment": "practice; practising; performance; execution (e.g. program) (programme); realization; realisation; implementation" },
	{ "question": "実証", "answers": [ "じっしょう" ], "comment": "demonstration; verification; substantiation; actual proof" },
	{ "question": "実話", "answers": [ "じつわ" ], "comment": "true story" },
	{ "question": "実費", "answers": [ "じっぴ" ], "comment": "actual expense; cost price" },
	{ "question": "実質", "answers": [ "じっしつ" ], "comment": "substance; essence\nreal (in economics, vs. nominal, e.g. real interest rate); substantive; substantial; essential; tangible" },
	{ "question": "実質的", "answers": [ "じっしつてき" ], "comment": "substantial; real (as opposed to nominal)" },
	{ "question": "実践", "answers": [ "じっせん" ], "comment": "practice; practising; putting into practice; implementation" },
	{ "question": "実際", "answers": [ "じっさい" ], "comment": "practicality; practical\nreality; actuality; actual conditions\nbhutakoti (limit of reality)" },
	{ "question": "実際は", "answers": [ "じっさいは" ], "comment": "in fact; actually; to tell the truth" },
	{ "question": "実験", "answers": [ "じっけん" ], "comment": "experiment" },
	{ "question": "実験室", "answers": [ "じっけんしつ" ], "comment": "laboratory" },
	{ "question": "客", "answers": [ "きゃく", "かく" ], "comment": "guest; visitor\ncustomer; client; shopper; spectator; audience; tourist; sightseer; passenger" },
	{ "question": "客体", "answers": [ "きゃくたい", "かくたい" ], "comment": "object" },
	{ "question": "客員", "answers": [ "きゃくいん", "かくいん" ], "comment": "guest (associate) member" },
	{ "question": "客室", "answers": [ "きゃくしつ" ], "comment": "guest room (at a hotel); guest cabin (on a boat); passenger cabin (on a plane)\ndrawing room" },
	{ "question": "客席", "answers": [ "きゃくせき" ], "comment": "guest seating (e.g. theater, stadium); passenger seat (e.g. taxi)\naudience" },
	{ "question": "客船", "answers": [ "きゃくせん" ], "comment": "passenger boat" },
	{ "question": "客観", "answers": [ "かっかん", "かくかん", "きゃっかん" ], "comment": "objectivity; objective; object (philosophical)" },
	{ "question": "客観的", "answers": [ "きゃっかんてき" ], "comment": "objective" },
	{ "question": "客足", "answers": [ "きゃくあし" ], "comment": "customer traffic; customers; custom" },
	{ "question": "客車", "answers": [ "かくしゃ", "きゃくしゃ" ], "comment": "passenger car" },
	{ "question": "客間", "answers": [ "きゃくま" ], "comment": "parlor; parlour; guest room" },
	{ "question": "宣伝", "answers": [ "せんでん" ], "comment": "publicity; advertisement; advertising; propaganda" },
	{ "question": "宣告", "answers": [ "せんこく" ], "comment": "sentence; verdict; pronouncement" },
	{ "question": "宣戦", "answers": [ "せんせん" ], "comment": "declaration of war" },
	{ "question": "宣教師", "answers": [ "せんきょうし" ], "comment": "missionary" },
	{ "question": "宣言", "answers": [ "せんげん" ], "comment": "declaration; proclamation; announcement" },
	{ "question": "宣誓", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "oath; abjuration; pledge" },
	{ "question": "室", "answers": [ "しつ" ], "comment": "room\nwife (of someone of high rank)\nscabbard\nChinese \"Encampment\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "室内", "answers": [ "しつない" ], "comment": "indoor; inside the room" },
	{ "question": "室内楽", "answers": [ "しつないがく" ], "comment": "chamber music" },
	{ "question": "室町", "answers": [ "むろまち" ], "comment": "Muromachi (era 1392-1573, or 1333-1573, or 1336-1573)" },
	{ "question": "室長", "answers": [ "しつちょう" ], "comment": "section chief; laboratory manager; office head; room monitor" },
	{ "question": "宮中", "answers": [ "きゅうちゅう" ], "comment": "imperial court" },
	{ "question": "宮内庁", "answers": [ "くないちょう" ], "comment": "Imperial Household Agency" },
	{ "question": "宮廷", "answers": [ "きゅうてい" ], "comment": "imperial court; royal court" },
	{ "question": "宮殿", "answers": [ "きゅうでん" ], "comment": "palace" },
	{ "question": "宰相", "answers": [ "さいしょう" ], "comment": "prime minister" },
	{ "question": "害", "answers": [ "がい" ], "comment": "injury; harm; evil influence; damage" },
	{ "question": "害する", "answers": [ "がいする" ], "comment": "to injure; to damage; to harm; to hurt\nto kill\nto hinder; to obstruct" },
	{ "question": "害虫", "answers": [ "がいちゅう" ], "comment": "harmful insect; noxious insect; vermin; pest" },
	{ "question": "宴", "answers": [ "えん", "うたげ" ], "comment": "party; banquet; feast" },
	{ "question": "宴会", "answers": [ "えんかい" ], "comment": "party; banquet; reception; feast; dinner" },
	{ "question": "家", "answers": [ "け", "いえ" ], "comment": "house; residence; dwelling\nfamily; household\nlineage; family name /\n house (e.g. of Tokugawa); family" },
	{ "question": "家主", "answers": [ "いえぬし", "やぬし" ], "comment": "landlord; landlady\nhouse owner; home owner; head of the household" },
	{ "question": "家事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "housework; domestic chores\nfamily affairs; household matters" },
	{ "question": "家人", "answers": [ "かじん" ], "comment": "the family; one's folks" },
	{ "question": "家元", "answers": [ "いえもと" ], "comment": "head of a school (of music, dance); head family of a school" },
	{ "question": "家具", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "furniture" },
	{ "question": "家内", "answers": [ "かない" ], "comment": "(my) wife\ninside the home; one's family" },
	{ "question": "家出", "answers": [ "いえで" ], "comment": "running away from home; elopement\nouting; going out\nbecoming a Buddhist monk; entering the priesthood" },
	{ "question": "家宅", "answers": [ "かたく" ], "comment": "domicile; premises" },
	{ "question": "家屋", "answers": [ "かおく" ], "comment": "house; building" },
	{ "question": "家庭", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "home; family; household" },
	{ "question": "家庭内", "answers": [ "かていない" ], "comment": "domestic; in the family" },
	{ "question": "家庭教師", "answers": [ "かていきょうし" ], "comment": "private tutor; coach; governess" },
	{ "question": "家庭科", "answers": [ "かていか" ], "comment": "home economics" },
	{ "question": "家政婦", "answers": [ "かせいふ" ], "comment": "housekeeper; maid" },
	{ "question": "家族", "answers": [ "かぞく" ], "comment": "family; members of a family" },
	{ "question": "家族計画", "answers": [ "かぞくけいかく" ], "comment": "family planning" },
	{ "question": "家柄", "answers": [ "いえがら" ], "comment": "social standing of a family; lineage; parentage; pedigree\ngood family" },
	{ "question": "家業", "answers": [ "かぎょう" ], "comment": "family business; trade; occupation; line of work; one's father's occupation" },
	{ "question": "家畜", "answers": [ "かちく" ], "comment": "domestic animals; livestock; cattle" },
	{ "question": "家系", "answers": [ "かけい" ], "comment": "family lineage" },
	{ "question": "家裁", "answers": [ "かさい" ], "comment": "family court" },
	{ "question": "家計", "answers": [ "かけい" ], "comment": "household economy; family finances" },
	{ "question": "家計簿", "answers": [ "かけいぼ" ], "comment": "household account book" },
	{ "question": "家財", "answers": [ "かざい" ], "comment": "household belongings; household goods\nfamily fortune; family assets" },
	{ "question": "家賃", "answers": [ "やちん" ], "comment": "rent" },
	{ "question": "家電", "answers": [ "かでん" ], "comment": "consumer electronics; consumer electrical appliances" },
	{ "question": "容器", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "container; vessel" },
	{ "question": "容姿", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "(physical) appearance (of a person); one's face and figure" },
	{ "question": "容易", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "easy; simple; plain" },
	{ "question": "容疑", "answers": [ "ようぎ" ], "comment": "suspicion; charge" },
	{ "question": "容疑者", "answers": [ "ようぎしゃ" ], "comment": "suspect (person)" },
	{ "question": "容積", "answers": [ "ようせき" ], "comment": "capacity; volume" },
	{ "question": "容認", "answers": [ "ようにん" ], "comment": "approval" },
	{ "question": "容赦", "answers": [ "ようしゃ" ], "comment": "pardon; forgiveness; mercy\nleniency; going easy (on someone)" },
	{ "question": "容赦なく", "answers": [ "ようしゃなく" ], "comment": "relentlessly; mercilessly" },
	{ "question": "容量", "answers": [ "ようりょう" ], "comment": "capacity; volume\ncapacitance" },
	{ "question": "宿", "answers": [ "やど" ], "comment": "lodging; inn; hotel\nhouse; home; dwelling\nhome of a servant's parents (or guarantor, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "宿命", "answers": [ "しゅくめい" ], "comment": "fate; destiny; predestination" },
	{ "question": "宿屋", "answers": [ "やどや" ], "comment": "inn" },
	{ "question": "宿泊", "answers": [ "しゅくはく" ], "comment": "lodging" },
	{ "question": "宿舎", "answers": [ "しゅくしゃ" ], "comment": "lodging house" },
	{ "question": "宿題", "answers": [ "しゅくだい" ], "comment": "homework" },
	{ "question": "宿駅", "answers": [ "しゅくえき" ], "comment": "relay station; post station; stage" },
	{ "question": "寂しい", "answers": [ "さびしい", "さみしい" ], "comment": "lonely; lonesome; solitary; desolate" },
	{ "question": "寂然", "answers": [ "じゃくねん", "せきぜん" ], "comment": "lonely; desolate\nforlornness; desolation" },
	{ "question": "寄せ", "answers": [ "よせ" ], "comment": "last moves (in go, shogi, or chess); endgame\ngathering; collecting; coming together" },
	{ "question": "寄せる", "answers": [ "よせる" ], "comment": "to come near; to let someone approach\nto bring near; to bring together; to collect; to gather\nto deliver (opinion, news, etc.); to send (e.g. a letter); to contribute; to donate\nto let someone drop by\nto add (numbers)\nto have feelings for (love, goodwill, trust, etc.)\nto rely upon for a time; to depend on\nto use as a pretext\nto put aside\nto press; to push; to force\nto include; to welcome (in a group); to let in" },
	{ "question": "寄せ集め", "answers": [ "よせあつめ" ], "comment": "mish-mash; miscellany; medley; odds and ends; gathering" },
	{ "question": "寄り道", "answers": [ "よりみち" ], "comment": "dropping in on the way; breaking one's journey; making a stopover; going out of one's way" },
	{ "question": "寄り集まる", "answers": [ "よりあつまる" ], "comment": "to gather together" },
	{ "question": "寄る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to come near; to be close to\nto gather (in one place); to come together; to meet\nto stop by (while on one's way to another place); to drop by; to make a short visit\nto grow old; to grow high (number, etc.)\nto grow (wrinkly)\nto lean against; to recline on\nto push one's opponent while holding their belt\nto decide on a price and come to a deal\nto be swayed by (a person); to yield to" },
	{ "question": "寄与", "answers": [ "きよ" ], "comment": "contribution; service" },
	{ "question": "寄付", "answers": [ "きふ" ], "comment": "contribution; donation" },
	{ "question": "寄席", "answers": [ "よせ", "よせせき" ], "comment": "entertainment hall (for rakugo, manzai, magic, music, etc.); vaudeville theater (theatre); music hall" },
	{ "question": "寄港", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "stopping at a port" },
	{ "question": "寄生", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "parasitism; parasitic" },
	{ "question": "寄生虫", "answers": [ "きせいちゅう" ], "comment": "parasite" },
	{ "question": "寄贈", "answers": [ "きそう", "きぞう" ], "comment": "donation; presentation; gift" },
	{ "question": "寄金", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "contribution; donation" },
	{ "question": "寄附", "answers": [ "きふ" ], "comment": "contribution; donation" },
	{ "question": "寅", "answers": [ "とら" ], "comment": "third sign of Chinese zodiac (The Tiger, 3am-5am, east-northeast, January)" },
	{ "question": "密入国", "answers": [ "みつにゅうこく", "みつにゅうごく" ], "comment": "smuggling oneself into a country; illegal immigration" },
	{ "question": "密売", "answers": [ "みつばい" ], "comment": "smuggling; bootlegging; illicit trade" },
	{ "question": "密室", "answers": [ "みっしつ" ], "comment": "room that cannot be entered (e.g. because it's locked from the inside)\nsecret room" },
	{ "question": "密度", "answers": [ "みつど" ], "comment": "density" },
	{ "question": "密接", "answers": [ "みっせつ" ], "comment": "related; connected; close; intimate" },
	{ "question": "密林", "answers": [ "みつりん" ], "comment": "close thicket; dense forest; jungle\namazon.com" },
	{ "question": "密猟", "answers": [ "みつりょう" ], "comment": "poaching" },
	{ "question": "密着", "answers": [ "みっちゃく" ], "comment": "glued to; closely related to\ngiving total coverage to the key figure(s) of a TV or film documentary" },
	{ "question": "密約", "answers": [ "みつやく" ], "comment": "secret agreement" },
	{ "question": "密航", "answers": [ "みっこう" ], "comment": "smuggling" },
	{ "question": "密輸", "answers": [ "みつゆ" ], "comment": "smuggling; contraband trade" },
	{ "question": "密集", "answers": [ "みっしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; close formation; dense" },
	{ "question": "富", "answers": [ "とみ" ], "comment": "riches; wealth; fortune\nresources\nlottery" },
	{ "question": "富む", "answers": [ "とむ" ], "comment": "to be rich; to become rich; to be abundant (with); to abound (with); to be rich (in)" },
	{ "question": "富士山", "answers": [ "ふじやま", "ふじさん" ], "comment": "Mount Fuji; Mt. Fuji; Fujiyama; Fuji-san" },
	{ "question": "富者", "answers": [ "ふしゃ", "ふうしゃ" ], "comment": "rich person; millionaire; the wealthy" },
	{ "question": "富裕", "answers": [ "ふゆう" ], "comment": "wealth; riches; opulence" },
	{ "question": "富豪", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "wealthy person; millionaire" },
	{ "question": "寒い", "answers": [ "さむい", "さぶい" ], "comment": "cold (e.g. weather)\nuninteresting (esp. joke); lame; dull; weak; corny" },
	{ "question": "寒さ", "answers": [ "さむさ" ], "comment": "coldness" },
	{ "question": "寒冷", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "cold; coldness; chilliness" },
	{ "question": "寒暖計", "answers": [ "かんだんけい" ], "comment": "thermometer" },
	{ "question": "寒気", "answers": [ "かんき", "さむけ" ], "comment": "chill; the shivers; shivering fit\ncold; coldness; cold air" },
	{ "question": "寒波", "answers": [ "かんぱ" ], "comment": "cold wave" },
	{ "question": "寛大", "answers": [ "かんだい" ], "comment": "tolerant; generous; lenient; broad-minded; magnanimous" },
	{ "question": "寛容", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "tolerance; open-mindedness; forbearance; generosity" },
	{ "question": "寝", "answers": [ "しん", "ね" ], "comment": "sleep" },
	{ "question": "寝かす", "answers": [ "ねかす" ], "comment": "to put to sleep; to lay (something) on its side" },
	{ "question": "寝かせる", "answers": [ "ねかせる" ], "comment": "to put to bed\nto lay down lengthwise; to put a thing on its side\nto set something aside unused; to let lie idle\nto ferment; to lay down (wine)" },
	{ "question": "寝ぼける", "answers": [ "ねぼける" ], "comment": "to be still half asleep; to be half awake; to be not yet quite awake" },
	{ "question": "寝る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "to lie down\nto go to bed; to lie in bed\nto sleep (lying down)\nto sleep (with someone, i.e. have intercourse)\nto lie idle" },
	{ "question": "寝付く", "answers": [ "ねつく" ], "comment": "to go to bed; to go to sleep; to fall asleep\nto be laid up (with a cold); to be ill in bed" },
	{ "question": "寝具", "answers": [ "しんぐ" ], "comment": "bedding" },
	{ "question": "寝冷え", "answers": [ "ねびえ" ], "comment": "get chilled while asleep" },
	{ "question": "寝台", "answers": [ "ねだい", "しんだい" ], "comment": "bed; couch" },
	{ "question": "寝坊", "answers": [ "ねぼう" ], "comment": "sleeping in late; oversleeping\nlate riser; sleepyhead" },
	{ "question": "寝室", "answers": [ "しんしつ" ], "comment": "bedroom" },
	{ "question": "寝巻", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "sleep-wear; nightclothes; pyjamas; pajamas; nightgown; nightdress" },
	{ "question": "寝巻き", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "sleep-wear; nightclothes; pyjamas; pajamas; nightgown; nightdress" },
	{ "question": "寝床", "answers": [ "ねどこ" ], "comment": "bed; berth; crib; cot; kip" },
	{ "question": "寝息", "answers": [ "ねいき" ], "comment": "sleeper's breathing" },
	{ "question": "寝泊まり", "answers": [ "ねとまり" ], "comment": "staying at; lodging at" },
	{ "question": "寝相", "answers": [ "ねぞう" ], "comment": "one's sleeping posture" },
	{ "question": "寝言", "answers": [ "ねごと" ], "comment": "sleep-talking\nnonsense; gibberish" },
	{ "question": "寝転ぶ", "answers": [ "ねころぶ" ], "comment": "to lie down; to throw oneself down" },
	{ "question": "寝返り", "answers": [ "ねがえり" ], "comment": "turning over while sleeping in bed\nbetrayal; double-crossing" },
	{ "question": "寝返る", "answers": [ "ねがえる" ], "comment": "to change sides; to double-cross; to betray" },
	{ "question": "寝過ごす", "answers": [ "ねすごす" ], "comment": "to oversleep" },
	{ "question": "寝間着", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "sleep-wear; nightclothes; pyjamas; pajamas; nightgown; nightdress" },
	{ "question": "寝顔", "answers": [ "ねがお" ], "comment": "sleeping face" },
	{ "question": "察する", "answers": [ "さっする" ], "comment": "to guess; to sense; to presume; to judge\nto sympathize with; to sympathise with" },
	{ "question": "察知", "answers": [ "さっち" ], "comment": "sense; infer" },
	{ "question": "寡占", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "oligopoly" },
	{ "question": "寡婦", "answers": [ "やもめ", "かふ" ], "comment": "widow; divorced woman not remarried; unmarried woman" },
	{ "question": "審判", "answers": [ "しんばん", "しんぱん" ], "comment": "refereeing; trial; judgement; judgment; umpire; referee" },
	{ "question": "審査", "answers": [ "しんさ" ], "comment": "judging; inspection; examination; investigation; review" },
	{ "question": "審理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "trial" },
	{ "question": "審議", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "deliberation" },
	{ "question": "寮", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "hostel; dormitory\nbureau (government department beneath a ministry under the ritsuryo system)" },
	{ "question": "寸前", "answers": [ "すんぜん" ], "comment": "on the verge; on the brink; just in front of; just before" },
	{ "question": "寸断", "answers": [ "すんだん" ], "comment": "cut (tear) to pieces" },
	{ "question": "寸法", "answers": [ "すんぽう" ], "comment": "measurement; size; extent; dimension\nplan; intention; arrangement; schedule" },
	{ "question": "寺", "answers": [ "てら" ], "comment": "temple (Buddhist)" },
	{ "question": "寺院", "answers": [ "じいん" ], "comment": "temple" },
	{ "question": "対", "answers": [ "つい", "たい" ], "comment": "opposite; opposition\nversus; vs.; v.\nto (e.g. \"winning a game five to three\")\nequal footing; equal terms\nagainst ...; anti-; toward ...; to ... /\n pair; couple; set\nantithesis\ncounter for items that come in pairs\ncounter for sets (of clothes, small furniture, utensils, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "対する", "answers": [ "たいする" ], "comment": "to face (each other); to be facing\nto be directed toward (the future, etc.); to be in response to; to be related to\nto receive (a client, etc.)\nto compare with; to contrast with; to be in opposition with; to be opposed to\nto confront; to oppose; to compete with" },
	{ "question": "対中", "answers": [ "たいちゅう" ], "comment": "relating to China" },
	{ "question": "対価", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "compensation; equivalent value; consideration" },
	{ "question": "対処", "answers": [ "たいしょ" ], "comment": "dealing with; coping with" },
	{ "question": "対向", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "counter-; corresponding; face; opposite" },
	{ "question": "対地", "answers": [ "たいち" ], "comment": "ground to ground" },
	{ "question": "対外", "answers": [ "たいがい" ], "comment": "external; foreign" },
	{ "question": "対局", "answers": [ "たいきょく" ], "comment": "(playing) a game of go, shogi or chess, etc." },
	{ "question": "対岸", "answers": [ "たいがん" ], "comment": "opposite shore" },
	{ "question": "対峙", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "confrontation; standing facing each other (e.g. mountains, buildings)\nsquaring off against (adversaries, armies, forces); standing off against; holding one's own with" },
	{ "question": "対応", "answers": [ "たいおう" ], "comment": "interaction; correspondence; coping with; dealing with; support; response; reception\nsoftware support; ability of a computer system to run specific software; compatibility" },
	{ "question": "対戦", "answers": [ "たいせん" ], "comment": "waging war; competition" },
	{ "question": "対抗", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対日", "answers": [ "たいにち" ], "comment": "with respect to Japan; with Japan" },
	{ "question": "対案", "answers": [ "たいあん" ], "comment": "counter-proposal; counter-suggestion" },
	{ "question": "対極", "answers": [ "たいきょく" ], "comment": "antipodes\nother (opposite) extreme; opposite; antithesis" },
	{ "question": "対比", "answers": [ "たいひ" ], "comment": "contrast; comparison" },
	{ "question": "対決", "answers": [ "たいけつ" ], "comment": "confrontation; showdown" },
	{ "question": "対照", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "contrast; antithesis; comparison" },
	{ "question": "対照的", "answers": [ "たいしょうてき" ], "comment": "contrastive" },
	{ "question": "対症療法", "answers": [ "たいしょうりょうほう" ], "comment": "symptomatic therapy; makeshift solution" },
	{ "question": "対称", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "symmetry\nsecond person" },
	{ "question": "対立", "answers": [ "たいりつ" ], "comment": "confrontation; opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対等", "answers": [ "たいとう" ], "comment": "equality (esp. of status, on equal terms); equivalence\nequivalent; equal" },
	{ "question": "対策", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "measure; provision; step; countermeasure; counterplan; countermove" },
	{ "question": "対米", "answers": [ "たいべい" ], "comment": "relating to the USA; toward America; with America" },
	{ "question": "対話", "answers": [ "たいわ" ], "comment": "dialogue; discussion; conversation; interaction" },
	{ "question": "対談", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "talk; dialogue; conversation" },
	{ "question": "対論", "answers": [ "たいろん" ], "comment": "arguing face to face" },
	{ "question": "対象", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "target; object (of worship, study, etc.); subject (of taxation, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "対面", "answers": [ "たいめん" ], "comment": "interview; meeting\nopposing (traffic, etc.); facing; confronting" },
	{ "question": "寿", "answers": [ "ことぶき" ], "comment": "congratulations; felicitations; best wishes\nlongevity; long life" },
	{ "question": "寿司", "answers": [ "すし" ], "comment": "sushi; anything made with vinegared rice (may also contain vegetables, spices, fish, or other delicacies)" },
	{ "question": "寿命", "answers": [ "じゅみょう" ], "comment": "life span" },
	{ "question": "封", "answers": [ "ふう" ], "comment": "seal" },
	{ "question": "封じる", "answers": [ "ふうじる" ], "comment": "to seal (letter)\nto prevent; to forbid; to block" },
	{ "question": "封じ手", "answers": [ "ふうじて" ], "comment": "a sealed move" },
	{ "question": "封建主義", "answers": [ "ほうけんしゅぎ" ], "comment": "feudalism" },
	{ "question": "封建的", "answers": [ "ほうけんてき" ], "comment": "feudal" },
	{ "question": "封書", "answers": [ "ふうしょ" ], "comment": "sealed letter" },
	{ "question": "封筒", "answers": [ "ふうとう" ], "comment": "envelope" },
	{ "question": "封鎖", "answers": [ "ふうさ" ], "comment": "blockade\nfreezing (funds)" },
	{ "question": "専任", "answers": [ "せんにん" ], "comment": "full-time service" },
	{ "question": "専修", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "specialization; specialisation" },
	{ "question": "専務", "answers": [ "せんむ" ], "comment": "special duty; being in sole charge of a duty\nsenior managing director; executive director" },
	{ "question": "専売", "answers": [ "せんばい" ], "comment": "monopoly" },
	{ "question": "専守防衛", "answers": [ "せんしゅぼうえい" ], "comment": "nonaggressive defense (policy) (defence)" },
	{ "question": "専属", "answers": [ "せんぞく" ], "comment": "exclusive; attached to; specialist" },
	{ "question": "専従", "answers": [ "せんじゅう" ], "comment": "working exclusively for; working full-time (for)" },
	{ "question": "専念", "answers": [ "せんねん" ], "comment": "absorption; giving undivided attention; devoting oneself (to)" },
	{ "question": "専攻", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "major subject; special study" },
	{ "question": "専業", "answers": [ "せんぎょう" ], "comment": "special occupation; principal occupation; specialty; monopoly" },
	{ "question": "専用", "answers": [ "せんよう" ], "comment": "exclusive use; personal use; dedicated\nprivate (e.g. network)" },
	{ "question": "専門", "answers": [ "せんもん" ], "comment": "speciality; specialty; subject of study; expert; area of expertise" },
	{ "question": "専門医", "answers": [ "せんもんい" ], "comment": "medical specialist" },
	{ "question": "専門学校", "answers": [ "せんもんガッコウ", "せんもんガッコ", "せんもんがっこう" ], "comment": "vocational school; technical school" },
	{ "question": "専門家", "answers": [ "せんもんか" ], "comment": "specialist; expert; professional; authority; pundit" },
	{ "question": "専門店", "answers": [ "せんもんてん" ], "comment": "specialist shops" },
	{ "question": "専門的", "answers": [ "せんもんてき" ], "comment": "technical (e.g. discussion); exclusive; professional" },
	{ "question": "射す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to shine" },
	{ "question": "射撃", "answers": [ "しゃげき" ], "comment": "firing; shooting; fire; gunshot; marksmanship" },
	{ "question": "射止める", "answers": [ "いとめる" ], "comment": "to shoot dead; to make something one's own" },
	{ "question": "射殺", "answers": [ "しゃさつ" ], "comment": "shooting to death" },
	{ "question": "射程", "answers": [ "しゃてい" ], "comment": "range (e.g. of a rifle, missile, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "射精", "answers": [ "しゃせい" ], "comment": "ejaculation" },
	{ "question": "将", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "commander; general; leader" },
	{ "question": "将兵", "answers": [ "しょうへい" ], "comment": "officers and men" },
	{ "question": "将来", "answers": [ "しょうらい" ], "comment": "future (usually near); prospects" },
	{ "question": "将来像", "answers": [ "しょうらいぞう" ], "comment": "vision of the future" },
	{ "question": "将来性", "answers": [ "しょうらいせい" ], "comment": "future prospects; promise" },
	{ "question": "将校", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "commissioned officer" },
	{ "question": "将棋", "answers": [ "しょうぎ" ], "comment": "shogi; Japanese chess; xianqi" },
	{ "question": "将軍", "answers": [ "しょうぐん" ], "comment": "general; shogun" },
	{ "question": "尊い", "answers": [ "たっとい", "とうとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "尊ぶ", "answers": [ "たっとぶ", "とうとぶ" ], "comment": "to value; to prize; to esteem; to respect" },
	{ "question": "尊厳", "answers": [ "そんげん" ], "comment": "dignity; majesty; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "尊敬", "answers": [ "そんけい" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; reverence; honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "尊重", "answers": [ "そんちょう" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; regard" },
	{ "question": "尋ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to ask; to enquire; to inquire\nto search; to look for; to look into; to investigate" },
	{ "question": "尋問", "answers": [ "じんもん" ], "comment": "cross-examination; interrogation; questioning" },
	{ "question": "導く", "answers": [ "みちびく" ], "comment": "to guide; to lead; to show the way; to conduct\nto derive; to deduce" },
	{ "question": "導入", "answers": [ "どうにゅう" ], "comment": "introduction; bringing in; leading in; installation" },
	{ "question": "小さい", "answers": [ "ちいさい" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "小さじ", "answers": [ "こさじ" ], "comment": "teaspoon" },
	{ "question": "小さな", "answers": [ "ちいさな" ], "comment": "small; little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "小中学生", "answers": [ "しょうちゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "elementary and middle school pupils" },
	{ "question": "小人", "answers": [ "こども", "こびと", "しょうじん", "しょうにん" ], "comment": "child; small person\ndwarf; midget\nnarrow-minded person; mean person" },
	{ "question": "小便", "answers": [ "しょんべん", "しょうべん" ], "comment": "urine; piss; pee\nbreaking a contract" },
	{ "question": "小僧", "answers": [ "こぞう" ], "comment": "youngster\nyoung Buddhist priest\nyoung shopboy; errand boy; apprentice" },
	{ "question": "小児", "answers": [ "しょうに" ], "comment": "young child; infant" },
	{ "question": "小児病", "answers": [ "しょうにびょう" ], "comment": "childhood diseases" },
	{ "question": "小児科", "answers": [ "しょうにか" ], "comment": "pediatrics" },
	{ "question": "小冊子", "answers": [ "しょうさっし" ], "comment": "booklet; pamphlet" },
	{ "question": "小切手", "answers": [ "こぎって" ], "comment": "cheque; check" },
	{ "question": "小刻み", "answers": [ "こきざみ" ], "comment": "mincing\ndoing something repeatedly over a short interval (trembling, stepping quickly, etc.)\nbit by bit; little by little" },
	{ "question": "小包", "answers": [ "こづつみ" ], "comment": "parcel; package" },
	{ "question": "小包み", "answers": [ "こづつみ" ], "comment": "parcel; package" },
	{ "question": "小口", "answers": [ "こぐち" ], "comment": "cut end; edge (of a page, etc.)\nsmall amount; small sum\nbeginning; clue\ntiger's den; jaws of death; dangerous place" },
	{ "question": "小品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "short piece (of music, writing); small work (painting, sculpture, etc.); literary sketch; essay\nsmall article; small item" },
	{ "question": "小国", "answers": [ "しょうこく" ], "comment": "small country" },
	{ "question": "小型", "answers": [ "こがた" ], "comment": "small; small-sized; small-scale; miniature" },
	{ "question": "小声", "answers": [ "こごえ" ], "comment": "low voice; whisper" },
	{ "question": "小売", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "retail" },
	{ "question": "小売り", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "retail" },
	{ "question": "小売り店", "answers": [ "こうりてん" ], "comment": "retail store; retail shop" },
	{ "question": "小売価格", "answers": [ "こうりかかく" ], "comment": "retail price" },
	{ "question": "小売店", "answers": [ "こうりてん" ], "comment": "retail store; retail shop" },
	{ "question": "小学", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "elementary school; primary school; grade school" },
	{ "question": "小学校", "answers": [ "しょうがっこう" ], "comment": "primary school; elementary school; grade school" },
	{ "question": "小学生", "answers": [ "しょうがくせい" ], "comment": "elementary school student; primary school student; grade school student" },
	{ "question": "小屋", "answers": [ "しょうおく", "こや" ], "comment": "hut; cabin; shed; (animal) pen\nsmall theatre (theater); temporary playhouse; circus tent; booth\none's own house" },
	{ "question": "小山", "answers": [ "こやま" ], "comment": "hill; knoll" },
	{ "question": "小島", "answers": [ "しょうとう", "こじま", "おじま" ], "comment": "small island; islet" },
	{ "question": "小川", "answers": [ "おがわ" ], "comment": "streamlet; brook" },
	{ "question": "小差", "answers": [ "しょうさ" ], "comment": "slight difference" },
	{ "question": "小幅", "answers": [ "こはば" ], "comment": "small; narrow\nsingle-breadth cloth (approx. 36 cm wide)" },
	{ "question": "小康", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "lull" },
	{ "question": "小惑星", "answers": [ "しょうわくせい" ], "comment": "asteroid" },
	{ "question": "小手先", "answers": [ "こてさき" ], "comment": "tip of one's hand\ncheap (trick); superficial (wit); lukewarm; perfunctory" },
	{ "question": "小指", "answers": [ "こゆび" ], "comment": "little finger; pinky\nlittle toe" },
	{ "question": "小数", "answers": [ "しょうすう" ], "comment": "fraction (part of); decimal fraction" },
	{ "question": "小数点", "answers": [ "しょうすうてん" ], "comment": "decimal point; radix point" },
	{ "question": "小文字", "answers": [ "こもじ" ], "comment": "lower case letters" },
	{ "question": "小柄", "answers": [ "こがら" ], "comment": "small build; small stature; petite\nsmall pattern" },
	{ "question": "小火", "answers": [ "ぼや", "しょうか" ], "comment": "small fire" },
	{ "question": "小牛", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "calf; small cow" },
	{ "question": "小物", "answers": [ "こもの" ], "comment": "accessories; small articles" },
	{ "question": "小結", "answers": [ "こむすび" ], "comment": "wrestler of the fourth highest rank" },
	{ "question": "小羊", "answers": [ "こひつじ" ], "comment": "lamb" },
	{ "question": "小規模", "answers": [ "しょうきぼ" ], "comment": "small scale" },
	{ "question": "小説", "answers": [ "しょうせつ" ], "comment": "novel; (short) story" },
	{ "question": "小説家", "answers": [ "しょうせつか" ], "comment": "novelist; fiction writer" },
	{ "question": "小豆", "answers": [ "あずき", "しょうず" ], "comment": "adzuki bean (Vigna angularis)" },
	{ "question": "小道具", "answers": [ "こどうぐ" ], "comment": "props; (stage) properties; gadgets" },
	{ "question": "小遣い", "answers": [ "こづかい" ], "comment": "pocket money; spending money; pin money; allowance" },
	{ "question": "小選挙区", "answers": [ "しょうせんきょく" ], "comment": "small electoral district; single-member constituency" },
	{ "question": "小量", "answers": [ "しょうりょう" ], "comment": "small dose; small quantity\nnarrowmindedness" },
	{ "question": "小銃", "answers": [ "しょうじゅう" ], "comment": "rifle; small arms" },
	{ "question": "小雨", "answers": [ "しょうう", "こあめ", "こさめ" ], "comment": "light rain; drizzle" },
	{ "question": "小鳥", "answers": [ "ことり" ], "comment": "small bird; songbird\nbirdie; dickeybird; dickybird" },
	{ "question": "小麦", "answers": [ "こむぎ" ], "comment": "wheat" },
	{ "question": "小麦粉", "answers": [ "こむぎこ" ], "comment": "wheat flour" },
	{ "question": "少々", "answers": [ "しょうしょう" ], "comment": "just a minute; small quantity" },
	{ "question": "少し", "answers": [ "すこし" ], "comment": "small quantity; little; few; something\nlittle while\nshort distance" },
	{ "question": "少しずつ", "answers": [ "すこしづつ", "すこしずつ" ], "comment": "little by little" },
	{ "question": "少しも", "answers": [ "すこしも" ], "comment": "anything of; not one bit (with negative sentence)" },
	{ "question": "少ない", "answers": [ "すくない" ], "comment": "few; a little; scarce; insufficient; seldom" },
	{ "question": "少なからず", "answers": [ "すくなからず" ], "comment": "considerably; not a little; in no small numbers" },
	{ "question": "少なくとも", "answers": [ "すくなくとも" ], "comment": "at least" },
	{ "question": "少佐", "answers": [ "しょうさ" ], "comment": "major; lieutenant commander; wing commander" },
	{ "question": "少女", "answers": [ "おとめ", "しょうじょ" ], "comment": "little girl; maiden; young lady; female usually between 7 and 18 years old\nfemale between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period)" },
	{ "question": "少将", "answers": [ "しょうしょう" ], "comment": "major general; rear admiral; air commodore" },
	{ "question": "少年", "answers": [ "しょうねん" ], "comment": "boy; juvenile; young boy; youth; lad" },
	{ "question": "少数", "answers": [ "しょうすう" ], "comment": "minority; few" },
	{ "question": "少数意見", "answers": [ "しょうすういけん" ], "comment": "minority opinion" },
	{ "question": "少量", "answers": [ "しょうりょう" ], "comment": "small dose; small quantity\nnarrowmindedness" },
	{ "question": "少額", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "small sum (e.g. of money); small denomination" },
	{ "question": "尖る", "answers": [ "とんがる", "とがる" ], "comment": "to taper to a point; to become sharp\nto look displeased; to look sour; to be on edge; to be touchy" },
	{ "question": "就く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to ascend (the throne); to accede\nto take (seat, position, course, etc.); to assume\nto start (on a journey); to commence; to depart\nto study (under teacher); to be an apprentice" },
	{ "question": "就任", "answers": [ "しゅうにん" ], "comment": "inauguration; assumption of office" },
	{ "question": "就労", "answers": [ "しゅうろう" ], "comment": "working; being employed; being hired" },
	{ "question": "就学", "answers": [ "しゅうがく" ], "comment": "entering school; school attendance" },
	{ "question": "就寝", "answers": [ "しゅうしん" ], "comment": "going to bed; retiring (for the night)" },
	{ "question": "就業", "answers": [ "しゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "employment; starting work" },
	{ "question": "就活", "answers": [ "しゅうかつ" ], "comment": "job hunting; job searching" },
	{ "question": "就職", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "finding employment; getting a job" },
	{ "question": "就航", "answers": [ "しゅうこう" ], "comment": "going into commission (e.g. ships)" },
	{ "question": "尺度", "answers": [ "しゃくど" ], "comment": "linear measure; scale" },
	{ "question": "尻", "answers": [ "しり" ], "comment": "buttocks; behind; rump; bottom\nundersurface; bottom\nlast place; end\nconsequence" },
	{ "question": "尽きる", "answers": [ "つきる" ], "comment": "to be used up; to be run out; to be exhausted; to be consumed; to come to an end" },
	{ "question": "尽くす", "answers": [ "つくす" ], "comment": "to exhaust; to run out\nto devote; to serve (a person); to befriend\nto do to exhaustion" },
	{ "question": "尾", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "tail (animal, kite, comet, etc.); tail end\nslope at the foot of a mountain" },
	{ "question": "尾根", "answers": [ "おね" ], "comment": "(mountain) ridge; spur" },
	{ "question": "尿", "answers": [ "にょう" ], "comment": "urine" },
	{ "question": "局", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "bureau; department\noffice (e.g. post, telephone); broadcasting station (e.g. television, radio); channel; exchange\naffair; situation\ngame (of go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "局員", "answers": [ "きょくいん" ], "comment": "clerk; (bureau, post-office) staff" },
	{ "question": "局地", "answers": [ "きょくち" ], "comment": "municipal; limited area; locality" },
	{ "question": "局長", "answers": [ "きょくちょう" ], "comment": "bureau director; office chief" },
	{ "question": "局面", "answers": [ "きょくめん" ], "comment": "position in a game of go or shogi; state of the game\naspect of an affair; situation" },
	{ "question": "居住", "answers": [ "きょじゅう" ], "comment": "residence" },
	{ "question": "居住者", "answers": [ "きょじゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "resident; inhabitant" },
	{ "question": "居合わせる", "answers": [ "いあわせる" ], "comment": "to happen to be present" },
	{ "question": "居場所", "answers": [ "いばしょ" ], "comment": "whereabouts; place; location\nplace where one belongs; where one fits in; place where one can be oneself" },
	{ "question": "居室", "answers": [ "きょしつ" ], "comment": "living room" },
	{ "question": "居心地", "answers": [ "いごこち" ], "comment": "comfort" },
	{ "question": "居眠り", "answers": [ "いねむり" ], "comment": "nodding off (while sitting); dozing" },
	{ "question": "居酒屋", "answers": [ "いざかや" ], "comment": "izakaya; informal Japanese gastropub" },
	{ "question": "居間", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "living room (Western style)" },
	{ "question": "屈折", "answers": [ "くっせつ" ], "comment": "bending; indentation\nrefraction\ninflection\nwarping (e.g. of opinion, reasoning, etc.); distortion" },
	{ "question": "屈指", "answers": [ "くっし" ], "comment": "leading; foremost; preeminent; outstanding; one of the best" },
	{ "question": "屈託", "answers": [ "くったく" ], "comment": "worry; care; concern\nennui; boredom" },
	{ "question": "屈辱", "answers": [ "くつじょく" ], "comment": "disgrace; humiliation" },
	{ "question": "届", "answers": [ "とどけ" ], "comment": "report; notification; registration" },
	{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at\nto be attentive; to pay attention\nto be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)" },
	{ "question": "届け", "answers": [ "とどけ" ], "comment": "report; notification; registration" },
	{ "question": "届ける", "answers": [ "とどける" ], "comment": "to deliver; to forward; to send\nto report; to notify; to file notice (to the authorities); to give notice; to register" },
	{ "question": "届け出", "answers": [ "とどけで" ], "comment": "report; notification" },
	{ "question": "屋上", "answers": [ "おくじょう" ], "comment": "rooftop" },
	{ "question": "屋内", "answers": [ "おくない" ], "comment": "indoor (court, pool, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "屋台", "answers": [ "やたい" ], "comment": "cart (esp. a food cart); stall; stand\nfestival float; portable shrine dedicated to a god and shaped like a house; dancing platform\nstage prop fashioned after a large building\nframework (of a house, etc.)\nhouse (esp. a small and miserable house)" },
	{ "question": "屋外", "answers": [ "おくがい" ], "comment": "outdoors; alfresco" },
	{ "question": "屋敷", "answers": [ "やしき" ], "comment": "residence; estate; grounds; premises; mansion" },
	{ "question": "屋根", "answers": [ "やね" ], "comment": "roof" },
	{ "question": "屏風", "answers": [ "びょうぶ" ], "comment": "folding screen" },
	{ "question": "展望", "answers": [ "てんぼう" ], "comment": "view; outlook; prospect" },
	{ "question": "展示", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display" },
	{ "question": "展示会", "answers": [ "てんじかい" ], "comment": "exhibition" },
	{ "question": "展覧会", "answers": [ "てんらんかい" ], "comment": "exhibition" },
	{ "question": "展開", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "development; evolution; progressing; unfolding\nexpansion; spreading out; extending; deployment; building up\nexpansion" },
	{ "question": "属する", "answers": [ "ぞくする" ], "comment": "to belong to; to come under; to be affiliated with; to be subject to" },
	{ "question": "履く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to put on (or wear) lower-body clothing (i.e. pants, skirt, etc.); to put on (or wear) footwear\nto affix a sword to one's hip\nto affix a bowstring to a bow" },
	{ "question": "履歴", "answers": [ "りれき" ], "comment": "personal history; background; career\nlog; record\nhysteresis" },
	{ "question": "履歴書", "answers": [ "りれきしょ" ], "comment": "personal history; curriculum vitae; resume" },
	{ "question": "履物", "answers": [ "はきもの" ], "comment": "footwear; clogs" },
	{ "question": "履行", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "performance; fulfillment; fulfilment; discharge; implementation" },
	{ "question": "山", "answers": [ "やま" ], "comment": "mountain; hill\nmine (e.g. coal mine)\nheap; pile\ncrown (of a hat); thread (of a screw); tread (of a tire); protruding part of an object\nclimax; peak; critical point\nguess; speculation\ncriminal case; crime\nmountain climbing; mountaineering\nfestival float (esp. one mounted with a decorative halberd)\nwall; wall tile\ntemple; temple grounds\nwild" },
	{ "question": "山地", "answers": [ "やまち", "さんち" ], "comment": "mountainous district" },
	{ "question": "山小屋", "answers": [ "やまごや" ], "comment": "hut (esp. on a mountain); shack; refuge; shanty" },
	{ "question": "山岳", "answers": [ "さんがく" ], "comment": "mountains" },
	{ "question": "山川", "answers": [ "さんせん", "やまかわ" ], "comment": "mountains and rivers" },
	{ "question": "山形", "answers": [ "やまがた" ], "comment": "mountain-shape; chevron; cone" },
	{ "question": "山手", "answers": [ "やまて" ], "comment": "place near the mountains\nhilly section of a city (e.g. Tokyo, Kobe, Yokohama)" },
	{ "question": "山村", "answers": [ "さんそん" ], "comment": "mountain village" },
	{ "question": "山林", "answers": [ "さんりん" ], "comment": "mountain forest; forest on a mountain; montane forest\nmountains and forest" },
	{ "question": "山火事", "answers": [ "やまかじ" ], "comment": "forest fire (on a mountain); wildfire; bushfire" },
	{ "question": "山登り", "answers": [ "やまのぼり" ], "comment": "mountain climbing; mountaineering" },
	{ "question": "山積", "answers": [ "さんせき" ], "comment": "lying in piles; form into piles; forming a (huge) pile" },
	{ "question": "山系", "answers": [ "さんけい" ], "comment": "mountain range; mountain system" },
	{ "question": "山脈", "answers": [ "さんみゃく", "やまなみ" ], "comment": "mountain range" },
	{ "question": "山荘", "answers": [ "さんそう" ], "comment": "mountain villa; mountain retreat; mountain cottage" },
	{ "question": "山菜", "answers": [ "さんさい" ], "comment": "edible wild plants" },
	{ "question": "山道", "answers": [ "さんどう", "やまみち", "せんどう" ], "comment": "mountain road; mountain trail" },
	{ "question": "山野", "answers": [ "さんや" ], "comment": "hills and fields; countryside" },
	{ "question": "山間", "answers": [ "さんかん" ], "comment": "among the mountains" },
	{ "question": "山陰", "answers": [ "やまかげ", "さんいん" ], "comment": "place in the shade of a mountain; shelter of the mountains\nmountain recess" },
	{ "question": "山陽", "answers": [ "さんよう" ], "comment": "south side of a mountain; Sanyo district" },
	{ "question": "山頂", "answers": [ "さんちょう" ], "comment": "summit (of a mountain)" },
	{ "question": "岐路", "answers": [ "きろ" ], "comment": "forked road; crossroads" },
	{ "question": "岐阜", "answers": [ "ぎふ" ], "comment": "Gifu (city)" },
	{ "question": "岩", "answers": [ "いわ" ], "comment": "rock; boulder\ncrag; cliff\nanchor" },
	{ "question": "岩山", "answers": [ "いわやま" ], "comment": "rocky mountain" },
	{ "question": "岩盤", "answers": [ "がんばん" ], "comment": "bedrock" },
	{ "question": "岩石", "answers": [ "がんせき" ], "comment": "rock" },
	{ "question": "岩間", "answers": [ "いわま" ], "comment": "among rocks" },
	{ "question": "岬", "answers": [ "みさき" ], "comment": "cape (on coast)" },
	{ "question": "岳", "answers": [ "だけ", "たけ" ], "comment": "peak\nmountain" },
	{ "question": "岸", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "bank; coast; shore" },
	{ "question": "岸壁", "answers": [ "がんぺき" ], "comment": "wharf; breakwater; steep cliff" },
	{ "question": "岸辺", "answers": [ "きしべ" ], "comment": "shore; bank (of a body of water)" },
	{ "question": "峠", "answers": [ "とうげ" ], "comment": "ridge; (mountain) pass; difficult part" },
	{ "question": "峰", "answers": [ "みね" ], "comment": "peak; summit; ridge; top\nback of a blade" },
	{ "question": "島々", "answers": [ "しまじま" ], "comment": "islands" },
	{ "question": "島内", "answers": [ "とうない" ], "comment": "on an island; on-island" },
	{ "question": "島国", "answers": [ "とうごく", "しまぐに" ], "comment": "island country (sometimes used as a metaphor for Japan)" },
	{ "question": "島根", "answers": [ "しまね" ], "comment": "island country" },
	{ "question": "崇拝", "answers": [ "すうはい" ], "comment": "worship; adoration; admiration; cult" },
	{ "question": "崎", "answers": [ "さき" ], "comment": "small peninsula" },
	{ "question": "崖", "answers": [ "がけ" ], "comment": "cliff" },
	{ "question": "崩し書き", "answers": [ "くずしがき" ], "comment": "cursive style of writing or calligraphy" },
	{ "question": "崩す", "answers": [ "くずす" ], "comment": "to destroy; to demolish; to pull down; to tear down; to level\nto disturb; to put into disorder; to throw off balance; to make shaky\nto relax (one's pose); to make oneself at ease\nto break (a bill); to change; to make change\nto write in cursive style; to write in running style\nto break into a smile; to let off a smile\nto lower (a price)" },
	{ "question": "崩れ", "answers": [ "くずれ" ], "comment": "crumbling; collapse; ruin\nhas-been; wannabe" },
	{ "question": "崩れる", "answers": [ "くずれる" ], "comment": "to collapse; to crumble\nto get out of shape; to lose one's shape; to become disorganized; to become untidy\nto break down; to be thrown into disarray\nto crash (stock market); to slump; to decline\nto break money into small change\nto turn bad (e.g. weather); to change for the worse; to deteriorate" },
	{ "question": "崩壊", "answers": [ "ほうかい" ], "comment": "collapse; crumbling; breaking down; caving in\ndecay" },
	{ "question": "崩落", "answers": [ "ほうらく" ], "comment": "collapse; break; cave-in; crash; (market) decline" },
	{ "question": "嵐", "answers": [ "あらし" ], "comment": "storm; tempest\ndifficulty; trouble" },
	{ "question": "川", "answers": [ "がわ", "かわ" ], "comment": "river; stream\nthe .... river; (suffix used with the names of rivers)" },
	{ "question": "川上", "answers": [ "かわかみ" ], "comment": "upper reaches of a river; upstream" },
	{ "question": "川原", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "dry river bed; river beach" },
	{ "question": "川口", "answers": [ "かこう", "かわぐち" ], "comment": "mouth of river; estuary" },
	{ "question": "川岸", "answers": [ "かがん", "かし", "かわぎし" ], "comment": "riverbank; riverside\nfish market" },
	{ "question": "川柳", "answers": [ "せんりゅう" ], "comment": "senryu; comic haiku; humorous seventeen-syllable poem" },
	{ "question": "川沿い", "answers": [ "かわぞい" ], "comment": "along the river; riverside" },
	{ "question": "川端", "answers": [ "かわばた" ], "comment": "riverbank" },
	{ "question": "州", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "state; province; county; oblast; department (of ancient China)\ncontinent\ndear" },
	{ "question": "州政府", "answers": [ "しゅうせいふ" ], "comment": "state government" },
	{ "question": "州都", "answers": [ "しゅうと" ], "comment": "state capital; provincial capital; county town" },
	{ "question": "巡り会う", "answers": [ "めぐりあう" ], "comment": "to meet fortuitously (e.g. running into an old friend); to meet by chance; to happen across" },
	{ "question": "巡回", "answers": [ "じゅんかい" ], "comment": "going around; patrol; round; tour" },
	{ "question": "巡査", "answers": [ "じゅんさ" ], "comment": "police officer; policeman; constable" },
	{ "question": "巡業", "answers": [ "じゅんぎょう" ], "comment": "provincial tour" },
	{ "question": "巡礼", "answers": [ "じゅんれい" ], "comment": "pilgrimage; pilgrim" },
	{ "question": "巡航", "answers": [ "じゅんこう" ], "comment": "cruise; cruising" },
	{ "question": "巡視", "answers": [ "じゅんし" ], "comment": "inspection tour" },
	{ "question": "巣", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "nest; rookery; breeding place; hive\nden\nhaunt\n(spider's) web" },
	{ "question": "工事", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "construction work; construction; work (related to construction, e.g. painting, concrete-pouring, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "工作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "handicraft\nwork; construction; manufacturing\nmaneuvering; manoeuvering" },
	{ "question": "工作員", "answers": [ "こうさくいん" ], "comment": "spy; agent provocateur; covert operative\nmaker; builder; constructor" },
	{ "question": "工作機械", "answers": [ "こうさくきかい" ], "comment": "machine tools" },
	{ "question": "工兵", "answers": [ "こうへい" ], "comment": "combat engineer; military engineer; combat engineering; military engineering" },
	{ "question": "工務", "answers": [ "こうむ" ], "comment": "engineering; engineering works" },
	{ "question": "工員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "factory worker" },
	{ "question": "工場", "answers": [ "こうじょう", "こうば" ], "comment": "factory; plant; mill; workshop" },
	{ "question": "工夫", "answers": [ "くふう" ], "comment": "scheme; device; scheming; devising; figuring out; coming up with; solving ingeniously\ndedication to spiritual improvement (esp. through Zen meditation)" },
	{ "question": "工学", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "engineering" },
	{ "question": "工学部", "answers": [ "こうがくぶ" ], "comment": "department (or school) of technology, engineering or science" },
	{ "question": "工房", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "workshop; studio; atelier" },
	{ "question": "工業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(manufacturing) industry" },
	{ "question": "工法", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "method of construction" },
	{ "question": "工科", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "engineering course" },
	{ "question": "工程", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "process; operation; stage of a process; progress of work" },
	{ "question": "工芸", "answers": [ "こうげい" ], "comment": "industrial arts; craft" },
	{ "question": "工費", "answers": [ "こうひ" ], "comment": "construction cost" },
	{ "question": "左", "answers": [ "ひだり" ], "comment": "left; left hand side" },
	{ "question": "左側", "answers": [ "さそく", "ひだりがわ" ], "comment": "left; left (hand) side" },
	{ "question": "左利き", "answers": [ "ひだりきき" ], "comment": "left-handedness; left-hander\ndrinker; wine lover" },
	{ "question": "左前", "answers": [ "ひだりまえ" ], "comment": "wearing a kimono with the right side over the left (normally used only for the dead)\ngoing badly (one's business, one's fortune, the economy); being in a bad financial situation" },
	{ "question": "左右", "answers": [ "さゆう" ], "comment": "left and right\ninfluence; control; domination" },
	{ "question": "左手", "answers": [ "ひだりて" ], "comment": "left hand\nleft-hand side; left-hand direction; (on) the left" },
	{ "question": "左派", "answers": [ "さは" ], "comment": "left wing" },
	{ "question": "左翼", "answers": [ "さよく" ], "comment": "left-wing (politics)" },
	{ "question": "左腕", "answers": [ "さわん", "ひだりうで" ], "comment": "left arm\nleft-handed (baseball pitcher)" },
	{ "question": "左記", "answers": [ "さき" ], "comment": "undermentioned (statement); the following; at left" },
	{ "question": "左遷", "answers": [ "させん" ], "comment": "demotion; relegation; reduction in rank; degradation; downward move" },
	{ "question": "巧み", "answers": [ "たくみ" ], "comment": "skillful; adroit; dexterous; masterful; clever; ingenious; cunning" },
	{ "question": "巧妙", "answers": [ "こうみょう" ], "comment": "ingenious; skillful; clever; deft" },
	{ "question": "巨人", "answers": [ "きょじん" ], "comment": "giant; great man\nTokyo Giants (baseball team)" },
	{ "question": "巨体", "answers": [ "きょたい" ], "comment": "large build" },
	{ "question": "巨匠", "answers": [ "きょしょう" ], "comment": "master; masterhand; maestro" },
	{ "question": "巨大", "answers": [ "きょだい" ], "comment": "huge; gigantic; enormous" },
	{ "question": "巨視的", "answers": [ "きょしてき" ], "comment": "macroscopic" },
	{ "question": "巨額", "answers": [ "きょがく" ], "comment": "great sum" },
	{ "question": "差", "answers": [ "さ" ], "comment": "difference; variation\ndifference" },
	{ "question": "差し上げる", "answers": [ "さしあげる" ], "comment": "to give; to offer\nto lift up; to hold up; to raise" },
	{ "question": "差し伸べる", "answers": [ "さしのべる" ], "comment": "to hold out; to extend (e.g. one's hands); to stretch; to reach out for\nto thrust (javelin)\nto offer (e.g. aid, help, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "差し出す", "answers": [ "さしだす" ], "comment": "to present; to submit; to tender; to hold out" },
	{ "question": "差し引き", "answers": [ "さしひき" ], "comment": "deduction; subtraction; balance\nebb and flow; rise and fall" },
	{ "question": "差し戻す", "answers": [ "さしもどす" ], "comment": "to send back; to refer back" },
	{ "question": "差し掛かる", "answers": [ "さしかかる" ], "comment": "to come near to; to approach" },
	{ "question": "差し控える", "answers": [ "さしひかえる" ], "comment": "to practice moderation in something; to not do too much of something\nto refrain from doing something; to withhold (e.g. consent, announcement)\nto be close by" },
	{ "question": "差し支え", "answers": [ "さしつかえ" ], "comment": "hindrance; impediment" },
	{ "question": "差し支える", "answers": [ "さしつかえる" ], "comment": "to interfere; to hinder; to become impeded" },
	{ "question": "差し止め", "answers": [ "さしとめ" ], "comment": "prohibition; ban; suspension" },
	{ "question": "差し込む", "answers": [ "さしこむ" ], "comment": "to insert; to put in; to thrust in; to plug in\nto have a griping pain\nto flow in; to shine in" },
	{ "question": "差す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to shine\nto be visible\nto be tinged with\nto rise (of water levels); to flow in\nto be felt (i.e. as an emotion); to come over one\nto hold up (an umbrella, etc.); to put up; to raise\nto extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance)\nto insert; to put in\nto wear (a sword) in one's belt; to wear at one's side; to carry under one's arm\nto insert one's arm under an opponent's arm\nto pole (a boat)\nto pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks)\nto put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye\nto light (a fire); to burn\nto shut; to close; to lock; to fasten\nto stop in the midst of; to leave undone" },
	{ "question": "差出人", "answers": [ "さしだしにん" ], "comment": "sender" },
	{ "question": "差別", "answers": [ "さべつ" ], "comment": "discrimination; distinction; differentiation" },
	{ "question": "差異", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "difference; disparity; gap" },
	{ "question": "差益", "answers": [ "さえき" ], "comment": "marginal profits" },
	{ "question": "差額", "answers": [ "さがく" ], "comment": "balance; difference; margin" },
	{ "question": "己", "answers": [ "おのれ" ], "comment": "oneself (itself, etc.)\nI; me\nyou\nby oneself (itself, etc.)\ninterjection expressing anger or chagrin" },
	{ "question": "巳", "answers": [ "み" ], "comment": "sixth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Serpent, 9am-11am, south-southeast, April)" },
	{ "question": "巴", "answers": [ "ともえ" ], "comment": "huge comma design" },
	{ "question": "巻", "answers": [ "まき", "かん" ], "comment": "roll (e.g. of cloth)\nwinding\nvolume (of book)" },
	{ "question": "巻き添え", "answers": [ "まきぞえ" ], "comment": "getting mixed up in; getting embroiled in; involvement; entanglement; by-blow" },
	{ "question": "巻き込む", "answers": [ "まきこむ" ], "comment": "to roll up; to enfold; to swallow up\nto involve; to drag into" },
	{ "question": "巻き返し", "answers": [ "まきかえし" ], "comment": "rally; recovery; rollback; rewind" },
	{ "question": "巻く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to wind; to coil; to roll; to wear (e.g. turban, scarf)\nto envelope; to shroud\nto outflank; to skirt\nto link (verse)\nto move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up" },
	{ "question": "巻尺", "answers": [ "まきじゃく" ], "comment": "tape measure" },
	{ "question": "巻末", "answers": [ "かんまつ" ], "comment": "end of a book" },
	{ "question": "巻添え", "answers": [ "まきぞえ" ], "comment": "getting mixed up in; getting embroiled in; involvement; entanglement; by-blow" },
	{ "question": "巻込む", "answers": [ "まきこむ" ], "comment": "to roll up; to enfold; to swallow up\nto involve; to drag into" },
	{ "question": "巽", "answers": [ "そん" ], "comment": "xun (one of the trigrams of the I Ching: wind, southeast)" },
	{ "question": "市", "answers": [ "し", "いち" ], "comment": "market; fair /\n city" },
	{ "question": "市中", "answers": [ "しちゅう" ], "comment": "in the city" },
	{ "question": "市内", "answers": [ "しない" ], "comment": "(within a) city; local" },
	{ "question": "市営", "answers": [ "しえい" ], "comment": "municipal management" },
	{ "question": "市場", "answers": [ "しじょう", "いちば" ], "comment": "(town) market\n(the) marketplace /\n (the) market (as a concept)" },
	{ "question": "市場調査", "answers": [ "しじょうちょうさ" ], "comment": "market research" },
	{ "question": "市外", "answers": [ "しがい" ], "comment": "outside the city area; suburbs" },
	{ "question": "市役所", "answers": [ "しやくしょ" ], "comment": "municipal office; council; city hall" },
	{ "question": "市政", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "municipal government" },
	{ "question": "市民", "answers": [ "しみん" ], "comment": "citizen; citizenry; public\ncity inhabitant; townspeople\nbourgeoisie; middle class" },
	{ "question": "市民権", "answers": [ "しみんけん" ], "comment": "citizenship; civic rights; civil rights\nwidespread acceptance; social recognition; common use" },
	{ "question": "市民社会", "answers": [ "しみんしゃかい" ], "comment": "civil society" },
	{ "question": "市況", "answers": [ "しきょう" ], "comment": "market conditions" },
	{ "question": "市町村", "answers": [ "しちょうそん" ], "comment": "cities, towns and villages; municipalities" },
	{ "question": "市立", "answers": [ "しりつ", "いちりつ" ], "comment": "municipal; city" },
	{ "question": "市街", "answers": [ "しがい" ], "comment": "urban areas; the streets; town; city" },
	{ "question": "市街地", "answers": [ "しがいち" ], "comment": "town area; urban area; metropolitan area; built-up area" },
	{ "question": "市議", "answers": [ "しぎ" ], "comment": "city councillor; city councilor; city assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "市議会", "answers": [ "しぎかい" ], "comment": "city council" },
	{ "question": "市販", "answers": [ "しはん" ], "comment": "selling on the market (in the marketplace, in stores, etc.); making something commercially available\ncommercial (e.g. software); over-the-counter; off-the-shelf; store-bought" },
	{ "question": "市道", "answers": [ "しどう" ], "comment": "municipal roads" },
	{ "question": "市部", "answers": [ "しぶ" ], "comment": "urban areas" },
	{ "question": "市長", "answers": [ "しちょう" ], "comment": "mayor" },
	{ "question": "布", "answers": [ "ぬの", "ふ" ], "comment": "cloth\nbujian (spade-shaped bronze coin of ancient China)" },
	{ "question": "布告", "answers": [ "ふこく" ], "comment": "edict; ordinance; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "布団", "answers": [ "ふとん" ], "comment": "futon (quilted Japanese-style mattress laid out on the floor)\nround cushion used for Zen meditation (traditionally made of woven bulrush leaves)" },
	{ "question": "布地", "answers": [ "きれじ", "ぬのじ" ], "comment": "cloth; fabric" },
	{ "question": "布巾", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "tea-towel; dish cloth" },
	{ "question": "布教", "answers": [ "ふきょう" ], "comment": "propagation (e.g. a religion); proselytizing; missionary work" },
	{ "question": "布施", "answers": [ "ふせ" ], "comment": "alms; offerings" },
	{ "question": "布石", "answers": [ "ふせき" ], "comment": "strategic arrangement of go stones; opening moves\npreparation; preparatory steps; groundwork" },
	{ "question": "布陣", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "battle formation; lineup" },
	{ "question": "帆", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "sail" },
	{ "question": "帆船", "answers": [ "ほぶね", "はんせん" ], "comment": "sailing ship; sailing boat; sailing vessel" },
	{ "question": "希少", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "scarce; rare" },
	{ "question": "希望", "answers": [ "きぼう" ], "comment": "hope; wish; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "希薄", "answers": [ "きはく" ], "comment": "thin (e.g. air); diluted; sparse; lean; weak; rarified; rarefied\nlacking (e.g. empathy); deficient; insufficient (e.g. zeal)" },
	{ "question": "帝", "answers": [ "みかど", "ごもん" ], "comment": "emperor (of Japan); mikado\n(the gates of an) imperial residence" },
	{ "question": "帝京", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "the capital" },
	{ "question": "帝国", "answers": [ "ていこく" ], "comment": "empire\nimperial" },
	{ "question": "帝国主義", "answers": [ "ていこくしゅぎ" ], "comment": "imperialism" },
	{ "question": "帝政", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "imperial government; imperialism; monarchical rule" },
	{ "question": "師事", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "studying under; looking up to; apprenticing oneself to" },
	{ "question": "師匠", "answers": [ "ししょう" ], "comment": "master; teacher\ncoach who owns his stable" },
	{ "question": "師団", "answers": [ "しだん" ], "comment": "(army) division" },
	{ "question": "師範", "answers": [ "しはん" ], "comment": "instructor; (fencing) teacher; model" },
	{ "question": "師走", "answers": [ "しはす", "しわす" ], "comment": "twelfth month (esp. of the lunar calendar); December" },
	{ "question": "席", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "seat\nlocation (of a gathering, etc.); place\nposition; post" },
	{ "question": "席上", "answers": [ "せきじょう" ], "comment": "at the meeting; on the occasion" },
	{ "question": "席巻", "answers": [ "せっけん" ], "comment": "sweeping conquest; sweeping over; conquering; invading" },
	{ "question": "帯", "answers": [ "たい", "おび" ], "comment": "obi; kimono sash\npaper wrapper on books, CDs, etc. /\n band (e.g. conduction, valence); belt (e.g. Van-Allen, asteroid, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "帯びる", "answers": [ "おびる" ], "comment": "to wear (sword, decoration, etc.); to carry\nto be entrusted (e.g. with a mission); to take on\nto have a trace of; to be tinged with" },
	{ "question": "帰す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "to send (someone) back; to send (someone) home" },
	{ "question": "帰り", "answers": [ "かえり" ], "comment": "return; coming back" },
	{ "question": "帰り道", "answers": [ "かえりみち" ], "comment": "the way back or home; return trip" },
	{ "question": "帰る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to return; to come home; to go home; to go back\nto leave\nto get home; to get to home plate" },
	{ "question": "帰京", "answers": [ "ききょう" ], "comment": "returning to Tokyo\nreturning to the capital" },
	{ "question": "帰休", "answers": [ "ききゅう" ], "comment": "leave; furlough\ntemporary layoff" },
	{ "question": "帰化", "answers": [ "きか" ], "comment": "naturalization; naturalisation" },
	{ "question": "帰国", "answers": [ "きこく" ], "comment": "return to one's country" },
	{ "question": "帰宅", "answers": [ "きたく" ], "comment": "returning home" },
	{ "question": "帰属", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "belonging; ascription; attribution; imputation; possession; jurisdiction\nreversion; return; restoration" },
	{ "question": "帰省", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "homecoming; returning home" },
	{ "question": "帰途", "answers": [ "きと" ], "comment": "on the way back; returning" },
	{ "question": "帰還", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "repatriation; return\n(electrical) feedback" },
	{ "question": "帳消し", "answers": [ "ちょうけし" ], "comment": "cancellation; writing off" },
	{ "question": "帳簿", "answers": [ "ちょうぼ" ], "comment": "account book; register; ledger" },
	{ "question": "常", "answers": [ "つね" ], "comment": "usual state of things" },
	{ "question": "常に", "answers": [ "つねに" ], "comment": "always; constantly" },
	{ "question": "常任", "answers": [ "じょうにん" ], "comment": "standing; regular; permanent" },
	{ "question": "常任委員会", "answers": [ "じょうにんいいんかい" ], "comment": "standing committee" },
	{ "question": "常務", "answers": [ "じょうむ" ], "comment": "managing director; executive director\nroutine business; regular business" },
	{ "question": "常勤", "answers": [ "じょうきん" ], "comment": "full-time employment" },
	{ "question": "常時", "answers": [ "じょうじ" ], "comment": "usually; ordinarily\ncontinuous; 24-hour (e.g. observation, operation (of a machine), care (of patient)); always on" },
	{ "question": "常用", "answers": [ "じょうよう" ], "comment": "habitual use; daily use" },
	{ "question": "常用漢字", "answers": [ "じょうようかんじ" ], "comment": "kanji for common use; jōyō kanji; list of 2,136 kanji established in 2010, formerly a list of 1,945 established in 1981" },
	{ "question": "常習", "answers": [ "じょうしゅう" ], "comment": "custom; common practice; habit" },
	{ "question": "常設", "answers": [ "じょうせつ" ], "comment": "standing (committee); permanent (exhibit)" },
	{ "question": "常識", "answers": [ "じょうしき" ], "comment": "common sense; good sense; common knowledge; general knowledge; common practice; accepted practice; social etiquette" },
	{ "question": "常識的", "answers": [ "じょうしきてき" ], "comment": "ordinary; sensible; commonplace" },
	{ "question": "常連", "answers": [ "じょうれん" ], "comment": "regular customer; regular patron; frequenter\nconstant companion" },
	{ "question": "常駐", "answers": [ "じょうちゅう" ], "comment": "staying permanently; being stationed; resident" },
	{ "question": "帽子", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "hat; cap" },
	{ "question": "幅", "answers": [ "はば" ], "comment": "width; breadth\nfreedom (e.g. of thought); latitude\ngap; difference (e.g. in price); range (e.g. of voice)" },
	{ "question": "幅広い", "answers": [ "はばひろい" ], "comment": "extensive; wide; broad" },
	{ "question": "幕", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "curtain; bunting\nact (in play)" },
	{ "question": "幕下", "answers": [ "まくした" ], "comment": "third highest division; wrestlers of the third highest division" },
	{ "question": "幕僚", "answers": [ "ばくりょう" ], "comment": "staff; staff officer" },
	{ "question": "幕内", "answers": [ "まくうち" ], "comment": "highest-ranking division" },
	{ "question": "幕切れ", "answers": [ "まくぎれ" ], "comment": "fall of the curtain; last scene; end of act" },
	{ "question": "幕府", "answers": [ "ばくふ" ], "comment": "bakufu; shogunate" },
	{ "question": "幕末", "answers": [ "ばくまつ" ], "comment": "closing days of the Tokugawa shogunate; end of Edo era" },
	{ "question": "幕開け", "answers": [ "まくあけ" ], "comment": "the rise of the curtain; opening (of play)\nbeginning (e.g. of an era); opening (festival, event, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "干す", "answers": [ "ほす" ], "comment": "to air; to dry; to desiccate\nto drain (off)\nto drink up\nto deprive of a role, job, etc. (usu. in the passive)" },
	{ "question": "干渉", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "interference; intervention; meddling" },
	{ "question": "干潟", "answers": [ "ひがた" ], "comment": "tidal flat; tideland" },
	{ "question": "平たい", "answers": [ "ひらたい" ], "comment": "flat; even; level; simple\nplain (speech, etc.); simple" },
	{ "question": "平ら", "answers": [ "たいら" ], "comment": "flatness; level; smooth; calm; plain; sitting tailor fashion" },
	{ "question": "平凡", "answers": [ "へいぼん" ], "comment": "common; commonplace; ordinary; mediocre" },
	{ "question": "平和", "answers": [ "へいわ" ], "comment": "peace; harmony" },
	{ "question": "平地", "answers": [ "へいち", "ひらち" ], "comment": "level ground; plain" },
	{ "question": "平均", "answers": [ "へいきん" ], "comment": "average; mean\nbalance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "平均点", "answers": [ "へいきんてん" ], "comment": "average mark; mean point" },
	{ "question": "平壌", "answers": [ "ピョンヤン", "へいじょう" ], "comment": "Pyongyang" },
	{ "question": "平安", "answers": [ "へいあん" ], "comment": "peace; tranquility; tranquillity\nHeian era (794-1185)" },
	{ "question": "平常", "answers": [ "へいじょう" ], "comment": "normal; usual" },
	{ "question": "平幕", "answers": [ "ひらまく" ], "comment": "rank-and-file wrestlers in the highest division" },
	{ "question": "平年", "answers": [ "へいねん" ], "comment": "non-leap year\nnormal year (esp. as pertains to weather patterns, vegetative growth, harvest yields, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "平年並み", "answers": [ "へいねんなみ" ], "comment": "average year; normal year" },
	{ "question": "平成", "answers": [ "へいせい" ], "comment": "Heisei era (1989.1.8- )" },
	{ "question": "平方", "answers": [ "へいほう" ], "comment": "square (e.g. metre)" },
	{ "question": "平方キロメートル", "answers": [ "へいほうキロメートル" ], "comment": "square kilometer; square kilometre" },
	{ "question": "平日", "answers": [ "へいじつ", "ひらび" ], "comment": "weekday; ordinary days (i.e. non-holiday)\nkanji radical 73" },
	{ "question": "平時", "answers": [ "へいじ" ], "comment": "normal times; peace time" },
	{ "question": "平気", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "coolness; calmness; composure; unconcern\nall right; OK; okay" },
	{ "question": "平泳ぎ", "answers": [ "ひらおよぎ" ], "comment": "breaststroke (swimming)" },
	{ "question": "平穏", "answers": [ "へいおん" ], "comment": "tranquil; calm; restful; peaceful; quiet" },
	{ "question": "平等", "answers": [ "びょうどう" ], "comment": "equality; impartiality; evenness" },
	{ "question": "平行", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "(going) side-by-side; abreast\nconcurrent; occurring together; at the same time\nparallel" },
	{ "question": "平行線", "answers": [ "へいこうせん" ], "comment": "parallel line" },
	{ "question": "平野", "answers": [ "へいや" ], "comment": "plain; open field" },
	{ "question": "平静", "answers": [ "へいせい" ], "comment": "calm; serenity; tranquillity; tranquility" },
	{ "question": "平面", "answers": [ "へいめん" ], "comment": "level surface; plane" },
	{ "question": "年", "answers": [ "とし", "ねん" ], "comment": "year\nage; years\npast one's prime; old age /\n year (e.g. AD)\ncounter for years" },
	{ "question": "年々", "answers": [ "ねんねん", "としどし" ], "comment": "years; year by year; annually; considering his age" },
	{ "question": "年をとる", "answers": [ "としをとる" ], "comment": "to grow old; to age" },
	{ "question": "年上", "answers": [ "としうえ" ], "comment": "older; senior" },
	{ "question": "年下", "answers": [ "としした" ], "comment": "younger; junior" },
	{ "question": "年中", "answers": [ "ねんじゅう", "ねんちゅう", "ねんぢゅう" ], "comment": "whole year; all year round; throughout the year\nalways; all the time\nmiddle class (of a nursery school, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "年代", "answers": [ "ねんだい" ], "comment": "age; era; period; date" },
	{ "question": "年会", "answers": [ "ねんかい" ], "comment": "conference; annual convention" },
	{ "question": "年俸", "answers": [ "ねんぽう" ], "comment": "annual salary" },
	{ "question": "年内", "answers": [ "ねんない" ], "comment": "by the end of the year" },
	{ "question": "年刊", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "annual publication; year of publication" },
	{ "question": "年初", "answers": [ "ねんしょ" ], "comment": "beginning of the year; New Year's greetings" },
	{ "question": "年功序列", "answers": [ "ねんこうじょれつ" ], "comment": "seniority by length of service" },
	{ "question": "年収", "answers": [ "ねんしゅう" ], "comment": "annual income" },
	{ "question": "年取った", "answers": [ "としとった" ], "comment": "aged" },
	{ "question": "年号", "answers": [ "ねんごう" ], "comment": "name of an era; year number" },
	{ "question": "年商", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "yearly (annual) turnover" },
	{ "question": "年始", "answers": [ "ねんし" ], "comment": "New Year's call; beginning of the year; New Year's greetings" },
	{ "question": "年寄り", "answers": [ "としより" ], "comment": "old people; the aged\ntrustee of the Japan Sumo Association; retired high-ranking wrestler who is licensed to coach and receives retirement pay\nsenior statesman (of the Tokugawa shogunate)\nimportant local official (under the Tokugawa Shogunate)" },
	{ "question": "年度", "answers": [ "ねんど" ], "comment": "fiscal year (usu. April 1 to March 31 in Japan); financial year\nacademic year; school year\nproduct year" },
	{ "question": "年数", "answers": [ "ねんすう" ], "comment": "number of years" },
	{ "question": "年明け", "answers": [ "としあけ" ], "comment": "beginning of the year; early in the New Year" },
	{ "question": "年月", "answers": [ "としつき", "ねんげつ" ], "comment": "months and years" },
	{ "question": "年月日", "answers": [ "ねんがっぴ" ], "comment": "date" },
	{ "question": "年末", "answers": [ "ねんまつ" ], "comment": "end-of-year" },
	{ "question": "年来", "answers": [ "ねんらい" ], "comment": "for some years" },
	{ "question": "年次", "answers": [ "ねんじ" ], "comment": "annual\nfiscal year; school year\nyear (in some sequence)" },
	{ "question": "年率", "answers": [ "ねんりつ" ], "comment": "annual rate (of interest)" },
	{ "question": "年生", "answers": [ "ねんせい" ], "comment": "pupil in ... year; student in ... year" },
	{ "question": "年産", "answers": [ "ねんさん" ], "comment": "annual production" },
	{ "question": "年男", "answers": [ "としおとこ" ], "comment": "Man of the Year, referring to a man born in a year with the same Chinese zodiac sign as the current year" },
	{ "question": "年表", "answers": [ "ねんぴょう" ], "comment": "chronological table" },
	{ "question": "年賀", "answers": [ "ねんが" ], "comment": "New Year's greetings; New Year's card" },
	{ "question": "年賀状", "answers": [ "ねんがじょう" ], "comment": "New Year's card" },
	{ "question": "年輩", "answers": [ "ねんぱい" ], "comment": "elderly; age; years" },
	{ "question": "年輪", "answers": [ "ねんりん" ], "comment": "annual tree ring" },
	{ "question": "年配", "answers": [ "ねんぱい" ], "comment": "elderly; age; years" },
	{ "question": "年金", "answers": [ "ねんきん" ], "comment": "annuity; pension" },
	{ "question": "年長", "answers": [ "ねんちょう" ], "comment": "senior; older" },
	{ "question": "年間", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "years (period of)" },
	{ "question": "年頃", "answers": [ "としごろ" ], "comment": "approximate age; apparent age\nmarriageable age (esp. of a woman); age of maturity; age of adulthood\nappropriate age (to ...); old enough (to ...)\npast few years; for some years" },
	{ "question": "年頭", "answers": [ "としがしら", "ねんとう" ], "comment": "beginning of the year\nthe oldest person" },
	{ "question": "年額", "answers": [ "ねんがく" ], "comment": "yearly amount" },
	{ "question": "年齢", "answers": [ "ねんれい" ], "comment": "age; years" },
	{ "question": "年齢層", "answers": [ "ねんれいそう" ], "comment": "age range; age-group; age bracket" },
	{ "question": "幸い", "answers": [ "さいわい" ], "comment": "happiness; blessedness; luck; fortune; felicity\nluckily; fortunately" },
	{ "question": "幸せ", "answers": [ "しあわせ" ], "comment": "happiness; good fortune; luck; blessing" },
	{ "question": "幸福", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "happiness; blessedness; joy; well-being" },
	{ "question": "幸運", "answers": [ "こううん" ], "comment": "good luck; fortune" },
	{ "question": "幹", "answers": [ "かん", "みき" ], "comment": "(tree) trunk; (arrow) shaft; (tool) handle; backbone; base" },
	{ "question": "幹事", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "executive secretary; coordinator; organizer; person in charge of making arrangements" },
	{ "question": "幹線", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "main line; trunk line" },
	{ "question": "幹部", "answers": [ "かんぶ" ], "comment": "management; (executive) staff; leaders; leadership; top brass; upper echelons" },
	{ "question": "幻", "answers": [ "まぼろし" ], "comment": "phantom; vision; illusion; dream; apparition" },
	{ "question": "幻想", "answers": [ "げんそう" ], "comment": "illusions" },
	{ "question": "幻覚", "answers": [ "げんかく" ], "comment": "hallucination; illusion" },
	{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない", "いとけない" ], "comment": "very young\nchildish; immature" },
	{ "question": "幼なじみ", "answers": [ "おさななじみ" ], "comment": "childhood friend; friend from infancy; old playmate" },
	{ "question": "幼児", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "infant; baby; child\nchild over 1 but not yet of school age" },
	{ "question": "幼少", "answers": [ "ようしょう" ], "comment": "infancy; childhood; tender age" },
	{ "question": "幼少期", "answers": [ "ようしょうき" ], "comment": "(early) childhood" },
	{ "question": "幼稚", "answers": [ "ようち" ], "comment": "infancy\nchildish; infantile; immature; primitive" },
	{ "question": "幼稚園", "answers": [ "ようちえん" ], "comment": "kindergarten" },
	{ "question": "幼虫", "answers": [ "ようちゅう" ], "comment": "larva; grub; maggot" },
	{ "question": "幽霊", "answers": [ "ゆうれい" ], "comment": "ghost; specter; spectre; apparition; phantom" },
	{ "question": "幾", "answers": [ "いく" ], "comment": "some; several\nmany\nhow many?; how much?" },
	{ "question": "幾何", "answers": [ "きか" ], "comment": "geometry" },
	{ "question": "幾何学", "answers": [ "きかがく" ], "comment": "geometry" },
	{ "question": "幾分", "answers": [ "いくぶん" ], "comment": "somewhat; to some extent; to some degree\nsome; part; portion" },
	{ "question": "幾度", "answers": [ "いくど", "いくたび" ], "comment": "(how) many times; (how) often" },
	{ "question": "幾日", "answers": [ "いくにち" ], "comment": "how many days?; what day (of month)?" },
	{ "question": "庁", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "government office; agency; board" },
	{ "question": "庁舎", "answers": [ "ちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "government office building" },
	{ "question": "広々", "answers": [ "ひろびろ" ], "comment": "extensive; spacious" },
	{ "question": "広い", "answers": [ "ひろい" ], "comment": "spacious; vast; wide" },
	{ "question": "広がり", "answers": [ "ひろがり" ], "comment": "spread; span; expanse; extent" },
	{ "question": "広がる", "answers": [ "ひろがる" ], "comment": "to spread (out); to extend; to stretch; to reach to; to get around; to fill (e.g. a space)" },
	{ "question": "広げる", "answers": [ "ひろげる" ], "comment": "to spread; to extend; to expand; to enlarge; to widen; to broaden\nto unfold; to open; to unroll; to unwrap\nto scatter about; to spread around\nto make flourish; to cause to prosper" },
	{ "question": "広さ", "answers": [ "ひろさ" ], "comment": "extent" },
	{ "question": "広まり", "answers": [ "ひろまり" ], "comment": "spread" },
	{ "question": "広まる", "answers": [ "ひろまる" ], "comment": "to spread; to be propagated" },
	{ "question": "広める", "answers": [ "ひろめる" ], "comment": "to spread; to propagate; to popularize; to disseminate\nto broaden; to extend; to widen; to enlarge" },
	{ "question": "広告", "answers": [ "こうこく" ], "comment": "advertisement" },
	{ "question": "広域", "answers": [ "こういき" ], "comment": "wide area" },
	{ "question": "広報", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "public relations; PR; publicity; information; publicizing" },
	{ "question": "広場", "answers": [ "ひろば" ], "comment": "plaza; (public) square; piazza; forum; open space" },
	{ "question": "広大", "answers": [ "こうだい" ], "comment": "huge; very large; vast; extensive; magnificent; grand" },
	{ "question": "広州", "answers": [ "こうしゅう", "コワンチョウ", "コアンチョウ" ], "comment": "Guangzhou (China); Kwangchow; Canton" },
	{ "question": "広東", "answers": [ "カントン" ], "comment": "Guangdong (China); Kwangtung\nGuangzhou; Kwangchow; Canton (China)" },
	{ "question": "広範", "answers": [ "こうはん" ], "comment": "wide; extensive; comprehensive; far-reaching; widespread" },
	{ "question": "広範囲", "answers": [ "こうはんい" ], "comment": "extensive; vast range; wide scope" },
	{ "question": "広葉樹", "answers": [ "こうようじゅ" ], "comment": "broadleaf tree" },
	{ "question": "床", "answers": [ "とこ", "ゆか" ], "comment": "bed; bedding\nsickbed\nalcove\nriverbed\nseedbed\nstraw \"core\" of a tatami mat\nfloor /\n floor\nstage (for the narrator and the shamisen player)\ndining platform built across a river" },
	{ "question": "床の間", "answers": [ "とこのま" ], "comment": "tokonoma (alcove where art or flowers are displayed)" },
	{ "question": "床下", "answers": [ "ゆかした" ], "comment": "under the floor" },
	{ "question": "床屋", "answers": [ "とこや" ], "comment": "barbershop; barber" },
	{ "question": "序列", "answers": [ "じょれつ" ], "comment": "rank; ranking order; hierarchy" },
	{ "question": "序盤", "answers": [ "じょばん" ], "comment": "the opening(s) (e.g. in a game of go or chess)" },
	{ "question": "底", "answers": [ "そこ" ], "comment": "bottom; sole" },
	{ "question": "底値", "answers": [ "そこね" ], "comment": "bottom price" },
	{ "question": "底入れ", "answers": [ "そこいれ" ], "comment": "bottoming out (of prices)" },
	{ "question": "底力", "answers": [ "そこぢから" ], "comment": "latent energy; reserve strength; potentiality" },
	{ "question": "底打ち", "answers": [ "そこうち" ], "comment": "bottoming out" },
	{ "question": "底流", "answers": [ "ていりゅう" ], "comment": "bottom current; undercurrent" },
	{ "question": "底辺", "answers": [ "ていへん" ], "comment": "base (e.g. of a triangle)\nlow class; low in social standing; low level; of poor reputation\nbase (e.g. of support); foundation; basis" },
	{ "question": "店", "answers": [ "てん", "みせ" ], "comment": "store; shop; establishment; restaurant /\n -store; -shop" },
	{ "question": "店主", "answers": [ "てんしゅ" ], "comment": "shopkeeper" },
	{ "question": "店先", "answers": [ "みせさき" ], "comment": "storefront; shopfront" },
	{ "question": "店内", "answers": [ "てんない" ], "comment": "store interior" },
	{ "question": "店員", "answers": [ "てんいん" ], "comment": "shop assistant; employee; clerk; salesperson" },
	{ "question": "店舗", "answers": [ "てんぽ" ], "comment": "shop; store" },
	{ "question": "店長", "answers": [ "てんちょう" ], "comment": "shop manager" },
	{ "question": "店開き", "answers": [ "みせびらき" ], "comment": "starting a business\nopening a store (for the day)" },
	{ "question": "店頭", "answers": [ "てんとう" ], "comment": "shopfront; storefront; shopwindow; (near the) shop entrance\nover-the-counter" },
	{ "question": "府庁", "answers": [ "ふちょう" ], "comment": "prefectural office" },
	{ "question": "府県", "answers": [ "ふけん" ], "comment": "prefecture" },
	{ "question": "府知事", "answers": [ "ふちじ" ], "comment": "prefectural governor (of Osaka or Kyoto)" },
	{ "question": "府立", "answers": [ "ふりつ" ], "comment": "managed by an urban prefecture" },
	{ "question": "府警", "answers": [ "ふけい" ], "comment": "prefectural police" },
	{ "question": "度", "answers": [ "ど", "たんび", "たび" ], "comment": "time (three times, each time, etc.); times /\n degree (angle, temperature, scale, etc.)\ncounter for occurrences and times\nstrength (of alcohol)" },
	{ "question": "度合", "answers": [ "どあい" ], "comment": "degree; extent" },
	{ "question": "度合い", "answers": [ "どあい" ], "comment": "degree; extent" },
	{ "question": "度数", "answers": [ "どすう" ], "comment": "frequency; number of times; incidence\ndegree (e.g. temperature); strength (e.g. alcohol, lens, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "度胸", "answers": [ "どきょう" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; pluck; nerve; grit; guts" },
	{ "question": "座", "answers": [ "ざ" ], "comment": "seat; place; position\nstatus\ngathering; group\nstand; pedestal; platform\n(historical) trade guild\nattaches to the names of theatres, theatrical troupes, and constellations\ncounter for theatres, deities, Buddhist images, tall mountains, and satokagura songs" },
	{ "question": "座り", "answers": [ "すわり" ], "comment": "sitting\nstability" },
	{ "question": "座り込み", "answers": [ "すわりこみ" ], "comment": "sit-in (i.e. in protest)" },
	{ "question": "座る", "answers": [ "すわる" ], "comment": "to sit; to squat\nto assume (a position)\nto hold steady; to hold still" },
	{ "question": "座布団", "answers": [ "ざぶとん" ], "comment": "zabuton (flat floor cushion used when sitting or kneeling; usu. rectangular)" },
	{ "question": "座席", "answers": [ "ざせき" ], "comment": "seat" },
	{ "question": "座敷", "answers": [ "ざしき" ], "comment": "tatami room; tatami mat room; formal Japanese room\ndinner party in a tatami room (esp. when a geisha or maiko attends)" },
	{ "question": "座禅", "answers": [ "ざぜん" ], "comment": "zazen (seated Zen meditation, usu. in a cross-legged position)" },
	{ "question": "座談会", "answers": [ "ざだんかい" ], "comment": "symposium; round-table discussion" },
	{ "question": "座長", "answers": [ "ざちょう" ], "comment": "chairman\nleader of a troupe; proprietor of a theatrical company" },
	{ "question": "庭", "answers": [ "にわ" ], "comment": "garden; yard; courtyard\nfield (of action); area" },
	{ "question": "庭園", "answers": [ "ていえん" ], "comment": "garden; park" },
	{ "question": "庭木", "answers": [ "にわき" ], "comment": "garden tree" },
	{ "question": "庵", "answers": [ "いおり", "いお", "あん" ], "comment": "hermitage; retreat" },
	{ "question": "庶民", "answers": [ "しょみん" ], "comment": "masses; common people" },
	{ "question": "廃材", "answers": [ "はいざい" ], "comment": "scrap wood; scrap material" },
	{ "question": "廃案", "answers": [ "はいあん" ], "comment": "rejected bill (project)" },
	{ "question": "廃棄", "answers": [ "はいき" ], "comment": "disposal; abandonment; scrapping; discarding; abolition\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; repeal" },
	{ "question": "廃業", "answers": [ "はいぎょう" ], "comment": "cessation of business; discontinuation of business" },
	{ "question": "廃止", "answers": [ "はいし" ], "comment": "abolition; repeal" },
	{ "question": "廃絶", "answers": [ "はいぜつ" ], "comment": "abolition; elimination\nextinction; discontinuation" },
	{ "question": "廊下", "answers": [ "ろうか" ], "comment": "corridor; hallway; passageway" },
	{ "question": "延々", "answers": [ "えんえん" ], "comment": "forever; endlessly; on and on\nmeandering; wandering; winding; sinuous; serpentine; zigzagging" },
	{ "question": "延ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "to grow long (e.g. hair, nails)\nto lengthen; to extend; to stretch\nto reach out; to hold out\nto straighten; to smooth out\nto spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.)\nto dilute; to thin out\nto postpone\nto prolong\nto strengthen; to develop; to expand" },
	{ "question": "延びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "to stretch; to extend; to lengthen; to spread\nto make progress; to grow (beard, body height)\nto grow stale (soba)\nto be straightened; to be flattened; to be smoothed\nto be exhausted\nto be postponed; to be prolonged" },
	{ "question": "延べ", "answers": [ "のべ" ], "comment": "futures\ncredit (buying)\nstretching\ntotal (preceding counter, unit, etc.); aggregate; gross" },
	{ "question": "延命", "answers": [ "えんめい" ], "comment": "keeping alive longer; prolonging life; life extension; life-support" },
	{ "question": "延期", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "postponement; adjournment" },
	{ "question": "延滞", "answers": [ "えんたい" ], "comment": "arrears; (being) overdue; delay (e.g. in payment); procrastination" },
	{ "question": "延長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "extension; elongation; prolongation; lengthening\nEnchou era (923.4.11-931.4.26)" },
	{ "question": "建つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to be erected; to be built" },
	{ "question": "建てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "to build; to construct" },
	{ "question": "建て前", "answers": [ "たてまえ", "てまえ" ], "comment": "face; official stance; public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)\nceremony for the erection of the framework of a house\ntea ceremony procedures; tea ceremony etiquette" },
	{ "question": "建前", "answers": [ "たてまえ", "てまえ" ], "comment": "face; official stance; public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)\nceremony for the erection of the framework of a house\ntea ceremony procedures; tea ceremony etiquette" },
	{ "question": "建国", "answers": [ "けんこく" ], "comment": "founding of a nation" },
	{ "question": "建材", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "building material" },
	{ "question": "建物", "answers": [ "たてもの" ], "comment": "building" },
	{ "question": "建立", "answers": [ "こんりゅう", "けんりつ" ], "comment": "(act of) building (temple, monument, etc.); erection" },
	{ "question": "建築", "answers": [ "けんちく" ], "comment": "construction; architecture (of buildings)" },
	{ "question": "建築士", "answers": [ "けんちくし" ], "comment": "(authorized) architect and builder (authorised)" },
	{ "question": "建築学", "answers": [ "けんちくがく" ], "comment": "architecture" },
	{ "question": "建設", "answers": [ "けんせつ" ], "comment": "construction; establishment" },
	{ "question": "建設的", "answers": [ "けんせつてき" ], "comment": "constructive" },
	{ "question": "建設省", "answers": [ "けんせつしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Construction" },
	{ "question": "建議", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "proposition; motion; proposal; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "建造", "answers": [ "けんぞう" ], "comment": "building; construction" },
	{ "question": "建造物", "answers": [ "けんぞうぶつ" ], "comment": "structure" },
	{ "question": "弁", "answers": [ "べん" ], "comment": "speech; tongue; talk; eloquence\ndialect; brogue; accent\nbento; Japanese box lunch\npetal\nvalve\nOversight Department; division of the daijokan under the ritsuryo system responsible for controlling central and provincial governmental offices" },
	{ "question": "弁償", "answers": [ "べんしょう" ], "comment": "reimbursement; compensation; reparation; indemnity" },
	{ "question": "弁務官", "answers": [ "べんむかん" ], "comment": "commissioner" },
	{ "question": "弁当", "answers": [ "べんとう" ], "comment": "bento; Japanese box lunch" },
	{ "question": "弁慶", "answers": [ "べんけい" ], "comment": "strong person; person putting on a brave front\nbamboo tube with holes drilled in it (used as a stand for kitchen utensils, fans, etc.)\nchecks; plaid; checked pattern" },
	{ "question": "弁明", "answers": [ "べんめい" ], "comment": "explanation; excuse; vindication; apology" },
	{ "question": "弁済", "answers": [ "べんさい" ], "comment": "settlement; payment" },
	{ "question": "弁解", "answers": [ "べんかい" ], "comment": "explanation (e.g. for one's actions); excuse; justification; defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "弁論", "answers": [ "べんろん" ], "comment": "discussion; debate; argument" },
	{ "question": "弁護", "answers": [ "べんご" ], "comment": "defense; defence; pleading; advocacy" },
	{ "question": "弁護人", "answers": [ "べんごにん" ], "comment": "counsel; defender; advocate" },
	{ "question": "弁護士", "answers": [ "べんごし" ], "comment": "lawyer; attorney" },
	{ "question": "弊害", "answers": [ "へいがい" ], "comment": "harmful effect; harmful influence; evil practice; abuse; malady" },
	{ "question": "式", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "equation; formula; expression\nceremony\nstyle\nenforcement regulations (of the ritsuryo)" },
	{ "question": "式典", "answers": [ "しきてん" ], "comment": "ceremony; rites" },
	{ "question": "式場", "answers": [ "しきじょう" ], "comment": "ceremonial hall (e.g. wedding, funeral); hall for ceremonies; place of ceremony" },
	{ "question": "式部", "answers": [ "しきぶ" ], "comment": "(Meiji era) official responsible for court ceremonies" },
	{ "question": "弓", "answers": [ "ゆ", "ゆみ" ], "comment": "bow (and arrow)\narchery\nbow (for a violin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "弔問", "answers": [ "ちょうもん" ], "comment": "condolence call" },
	{ "question": "弔辞", "answers": [ "ちょうじ" ], "comment": "message of condolence; memorial address" },
	{ "question": "引きこもり", "answers": [ "ひきこもり" ], "comment": "shut-in; stay-at-home; hikikomori; people who withdraw from society\nsocial withdrawal; shunning other people" },
	{ "question": "引きずる", "answers": [ "ひきずる" ], "comment": "to drag along; to pull\nto force someone along\nto prolong; to drag out\nto influence strongly; to seduce" },
	{ "question": "引きつる", "answers": [ "ひきつる" ], "comment": "to have a cramp (spasm, convulsion, twitch); to become stiff" },
	{ "question": "引き上げ", "answers": [ "ひきあげ" ], "comment": "pulling up; drawing up; salvage; re-flotation\nraising; increase; upward revision\nrepatriation; evacuation" },
	{ "question": "引き上げる", "answers": [ "ひきあげる" ], "comment": "to pull up; to drag up; to lift up\nto increase; to raise (e.g. taxes)\nto withdraw; to leave; to pull out; to retire\nto promote (someone to a higher position)\nto return home\nto expedite the schedule" },
	{ "question": "引き下げ", "answers": [ "ひきさげ" ], "comment": "reduction; cut" },
	{ "question": "引き下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "to pull down; to lower; to reduce; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引き付ける", "answers": [ "ひきつける" ], "comment": "to fascinate; to attract; to charm\nto have a convulsion" },
	{ "question": "引き伸ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引き出し", "answers": [ "ひきだし" ], "comment": "drawer\nwithdrawal; drawing out\nvariety of knowledge and experience useful for handling things impromptu" },
	{ "question": "引き出す", "answers": [ "ひきだす" ], "comment": "to pull out; to take out; to draw out; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引き分け", "answers": [ "ひきわけ" ], "comment": "draw (in competition); tie game" },
	{ "question": "引き取り", "answers": [ "ひきとり" ], "comment": "leaving; accepting" },
	{ "question": "引き取る", "answers": [ "ひきとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to take back; to collect; to claim\nto take charge of; to take custody of; to look after; to take care of; to adopt\nto retire to a private place; to withdraw; to get out" },
	{ "question": "引き受け", "answers": [ "ひきうけ" ], "comment": "undertaking; underwriting; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "引き受ける", "answers": [ "ひきうける" ], "comment": "to take on; to undertake; to accept; to take charge of; to assume responsibility for\nto take over; to inherit\nto guarantee; to vouch for\nto contract (a disease)" },
	{ "question": "引き合い", "answers": [ "ひきあい" ], "comment": "reference; comparison; example\ninquiry; enquiry\nwitness; being involved in a court case; deal" },
	{ "question": "引き延ばし", "answers": [ "ひきのばし" ], "comment": "extension; prolongation\nenlargement" },
	{ "question": "引き延ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引き戻す", "answers": [ "ひきもどす" ], "comment": "to bring back; to restore" },
	{ "question": "引き抜く", "answers": [ "ひきぬく" ], "comment": "to extract; to pull out; to draw out; to uproot\nto headhunt; to lure away; to poach; to entice" },
	{ "question": "引き換え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引き替え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引き止める", "answers": [ "ひきとめる" ], "comment": "to detain; to check; to restrain" },
	{ "question": "引き渡し", "answers": [ "ひきわたし" ], "comment": "delivery; handing over; turning over; extradition" },
	{ "question": "引き渡す", "answers": [ "ひきわたす" ], "comment": "to deliver; to extradite; to stretch across; to hand over" },
	{ "question": "引き算", "answers": [ "ひきざん" ], "comment": "subtraction" },
	{ "question": "引き継ぎ", "answers": [ "ひきつぎ" ], "comment": "taking over; handing over; transfer of control; inheriting; passing on the baton" },
	{ "question": "引き継ぐ", "answers": [ "ひきつぐ" ], "comment": "to take over; to hand over" },
	{ "question": "引き続き", "answers": [ "ひきつづき" ], "comment": "continuously; continually; without a break\nnext; then; after that" },
	{ "question": "引き締まる", "answers": [ "ひきしまる" ], "comment": "to become tense; to be tightened" },
	{ "question": "引き締め", "answers": [ "ひきしめ" ], "comment": "tightening" },
	{ "question": "引き締める", "answers": [ "ひきしめる" ], "comment": "to tighten; to stiffen; to brace; to strain" },
	{ "question": "引き裂く", "answers": [ "ひきさく" ], "comment": "to tear up; to tear off; to rip up\nto separate (e.g. a couple); to disrupt (a relationship)" },
	{ "question": "引き起こす", "answers": [ "ひきおこす" ], "comment": "to cause; to induce; to bring about; to provoke\nto pull upright; to help up (e.g. a fallen person)" },
	{ "question": "引き起す", "answers": [ "ひきおこす" ], "comment": "to cause; to induce; to bring about; to provoke\nto pull upright; to help up (e.g. a fallen person)" },
	{ "question": "引き返す", "answers": [ "ひきかえす" ], "comment": "to turn back; to go back; to come back; to return; to retrace one's steps" },
	{ "question": "引き金", "answers": [ "ひきがね" ], "comment": "trigger; gunlock" },
	{ "question": "引き離す", "answers": [ "ひきはなす" ], "comment": "to pull apart; to separate" },
	{ "question": "引く", "answers": [ "ひく" ], "comment": "to pull\nto draw (attention, etc.); to attract (interest, etc.)\nto draw back\nto draw (card, mahjong tile, etc.)\nto draw (plan, line, etc.)\nto catch (cold)\nto play (string instr.)\nto look up (e.g. dictionary); to consult\nto haul; to pull (vehicles)\nto subtract\nto ebb; to fade\nto descend (from); to inherit (a characteristic)\nto quote; to raise (as evidence)\nto lay (a cable); to draw (a cable)" },
	{ "question": "引け目", "answers": [ "ひけめ" ], "comment": "sense of inferiority; one's weak point" },
	{ "question": "引っかかる", "answers": [ "ひっかかる" ], "comment": "to be caught in; to be stuck in\nto stop by; to drop in for a short visit; to be delayed; to take time\nto get mixed up in (trouble); to get entangled in (a problem); to be involved with\nto fall for (a trick); to be deceived; to be cheated\nto be on one's mind; to worry one; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy\nto be obstructed; to be hindered\nto splash" },
	{ "question": "引っ付く", "answers": [ "ひっつく" ], "comment": "to stick to; to cling to; to adhere to\nto become intimate (of a man and woman); to get close; to get married" },
	{ "question": "引っ張る", "answers": [ "ひっぱる" ], "comment": "to pull; to draw; to pull tight\nto string (lines); to run (cable); to stretch\nto pull towards oneself (e.g. someone's sleeve)\nto drag; to haul; to tow\nto lead (e.g. one's followers)\nto take someone somewhere (e.g. a suspect to the police)\nto tempt into joining; to strongly invite to join\nto delay; to prolong\nto lengthen the pronunciation (of a word)\nto quote; to cite; to reference\nto pull the ball\nto wear; to put on" },
	{ "question": "引っ掛かる", "answers": [ "ひっかかる" ], "comment": "to be caught in; to be stuck in\nto stop by; to drop in for a short visit; to be delayed; to take time\nto get mixed up in (trouble); to get entangled in (a problem); to be involved with\nto fall for (a trick); to be deceived; to be cheated\nto be on one's mind; to worry one; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy\nto be obstructed; to be hindered\nto splash" },
	{ "question": "引っ掛ける", "answers": [ "ひっかける" ], "comment": "to hang (something) on (something); to throw on (clothes)\nto hook; to catch; to trap; to ensnare\nto cheat; to evade payment; to jump a bill\nto drink (alcohol)\nto splash someone (with)\nto hit the ball off the end of the bat" },
	{ "question": "引っ掛る", "answers": [ "ひっかかる" ], "comment": "to be caught in; to be stuck in\nto stop by; to drop in for a short visit; to be delayed; to take time\nto get mixed up in (trouble); to get entangled in (a problem); to be involved with\nto fall for (a trick); to be deceived; to be cheated\nto be on one's mind; to worry one; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy\nto be obstructed; to be hindered\nto splash" },
	{ "question": "引っ越し", "answers": [ "ひっこし" ], "comment": "moving (dwelling, office, etc.); changing residence" },
	{ "question": "引っ越す", "answers": [ "ひっこす", "ひきこす" ], "comment": "to move (house); to change residence" },
	{ "question": "引っ込む", "answers": [ "ひっこむ" ], "comment": "to draw back; to sink; to cave in\nto be set back (e.g. from a road)\nto withdraw (e.g. from the public eye); to retire to (somewhere); to stay indoors; to butt out; to stay out of it" },
	{ "question": "引上げる", "answers": [ "ひきあげる" ], "comment": "to pull up; to drag up; to lift up\nto increase; to raise (e.g. taxes)\nto withdraw; to leave; to pull out; to retire\nto promote (someone to a higher position)\nto return home\nto expedite the schedule" },
	{ "question": "引下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "to pull down; to lower; to reduce; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引付ける", "answers": [ "ひきつける" ], "comment": "to fascinate; to attract; to charm\nto have a convulsion" },
	{ "question": "引伸ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引出し", "answers": [ "ひきだし" ], "comment": "drawer\nwithdrawal; drawing out\nvariety of knowledge and experience useful for handling things impromptu" },
	{ "question": "引出す", "answers": [ "ひきだす" ], "comment": "to pull out; to take out; to draw out; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引分け", "answers": [ "ひきわけ" ], "comment": "draw (in competition); tie game" },
	{ "question": "引力", "answers": [ "いんりょく" ], "comment": "attraction (e.g. magnetic, gravitation); affinity; gravitational pull\nattractiveness; magnetism" },
	{ "question": "引取る", "answers": [ "ひきとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to take back; to collect; to claim\nto take charge of; to take custody of; to look after; to take care of; to adopt\nto retire to a private place; to withdraw; to get out" },
	{ "question": "引受ける", "answers": [ "ひきうける" ], "comment": "to take on; to undertake; to accept; to take charge of; to assume responsibility for\nto take over; to inherit\nto guarantee; to vouch for\nto contract (a disease)" },
	{ "question": "引延ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引戻す", "answers": [ "ひきもどす" ], "comment": "to bring back; to restore" },
	{ "question": "引抜く", "answers": [ "ひきぬく" ], "comment": "to extract; to pull out; to draw out; to uproot\nto headhunt; to lure away; to poach; to entice" },
	{ "question": "引換え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引替え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引止める", "answers": [ "ひきとめる" ], "comment": "to detain; to check; to restrain" },
	{ "question": "引用", "answers": [ "いんよう" ], "comment": "quotation; citation; reference" },
	{ "question": "引算", "answers": [ "ひきざん" ], "comment": "subtraction" },
	{ "question": "引継ぎ", "answers": [ "ひきつぎ" ], "comment": "taking over; handing over; transfer of control; inheriting; passing on the baton" },
	{ "question": "引継ぐ", "answers": [ "ひきつぐ" ], "comment": "to take over; to hand over" },
	{ "question": "引続き", "answers": [ "ひきつづき" ], "comment": "continuously; continually; without a break\nnext; then; after that" },
	{ "question": "引締め", "answers": [ "ひきしめ" ], "comment": "tightening" },
	{ "question": "引裂く", "answers": [ "ひきさく" ], "comment": "to tear up; to tear off; to rip up\nto separate (e.g. a couple); to disrupt (a relationship)" },
	{ "question": "引責", "answers": [ "いんせき" ], "comment": "taking responsibility" },
	{ "question": "引返す", "answers": [ "ひきかえす" ], "comment": "to turn back; to go back; to come back; to return; to retrace one's steps" },
	{ "question": "引退", "answers": [ "いんたい" ], "comment": "retire" },
	{ "question": "引金", "answers": [ "ひきがね" ], "comment": "trigger; gunlock" },
	{ "question": "引離す", "answers": [ "ひきはなす" ], "comment": "to pull apart; to separate" },
	{ "question": "弟", "answers": [ "おとうと", "てい", "おと" ], "comment": "younger brother; little brother; kid brother\npupil; apprentice" },
	{ "question": "弟子", "answers": [ "でし", "ていし" ], "comment": "pupil; disciple; adherent; follower; apprentice; young person; teacher's student-helper" },
	{ "question": "弟子入り", "answers": [ "でしいり" ], "comment": "apprenticeship; enrolling" },
	{ "question": "弥生", "answers": [ "やよい", "いやおい" ], "comment": "third month of the lunar calendar\nthick growth (of grass, etc.)\nYayoi period (ca. 300 BCE - 300 CE)" },
	{ "question": "弦", "answers": [ "つる", "げん" ], "comment": "string (of shamisen, guitar, violin, etc.)\nbail (arched pot handle)\ndiagonal levelling wire across the top of a masu\nbowstring" },
	{ "question": "弦楽", "answers": [ "げんがく" ], "comment": "music for strings; string music" },
	{ "question": "弱", "answers": [ "じゃく" ], "comment": "little less than; fewer than; under\nweakness; the weak" },
	{ "question": "弱い", "answers": [ "よわい" ], "comment": "weak; frail; delicate; tender; unskilled; weak (wine)" },
	{ "question": "弱まる", "answers": [ "よわまる" ], "comment": "to abate; to weaken; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed" },
	{ "question": "弱み", "answers": [ "よわみ" ], "comment": "(a) weakness; shortcoming; failing; sore point" },
	{ "question": "弱める", "answers": [ "よわめる" ], "comment": "to weaken" },
	{ "question": "弱る", "answers": [ "よわる" ], "comment": "to weaken; to be troubled; to be downcast; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed; to impair" },
	{ "question": "弱体", "answers": [ "じゃくたい" ], "comment": "weak (organization, organisation)" },
	{ "question": "弱気", "answers": [ "よわき" ], "comment": "timid; weak-kneed; fainthearted\nbearish (e.g. market)" },
	{ "question": "弱点", "answers": [ "じゃくてん" ], "comment": "weak point; weakness; shortcoming; defect; flaw; sore spot; tender spot" },
	{ "question": "弱者", "answers": [ "じゃくしゃ" ], "comment": "weak person; the weak; vulnerable person; disadvantaged person" },
	{ "question": "弱虫", "answers": [ "よわむし" ], "comment": "coward; weakling; scaredy cat; wimp; sissy" },
	{ "question": "弱音", "answers": [ "よわね" ], "comment": "feeble complaint; whine" },
	{ "question": "張り", "answers": [ "ばり" ], "comment": "in the style of (esp. literary, artistic, etc. works); reminiscent of\nattached or stretched on" },
	{ "question": "張り出す", "answers": [ "はりだす" ], "comment": "to project; to overhang; to stick out; to jut out; to overlie\nto put up (a notice); to post" },
	{ "question": "張り切る", "answers": [ "はりきる" ], "comment": "to be in high spirits; to be full of vigor (vigour); to be enthusiastic; to be eager; to stretch to breaking point" },
	{ "question": "張り紙", "answers": [ "はりがみ" ], "comment": "paper patch; paper backing; poster; sticker; label" },
	{ "question": "張る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "to stick; to paste; to affix\nto stretch; to spread; to strain; to tighten; to put up (tent)\nto form (e.g. ice on a pond)\nto fill; to swell\nto stick out; to put; to slap\nto be expensive\nto keep a watch on; to be on the lookout\nto become one tile away from completion\nto span; to generate" },
	{ "question": "張本人", "answers": [ "ちょうほんにん" ], "comment": "ringleader; originator; perpetrator" },
	{ "question": "強い", "answers": [ "つよい" ], "comment": "strong; powerful; mighty; potent\nresistant; resilient; durable" },
	{ "question": "強いて", "answers": [ "しいて" ], "comment": "by force" },
	{ "question": "強いる", "answers": [ "しいる" ], "comment": "to force; to compel; to coerce" },
	{ "question": "強さ", "answers": [ "つよさ" ], "comment": "strength; power" },
	{ "question": "強まる", "answers": [ "つよまる" ], "comment": "to get strong; to gain strength" },
	{ "question": "強み", "answers": [ "つよみ" ], "comment": "forte; strong point" },
	{ "question": "強める", "answers": [ "つよめる" ], "comment": "to strengthen; to emphasize; to emphasise" },
	{ "question": "強制", "answers": [ "きょうせい" ], "comment": "obligation; coercion; compulsion; enforcement" },
	{ "question": "強力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "powerful; strong" },
	{ "question": "強化", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "strengthening; intensifying; reinforcement; solidification" },
	{ "question": "強固", "answers": [ "きょうこ" ], "comment": "firmness; stability; security; strength" },
	{ "question": "強大", "answers": [ "きょうだい" ], "comment": "mighty; powerful" },
	{ "question": "強度", "answers": [ "きょうど" ], "comment": "strength; intensity" },
	{ "question": "強引", "answers": [ "ごういん" ], "comment": "overbearing; coercive; pushy; forcible; high-handed" },
	{ "question": "強情", "answers": [ "ごうじょう" ], "comment": "obstinate; stubborn; headstrong" },
	{ "question": "強打", "answers": [ "きょうだ" ], "comment": "smiting; blow" },
	{ "question": "強敵", "answers": [ "きょうてき" ], "comment": "formidable enemy; strong enemy; tough enemy" },
	{ "question": "強権", "answers": [ "きょうけん" ], "comment": "power of the state" },
	{ "question": "強気", "answers": [ "つよき" ], "comment": "confident; assured; self-assured; firm; strong; cocksure\nbullish (e.g. market)" },
	{ "question": "強烈", "answers": [ "きょうれつ" ], "comment": "strong; intense; severe" },
	{ "question": "強盗", "answers": [ "ごうとう" ], "comment": "robber; mugger\nrobbery; burglary" },
	{ "question": "強硬", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "firm; vigorous; unbending; unyielding; strong; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "強者", "answers": [ "きょうしゃ" ], "comment": "strong person" },
	{ "question": "強行", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "forcing; enforcement\nforced; enforced" },
	{ "question": "強行採決", "answers": [ "きょうこうさいけつ" ], "comment": "steamroller voting; steamrollering" },
	{ "question": "強要", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "coercion; extortion; compulsion; force" },
	{ "question": "強調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "emphasis; highlight; stress; stressed point" },
	{ "question": "強豪", "answers": [ "きょうごう" ], "comment": "veteran; champion" },
	{ "question": "強風", "answers": [ "きょうふう" ], "comment": "strong wind; high wind; moderate gale" },
	{ "question": "弾く", "answers": [ "ひく", "はじく" ], "comment": "to play (piano, guitar)\nto flip; to snap; to flick\nto repel​\nto use (an abacus); to calculate​\nto strum; to pluck the strings (of a guitar, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "弾む", "answers": [ "はずむ" ], "comment": "to spring; to bound; to bounce; to be stimulated; to be encouraged; to get lively; to treat oneself to; to splurge on" },
	{ "question": "弾丸", "answers": [ "だんがん" ], "comment": "bullet; shot; shell" },
	{ "question": "弾力", "answers": [ "だんりょく" ], "comment": "elasticity; flexibility" },
	{ "question": "弾劾", "answers": [ "だんがい" ], "comment": "impeachment\ndenunciation; accusation; censure; arraignment" },
	{ "question": "弾圧", "answers": [ "だんあつ" ], "comment": "oppression; suppression; pressure" },
	{ "question": "弾薬", "answers": [ "だんやく" ], "comment": "ammunition; ammo" },
	{ "question": "弾道", "answers": [ "だんどう" ], "comment": "trajectory; line of fire\nballistic" },
	{ "question": "弾頭", "answers": [ "だんとう" ], "comment": "warhead" },
	{ "question": "当たり", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "hit\nsuccess\nguess; prediction\naffability; friendliness\nsensation; touch\nbruise (on fruit)\nsituation in which a stone or chain of stones may be captured on the next move (in the game of go)\nbite (of a fish on a hook); strike\nper; each" },
	{ "question": "当たり前", "answers": [ "あたりまえ" ], "comment": "natural; reasonable; obvious\nusual; common; ordinary; commonplace; the norm" },
	{ "question": "当たり役", "answers": [ "あたりやく" ], "comment": "successful role" },
	{ "question": "当たる", "answers": [ "あたる" ], "comment": "to be hit; to strike\nto touch; to be in contact; to be affixed\nto be equivalent to; to be applicable; to apply to\nto be right on the money (of a prediction, criticism, etc.)\nto be selected (in a lottery, etc.); to win\nto be successful; to go well; to be a hit\nto face; to confront\nto lie (in the direction of)\nto undertake; to be assigned\nto be stricken (by food poisoning, heat, etc.); to be afflicted\nto be called upon (by the teacher)\nto treat (esp. harshly); to lash out at\nto be unnecessary\nto be hitting well; to be on a hitting streak\n(in fishing) to feel a bite\n(of fruit, etc.) to be bruised; to spoil\nto feel (something) out; to probe into; to check (i.e. by comparison)\nto shave\nto be a relative of a person; to stand in a relationship" },
	{ "question": "当てはまる", "answers": [ "あてはまる" ], "comment": "to apply (a rule); to be applicable; to come under (a category); to fulfill; to hold true" },
	{ "question": "当てはめる", "answers": [ "あてはめる" ], "comment": "to apply; to adapt" },
	{ "question": "当てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "to hit\nto expose\nto apply (e.g. patch); to put on; to put against; to hold on; to hold against\nto allot; to call on someone (e.g. in class)\nto guess (an answer)\nto make a hit (e.g. in a lottery)" },
	{ "question": "当の", "answers": [ "とうの" ], "comment": "the ... in question" },
	{ "question": "当り", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "hit\nsuccess\nguess; prediction\naffability; friendliness\nsensation; touch\nbruise (on fruit)\nsituation in which a stone or chain of stones may be captured on the next move (in the game of go)\nbite (of a fish on a hook); strike\nper; each" },
	{ "question": "当り前", "answers": [ "あたりまえ" ], "comment": "natural; reasonable; obvious\nusual; common; ordinary; commonplace; the norm" },
	{ "question": "当事", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "matter under concern" },
	{ "question": "当事者", "answers": [ "とうじしゃ" ], "comment": "person concerned; interested party; related party" },
	{ "question": "当人", "answers": [ "とうにん" ], "comment": "the one concerned; the said person" },
	{ "question": "当分", "answers": [ "とうぶん" ], "comment": "for the present; currently; presently; at this time; for the next while" },
	{ "question": "当初", "answers": [ "とうしょ" ], "comment": "at first; at the beginning; initially; originally" },
	{ "question": "当地", "answers": [ "とうち" ], "comment": "this place; here" },
	{ "question": "当局", "answers": [ "とうきょく" ], "comment": "authorities\nthis office" },
	{ "question": "当惑", "answers": [ "とうわく" ], "comment": "bewilderment; perplexity; embarrassment; confusion" },
	{ "question": "当方", "answers": [ "とうほう" ], "comment": "us; me; my (our) part" },
	{ "question": "当日", "answers": [ "とうじつ" ], "comment": "appointed day; very day" },
	{ "question": "当時", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "at that time; in those days" },
	{ "question": "当期", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "current term (period)" },
	{ "question": "当然", "answers": [ "とうぜん" ], "comment": "natural; as a matter of course; justified; deserved; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "当番", "answers": [ "とうばん" ], "comment": "being on duty" },
	{ "question": "当直", "answers": [ "とうちょく" ], "comment": "on duty; on a shift; keeping watch" },
	{ "question": "当確", "answers": [ "とうかく" ], "comment": "projected to win; sure to be elected; home free" },
	{ "question": "当社", "answers": [ "とうしゃ" ], "comment": "(this) shrine\n(this) company; (this) firm" },
	{ "question": "当落", "answers": [ "とうらく" ], "comment": "result of an election; success or defeat in an election" },
	{ "question": "当選", "answers": [ "とうせん" ], "comment": "being elected\nbeing selected (to win a prize, etc.)\nwinning (in a lottery, raffle, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "当面", "answers": [ "とうめん" ], "comment": "current; urgent; pressing; impending\nto confront (an issue); to face (up to something)\nfor the meantime; at present" },
	{ "question": "形", "answers": [ "かたち", "よう" ], "comment": "form; shape; figure\nvisage" },
	{ "question": "形勢", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "condition; situation; prospects" },
	{ "question": "形容詞", "answers": [ "けいようし" ], "comment": "adjective; i-adjective (in Japanese)" },
	{ "question": "形式", "answers": [ "けいしき" ], "comment": "form (as opposed to substance); formality\nmethod; system; style\nformat; mode; appearance; form (something takes)\nmath expression" },
	{ "question": "形式的", "answers": [ "けいしきてき" ], "comment": "formal" },
	{ "question": "形態", "answers": [ "けいたい" ], "comment": "form; shape; figure" },
	{ "question": "形成", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "formation; molding; taking form\nrepair (e.g. plastic surgery); replacement; -plasty" },
	{ "question": "形状", "answers": [ "けいじょう" ], "comment": "shape; form" },
	{ "question": "形見", "answers": [ "かたみ" ], "comment": "memento; keepsake; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "形跡", "answers": [ "けいせき" ], "comment": "traces; evidence" },
	{ "question": "彩り", "answers": [ "いろどり" ], "comment": "coloring; colouring; coloration; colouration; assortment; color scheme; colour scheme; makeup" },
	{ "question": "彩る", "answers": [ "いろどる" ], "comment": "to colour; to color; to paint\nto apply make-up\nto decorate; to garnish; to adorn; to add flair" },
	{ "question": "彩色", "answers": [ "さいしき", "さいしょく" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colouration; coloration; painting" },
	{ "question": "彫る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "to carve; to engrave; to sculpt; to chisel\nto tattoo" },
	{ "question": "彫刻", "answers": [ "ちょうこく" ], "comment": "carving; engraving; sculpture" },
	{ "question": "影", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "shadow; silhouette; figure; shape\nreflection; image\nominous sign\nlight (stars, moon)\ntrace; shadow (of one's former self)" },
	{ "question": "影の内閣", "answers": [ "かげのないかく" ], "comment": "shadow cabinet" },
	{ "question": "影響", "answers": [ "えいきょう" ], "comment": "influence; effect\nto influence; to affect; to have an influence on; to impact; to have an effect on" },
	{ "question": "役", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "use; service; role\npost; position\nscoring combination (e.g. in mahjong, card games, etc.); hand" },
	{ "question": "役に立たない", "answers": [ "やくにたたない" ], "comment": "of no avail; useless" },
	{ "question": "役に立つ", "answers": [ "やくにたつ" ], "comment": "to be helpful; to be useful" },
	{ "question": "役人", "answers": [ "やくにん" ], "comment": "government official" },
	{ "question": "役割", "answers": [ "やくわり" ], "comment": "part; assigning (allotment of) parts; role; duties" },
	{ "question": "役員", "answers": [ "やくいん" ], "comment": "officer; official; executive; staff" },
	{ "question": "役回り", "answers": [ "やくまわり" ], "comment": "role; part; duty" },
	{ "question": "役場", "answers": [ "やくば" ], "comment": "town hall" },
	{ "question": "役所", "answers": [ "やくしょ" ], "comment": "government office; public office" },
	{ "question": "役柄", "answers": [ "やくがら" ], "comment": "role" },
	{ "question": "役目", "answers": [ "やくめ" ], "comment": "duty; role; function" },
	{ "question": "役立つ", "answers": [ "やくだつ" ], "comment": "to be useful; to be helpful; to serve the purpose" },
	{ "question": "役者", "answers": [ "やくしゃ" ], "comment": "actor; actress" },
	{ "question": "役職", "answers": [ "やくしょく" ], "comment": "post; managerial position; official position" },
	{ "question": "彼", "answers": [ "かれ" ], "comment": "he; him\nhis\nboyfriend" },
	{ "question": "彼ら", "answers": [ "かれら" ], "comment": "they (usually male); them" },
	{ "question": "彼女", "answers": [ "かのじょ" ], "comment": "she; her\nher\ngirlfriend; sweetheart" },
	{ "question": "彼岸", "answers": [ "ひがん" ], "comment": "equinoctial week (when Buddhist services are held)\nBuddhist services during the equinoctial week\nnirvana" },
	{ "question": "往年", "answers": [ "おうねん" ], "comment": "former; one-time; years ago" },
	{ "question": "往復", "answers": [ "おうふく" ], "comment": "making a round trip; going and returning; coming and going\nround-trip ticket; return ticket\ncorrespondence; exchanging (letters)\nsocializing; visiting one another" },
	{ "question": "往来", "answers": [ "おうらい" ], "comment": "coming and going; traffic\nroad; street\nassociation; socializing; socialising; fellowship; mutual visits\nrecurring (e.g. thoughts)\ncorrespondence" },
	{ "question": "往生", "answers": [ "おうじょう" ], "comment": "passing on to the next life\ndeath\ngiving up a struggle; submission\nbeing at one's wits' end; being flummoxed\ncoercion" },
	{ "question": "征服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "conquest; subjugation; overcoming" },
	{ "question": "待たす", "answers": [ "またす" ], "comment": "to keep (a person) waiting" },
	{ "question": "待たせる", "answers": [ "またせる" ], "comment": "to keep (a person) waiting" },
	{ "question": "待ち", "answers": [ "まち" ], "comment": "waiting; waiting time" },
	{ "question": "待ち伏せ", "answers": [ "まちぶせ" ], "comment": "ambush; lying in wait for an ambush" },
	{ "question": "待ち兼ねる", "answers": [ "まちかねる" ], "comment": "to wait impatiently for" },
	{ "question": "待ち受ける", "answers": [ "まちうける" ], "comment": "to await; to expect" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせ", "answers": [ "まちあわせ" ], "comment": "appointment" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせる", "answers": [ "まちあわせる" ], "comment": "to rendezvous; to meet at a prearranged place and time; to arrange to meet" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせ場所", "answers": [ "まちあわせばしょ" ], "comment": "meeting place" },
	{ "question": "待ち望む", "answers": [ "まちのぞむ" ], "comment": "to wait eagerly for; to look forward to" },
	{ "question": "待ち構える", "answers": [ "まちかまえる" ], "comment": "to lie in wait; to be on the watch for" },
	{ "question": "待ち遠しい", "answers": [ "まちどおしい" ], "comment": "looking forward to; anxiously awaited" },
	{ "question": "待つ", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "to wait\nto await; to look forward to; to anticipate\nto depend on; to need" },
	{ "question": "待合", "answers": [ "まちあい" ], "comment": "rendezvous; meeting; assignation\narea where guests gather before the start of a tea ceremony\nwaiting room\nmeeting place for assignations, drinking, etc." },
	{ "question": "待合室", "answers": [ "まちあいしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "待望", "answers": [ "たいぼう" ], "comment": "waiting expectantly; waiting eagerly; looking forward to\nlong-awaited" },
	{ "question": "待機", "answers": [ "たいき" ], "comment": "alert; standby; await an opportunity; wait for orders" },
	{ "question": "待遇", "answers": [ "たいぐう" ], "comment": "treatment; reception; service\nworking conditions; salary; pay; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "後", "answers": [ "あと" ], "comment": "behind; rear\nafter; later\nafter one's death\nremainder; the rest\ndescendant; successor; heir\nmore (e.g. five more minutes); left\nalso; in addition\npast; previous" },
	{ "question": "後ろ", "answers": [ "うしろ" ], "comment": "back; behind; rear" },
	{ "question": "後ろ向き", "answers": [ "うしろむき" ], "comment": "back facing; turning one's back to; pessimistic; backwards\nreactionary; backward-looking" },
	{ "question": "後ろ姿", "answers": [ "うしろすがた" ], "comment": "retreating figure; appearance from behind" },
	{ "question": "後ろ盾", "answers": [ "うしろだて" ], "comment": "backing; support; backer; supporter; patron; sponsor\nshield that protects one's back" },
	{ "question": "後世", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "posterity; future life; life to come" },
	{ "question": "後任", "answers": [ "こうにん" ], "comment": "successor" },
	{ "question": "後半", "answers": [ "こうはん" ], "comment": "second half; latter half" },
	{ "question": "後半戦", "answers": [ "こうはんせん" ], "comment": "second half" },
	{ "question": "後回し", "answers": [ "あとまわし" ], "comment": "putting off; postponing" },
	{ "question": "後天的", "answers": [ "こうてんてき" ], "comment": "a posteriori; acquired" },
	{ "question": "後始末", "answers": [ "あとしまつ" ], "comment": "settlement (of affairs); remedial measures; cleaning up afterwards" },
	{ "question": "後悔", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "regret; repentance; remorse" },
	{ "question": "後戻り", "answers": [ "あともどり" ], "comment": "going backward; turning back; backtracking; doubling back\nretrogression; relapse; returning to a bad state" },
	{ "question": "後手", "answers": [ "ごて" ], "comment": "losing initiative; being forestalled\nsecond move (in go or shogi); moving second; person with the second move\nrear guard" },
	{ "question": "後押し", "answers": [ "あとおし" ], "comment": "pushing; backing; boosting; supporting\npushing from behind (a cart, etc.); pusher" },
	{ "question": "後援", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "support; backing" },
	{ "question": "後方", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "behind; in the rear; in back" },
	{ "question": "後日", "answers": [ "ごじつ", "ごにち" ], "comment": "in the future; another day; later" },
	{ "question": "後書", "answers": [ "あとがき" ], "comment": "afterword; postscript" },
	{ "question": "後書き", "answers": [ "あとがき" ], "comment": "afterword; postscript" },
	{ "question": "後期", "answers": [ "こうき" ], "comment": "latter period; second half; late stage; third trimester; second semester" },
	{ "question": "後片付け", "answers": [ "あとかたづけ" ], "comment": "tidying up; cleaning; clearing away; putting in order" },
	{ "question": "後発", "answers": [ "こうはつ" ], "comment": "starting late" },
	{ "question": "後継", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "succession\nsuccessor" },
	{ "question": "後続", "answers": [ "こうぞく" ], "comment": "succeeding; following; trailing" },
	{ "question": "後者", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "the latter" },
	{ "question": "後見", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "guardianship; guardian\n(theatrical) assistant; prompter" },
	{ "question": "後輩", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "junior (at work, school, etc.); younger people; younger student" },
	{ "question": "後退", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "retreat\nbackspace; BS" },
	{ "question": "後進", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "one's junior; next generation\nreversing; going astern; going backwards" },
	{ "question": "後遺症", "answers": [ "こういしょう" ], "comment": "prognostic symptoms; after-effect" },
	{ "question": "後部", "answers": [ "こうぶ" ], "comment": "rear; stern" },
	{ "question": "徐々", "answers": [ "じょじょ" ], "comment": "gradually; steadily; quietly; slowly; little by little\nsoon" },
	{ "question": "徐行", "answers": [ "じょこう" ], "comment": "going slowly" },
	{ "question": "徒歩", "answers": [ "とほ" ], "comment": "walking; going on foot" },
	{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany" },
	{ "question": "従える", "answers": [ "したがえる" ], "comment": "to be accompanied by\nto conquer; to subjugate; to subdue" },
	{ "question": "従事", "answers": [ "じゅうじ" ], "comment": "engaging; pursuing; following (e.g. profession or occupation)" },
	{ "question": "従属", "answers": [ "じゅうぞく" ], "comment": "subordination; dependency" },
	{ "question": "従来", "answers": [ "じゅうらい" ], "comment": "up to now; so far\ntraditional; conventional; usual; existing" },
	{ "question": "従業員", "answers": [ "じゅうぎょういん" ], "comment": "employee; worker" },
	{ "question": "従軍", "answers": [ "じゅうぐん" ], "comment": "military service; serving in a war; taking part in a campaign" },
	{ "question": "得", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "profit; advantage; benefit; gain\nrebirth in paradise, entering nirvana" },
	{ "question": "得々", "answers": [ "とくとく" ], "comment": "triumphantly; proudly" },
	{ "question": "得する", "answers": [ "とくする" ], "comment": "to make a profit" },
	{ "question": "得る", "answers": [ "える", "うる" ], "comment": "to be able to ...; can ...\nto get; to acquire; to obtain; to procure; to earn; to win; to gain; to secure; to attain /\n to get; to earn; to acquire; to procure; to gain; to secure; to attain; to obtain; to win\nto understand; to comprehend\nto receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment); to get (ill)\nto be able to ..., can ..." },
	{ "question": "得失", "answers": [ "とくしつ" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; plus and minuses" },
	{ "question": "得意", "answers": [ "とくい" ], "comment": "triumph; prosperity\npride\none's strong point; one's forte; one's specialty\nfrequent customer (client, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "得意先", "answers": [ "とくいさき" ], "comment": "customer; client; patron; clientele; constituency" },
	{ "question": "得点", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "score; points made; marks obtained; runs" },
	{ "question": "得票", "answers": [ "とくひょう" ], "comment": "number of votes polled; poll votes" },
	{ "question": "得策", "answers": [ "とくさく" ], "comment": "profitable plan; good plan" },
	{ "question": "御中 (not おなか)", "answers": [ "おんちゅう" ], "comment": "and Company; Messrs; for the attention of ..." },
	{ "question": "御前", "answers": [ "おまえ", "おめえ", "おまい" ], "comment": "you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)\npresence (of a god, nobleman, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "御化け", "answers": [ "おばけ" ], "comment": "goblin; monster; demon\nghost; apparition" },
	{ "question": "御所", "answers": [ "ごしょ" ], "comment": "old imperial palace" },
	{ "question": "御無沙汰", "answers": [ "ごぶさた" ], "comment": "not writing or contacting for a while; neglecting (failing) to write (call, visit, etc.); long silence" },
	{ "question": "御用邸", "answers": [ "ごようてい" ], "comment": "imperial villa" },
	{ "question": "御苑", "answers": [ "ぎょえん" ], "comment": "imperial garden" },
	{ "question": "御願い", "answers": [ "おねがい" ], "comment": "request; wish\nplease" },
	{ "question": "御飯", "answers": [ "ごはん" ], "comment": "cooked rice\nmeal" },
	{ "question": "復元", "answers": [ "ふくげん" ], "comment": "restoration (to original state); reconstruction" },
	{ "question": "復党", "answers": [ "ふくとう" ], "comment": "rejoining a political party" },
	{ "question": "復刻", "answers": [ "ふっこく" ], "comment": "republishing; republication; reissuing; reproduction" },
	{ "question": "復員", "answers": [ "ふくいん" ], "comment": "demobilization; demobilisation; repatriation" },
	{ "question": "復帰", "answers": [ "ふっき" ], "comment": "return; comeback; reinstatement\ncarriage return; CR" },
	{ "question": "復旧", "answers": [ "ふっきゅう", "ふくきゅう" ], "comment": "restoration; restitution; rehabilitation" },
	{ "question": "復権", "answers": [ "ふっけん", "ふくけん" ], "comment": "rehabilitation; reinstatement; restoration of rights" },
	{ "question": "復活", "answers": [ "ふっかつ" ], "comment": "revival (e.g. musical); come-back\nrestoration; rebirth; resurrection" },
	{ "question": "復習", "answers": [ "ふくしゅう" ], "comment": "review; revision" },
	{ "question": "復興", "answers": [ "ふっこう" ], "comment": "revival; renaissance; reconstruction; restoration" },
	{ "question": "復調", "answers": [ "ふくちょう" ], "comment": "demodulation\nrecovery; getting back to form" },
	{ "question": "復讐", "answers": [ "ふくしゅう" ], "comment": "revenge" },
	{ "question": "循環", "answers": [ "じゅんかん" ], "comment": "circulation; rotation; cycle" },
	{ "question": "循環器", "answers": [ "じゅんかんき" ], "comment": "circulatory organ" },
	{ "question": "微動", "answers": [ "びどう" ], "comment": "slight tremor; slight movement; a quiver" },
	{ "question": "微塵", "answers": [ "みじん" ], "comment": "particle; atom; little piece\nnot at all; not the slightest" },
	{ "question": "微妙", "answers": [ "びみょう" ], "comment": "delicate; subtle; sensitive\ndifficult; delicate (situation); complicated\ndoubtful; questionable; dicey; tricky" },
	{ "question": "微小", "answers": [ "びしょう" ], "comment": "microscopic" },
	{ "question": "微生物", "answers": [ "びせいぶつ" ], "comment": "microbe; germ" },
	{ "question": "微笑", "answers": [ "びしょう" ], "comment": "smile" },
	{ "question": "微笑む", "answers": [ "ほほえむ" ], "comment": "to smile" },
	{ "question": "微細", "answers": [ "びさい" ], "comment": "minute; micro; detailed; delicate; subtle" },
	{ "question": "微量", "answers": [ "びりょう" ], "comment": "minuscule amount; extremely small quantity" },
	{ "question": "微震", "answers": [ "びしん" ], "comment": "slight earthquake" },
	{ "question": "徴候", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "sign; indication; omen; symptom" },
	{ "question": "徴兵", "answers": [ "ちょうへい" ], "comment": "conscription; recruitment; enlistment" },
	{ "question": "徴収", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "collection (of fees, taxes, etc.); levy" },
	{ "question": "徹す", "answers": [ "とおす" ], "comment": "to stick through; to force through\nto spread throughout; to thoroughly diffuse\nto make a path between two points\nto proceed in a logical manner\nto let pass; to allow through\nto lead (someone) into (a house, room, etc.); to show in\nto go through (a middleman)\nto (look, listen) through (a window, wall, etc.)\nto pass (a law, applicant, etc.)\nto force to accept; to force agreement\nto continue (in a state); to persist in\nto do to the entirety of; to cover all of; to span the whole ...\nto do from beginning to end without a break\nto convey (one's ideas, etc.) to the other party\nto do to the end; to carry through; to complete" },
	{ "question": "徹する", "answers": [ "てっする" ], "comment": "to penetrate; to sink in\nto devote oneself (to); to do intently and exclusively\nto do throughout (e.g. the night)" },
	{ "question": "徹夜", "answers": [ "てつや" ], "comment": "all night; all-night vigil; sleepless night" },
	{ "question": "徹底", "answers": [ "てってい" ], "comment": "thoroughness; completeness; consistency\nthorough enforcement; seeing to it that a policy, etc. is carried out without exception" },
	{ "question": "徹底的", "answers": [ "てっていてき" ], "comment": "thorough; complete" },
	{ "question": "心", "answers": [ "こころ", "しん" ], "comment": "mind; heart; spirit\nthe meaning of a phrase (riddle, etc.) /\n heart; mind\nspirit; vitality; inner strength\nChinese \"Heart\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nfriend" },
	{ "question": "心から", "answers": [ "こころから", "しんから" ], "comment": "from the bottom of one's heart; heart and soul; by nature" },
	{ "question": "心がける", "answers": [ "こころがける" ], "comment": "to keep in mind; to bear in mind; to try; to aim to do; to endeavor; to endeavour" },
	{ "question": "心をこめて", "answers": [ "こころをこめて" ], "comment": "wholeheartedly" },
	{ "question": "心を込めて", "answers": [ "こころをこめて" ], "comment": "wholeheartedly" },
	{ "question": "心不全", "answers": [ "しんふぜん" ], "comment": "heart failure" },
	{ "question": "心中", "answers": [ "しんじゅう", "しんぢゅう", "しんちゅう" ], "comment": "double suicide; lovers suicide /\n in one's heart; true motives; mind" },
	{ "question": "心地", "answers": [ "ここち" ], "comment": "feeling; sensation; mood\nsensation of doing (usu. after -masu stem of verb)" },
	{ "question": "心境", "answers": [ "しんきょう" ], "comment": "mental state" },
	{ "question": "心外", "answers": [ "しんがい" ], "comment": "regrettable; vexing; upsetting\nunthinkable; wholly unexpected" },
	{ "question": "心強い", "answers": [ "こころづよい" ], "comment": "heartening; reassuring" },
	{ "question": "心当たり", "answers": [ "こころあたり" ], "comment": "having some knowledge of; happening to know" },
	{ "question": "心待ち", "answers": [ "こころまち" ], "comment": "anticipation; expectation" },
	{ "question": "心得", "answers": [ "こころえ" ], "comment": "knowledge; understanding\nrules; regulations; guideline; directions\ndeputy; acting" },
	{ "question": "心得る", "answers": [ "こころえる" ], "comment": "to know; to understand; to be aware of; to regard as; to take for\nto consent; to agree" },
	{ "question": "心情", "answers": [ "しんじょう" ], "comment": "sentiment; emotions; one's feelings; one's heart" },
	{ "question": "心意気", "answers": [ "こころいき" ], "comment": "spirit; disposition" },
	{ "question": "心掛け", "answers": [ "こころがけ" ], "comment": "intention; attention; dedication; care; prudence; readiness; mental attitude" },
	{ "question": "心掛ける", "answers": [ "こころがける" ], "comment": "to keep in mind; to bear in mind; to try; to aim to do; to endeavor; to endeavour" },
	{ "question": "心構え", "answers": [ "こころがまえ" ], "comment": "preparedness; readiness; mental attitude; frame of mind" },
	{ "question": "心理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "state of mind; mentality; psychology" },
	{ "question": "心理学", "answers": [ "しんりがく" ], "comment": "psychology" },
	{ "question": "心筋", "answers": [ "しんきん" ], "comment": "heart muscle; myocardium" },
	{ "question": "心細い", "answers": [ "こころぼそい" ], "comment": "helpless; forlorn; hopeless; unpromising; lonely; discouraging; disheartening" },
	{ "question": "心臓", "answers": [ "しんぞう" ], "comment": "heart\nguts; nerve; cheek; gall; spine\ncentral part" },
	{ "question": "心臓病", "answers": [ "しんぞうびょう" ], "comment": "heart trouble; heart disease" },
	{ "question": "心身", "answers": [ "しんしん" ], "comment": "mind and body" },
	{ "question": "心配", "answers": [ "しんぱい" ], "comment": "worry; concern; anxiety\ncare; help; aid; assistance" },
	{ "question": "必ず", "answers": [ "かならず" ], "comment": "always; without exception; necessarily; certainly; without fail; positively; invariably" },
	{ "question": "必ずしも", "answers": [ "かならずしも" ], "comment": "not always; not necessarily; not all; not entirely" },
	{ "question": "必修", "answers": [ "ひっしゅう" ], "comment": "required (subject)" },
	{ "question": "必勝", "answers": [ "ひっしょう" ], "comment": "certain victory" },
	{ "question": "必死", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "frantic; desperate\ninevitable death\nbrinkmate (inevitable checkmate)" },
	{ "question": "必死になって", "answers": [ "ひっしになって" ], "comment": "desperately; for one's dear life" },
	{ "question": "必然", "answers": [ "ひつぜん" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; certain; sure\ninevitability; necessity" },
	{ "question": "必然的", "answers": [ "ひつぜんてき" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary" },
	{ "question": "必着", "answers": [ "ひっちゃく" ], "comment": "must arrive; must be received" },
	{ "question": "必至", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; foregone\nbrinkmate (inevitable checkmate)" },
	{ "question": "必要", "answers": [ "ひつよう" ], "comment": "necessary; needed; essential; indispensable\nnecessity; need; requirement" },
	{ "question": "必要性", "answers": [ "ひつようせい" ], "comment": "necessity" },
	{ "question": "必読", "answers": [ "ひつどく" ], "comment": "must-read; obligatory reading" },
	{ "question": "必需", "answers": [ "ひつじゅ" ], "comment": "necessary" },
	{ "question": "必需品", "answers": [ "ひつじゅひん" ], "comment": "necessities; necessary article; requisite; essentials" },
	{ "question": "必須", "answers": [ "ひっすう", "ひっしゅ", "ひっす" ], "comment": "indispensable; required" },
	{ "question": "必須条件", "answers": [ "ひっすじょうけん" ], "comment": "essential condition" },
	{ "question": "忍ぶ", "answers": [ "しのぶ" ], "comment": "to conceal oneself; to hide\nto endure" },
	{ "question": "忍耐", "answers": [ "にんたい" ], "comment": "endurance; perseverance; patience" },
	{ "question": "志", "answers": [ "こころざし" ], "comment": "will; resolution; intention; ambition; aim; goal\nkindness; goodwill; kind offer\ngift (as a token of gratitude)" },
	{ "question": "志す", "answers": [ "こころざす" ], "comment": "to plan; to intend; to aspire to; to set aims (sights on)" },
	{ "question": "志向", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "intention; aim; preference (for)" },
	{ "question": "志望", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "wish; desire; ambition" },
	{ "question": "志願", "answers": [ "しがん" ], "comment": "aspiration; volunteering; desire; application" },
	{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)" },
	{ "question": "忘れ物", "answers": [ "わすれもの" ], "comment": "lost article; something forgotten" },
	{ "question": "忘却", "answers": [ "ぼうきゃく" ], "comment": "lapse of memory; forgetfulness; oblivion" },
	{ "question": "忘年会", "answers": [ "ぼうねんかい" ], "comment": "year-end party" },
	{ "question": "忙しい", "answers": [ "せわしい", "いそがしい" ], "comment": "busy; occupied; hectic\nrestless; hurried; fidgety" },
	{ "question": "応える", "answers": [ "こたえる" ], "comment": "to respond; to answer; to meet (e.g. demands, expectations)\nto affect; to take a toll; to strike home; to have an effect on; to be hard on someone (e.g. heat, cold, work, illness, etc.); to be a strain" },
	{ "question": "応じる", "answers": [ "おうじる" ], "comment": "to respond; to satisfy; to accept; to comply with; to apply for" },
	{ "question": "応ずる", "answers": [ "おうずる" ], "comment": "to answer; to respond; to meet\nto satisfy; to accept" },
	{ "question": "応分", "answers": [ "おうぶん" ], "comment": "according to one's abilities; appropriate; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "応募", "answers": [ "おうぼ" ], "comment": "application; subscription; entry (competition, raffle, etc.); enlistment" },
	{ "question": "応対", "answers": [ "おうたい" ], "comment": "receiving; dealing with" },
	{ "question": "応急", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "emergency; first-aid" },
	{ "question": "応接", "answers": [ "おうせつ" ], "comment": "reception" },
	{ "question": "応援", "answers": [ "おうえん" ], "comment": "aid; assistance; help; reinforcement; rooting; barracking; support; cheering" },
	{ "question": "応札", "answers": [ "おうさつ" ], "comment": "making a bid; tendering a bid" },
	{ "question": "応用", "answers": [ "おうよう" ], "comment": "application; put to practical use\napplied" },
	{ "question": "応答", "answers": [ "おうとう" ], "comment": "reply; answer; response" },
	{ "question": "応酬", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "exchange; reciprocation; give-and-take; return\nreply; riposte" },
	{ "question": "忠告", "answers": [ "ちゅうこく" ], "comment": "advice; warning" },
	{ "question": "忠実", "answers": [ "ちゅうじつ" ], "comment": "faithfulness; devotion; loyalty; honesty; truth; fidelity" },
	{ "question": "忠臣", "answers": [ "ちゅうしん" ], "comment": "loyal retainer; loyal subject" },
	{ "question": "忠誠", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "loyalty; sincerity; allegiance; fidelity; integrity" },
	{ "question": "快い", "answers": [ "こころよい" ], "comment": "pleasant; agreeable" },
	{ "question": "快勝", "answers": [ "かいしょう" ], "comment": "sweeping victory; easy victory" },
	{ "question": "快感", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "pleasant feeling" },
	{ "question": "快挙", "answers": [ "かいきょ" ], "comment": "brilliant achievement; spectacular feat; splendid accomplishment; remarkable deed" },
	{ "question": "快晴", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "clear weather; cloudless weather; good weather" },
	{ "question": "快楽", "answers": [ "かいらく", "けらく" ], "comment": "pleasure" },
	{ "question": "快調", "answers": [ "かいちょう" ], "comment": "good (condition); going well; fine; smooth" },
	{ "question": "快速", "answers": [ "かいそく" ], "comment": "high speed; rapidity\nrapid-service train (not as fast as express); rapid train" },
	{ "question": "快適", "answers": [ "かいてき" ], "comment": "pleasant; agreeable; comfortable" },
	{ "question": "念", "answers": [ "ねん" ], "comment": "sense; idea; thought; feeling\ndesire; concern\nattention; care" },
	{ "question": "念入り", "answers": [ "ねんいり" ], "comment": "careful; scrupulous; thorough; conscientious; elaborate; deliberate; attentive" },
	{ "question": "念力", "answers": [ "ねんりき" ], "comment": "willpower; faith\ntelekinesis; psychokinesis" },
	{ "question": "念書", "answers": [ "ねんしょ" ], "comment": "written pledge; signed note of assurance; memorandum; legal instrument" },
	{ "question": "念頭", "answers": [ "ねんとう" ], "comment": "(on one's) mind; heed" },
	{ "question": "念願", "answers": [ "ねんがん" ], "comment": "one's heart's desire; one's dearest wish" },
	{ "question": "怒らせる", "answers": [ "いからせる", "おこらせる" ], "comment": "to anger someone; to provoke; to offend someone; to make somebody's hackles rise\nto square one's shoulders" },
	{ "question": "怒り", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "anger; rage; fury; wrath; indignation" },
	{ "question": "怒る", "answers": [ "いかる", "おこる" ], "comment": "to get angry; to get mad\nto tell someone off; to scold\nto be angular; to be square" },
	{ "question": "怒鳴り込む", "answers": [ "どなりこむ" ], "comment": "to storm in with a yell" },
	{ "question": "怒鳴る", "answers": [ "どなる" ], "comment": "to shout; to yell" },
	{ "question": "怖い", "answers": [ "こわい" ], "comment": "scary; frightening; eerie; dreadful\n(I'm) afraid" },
	{ "question": "怖がる", "answers": [ "こわがる" ], "comment": "to be afraid of; to fear; to dread; to be nervous (about); to be shy (of)" },
	{ "question": "思い", "answers": [ "おもい" ], "comment": "thought\nimagination; mind; heart\ndesire; wish; hope; expectation\nlove; affection\nfeelings; emotion; sentiment; experience" },
	{ "question": "思いがけない", "answers": [ "おもいがけない" ], "comment": "unexpected; contrary to expectations; by chance; casual" },
	{ "question": "思いっきり", "answers": [ "おもいきり", "おもいっきり" ], "comment": "with all one's strength; with all one's heart; resignation; resolution" },
	{ "question": "思いつき", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "plan; idea; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "思いとどまる", "answers": [ "おもいとどまる" ], "comment": "to give up (a plan or idea); to desist from (doing)" },
	{ "question": "思いやり", "answers": [ "おもいやり" ], "comment": "consideration; thoughtfulness; sympathy; compassion; feeling; kindness; understanding; regard; kindheartedness" },
	{ "question": "思いやる", "answers": [ "おもいやる" ], "comment": "to be considerate; to sympathize with; to sympathise with" },
	{ "question": "思い上がる", "answers": [ "おもいあがる" ], "comment": "to be conceited" },
	{ "question": "思い付き", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "plan; idea; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "思い付く", "answers": [ "おもいつく" ], "comment": "to think of; to hit upon; to come into one's mind; to be struck with an idea\nto remember; to recall" },
	{ "question": "思い出", "answers": [ "おもいで" ], "comment": "memories; recollections; reminiscence" },
	{ "question": "思い出す", "answers": [ "おもいだす" ], "comment": "to recall; to remember; to recollect" },
	{ "question": "思い切って", "answers": [ "おもいきって" ], "comment": "resolutely; boldly; daringly" },
	{ "question": "思い切り", "answers": [ "おもいきり", "おもいっきり" ], "comment": "with all one's strength; with all one's heart; resignation; resolution" },
	{ "question": "思い切る", "answers": [ "おもいきる" ], "comment": "to give up all thoughts of; to abandon; to despair of\nto make up one's mind; to take a momentous decision" },
	{ "question": "思い当たる", "answers": [ "おもいあたる" ], "comment": "to suddenly understand (esp. on basis of experience or memory); to come to mind; to recall (in a flash); to be reminded of; to call to mind; to think of; to strike on; to hit on an answer; to seize the crux of a problem" },
	{ "question": "思い思い", "answers": [ "おもいおもい" ], "comment": "just as one likes; as one pleases; as one prefers" },
	{ "question": "思い描く", "answers": [ "おもいえがく" ], "comment": "to imagine; to picture; to figure; to see" },
	{ "question": "思い直す", "answers": [ "おもいなおす" ], "comment": "to re-think; to think back upon; to change one's mind" },
	{ "question": "思い起こす", "answers": [ "おもいおこす" ], "comment": "to recall; to remember" },
	{ "question": "思い込む", "answers": [ "おもいこむ" ], "comment": "to be under impression that; to be convinced that; to imagine that; to set one's heart on; to be bent on" },
	{ "question": "思う", "answers": [ "おもう" ], "comment": "to think; to consider; to believe\nto think (of doing); to plan (to do)\nto judge; to assess; to regard\nto imagine; to suppose; to dream\nto expect; to look forward to\nto feel; to desire; to want\nto recall; to remember" },
	{ "question": "思う存分", "answers": [ "おもうぞんぶん" ], "comment": "to one's heart's content" },
	{ "question": "思わく", "answers": [ "おもわく" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; prediction; forecast; calculations\npurpose; intention; motive; ulterior motive\nothers' opinions of one\nspeculation" },
	{ "question": "思わず", "answers": [ "おもわず" ], "comment": "unintentionally; reflexively; spontaneously; involuntarily; instinctively" },
	{ "question": "思惑", "answers": [ "おもわく" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; prediction; forecast; calculations\npurpose; intention; motive; ulterior motive\nothers' opinions of one\nspeculation" },
	{ "question": "思想", "answers": [ "しそう" ], "comment": "thought; idea; ideology" },
	{ "question": "思春期", "answers": [ "ししゅんき" ], "comment": "puberty" },
	{ "question": "思考", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "thought; consideration; thinking" },
	{ "question": "怠ける", "answers": [ "なまける" ], "comment": "to be idle; to slacken\nto neglect (e.g. one's work)" },
	{ "question": "怠る", "answers": [ "おこたる" ], "comment": "to be negligent in doing something; to shirk; to be off one's guard" },
	{ "question": "怠惰", "answers": [ "たいだ" ], "comment": "lazy; idle; indolent; slothful" },
	{ "question": "怠慢", "answers": [ "たいまん" ], "comment": "negligence; neglect; carelessness; procrastination" },
	{ "question": "急", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; sudden; abrupt\nsharp; steep; precipitous\nrapid; swift; fast\nemergency; crisis\nhurrying; haste\n(in gagaku or noh) end of a song" },
	{ "question": "急いで", "answers": [ "いそいで" ], "comment": "hurriedly" },
	{ "question": "急かす", "answers": [ "せかす" ], "comment": "to hurry; to urge on" },
	{ "question": "急きょ", "answers": [ "きゅうきょ" ], "comment": "hurriedly; in a hurry; in haste\nsudden" },
	{ "question": "急ぎ", "answers": [ "いそぎ" ], "comment": "haste; hurry; expedition; speed; dispatch" },
	{ "question": "急ぐ", "answers": [ "いそぐ" ], "comment": "to hurry; to rush; to hasten; to make something happen sooner" },
	{ "question": "急に", "answers": [ "きゅうに" ], "comment": "swiftly; rapidly\nsuddenly; abruptly; immediately" },
	{ "question": "急ピッチ", "answers": [ "きゅうピッチ" ], "comment": "quick pace" },
	{ "question": "急伸", "answers": [ "きゅうしん" ], "comment": "sudden rise (esp. of stock prices); jump" },
	{ "question": "急務", "answers": [ "きゅうむ" ], "comment": "urgent business" },
	{ "question": "急増", "answers": [ "きゅうぞう" ], "comment": "rapid increase; proliferation; surge; explosion" },
	{ "question": "急変", "answers": [ "きゅうへん" ], "comment": "sudden turn; sudden change\n(suddenly occurring) accident; emergency" },
	{ "question": "急性", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "acute (e.g. illness)" },
	{ "question": "急性期", "answers": [ "きゅうせいき" ], "comment": "acute phase" },
	{ "question": "急成長", "answers": [ "きゅうせいちょう" ], "comment": "rapid growth" },
	{ "question": "急所", "answers": [ "きゅうしょ" ], "comment": "vitals; tender spot\nkey (of a problem); crux; essential point; secret\nmale crotch (as a target in fighting)" },
	{ "question": "急死", "answers": [ "きゅうし" ], "comment": "sudden death" },
	{ "question": "急激", "answers": [ "きゅうげき" ], "comment": "sudden; precipitous; radical" },
	{ "question": "急用", "answers": [ "きゅうよう" ], "comment": "urgent business" },
	{ "question": "急病", "answers": [ "きゅうびょう" ], "comment": "sudden illness" },
	{ "question": "急落", "answers": [ "きゅうらく" ], "comment": "sudden fall; sharp fall; sudden drop; sharp drop" },
	{ "question": "急行", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "moving at high speed\nexpress (e.g. train that bypasses many stations)" },
	{ "question": "急速", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "rapid (e.g. progress)" },
	{ "question": "急進", "answers": [ "きゅうしん" ], "comment": "rapid progress; radical" },
	{ "question": "急遽", "answers": [ "きゅうきょ" ], "comment": "hurriedly; in a hurry; in haste\nsudden" },
	{ "question": "急騰", "answers": [ "きゅうとう" ], "comment": "sudden rise; jump; sharp rise" },
	{ "question": "性", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "nature (of a person)\nsex\ngender\n-ty; -ity; -ness; -cy" },
	{ "question": "性別", "answers": [ "せいべつ" ], "comment": "distinction by sex; sex; gender" },
	{ "question": "性向", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "inclination; tendency; nature; character" },
	{ "question": "性急", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "hasty; impatient; impetuous; quick-tempered" },
	{ "question": "性感帯", "answers": [ "せいかんたい" ], "comment": "erogenous zone" },
	{ "question": "性教育", "answers": [ "せいきょういく" ], "comment": "sex education" },
	{ "question": "性格", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "character; personality; disposition; nature" },
	{ "question": "性的", "answers": [ "せいてき" ], "comment": "(relating to) gender\nsex; sexual" },
	{ "question": "性能", "answers": [ "せいのう" ], "comment": "ability; performance; efficiency" },
	{ "question": "性行", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "character and conduct" },
	{ "question": "性質", "answers": [ "せいしつ" ], "comment": "nature; property; disposition" },
	{ "question": "怪しい", "answers": [ "あやしい" ], "comment": "suspicious; dubious; doubtful; dodgy; suspicious (referring to a potential amorous relation); dangerous (e.g. financial situation); ominous (e.g. weather); strange; shady; fishy\ncharming; bewitching; mysterious" },
	{ "question": "怪しむ", "answers": [ "あやしむ" ], "comment": "to suspect" },
	{ "question": "怪奇", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "bizarre; strange; wonderful; weird; outrageous" },
	{ "question": "怪我人", "answers": [ "けがにん", "ケガにん" ], "comment": "wounded person; injured person" },
	{ "question": "怪物", "answers": [ "かいぶつ" ], "comment": "monster" },
	{ "question": "怪獣", "answers": [ "かいじゅう" ], "comment": "monster" },
	{ "question": "怪談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "ghost story" },
	{ "question": "恋", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "(romantic) love" },
	{ "question": "恋しい", "answers": [ "こいしい" ], "comment": "yearned for; longed for; missed" },
	{ "question": "恋する", "answers": [ "こいする" ], "comment": "to fall in love with; to love" },
	{ "question": "恋人", "answers": [ "こいびと" ], "comment": "lover; sweetheart" },
	{ "question": "恋愛", "answers": [ "れんあい" ], "comment": "love; love-making; passion; emotion; affections" },
	{ "question": "恐るべき", "answers": [ "おそるべき" ], "comment": "dreadful; terrible; horrible; deplorable\nfearsome; formidable; awesome; redoubtable" },
	{ "question": "恐る恐る", "answers": [ "おそるおそる" ], "comment": "timidly" },
	{ "question": "恐れ", "answers": [ "おそれ" ], "comment": "fear; horror; anxiety; concern; uneasiness" },
	{ "question": "恐れる", "answers": [ "おそれる" ], "comment": "to fear; to be afraid of" },
	{ "question": "恐ろしい", "answers": [ "おそろしい" ], "comment": "terrible; dreadful; terrifying; frightening; frightened\nsurprising; startling; tremendous; amazing" },
	{ "question": "恐喝", "answers": [ "きょうかつ" ], "comment": "blackmail; extortion; threat (to extort money)" },
	{ "question": "恐怖", "answers": [ "きょうふ" ], "comment": "fear; dread; dismay; terror; horror; scare; panic" },
	{ "question": "恐慌", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "panic; scare; consternation" },
	{ "question": "恐竜", "answers": [ "きょうりゅう" ], "comment": "dinosaur" },
	{ "question": "恐縮", "answers": [ "きょうしゅく" ], "comment": "feeling obliged; being grateful; being thankful; being sorry; being ashamed\nshrinking back in fear" },
	{ "question": "恒久", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "permanent; perpetuity" },
	{ "question": "恒例", "answers": [ "こうれい" ], "comment": "established practice; custom" },
	{ "question": "恒常", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "constancy" },
	{ "question": "恥", "answers": [ "はじ" ], "comment": "shame; embarrassment; disgrace" },
	{ "question": "恥さらし", "answers": [ "はじさらし" ], "comment": "disgrace; shame" },
	{ "question": "恥じる", "answers": [ "はじる" ], "comment": "to feel ashamed" },
	{ "question": "恥ずかしい", "answers": [ "はずかしい" ], "comment": "shy; ashamed; embarrassed\ndisgraceful; shameful" },
	{ "question": "恥知らず", "answers": [ "はじしらず" ], "comment": "shameless (person)" },
	{ "question": "恨み", "answers": [ "うらみ" ], "comment": "resentment; grudge; malice; bitterness\nmatter for regret; regret" },
	{ "question": "恨む", "answers": [ "うらむ" ], "comment": "to resent; to curse; to feel bitter; to blame; to bear a grudge\nto regret" },
	{ "question": "恩", "answers": [ "おん" ], "comment": "favour; favor; obligation; debt of gratitude" },
	{ "question": "恩人", "answers": [ "おんじん" ], "comment": "benefactor; patron" },
	{ "question": "恩師", "answers": [ "おんし" ], "comment": "teacher; one's former teacher" },
	{ "question": "恩恵", "answers": [ "おんけい" ], "comment": "grace; favor; favour; blessing; benefit" },
	{ "question": "恩知らず", "answers": [ "おんしらず" ], "comment": "ingratitude" },
	{ "question": "恩赦", "answers": [ "おんしゃ" ], "comment": "amnesty; pardon" },
	{ "question": "恩返し", "answers": [ "おんがえし" ], "comment": "requital of a favour (favor); repayment (of an obligation, kindness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "息", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "breath; breathing\ntone; mood" },
	{ "question": "息切れ", "answers": [ "いきぎれ" ], "comment": "shortness of breath; panting; puffing\nrunning out of steam (e.g. economy); losing momentum" },
	{ "question": "息吹", "answers": [ "いぶき" ], "comment": "breath\nsign (of something new and fresh); breath (metaphor)" },
	{ "question": "息子", "answers": [ "むすこ" ], "comment": "son\npenis" },
	{ "question": "恵まれる", "answers": [ "めぐまれる" ], "comment": "to be blessed with; to be rich in; to abound in" },
	{ "question": "恵み", "answers": [ "めぐみ" ], "comment": "blessing; grace" },
	{ "question": "恵む", "answers": [ "めぐむ" ], "comment": "to bless; to show mercy to\nto give (money, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "恵比寿", "answers": [ "えべす", "ゑびす", "えびす", "ひるこ" ], "comment": "Ebisu; god of fishing and commerce" },
	{ "question": "悔い", "answers": [ "くい" ], "comment": "regret; repentance" },
	{ "question": "悔しい", "answers": [ "くやしい", "くちおしい" ], "comment": "vexing; annoying; frustrating; regrettable; mortifying" },
	{ "question": "悔し泣き", "answers": [ "くやしなき" ], "comment": "crying from vexation; tears of regret" },
	{ "question": "悟る", "answers": [ "さとる" ], "comment": "to perceive; to sense; to discern\nto understand; to comprehend; to realize\nto attain enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "悠々", "answers": [ "ゆうゆう" ], "comment": "quiet; calm; leisurely\ndistant; far off; boundless; endless\neasily; comfortably; without difficulty" },
	{ "question": "患う", "answers": [ "わずらう" ], "comment": "to be ill; to suffer from\nto worry about; to be concerned about\nto have trouble doing ...; to be unable to ...; to fail to ..." },
	{ "question": "患者", "answers": [ "かんじゃ" ], "comment": "(a) patient" },
	{ "question": "悩ます", "answers": [ "なやます" ], "comment": "to afflict; to torment; to harass; to molest" },
	{ "question": "悩み", "answers": [ "なやみ" ], "comment": "trouble; troubles; worry; distress; sorrows; anguish; agony; problem" },
	{ "question": "悩む", "answers": [ "なやむ" ], "comment": "to be worried; to be troubled" },
	{ "question": "悪", "answers": [ "あく" ], "comment": "evil; wickedness" },
	{ "question": "悪い", "answers": [ "わるい" ], "comment": "bad; poor; inferior\nevil; sinful\nunprofitable; unbeneficial\nat fault; to blame; in the wrong\nsorry" },
	{ "question": "悪さ", "answers": [ "わるさ" ], "comment": "badness; mean mischief" },
	{ "question": "悪事", "answers": [ "あくじ" ], "comment": "evil deed; crime; wickedness" },
	{ "question": "悪人", "answers": [ "あくにん" ], "comment": "bad person; villain; scoundrel; wrongdoer; wicked person" },
	{ "question": "悪化", "answers": [ "あっか" ], "comment": "(suffer) deterioration; growing worse; aggravation; degeneration; corruption" },
	{ "question": "悪口", "answers": [ "わるくち", "わるぐち", "あっこう" ], "comment": "abuse; insult; slander; evil speaking; bad mouth" },
	{ "question": "悪夢", "answers": [ "あくむ" ], "comment": "nightmare; bad dream" },
	{ "question": "悪天候", "answers": [ "あくてんこう" ], "comment": "bad weather" },
	{ "question": "悪女", "answers": [ "あくじょ" ], "comment": "wicked woman\nugly woman" },
	{ "question": "悪寒", "answers": [ "おかん" ], "comment": "chill; shakes; ague" },
	{ "question": "悪役", "answers": [ "あくやく" ], "comment": "villain; baddie; the villain's part" },
	{ "question": "悪循環", "answers": [ "あくじゅんかん" ], "comment": "vicious circle" },
	{ "question": "悪徳", "answers": [ "あくとく" ], "comment": "vice; immorality; corruption" },
	{ "question": "悪性", "answers": [ "あくせい" ], "comment": "malignancy; virulence; malignant (cancer); pernicious (anemia, anaemia)" },
	{ "question": "悪意", "answers": [ "あくい" ], "comment": "ill will; spite; evil intention; malice\nbad meaning\nmala fides; bad faith; criminal intent to deceive\nmalice" },
	{ "question": "悪気", "answers": [ "わるぎ" ], "comment": "ill will; malice; evil intent; ill feeling; distrust" },
	{ "question": "悪用", "answers": [ "あくよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; perversion" },
	{ "question": "悪者", "answers": [ "わるもの" ], "comment": "bad fellow; rascal; ruffian; scoundrel" },
	{ "question": "悪臭", "answers": [ "あくしゅう" ], "comment": "stink; bad odor; bad odour; stench" },
	{ "question": "悪賢い", "answers": [ "わるがしこい" ], "comment": "cunning; crafty; wily; sly" },
	{ "question": "悪質", "answers": [ "あくしつ" ], "comment": "bad quality; malignancy; vicious; malignant" },
	{ "question": "悪魔", "answers": [ "あくま" ], "comment": "devil; demon; fiend\nSatan; the Devil\nMāra; evil spirits or forces that hinder one's path to enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "悲しい", "answers": [ "かなしい" ], "comment": "sad; sorrowful" },
	{ "question": "悲しみ", "answers": [ "かなしみ" ], "comment": "sadness; sorrow; grief\naffection; love" },
	{ "question": "悲しむ", "answers": [ "かなしむ" ], "comment": "to be sad; to mourn for; to regret" },
	{ "question": "悲劇", "answers": [ "ひげき" ], "comment": "tragedy; tragic drama; tragic play\ntragedy; calamity; disaster" },
	{ "question": "悲哀", "answers": [ "ひあい" ], "comment": "sorrow; grief; sadness" },
	{ "question": "悲壮", "answers": [ "ひそう" ], "comment": "heroic; tragic; grim; pathetic; touching" },
	{ "question": "悲惨", "answers": [ "ひさん" ], "comment": "disastrous; tragic; miserable; wretched; pitiful; woeful" },
	{ "question": "悲痛", "answers": [ "ひつう" ], "comment": "grief; sorrow; extreme sadness; heartbreak" },
	{ "question": "悲観", "answers": [ "ひかん" ], "comment": "pessimism; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "悲観的", "answers": [ "ひかんてき" ], "comment": "pessimistic; gloomy" },
	{ "question": "悲願", "answers": [ "ひがん" ], "comment": "one's dearest wish; Buddha's vow to save humanity" },
	{ "question": "悲鳴", "answers": [ "ひめい" ], "comment": "shriek; scream" },
	{ "question": "悼む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to grieve over; to mourn; to lament" },
	{ "question": "情", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "feelings; emotion; sentiment\ncompassion; sympathy\npassion; affection; love\nthe way things really are; the actual situation" },
	{ "question": "情け", "answers": [ "なさけ" ], "comment": "pity; sympathy; compassion; mercy\naffection" },
	{ "question": "情けない", "answers": [ "なっさけない", "なさけない" ], "comment": "miserable; pitiable; shameful; deplorable; pathetic" },
	{ "question": "情け深い", "answers": [ "なさけぶかい" ], "comment": "tender-hearted; compassionate; charitable; good-hearted" },
	{ "question": "情勢", "answers": [ "じょうせい" ], "comment": "state of things; state of affairs; condition; situation; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "情報", "answers": [ "じょうほう" ], "comment": "information; news; intelligence; advices\ninformation; data contained in characters, signals, code, etc." },
	{ "question": "情報処理", "answers": [ "じょうほうしょり" ], "comment": "data processing" },
	{ "question": "情報化社会", "answers": [ "じょうほうかしゃかい" ], "comment": "information society" },
	{ "question": "情報産業", "answers": [ "じょうほうさんぎょう" ], "comment": "information industry" },
	{ "question": "情報部", "answers": [ "じょうほうぶ" ], "comment": "information bureau; intelligence department" },
	{ "question": "情感", "answers": [ "じょうかん" ], "comment": "feeling; sensitivity; emotion" },
	{ "question": "情景", "answers": [ "じょうけい" ], "comment": "spectacle; sight; scene" },
	{ "question": "情熱", "answers": [ "じょうねつ" ], "comment": "passion; enthusiasm; zeal" },
	{ "question": "情緒", "answers": [ "じょうしょ", "じょうちょ" ], "comment": "emotion; feeling\natmosphere; mood; spirit" },
	{ "question": "惑わす", "answers": [ "まどわす" ], "comment": "to bewilder; to perplex; to puzzle; to delude; to mislead; to deceive\nto tempt; to seduce" },
	{ "question": "惑星", "answers": [ "わくせい" ], "comment": "planet" },
	{ "question": "惚れる", "answers": [ "ほれる" ], "comment": "to fall in love; to be in love; to be charmed with; to lose one's heart to" },
	{ "question": "惜しい", "answers": [ "おしい" ], "comment": "regrettable; disappointing\nprecious; dear; valuable\ntoo good for; deserving better\nalmost but not quite" },
	{ "question": "惜しまない", "answers": [ "おしまない" ], "comment": "without sparing (effort, funds, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "惜しむ", "answers": [ "おしむ" ], "comment": "to be frugal; to be sparing\nto value; to hold dear\nto regret (e.g. a loss); to feel sorry (for)\nto be unwilling; to be reluctant" },
	{ "question": "惣菜", "answers": [ "そうざい" ], "comment": "side dish; daily (household) dish" },
	{ "question": "惨め", "answers": [ "みじめ" ], "comment": "miserable; wretched; unhappy; sad; pitiable" },
	{ "question": "惨事", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "disaster; tragedy; tragic incident; horrible accident" },
	{ "question": "惨敗", "answers": [ "ざんぱい", "さんぱい" ], "comment": "ignominious defeat; crushing failure; utterly beaten; overwhelming defeat" },
	{ "question": "惨状", "answers": [ "さんじょう" ], "comment": "disastrous scene; terrible spectacle" },
	{ "question": "想像", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "imagination; guess" },
	{ "question": "想定", "answers": [ "そうてい" ], "comment": "hypothesis; supposition; assumption" },
	{ "question": "愉快", "answers": [ "ゆかい" ], "comment": "pleasant; happy" },
	{ "question": "意向", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "intention; idea; inclination" },
	{ "question": "意味", "answers": [ "いみ" ], "comment": "meaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "意味不明", "answers": [ "いみふめい" ], "comment": "of uncertain meaning; ambiguous; cryptic" },
	{ "question": "意味合い", "answers": [ "いみあい" ], "comment": "implication; nuance; shade of meaning; connotation" },
	{ "question": "意図", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "intention; aim; design" },
	{ "question": "意図的", "answers": [ "いとてき" ], "comment": "intentional; on purpose" },
	{ "question": "意地", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "stubbornness; obstinacy; willpower; pride\ndisposition; nature\nappetite; desire; greed" },
	{ "question": "意地悪", "answers": [ "いじわる" ], "comment": "malicious; ill-tempered; unkind" },
	{ "question": "意外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "unexpected; surprising" },
	{ "question": "意志", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "will; volition; intention; intent; determination" },
	{ "question": "意思", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "intention; purpose" },
	{ "question": "意思決定", "answers": [ "いしけってい" ], "comment": "decision-making" },
	{ "question": "意思疎通", "answers": [ "いしそつう" ], "comment": "(coming to a) mutual understanding; understanding each other" },
	{ "question": "意思表示", "answers": [ "いしひょうじ" ], "comment": "declaration of intent; declaration of intention; expression of one's intention; manifestation of intention" },
	{ "question": "意欲", "answers": [ "いよく" ], "comment": "will; desire; ambition; urge (e.g. creative urge)" },
	{ "question": "意気", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "spirit; heart; disposition" },
	{ "question": "意気地", "answers": [ "いきじ", "いくじ" ], "comment": "self-respect; self-confidence; guts; backbone" },
	{ "question": "意気盛ん", "answers": [ "いきさかん" ], "comment": "in high spirits" },
	{ "question": "意気込み", "answers": [ "いきごみ" ], "comment": "ardor; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "意気込む", "answers": [ "いきごむ" ], "comment": "to be enthusiastic about; to be eager; to be keen" },
	{ "question": "意義", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "meaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "意表", "answers": [ "いひょう" ], "comment": "surprise; something unexpected" },
	{ "question": "意見", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "opinion; view; comment" },
	{ "question": "意識", "answers": [ "いしき" ], "comment": "consciousness\nawareness; sense\nmano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information)" },
	{ "question": "意識的", "answers": [ "いしきてき" ], "comment": "conscious; deliberate" },
	{ "question": "意識調査", "answers": [ "いしきちょうさ" ], "comment": "opinion poll; attitude survey" },
	{ "question": "愚", "answers": [ "ぐ" ], "comment": "foolishness; silliness; stupidity; folly\nI; me" },
	{ "question": "愚か", "answers": [ "おろか" ], "comment": "foolish; stupid" },
	{ "question": "愚痴", "answers": [ "ぐち" ], "comment": "idle complaint; grumble\nmoha (ignorance, folly)" },
	{ "question": "愛", "answers": [ "あい" ], "comment": "love; affection; care\nattachment; craving; desire" },
	{ "question": "愛す", "answers": [ "あいす" ], "comment": "to love" },
	{ "question": "愛する", "answers": [ "あいする" ], "comment": "to love" },
	{ "question": "愛人", "answers": [ "あいじん" ], "comment": "lover; mistress" },
	{ "question": "愛国", "answers": [ "あいこく" ], "comment": "love of (one's) country; patriotism" },
	{ "question": "愛好", "answers": [ "あいこう" ], "comment": "love; adoration" },
	{ "question": "愛情", "answers": [ "あいじょう" ], "comment": "love; affection" },
	{ "question": "愛想", "answers": [ "あいそ", "あいそう" ], "comment": "civility; courtesy; compliments; sociability; graces" },
	{ "question": "愛犬", "answers": [ "あいけん" ], "comment": "pet dog; beloved dog" },
	{ "question": "愛用", "answers": [ "あいよう" ], "comment": "favorite; favourite; habitual use" },
	{ "question": "愛着", "answers": [ "あいちゃく", "あいじゃく" ], "comment": "attachment; love; covetous affection" },
	{ "question": "愛称", "answers": [ "あいしょう" ], "comment": "pet name; nickname; name used to indicate affection, intimacy, informality, etc." },
	{ "question": "愛読", "answers": [ "あいどく" ], "comment": "reading with pleasure" },
	{ "question": "愛護", "answers": [ "あいご" ], "comment": "protection; tender care" },
	{ "question": "感じ", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "feeling; sense; impression" },
	{ "question": "感じる", "answers": [ "かんじる" ], "comment": "to feel; to sense; to experience" },
	{ "question": "感じ取る", "answers": [ "かんじとる" ], "comment": "to perceive; to sense; to take in; to grasp; to feel" },
	{ "question": "感ずる", "answers": [ "かんずる" ], "comment": "to feel; to sense" },
	{ "question": "感動", "answers": [ "かんどう" ], "comment": "being deeply moved emotionally; excitement; passion; inspiration; deep emotion; strong impression" },
	{ "question": "感化", "answers": [ "かんか" ], "comment": "influence; inspiration; reform; correction" },
	{ "question": "感受性", "answers": [ "かんじゅせい" ], "comment": "sensitivity; susceptibility" },
	{ "question": "感嘆", "answers": [ "かんたん" ], "comment": "admiration; wonder; astonishment" },
	{ "question": "感度", "answers": [ "かんど" ], "comment": "sensitivity; reception (e.g. radio and television); severity (quake)" },
	{ "question": "感心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "admiration; being impressed\nadmirable; praiseworthy\nastonishment; being appalled" },
	{ "question": "感性", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "sensitivity; sensitiveness; sense (of ...)" },
	{ "question": "感情", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "emotion; feeling; feelings; sentiment" },
	{ "question": "感情的", "answers": [ "かんじょうてき" ], "comment": "emotional; sentimental" },
	{ "question": "感想", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "impressions; thoughts" },
	{ "question": "感慨", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "strong feelings; deep emotion" },
	{ "question": "感染", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "infection; contagion" },
	{ "question": "感染症", "answers": [ "かんせんしょう" ], "comment": "infectious disease; infection" },
	{ "question": "感激", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "deep emotion; impression; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "感覚", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "sense; sensation; feeling; intuition" },
	{ "question": "感触", "answers": [ "かんしょく" ], "comment": "feel (i.e. tactile sensation); touch; feeling; sensation; texture (e.g. food, cloth)" },
	{ "question": "感謝", "answers": [ "かんしゃ" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude" },
	{ "question": "感銘", "answers": [ "かんめい" ], "comment": "deep impression" },
	{ "question": "慈善", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "charity; philanthropy" },
	{ "question": "慈悲", "answers": [ "じひ" ], "comment": "compassion (e.g. of Buddha); benevolence; charity; mercy\nHodgson's hawk-cuckoo (Cuculus fugax); Horsfield's hawk cuckoo" },
	{ "question": "態勢", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "attitude; posture; preparedness; readiness" },
	{ "question": "態度", "answers": [ "たいど" ], "comment": "attitude; manner; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "慌ただしい", "answers": [ "あわただしい" ], "comment": "busy; hurried; confused; flurried" },
	{ "question": "慌てる", "answers": [ "あわてる" ], "comment": "to become confused (disconcerted, disorganized, disorganised); to be flustered; to panic\nto be in a hurry; to rush" },
	{ "question": "慎む", "answers": [ "つつしむ" ], "comment": "to be careful; to be discreet\nto do in moderation; to refrain (from overdoing); to abstain\nto be reverent\nto be purified; to be chaste" },
	{ "question": "慎重", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "careful; cautious; prudent; discreet; deliberate" },
	{ "question": "慕う", "answers": [ "したう" ], "comment": "to yearn for; to long for; to pine for; to miss; to love dearly; to adore\nto follow (someone)\nto idolize (for virtue, learning, status, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "慢性", "answers": [ "まんせい" ], "comment": "chronicity; chronic" },
	{ "question": "慢性的", "answers": [ "まんせいてき" ], "comment": "chronic" },
	{ "question": "慣らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to accustom; to train (e.g. one's ear)\nto tame; to domesticate; to train (e.g. an animal)" },
	{ "question": "慣れ", "answers": [ "なれ" ], "comment": "practice; practising; experience" },
	{ "question": "慣れる", "answers": [ "なれる" ], "comment": "to get used to; to grow accustomed to; to become familiar with\nto become skilled in; to become experienced at\nto become tame; to become domesticated" },
	{ "question": "慣例", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "custom; precedent; of convention" },
	{ "question": "慣用句", "answers": [ "かんようく" ], "comment": "idiomatic usage; common usage" },
	{ "question": "慣習", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "usual (historical) custom" },
	{ "question": "慣行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "customary practice; habit; traditional event" },
	{ "question": "慰める", "answers": [ "なぐさめる" ], "comment": "to comfort; to console; to amuse" },
	{ "question": "慰安", "answers": [ "いあん" ], "comment": "solace; relaxation" },
	{ "question": "慰謝", "answers": [ "いしゃ" ], "comment": "consolation" },
	{ "question": "慰霊", "answers": [ "いれい" ], "comment": "comfort the spirit (of the dead)" },
	{ "question": "慰霊祭", "answers": [ "いれいさい" ], "comment": "memorial service" },
	{ "question": "憂える", "answers": [ "うれえる" ], "comment": "to worry about; to be anxious about; to be concerned about\nto lament; to grieve; to feel sorrow for" },
	{ "question": "憂慮", "answers": [ "ゆうりょ" ], "comment": "anxiety; concern; fear" },
	{ "question": "憂鬱", "answers": [ "ゆううつ" ], "comment": "depression; melancholy; dejection; gloom" },
	{ "question": "憎しみ", "answers": [ "にくしみ" ], "comment": "hatred" },
	{ "question": "憎む", "answers": [ "にくむ" ], "comment": "to hate; to detest" },
	{ "question": "憎らしい", "answers": [ "にくらしい" ], "comment": "odious; hateful" },
	{ "question": "憎悪", "answers": [ "ぞうお" ], "comment": "hatred" },
	{ "question": "憤り", "answers": [ "いきどおり" ], "comment": "resentment; indignation; anger" },
	{ "question": "憤慨", "answers": [ "ふんがい" ], "comment": "indignation; resentment" },
	{ "question": "憧れ", "answers": [ "あこがれ" ], "comment": "yearning; longing; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "憧れの的", "answers": [ "あこがれのまと" ], "comment": "object of adoration, longing" },
	{ "question": "憧れる", "answers": [ "あこがれる" ], "comment": "to long for; to yearn after; to admire; to be attracted by" },
	{ "question": "憩", "answers": [ "いこい" ], "comment": "rest" },
	{ "question": "憩い", "answers": [ "いこい" ], "comment": "rest" },
	{ "question": "憲政", "answers": [ "けんせい" ], "comment": "constitutional government" },
	{ "question": "憲法", "answers": [ "けんぽう" ], "comment": "constitution" },
	{ "question": "憲章", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "charter" },
	{ "question": "憶測", "answers": [ "おくそく" ], "comment": "guess; speculation; supposition" },
	{ "question": "懇親", "answers": [ "こんしん" ], "comment": "friendship; intimacy" },
	{ "question": "懇話", "answers": [ "こんわ" ], "comment": "friendly (familiar) chat (talk)" },
	{ "question": "懇談", "answers": [ "こんだん" ], "comment": "informal talk" },
	{ "question": "懐", "answers": [ "ふところ" ], "comment": "bosom; bust\n(breast) pocket; purse; handbag" },
	{ "question": "懐かしい", "answers": [ "なつかしい" ], "comment": "dear; desired; missed" },
	{ "question": "懐かしむ", "answers": [ "なつかしむ" ], "comment": "to yearn for (someone, something); to miss" },
	{ "question": "懐疑", "answers": [ "かいぎ" ], "comment": "doubt; skepticism; scepticism; disbelief" },
	{ "question": "懲りる", "answers": [ "こりる" ], "comment": "to learn by experience; to learn one's lesson; to learn the hard way\nto have enough (of); to be disgusted with" },
	{ "question": "懲役", "answers": [ "ちょうえき" ], "comment": "penal servitude; imprisonment with hard labor (hard labour)" },
	{ "question": "懲戒", "answers": [ "ちょうかい" ], "comment": "discipline; punishment; reprimand" },
	{ "question": "懲罰", "answers": [ "ちょうばつ" ], "comment": "discipline; punishment; reprimand" },
	{ "question": "懸命", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "eager; earnest; strenuous; fervent; assiduous; with utmost effort" },
	{ "question": "懸念", "answers": [ "けねん" ], "comment": "worry; fear; anxiety; concern" },
	{ "question": "懸案", "answers": [ "けんあん" ], "comment": "pending question; unresolved problem" },
	{ "question": "懸賞", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "offering prizes; winning; reward" },
	{ "question": "成し遂げる", "answers": [ "なしとげる" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to finish; to fulfill" },
	{ "question": "成り立つ", "answers": [ "なりたつ" ], "comment": "to consist of; to be made up of; to be composed of\nto be practical (logical, feasible, viable); to be concluded; to hold true" },
	{ "question": "成り行き", "answers": [ "なりゆき" ], "comment": "outcome; development; course of events; progress; result\nmarket order; order without limit" },
	{ "question": "成人", "answers": [ "せいじん" ], "comment": "adult\nto grow up; to mature\nto come of age" },
	{ "question": "成人病", "answers": [ "せいじんびょう" ], "comment": "adult diseases" },
	{ "question": "成分", "answers": [ "せいぶん" ], "comment": "ingredient; component; composition" },
	{ "question": "成功", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "success; hit" },
	{ "question": "成否", "answers": [ "せいひ" ], "comment": "success or failure; outcome; result" },
	{ "question": "成層圏", "answers": [ "せいそうけん" ], "comment": "stratosphere" },
	{ "question": "成年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "adult age; majority" },
	{ "question": "成果", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "fruits (of one's labors); results; outcome; accomplishment" },
	{ "question": "成案", "answers": [ "せいあん" ], "comment": "definite plan" },
	{ "question": "成熟", "answers": [ "せいじゅく" ], "comment": "maturity; ripeness" },
	{ "question": "成立", "answers": [ "せいりつ" ], "comment": "coming into existence; arrangements; establishment; conclusion; completion\nto come into existence; to be true; to hold (i.e. hold true)" },
	{ "question": "成算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "hope of success; prospects of success" },
	{ "question": "成約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "conclusion of a contract" },
	{ "question": "成績", "answers": [ "せいせき" ], "comment": "results; record; grades; marks" },
	{ "question": "成行き", "answers": [ "なりゆき" ], "comment": "outcome; development; course of events; progress; result\nmarket order; order without limit" },
	{ "question": "成金", "answers": [ "なりきん" ], "comment": "upstart; nouveau riche; new rich; coming into wealth suddenly\npiece promoted to gold general" },
	{ "question": "成長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "growth; grow to adulthood" },
	{ "question": "我", "answers": [ "われ", "わ" ], "comment": "I; me\noneself\nyou\nprefix indicating familiarity or contempt" },
	{ "question": "我々", "answers": [ "われわれ" ], "comment": "we" },
	{ "question": "我が", "answers": [ "わが" ], "comment": "my; our; one's own" },
	{ "question": "我が国", "answers": [ "わがくに" ], "comment": "our country; our land; one's own country" },
	{ "question": "我が家", "answers": [ "わがいえ", "わがや" ], "comment": "one's house; one's home; one's family" },
	{ "question": "我ら", "answers": [ "われら" ], "comment": "we; us\nI; me\nyou (referring to a group of one's equals or inferiors)" },
	{ "question": "我慢", "answers": [ "がまん" ], "comment": "patience; endurance; perseverance; tolerance; self-control; self-denial" },
	{ "question": "戒め", "answers": [ "いましめ" ], "comment": "caution; admonition; warning; lesson\nprohibition; ban; commandment; precept\npunishment\ncaution; guard" },
	{ "question": "戒める", "answers": [ "いましめる" ], "comment": "to warn against; to caution against\nto admonish; to scold; to rebuke\nto prohibit; to forbid; to ban\nto be cautious\nto detest; to loathe\nto punish" },
	{ "question": "戒厳令", "answers": [ "かいげんれい" ], "comment": "martial law" },
	{ "question": "戒告", "answers": [ "かいこく" ], "comment": "admonition; warning; caution" },
	{ "question": "戦", "answers": [ "いくさ" ], "comment": "war; battle; campaign; fight\ntroops; forces" },
	{ "question": "戦い", "answers": [ "たたかい" ], "comment": "battle; fight; struggle; conflict" },
	{ "question": "戦う", "answers": [ "たたかう" ], "comment": "to make war (on); to wage war (against); to go to war (with); to fight (with); to do battle (against)\nto compete (against)\nto struggle (against adversities, etc.); to fight; to contend; to resist" },
	{ "question": "戦中", "answers": [ "せんちゅう" ], "comment": "during the war" },
	{ "question": "戦争", "answers": [ "せんそう" ], "comment": "war" },
	{ "question": "戦列", "answers": [ "せんれつ" ], "comment": "line of battle" },
	{ "question": "戦前", "answers": [ "せんぜん" ], "comment": "pre-war days; before the war" },
	{ "question": "戦力", "answers": [ "せんりょく" ], "comment": "war potential; military strength; fighting power\nability (to compete); capabilities; valuable asset" },
	{ "question": "戦勝", "answers": [ "せんしょう" ], "comment": "victory; triumph" },
	{ "question": "戦友", "answers": [ "せんゆう" ], "comment": "comrade in arms; war buddy" },
	{ "question": "戦国", "answers": [ "せんごく" ], "comment": "belligerent country; country in civil war; warring states" },
	{ "question": "戦地", "answers": [ "せんち" ], "comment": "front (in battle)" },
	{ "question": "戦域", "answers": [ "せんいき" ], "comment": "war area; battlefield; theater; theatre" },
	{ "question": "戦場", "answers": [ "せんじょう" ], "comment": "battlefield; battleground" },
	{ "question": "戦士", "answers": [ "せんし" ], "comment": "soldier; combatant; warrior" },
	{ "question": "戦後", "answers": [ "せんご" ], "comment": "postwar period; period after Second World War" },
	{ "question": "戦時", "answers": [ "せんじ" ], "comment": "war time" },
	{ "question": "戦死", "answers": [ "せんし" ], "comment": "death in action; killed in action; KIA" },
	{ "question": "戦没", "answers": [ "せんぼつ" ], "comment": "death in battle; killed in action" },
	{ "question": "戦況", "answers": [ "せんきょう" ], "comment": "war situation; progress of a battle" },
	{ "question": "戦法", "answers": [ "せんぽう" ], "comment": "tactics; strategy" },
	{ "question": "戦火", "answers": [ "せんか" ], "comment": "wartime fire\nwar; wartime destruction; horrors of war" },
	{ "question": "戦災", "answers": [ "せんさい" ], "comment": "war damage" },
	{ "question": "戦犯", "answers": [ "せんぱん" ], "comment": "war criminal" },
	{ "question": "戦略", "answers": [ "せんりゃく" ], "comment": "strategy; tactics" },
	{ "question": "戦線", "answers": [ "せんせん" ], "comment": "(war) front" },
	{ "question": "戦績", "answers": [ "せんせき" ], "comment": "war or military record; score; military achievements; results" },
	{ "question": "戦艦", "answers": [ "せんかん" ], "comment": "battleship" },
	{ "question": "戦術", "answers": [ "せんじゅつ" ], "comment": "tactics" },
	{ "question": "戦費", "answers": [ "せんぴ" ], "comment": "war expenditures" },
	{ "question": "戦車", "answers": [ "せんしゃ" ], "comment": "tank (military vehicle)\nchariot" },
	{ "question": "戦闘", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "battle; fight; combat" },
	{ "question": "戦闘機", "answers": [ "せんとうき" ], "comment": "fighter (aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "戯れ", "answers": [ "たわむれ" ], "comment": "play; sport; fun; caprice; joke; jest; flirtation" },
	{ "question": "戯れる", "answers": [ "じゃれる", "ざれる", "たわむれる" ], "comment": "to be playful; to gambol; to be amused (with something); to play; to sport; to frolic; to joke\nto flirt with" },
	{ "question": "戯曲", "answers": [ "ぎきょく" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "戸", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "door (esp. Japanese-style)\nshutter; window shutter\nentrance (to a home)\nnarrows" },
	{ "question": "戸別訪問", "answers": [ "こべつほうもん" ], "comment": "door-to-door visit; door-to-door canvassing; door-to-door canvasing" },
	{ "question": "戸外", "answers": [ "こがい" ], "comment": "open-air; outdoors" },
	{ "question": "戸惑い", "answers": [ "とまどい" ], "comment": "being at sea; losing one's bearings; confusion; wonderment" },
	{ "question": "戸惑う", "answers": [ "とまどう" ], "comment": "to be bewildered; to be perplexed" },
	{ "question": "戸数", "answers": [ "こすう" ], "comment": "number of households (houses)" },
	{ "question": "戸棚", "answers": [ "とだな" ], "comment": "cupboard; locker; closet; wardrobe; cabinet" },
	{ "question": "戸籍", "answers": [ "こせき" ], "comment": "family register\ncensus" },
	{ "question": "戸籍謄本", "answers": [ "こせきとうほん" ], "comment": "official copy of the family register" },
	{ "question": "戸締まり", "answers": [ "とじまり" ], "comment": "closing up; fastening the doors" },
	{ "question": "戻し", "answers": [ "もどし" ], "comment": "returning; giving back" },
	{ "question": "戻す", "answers": [ "もどす" ], "comment": "to put back; to return; to give back; to restore (to a previous state, e.g. defrosting, reconstituting, reconciling); to turn back (e.g. clock hand)\nto vomit; to throw up\nto recover (of a market price)" },
	{ "question": "戻り", "answers": [ "もどり" ], "comment": "return; reaction; recovery\nreturn (from a procedure)" },
	{ "question": "戻る", "answers": [ "もどる" ], "comment": "to turn back (e.g. half-way)\nto return; to go back\nto recover (e.g. something lost); to be returned\nto rebound; to spring back" },
	{ "question": "房", "answers": [ "ふさ" ], "comment": "tuft; tassel\nbunch (of grapes, etc.)\nsection (of an orange, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "所々", "answers": [ "しょしょ", "ところどころ" ], "comment": "here and there; some parts (of something); several places" },
	{ "question": "所信", "answers": [ "しょしん" ], "comment": "belief; conviction; opinion" },
	{ "question": "所在", "answers": [ "しょざい" ], "comment": "whereabouts" },
	{ "question": "所在地", "answers": [ "しょざいち" ], "comment": "location; address" },
	{ "question": "所定", "answers": [ "しょてい" ], "comment": "fixed; prescribed; certain; given" },
	{ "question": "所属", "answers": [ "しょぞく" ], "comment": "attached to; belong to; member; affiliation" },
	{ "question": "所得", "answers": [ "しょとく" ], "comment": "income; earnings" },
	{ "question": "所得税", "answers": [ "しょとくぜい" ], "comment": "income tax" },
	{ "question": "所持", "answers": [ "しょじ" ], "comment": "possession; owning" },
	{ "question": "所有", "answers": [ "しょゆう" ], "comment": "one's possessions; ownership" },
	{ "question": "所有権", "answers": [ "しょゆうけん" ], "comment": "ownership; dominion; ownership rights; proprietorship; property rights" },
	{ "question": "所管", "answers": [ "しょかん" ], "comment": "jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "所蔵", "answers": [ "しょぞう" ], "comment": "(in one's) possession" },
	{ "question": "所要", "answers": [ "しょよう" ], "comment": "required; needed; necessary" },
	{ "question": "所見", "answers": [ "しょけん" ], "comment": "view; opinion; finding; findings" },
	{ "question": "所詮", "answers": [ "しょせん" ], "comment": "after all" },
	{ "question": "所長", "answers": [ "しょちょう" ], "comment": "chief; head (of an office, of a laboratory)" },
	{ "question": "扇", "answers": [ "おうぎ" ], "comment": "folding fan" },
	{ "question": "扇ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "to fan\nto incite; to instigate" },
	{ "question": "扇子", "answers": [ "せんす" ], "comment": "folding fan" },
	{ "question": "扇形", "answers": [ "おうぎがた", "せんけい" ], "comment": "fan shape" },
	{ "question": "扇風機", "answers": [ "せんぷうき" ], "comment": "electric fan" },
	{ "question": "扉", "answers": [ "とびら" ], "comment": "door; gate; opening\ntitle page" },
	{ "question": "手", "answers": [ "て" ], "comment": "hand; arm\nforepaw; foreleg\nhandle\nhand; worker; help\ntrouble; care; effort\nmeans; way; trick; move; technique; workmanship\nhand; handwriting\nkind; type; sort\none's hands; one's possession\nability to cope\nhand (of cards)\ndirection\nmove (in go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "手がかり", "answers": [ "てがかり" ], "comment": "clue; lead; key; trail; scent; track\nhandhold; hold" },
	{ "question": "手がける", "answers": [ "てがける" ], "comment": "to handle; to manage; to deal with; to work with; to have experience with\nto rear; to look after" },
	{ "question": "手ごろ", "answers": [ "てごろ" ], "comment": "moderate; handy; convenient; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "手ごわい", "answers": [ "てごわい" ], "comment": "difficult; tough; formidable; redoubtable; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "手すり", "answers": [ "てすり" ], "comment": "handrail; railing; banister" },
	{ "question": "手に入る", "answers": [ "てにはいる" ], "comment": "to obtain; to come into possession of; to get hold of; to get one's hands on" },
	{ "question": "手に入れる", "answers": [ "てにいれる" ], "comment": "to obtain; to procure" },
	{ "question": "手ぬぐい", "answers": [ "てぬぐい" ], "comment": "(hand) towel" },
	{ "question": "手のひら", "answers": [ "たなごころ", "てのひら" ], "comment": "palm (of one's hand)" },
	{ "question": "手中", "answers": [ "しゅちゅう" ], "comment": "in one's hands; in one's control" },
	{ "question": "手伝い", "answers": [ "てつだい" ], "comment": "helper; assistant\nhelp" },
	{ "question": "手伝う", "answers": [ "てつだう" ], "comment": "to help; to assist; to aid\nto contribute to; to be a factor in" },
	{ "question": "手作り", "answers": [ "てづくり" ], "comment": "handmade; homegrown; hand-crafted; homemade" },
	{ "question": "手元", "answers": [ "てもと" ], "comment": "at hand; on hand; nearby; close at hand\nway of moving one's arms; skill\nmoney at hand; pocket money\ngrip; handle" },
	{ "question": "手入れ", "answers": [ "ていれ" ], "comment": "care; looking after; repair; maintenance; tending; trimming; grooming\n(police) raid; crackdown" },
	{ "question": "手分け", "answers": [ "てわけ" ], "comment": "division of labour; division of labor; splitting into groups (e.g. to search)" },
	{ "question": "手前", "answers": [ "てまえ" ], "comment": "before; this side\none's standpoint; one's appearance\nwe\nyou" },
	{ "question": "手助け", "answers": [ "てだすけ" ], "comment": "a help; assistance" },
	{ "question": "手動", "answers": [ "しゅどう" ], "comment": "manual (operation)" },
	{ "question": "手取り", "answers": [ "てとり" ], "comment": "talented wrestler\ngood at manipulating (others); crafty person" },
	{ "question": "手口", "answers": [ "てぐち" ], "comment": "modus operandi; criminal technique; trick" },
	{ "question": "手品", "answers": [ "てじな" ], "comment": "magic (illusion); conjuring; magic trick; conjuring trick; sleight of hand" },
	{ "question": "手堅い", "answers": [ "てがたい" ], "comment": "steady; firm; solid; secure" },
	{ "question": "手始め", "answers": [ "てはじめ" ], "comment": "outset; start; beginning" },
	{ "question": "手帳", "answers": [ "てちょう" ], "comment": "notebook; memo pad; (pocket) diary\ncertificate\nidentification card" },
	{ "question": "手引", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "guidance; guide; introduction; guideline" },
	{ "question": "手引き", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "guidance; guide; introduction; guideline" },
	{ "question": "手引書", "answers": [ "てびきしょ" ], "comment": "handbook; manual; guide; primer" },
	{ "question": "手当", "answers": [ "てあて" ], "comment": "salary; pay; compensation; allowance (e.g. housing allowance); benefit; bonus\nmedical care; treatment\nadvance preparation" },
	{ "question": "手当たり次第", "answers": [ "てあたりしだい" ], "comment": "using anything one can lay one's hands on; haphazardly; on the rebound; at random; indiscriminately" },
	{ "question": "手当て", "answers": [ "てあて" ], "comment": "salary; pay; compensation; allowance (e.g. housing allowance); benefit; bonus\nmedical care; treatment\nadvance preparation" },
	{ "question": "手形", "answers": [ "てがた" ], "comment": "draft; draught; promissory note; bill\nhandprint\nsigned hand-print" },
	{ "question": "手応え", "answers": [ "てごたえ" ], "comment": "response (felt in the hands); resistance\nreaction; response; effect" },
	{ "question": "手抜き", "answers": [ "てぬき" ], "comment": "omitting crucial steps; cutting corners; skimping\nintentional negligence\ntenuki; taking the initiative by ignoring the opponent's last move and playing somewhere else (in go)" },
	{ "question": "手拭い", "answers": [ "てぬぐい" ], "comment": "(hand) towel" },
	{ "question": "手持ち", "answers": [ "てもち" ], "comment": "in hand; on hand; on one; in stock; in store\nhandheld" },
	{ "question": "手振り", "answers": [ "てぶり" ], "comment": "movements or gestures of hands or arms" },
	{ "question": "手掛かり", "answers": [ "てがかり" ], "comment": "clue; lead; key; trail; scent; track\nhandhold; hold" },
	{ "question": "手探り", "answers": [ "てさぐり" ], "comment": "fumbling; groping" },
	{ "question": "手提げ", "answers": [ "てさげ" ], "comment": "handbag; purse" },
	{ "question": "手摺り", "answers": [ "てすり" ], "comment": "handrail; railing; banister" },
	{ "question": "手放し", "answers": [ "てばなし" ], "comment": "without holding on; without using the hands; letting go one's hold\nlack of reserve; lack of restraint; openly" },
	{ "question": "手数", "answers": [ "てかず", "てすう" ], "comment": "trouble; bother\nnumber of moves (in go, shogi, etc.)\nnumber of punches (in boxing)" },
	{ "question": "手数料", "answers": [ "てすうりょう" ], "comment": "handling charge; commission" },
	{ "question": "手書き", "answers": [ "てがき" ], "comment": "handwriting\nhandwritten; hand-painted; hand-drawn" },
	{ "question": "手本", "answers": [ "てほん" ], "comment": "copybook\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "手柄", "answers": [ "てがら" ], "comment": "achievement; feat; meritorious deed; distinguished service" },
	{ "question": "手段", "answers": [ "しゅだん" ], "comment": "means; way; measure" },
	{ "question": "手法", "answers": [ "しゅほう" ], "comment": "technique; method" },
	{ "question": "手洗い", "answers": [ "てあらい" ], "comment": "washing one's hands; water (or basin, etc.) for washing one's hands\nrestroom; lavatory; toilet\nhand-washing (laundry, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "手渡す", "answers": [ "てわたす" ], "comment": "to hand over; to surrender" },
	{ "question": "手痛い", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "severe; hard" },
	{ "question": "手直し", "answers": [ "てなおし" ], "comment": "adjustment; tweaking; improvement; modification; tinkering; minor alteration; correction" },
	{ "question": "手立て", "answers": [ "てだて" ], "comment": "means; method" },
	{ "question": "手紙", "answers": [ "てがみ" ], "comment": "letter" },
	{ "question": "手続", "answers": [ "てつづき" ], "comment": "procedure; (legal) process; formalities" },
	{ "question": "手続き", "answers": [ "てつづき" ], "comment": "procedure; (legal) process; formalities" },
	{ "question": "手腕", "answers": [ "しゅわん" ], "comment": "ability" },
	{ "question": "手落ち", "answers": [ "ておち" ], "comment": "oversight; omission" },
	{ "question": "手薄", "answers": [ "てうす" ], "comment": "short of hands; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "手術", "answers": [ "しゅじゅつ" ], "comment": "(surgical) operation; procedure" },
	{ "question": "手袋", "answers": [ "てぶくろ" ], "comment": "glove; mitten; mitt" },
	{ "question": "手製", "answers": [ "てせい" ], "comment": "handmade" },
	{ "question": "手記", "answers": [ "しゅき" ], "comment": "note; memorandum" },
	{ "question": "手話", "answers": [ "しゅわ" ], "comment": "sign language" },
	{ "question": "手足", "answers": [ "てあし" ], "comment": "hands and feet; limbs" },
	{ "question": "手軽", "answers": [ "てがる" ], "comment": "easy; simple; informal; offhand; cheap" },
	{ "question": "手造り", "answers": [ "てづくり" ], "comment": "handmade; homegrown; hand-crafted; homemade" },
	{ "question": "手遅れ", "answers": [ "ておくれ" ], "comment": "being (too) late\nbelated treatment" },
	{ "question": "手配", "answers": [ "てはい" ], "comment": "arrangement; preparations\nsearch (by police)" },
	{ "question": "手錠", "answers": [ "てじょう" ], "comment": "handcuffs; manacles" },
	{ "question": "手間", "answers": [ "てま" ], "comment": "time; labour; labor" },
	{ "question": "手際", "answers": [ "てぎわ" ], "comment": "performance; skill; tact" },
	{ "question": "手際良く", "answers": [ "てぎわよく" ], "comment": "efficiently; skillfully; cleverly" },
	{ "question": "手順", "answers": [ "てじゅん" ], "comment": "process; procedure; sequence; protocol; instruction" },
	{ "question": "手首", "answers": [ "てくび" ], "comment": "wrist" },
	{ "question": "才", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "-years-old\nability; gift; talent; aptitude; genius" },
	{ "question": "才能", "answers": [ "さいのう" ], "comment": "talent; ability" },
	{ "question": "打ち上げ", "answers": [ "うちあげ" ], "comment": "launching; launch\nend (of a theatrical run, etc.)\nclosing party (e.g. a theater show); cast party; party to celebrate successful completion of a project" },
	{ "question": "打ち上げる", "answers": [ "うちあげる" ], "comment": "to launch; to shoot up\n(of waves) to dash; to wash up (ashore)\nto finish (e.g. a theater run, sumo tournament); to close\nto report (to boss, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "打ち出す", "answers": [ "うちだす" ], "comment": "to emboss\nto print out; to print\nto work out (e.g. policy); to hammer out; to come out with; to set forth\nto strike (a drum indicating the end of a performance)\nto begin striking; to start beating" },
	{ "question": "打ち切り", "answers": [ "うちきり" ], "comment": "end; close; finish; truncation; discontinuance" },
	{ "question": "打ち切る", "answers": [ "うちきる" ], "comment": "to stop; to abort; to discontinue; to close" },
	{ "question": "打ち合い", "answers": [ "うちあい" ], "comment": "exchange of blows; long rally" },
	{ "question": "打ち合せ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "打ち合わせ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "打ち合わせる", "answers": [ "うちあわせる" ], "comment": "to knock together\nto arrange (e.g. a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "打ち明ける", "answers": [ "うちあける" ], "comment": "to confide; to reveal; to disclose; to lay bare; to speak frankly; to open (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "打ち消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "negation; denial; negative" },
	{ "question": "打ち消す", "answers": [ "うちけす" ], "comment": "to deny; to contradict\nto negate (esp. a sound); to drown out" },
	{ "question": "打ち込み", "answers": [ "うちこみ" ], "comment": "driving; pounding in; shooting into; implantation; invasion\nfalling badly in love\nputting (one's heart) into\nstep recording (in electronic or computer music)" },
	{ "question": "打ち込む", "answers": [ "うちこむ" ], "comment": "to drive in (e.g. nail, stake); to hammer in\nto hit (a ball, etc.); to drive; to smash\nto fire into (e.g. a crowd); to launch (e.g. missiles); to lob (e.g. grenades)\nto input (data); to enter\nto devote oneself to; to go heart and soul into; to throw oneself into; to go head over heels for\nto practice hitting (baseball, tennis, etc.)\nto hit (an opponent in kendo, boxing, etc.); to get a blow in\nto invade one's opponent's territory (in the game of go); to place a stone in an opponent's formation\nto pour (concrete, etc.) into a form" },
	{ "question": "打つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "to hit; to strike; to knock; to beat; to punch; to slap; to tap; to bang; to clap; to pound\nto strike (noon, etc.); to sound (cymbals, etc.); to beat (a drum, etc.)\nto beat (rhythmically, e.g. pulse, waves, etc.)\nto move; to impress; to touch\nto drive in; to hammer in; to put in; to inject\nto type; to send; to transmit\nto insert; to write in; to mark\nto make (noodles, etc.); to prepare\nto till (soil)\nto sprinkle; to throw; to cast\nto do; to carry out; to play; to perform; to engage in (gambling, etc.)\nto pay (a deposit, etc.)\nto visit (on a pilgrimage)\nto line (a coat)\nto bind (a criminal)" },
	{ "question": "打倒", "answers": [ "だとう" ], "comment": "knockdown (e.g. in boxing); overthrow; defeat" },
	{ "question": "打力", "answers": [ "だりょく" ], "comment": "batting power" },
	{ "question": "打合せ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "打合わせ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "打席", "answers": [ "だせき" ], "comment": "batter's box; one's turn at bat" },
	{ "question": "打撃", "answers": [ "だげき" ], "comment": "blow; shock; strike; damage\nbatting" },
	{ "question": "打撲", "answers": [ "だぼく" ], "comment": "blow; hit (on the body); beating" },
	{ "question": "打数", "answers": [ "だすう" ], "comment": "times at bat" },
	{ "question": "打消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "negation; denial; negative" },
	{ "question": "打消す", "answers": [ "うちけす" ], "comment": "to deny; to contradict\nto negate (esp. a sound); to drown out" },
	{ "question": "打点", "answers": [ "だてん" ], "comment": "runs batted in; RBI" },
	{ "question": "打率", "answers": [ "だりつ" ], "comment": "batting average" },
	{ "question": "打球", "answers": [ "だきゅう" ], "comment": "batting; batted ball" },
	{ "question": "打破", "answers": [ "だは" ], "comment": "breaking down; defeating; abolishing" },
	{ "question": "打算的", "answers": [ "ださんてき" ], "comment": "calculating; mercenary" },
	{ "question": "打線", "answers": [ "だせん" ], "comment": "batting lineup (line-up)" },
	{ "question": "打者", "answers": [ "だしゃ" ], "comment": "batter" },
	{ "question": "打診", "answers": [ "だしん" ], "comment": "percussion; tapping\nsounding someone out" },
	{ "question": "打開", "answers": [ "だかい" ], "comment": "break in the deadlock" },
	{ "question": "打順", "answers": [ "だじゅん" ], "comment": "batting order" },
	{ "question": "払い", "answers": [ "はらい" ], "comment": "payment; bill; account\nsweeping; clearing away\nsweeping stroke (e.g. when writing kanji)" },
	{ "question": "払い戻し", "answers": [ "はらいもどし" ], "comment": "repayment; refund; payback" },
	{ "question": "払い戻す", "answers": [ "はらいもどす" ], "comment": "to repay; to pay back" },
	{ "question": "払い込む", "answers": [ "はらいこむ" ], "comment": "to deposit; to pay in" },
	{ "question": "払う", "answers": [ "はらう" ], "comment": "to pay (e.g. money, bill)\nto brush off; to wipe away; to clear away; to dust off; to cut off (e.g. branches)\nto drive away (e.g. one's competitors)\nto sell off (something unneeded); to dispose of\nto pay (e.g. attention); to show (e.g. respect, concern)\nto make (e.g. effort, sacrifice); to expend; to exert\nto move out (of one's own place); to vacate\nto sweep (e.g. one's legs); to knock aside\nto make a sweeping stroke (in Japanese calligraphy)\nto reset (an abacus)" },
	{ "question": "払拭", "answers": [ "ふっしょく", "ふっしき" ], "comment": "wiping out; sweeping away" },
	{ "question": "扱い", "answers": [ "あつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service" },
	{ "question": "扱う", "answers": [ "あつかう" ], "comment": "to deal with (a person); to treat; to handle; to take care of; to entertain\nto deal with (a problem); to handle; to manage\nto operate (e.g. a machine); to handle; to work\nto deal in; to sell\nto cover (a topic); to treat; to discuss; to take up\nto treat A as B\nto mediate (an argument)\nto be too much for one; to find unmanageable\nto gossip" },
	{ "question": "扶助", "answers": [ "ふじょ" ], "comment": "aid; help; assistance; support" },
	{ "question": "扶養", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "support (family, esp. dependents: children or spouse); maintenance" },
	{ "question": "批准", "answers": [ "ひじゅん" ], "comment": "ratification; ratify" },
	{ "question": "批判", "answers": [ "ひはん" ], "comment": "criticism; judgement; judgment; comment" },
	{ "question": "批判的", "answers": [ "ひはんてき" ], "comment": "critical; judgmental" },
	{ "question": "批評", "answers": [ "ひひょう" ], "comment": "criticism; review; commentary" },
	{ "question": "承る", "answers": [ "うけたまわる" ], "comment": "to hear; to be told; to know\nto receive (order); to undertake; to comply; to take (a reservation, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "承知", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "knowledge; awareness\nconsent; acceptance; assent; admitting; compliance; agreement; acknowledgment; acknowledgement\nforgiving; pardoning; excusing" },
	{ "question": "承認", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "recognition; acknowledgement; acknowledgment; approval; consent; agreement" },
	{ "question": "承諾", "answers": [ "しょうだく" ], "comment": "consent; acquiescence; agreement" },
	{ "question": "技", "answers": [ "わざ", "ぎ" ], "comment": "technique; art; skill" },
	{ "question": "技巧", "answers": [ "ぎこう" ], "comment": "technique; finesse" },
	{ "question": "技師", "answers": [ "ぎし" ], "comment": "engineer; technician" },
	{ "question": "技法", "answers": [ "ぎほう" ], "comment": "technique" },
	{ "question": "技能", "answers": [ "ぎのう" ], "comment": "technical skill; ability; capacity" },
	{ "question": "技術", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつ" ], "comment": "technology; engineering\ntechnique; skill\nart; craft" },
	{ "question": "技術的", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつてき" ], "comment": "technical; practical" },
	{ "question": "技術者", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつしゃ" ], "comment": "engineer; technical expert; technician; craftsperson" },
	{ "question": "把", "answers": [ "ぱ", "ば", "わ" ], "comment": "counter for bundles" },
	{ "question": "把握", "answers": [ "はあく" ], "comment": "grasp; catch; understanding" },
	{ "question": "抑え", "answers": [ "おさえ" ], "comment": "weight (e.g. paperweight); rear guard; control; check; pressure" },
	{ "question": "抑える", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "to pin something down; to hold something down; to hold something back; to stop; to restrain; to curb\nto seize; to grasp; to arrest\nto gain control of something; to govern; to keep down (e.g. information); to suppress\nto catch happening; to determine (important points); to find (proof); to understand" },
	{ "question": "抑制", "answers": [ "よくせい" ], "comment": "control; restraint; suppression; constraint; curtailment; inhibition; check; curb" },
	{ "question": "抑圧", "answers": [ "よくあつ" ], "comment": "check; restraint; oppression; suppression" },
	{ "question": "抑揚", "answers": [ "よくよう" ], "comment": "intonation; accent; modulation; inflection" },
	{ "question": "抑止", "answers": [ "よくし" ], "comment": "check; checkmate; stave off; control; restraint; inhibit; deterrent; deterrence" },
	{ "question": "抑留", "answers": [ "よくりゅう" ], "comment": "internment; detainment; detention" },
	{ "question": "投げ", "answers": [ "なげ" ], "comment": "a throw; a fall" },
	{ "question": "投げる", "answers": [ "なげる" ], "comment": "to throw; to cast away\nto face defeat; to give up" },
	{ "question": "投げ出す", "answers": [ "なげだす" ], "comment": "to throw down; to throw out; to stretch out (one's legs)\nto abandon; to resign\nto give freely; to give generously; to sacrifice (e.g. one's life)\nto start to throw" },
	{ "question": "投げ込む", "answers": [ "なげこむ" ], "comment": "to throw into" },
	{ "question": "投じる", "answers": [ "とうじる" ], "comment": "to throw; to cast (e.g. vote, light, shadow)\nto devote oneself (e.g. to a cause)\nto invest; to put in\nto administer (medicine); to give\nto surrender\nto take advantage of; to make full use of\nto fit well with; to match with; to be in tune with\nto stay (at a lodging)" },
	{ "question": "投下", "answers": [ "とうか" ], "comment": "throwing down; dropping; airdrop\ninvestment" },
	{ "question": "投与", "answers": [ "とうよ" ], "comment": "prescribing medicine; administering (medicine)" },
	{ "question": "投信", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "investment trust" },
	{ "question": "投入", "answers": [ "とうにゅう" ], "comment": "throwing into; inserting; depositing\ninvestment; putting in (personnel, etc.)\nrelease of a product\nmaking (an electrical circuit)" },
	{ "question": "投射", "answers": [ "とうしゃ" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "投影", "answers": [ "とうえい" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "投手", "answers": [ "とうしゅ" ], "comment": "pitcher" },
	{ "question": "投手戦", "answers": [ "とうしゅせん" ], "comment": "pitching duel; pitchers' battle" },
	{ "question": "投書", "answers": [ "とうしょ" ], "comment": "letter to the editor; letter from a reader; contribution" },
	{ "question": "投棄", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "abandonment; giving up; throwing away; disposal; dumping" },
	{ "question": "投機", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "speculation; venture; stockjobbing; gambling (on stocks)" },
	{ "question": "投球", "answers": [ "とうきゅう" ], "comment": "pitching; throwing a ball; bowling (in cricket); pitched ball" },
	{ "question": "投石", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "stone throwing" },
	{ "question": "投票", "answers": [ "とうひょう" ], "comment": "voting; poll" },
	{ "question": "投票所", "answers": [ "とうひょうしょ", "とうひょうじょ" ], "comment": "polling place" },
	{ "question": "投票箱", "answers": [ "とうひょうばこ" ], "comment": "ballot box" },
	{ "question": "投稿", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "contribution; submission; posting (e.g. to a newsgroup or mailing list)" },
	{ "question": "投薬", "answers": [ "とうやく" ], "comment": "administration; medication; dosage" },
	{ "question": "投融資", "answers": [ "とうゆうし" ], "comment": "investment and lending" },
	{ "question": "投資", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "investment" },
	{ "question": "投資信託", "answers": [ "とうししんたく" ], "comment": "investment trust" },
	{ "question": "投降", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "surrender" },
	{ "question": "抗争", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "dispute; resistance" },
	{ "question": "抗体", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "antibody" },
	{ "question": "抗原", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "antigen" },
	{ "question": "抗告", "answers": [ "こうこく" ], "comment": "kokoku (interlocutory) appeal; protest; complaint" },
	{ "question": "抗戦", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "resistance" },
	{ "question": "抗日", "answers": [ "こうにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "抗生物質", "answers": [ "こうせいぶっしつ" ], "comment": "antibiotic; antibiotics" },
	{ "question": "抗菌", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "antibacterial; antimicrobial" },
	{ "question": "抗議", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "protest; objection" },
	{ "question": "折", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; occasion; time\nfold; pleat; crease\nsmall food box (wooden or cardboard)" },
	{ "question": "折々", "answers": [ "おりおり" ], "comment": "occasionally" },
	{ "question": "折から", "answers": [ "おりから", "おりがら" ], "comment": "just then; at that time; right then; at that moment\nappropriate moment" },
	{ "question": "折りたたみ", "answers": [ "おりたたみ" ], "comment": "folding; collapsible; telescopic" },
	{ "question": "折り合い", "answers": [ "おりあい" ], "comment": "agreement (e.g. business, dispute); compromise\nmutual relations (e.g. between parents and child, coworkers, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "折り畳み", "answers": [ "おりたたみ" ], "comment": "folding; collapsible; telescopic" },
	{ "question": "折り紙", "answers": [ "おりがみ" ], "comment": "origami; art of paper folding\nhallmark; certificate of authenticity" },
	{ "question": "折り返し", "answers": [ "おりかえし" ], "comment": "by return; (call or write back) without delay\nlapel; cuffs; flap\nchorus; refrain\nrepetition\naliasing (in imaging)\nshuttle service\nback-to-back; BTB\nwrapping (text on computer screen); wrap" },
	{ "question": "折り返す", "answers": [ "おりかえす" ], "comment": "to turn up; to fold back\nto loopback (a signal, a message)" },
	{ "question": "折る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "to break; to fracture; to break off; to snap off; to pick (e.g. flowers)\nto fold; to bend\nto make (origami)\nto interrupt; to end" },
	{ "question": "折れる", "answers": [ "おれる" ], "comment": "to break; to be broken; to snap; to fracture\nto be folded\nto give in; to back down; to yield; to submit\nto turn (a corner)" },
	{ "question": "折半", "answers": [ "せっぱん" ], "comment": "halving; splitting evenly; sharing equally" },
	{ "question": "折紙", "answers": [ "おりがみ" ], "comment": "origami; art of paper folding\nhallmark; certificate of authenticity" },
	{ "question": "折衝", "answers": [ "せっしょう" ], "comment": "negotiation" },
	{ "question": "折衷", "answers": [ "せっちゅう" ], "comment": "compromise; cross; blending; eclecticism" },
	{ "question": "抜かす", "answers": [ "ぬかす" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to skip\nto say; to speak" },
	{ "question": "抜き", "answers": [ "ぬき" ], "comment": "without; not including; dispensed with\n(beating) in succession" },
	{ "question": "抜く", "answers": [ "ぬく" ], "comment": "to extract; to omit; to draw out; to unplug\nto do something to the end\nto surpass; to overtake\nto masturbate (of a male); to ejaculate (while masturbating)\nto take (a photo); to record (video)" },
	{ "question": "抜ける", "answers": [ "ぬける" ], "comment": "to come out; to fall out; to be omitted; to be missing; to escape; to come loose\nto fade; to discolour\nto wear a hole (e.g. clothes)\nto leave (e.g. a meeting)\nto be clear; to be transparent (e.g. of the sky)\nto be stupid; to be absentminded; to be careless; to be inattentive\nto exit (a program loop)\nto go through; to pass through" },
	{ "question": "抜け出す", "answers": [ "ぬけだす" ], "comment": "to slip out; to sneak away; to excel\nto break (out of a loop)" },
	{ "question": "抜本的", "answers": [ "ばっぽんてき" ], "comment": "drastic; radical" },
	{ "question": "抜粋", "answers": [ "ばっすい" ], "comment": "extract; excerpt; selection" },
	{ "question": "抜群", "answers": [ "ばつぐん" ], "comment": "preeminence; distinction; extraordinariness\noutstanding; excellent; exceptional; surpassing; extraordinary; distinguished" },
	{ "question": "択一", "answers": [ "たくいつ" ], "comment": "choosing an alternative" },
	{ "question": "披露", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "announcement; presentation; demonstration; displaying; showing; introducing; exhibiting; unveiling; revealing; showcasing; performing; giving a rendition" },
	{ "question": "披露宴", "answers": [ "ひろうえん" ], "comment": "reception (wedding)" },
	{ "question": "抱え", "answers": [ "かかえ" ], "comment": "armful\nemployee" },
	{ "question": "抱える", "answers": [ "かかえる" ], "comment": "to hold or carry under or in the arms\nto have (esp. problems, debts, etc.)\nto employ; to engage; to hire" },
	{ "question": "抱く", "answers": [ "いだく", "だく" ], "comment": "to embrace; to hold in the arms (e.g. a baby); to hug\nto harbour (e.g. grudge); to harbor; to bear; to have (e.g. ambition); to entertain (e.g. hope, suspicion)\nto have sex with; to make love to; to sleep with\nto sit on eggs" },
	{ "question": "抱っこ", "answers": [ "だっこ" ], "comment": "(child's) hug; carrying a baby in one's arms; carrying a pet in one's arms" },
	{ "question": "抱負", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "aspiration; ambition; pretension" },
	{ "question": "抵当権", "answers": [ "ていとうけん" ], "comment": "mortgage; a lien on one's mortgage" },
	{ "question": "抵抗", "answers": [ "ていこう" ], "comment": "resistance; opposition; standing up to\nreluctance; repulsion; repugnance\nresistance; drag; friction\nelectrical resistance\nresistor" },
	{ "question": "抵触", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "collision; conflict\nbeing contrary; being incompatible; being inconsistent; being contradictory\nbeing in violation (of a law, treaty, etc.); contravention" },
	{ "question": "抹消", "answers": [ "まっしょう" ], "comment": "erasure; striking off; crossing out; cancellation; deletion" },
	{ "question": "押さえる", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "to pin something down; to hold something down; to hold something back; to stop; to restrain; to curb\nto seize; to grasp; to arrest\nto gain control of something; to govern; to keep down (e.g. information); to suppress\nto catch happening; to determine (important points); to find (proof); to understand" },
	{ "question": "押し", "answers": [ "おし" ], "comment": "push; pressure; authority; audacity" },
	{ "question": "押し付ける", "answers": [ "おしつける" ], "comment": "to press; to push; to force" },
	{ "question": "押し入り", "answers": [ "おしいり" ], "comment": "breaking into; burglar" },
	{ "question": "押し入る", "answers": [ "おしいる" ], "comment": "to push in; to force into; to break in (e.g. into a house); to intrude" },
	{ "question": "押し入れ", "answers": [ "おしいれ" ], "comment": "closet" },
	{ "question": "押し出し", "answers": [ "おしだし" ], "comment": "pushing something out; extrusion\npresence; appearance\nrun walked in\npushing one's opponent out by pressing one's hands up against them" },
	{ "question": "押し切る", "answers": [ "おしきる" ], "comment": "to face down the opposition; to overcome resistance; to have one's own way\nto press and cut" },
	{ "question": "押し問答", "answers": [ "おしもんどう" ], "comment": "dispute; heated questioning and answering" },
	{ "question": "押し売り", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "押し込む", "answers": [ "おしこむ" ], "comment": "to push into; to cram into; to stuff into; to crowd into\nto break in; to burgle; to burglarize" },
	{ "question": "押す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "to push; to press\nto apply pressure from above; to press down\nto stamp (i.e. a passport); to apply a seal\nto affix (e.g. gold leaf)\nto press (someone for something); to urge; to compel; to influence\nto overwhelm; to overpower; to repress\nto push (events along); to advance (a plan)\nto do in spite of ...; to do even though ...; to force\nto make sure\nto be pressed for time\nto advance troops; to attack\n(of light) to be diffused across an entire surface" },
	{ "question": "押入", "answers": [ "おしいれ" ], "comment": "closet" },
	{ "question": "押入れ", "answers": [ "おしいれ" ], "comment": "closet" },
	{ "question": "押収", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "seizure; confiscation" },
	{ "question": "押売", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "押売り", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "抽出", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゅつ" ], "comment": "extraction; abstraction\nselection (from a group); sampling; eduction" },
	{ "question": "抽象", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "abstract" },
	{ "question": "抽象的", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょうてき" ], "comment": "abstract" },
	{ "question": "抽選", "answers": [ "ちゅうせん" ], "comment": "lottery; raffle; drawing (of lots)" },
	{ "question": "担い手", "answers": [ "にないて" ], "comment": "bearer; carrier\nperson bearing responsibility; person in charge; supporter" },
	{ "question": "担う", "answers": [ "になう" ], "comment": "to carry on shoulder; to shoulder (gun)\nto bear (burden, responsibility, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "担ぎ", "answers": [ "かつぎ" ], "comment": "carrier" },
	{ "question": "担ぐ", "answers": [ "かつぐ" ], "comment": "to shoulder; to carry on one's shoulder\nto nominate for a position; to choose as a representative\nto take (someone) for a ride; to deceive; to take in\nto be caught up in superstition" },
	{ "question": "担任", "answers": [ "たんにん" ], "comment": "in charge (of something)\nclass teacher; homeroom teacher; form teacher" },
	{ "question": "担保", "answers": [ "たんぽ" ], "comment": "security; guarantee; collateral (e.g. mortgage)" },
	{ "question": "担当", "answers": [ "たんとう" ], "comment": "being in charge (of an area of responsibility); being responsible (for a work role, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "担当者", "answers": [ "たんとうしゃ" ], "comment": "person in charge (of an area of work, but not necessarily supervising other staff); person responsible; one in charge; responsible party; contact (person)" },
	{ "question": "担架", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "stretcher; litter" },
	{ "question": "拉致問題", "answers": [ "らちもんだい" ], "comment": "abduction issue (esp. of those Japanese abducted by North Korea)" },
	{ "question": "拍子", "answers": [ "ひょうし" ], "comment": "(musical) time; tempo; beat; rhythm\nthe moment; the instance; chance" },
	{ "question": "拍手", "answers": [ "はくしゅ" ], "comment": "clapping hands; applause" },
	{ "question": "拍車", "answers": [ "はくしゃ" ], "comment": "(riding) spur" },
	{ "question": "拒む", "answers": [ "こばむ" ], "comment": "to refuse; to reject; to decline" },
	{ "question": "拒否", "answers": [ "きょひ" ], "comment": "denial; veto; rejection; refusal" },
	{ "question": "拒否権", "answers": [ "きょひけん" ], "comment": "right of veto" },
	{ "question": "拒絶", "answers": [ "きょぜつ" ], "comment": "refusal; rejection" },
	{ "question": "拒絶反応", "answers": [ "きょぜつはんのう" ], "comment": "(organ) rejection\nunthinking dismissal; strong reaction (against)" },
	{ "question": "拘束", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "restriction; restraint; binding; constraint" },
	{ "question": "拘禁", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "detention; custody; confinement; internment" },
	{ "question": "拘置", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "detention; confinement; arrest" },
	{ "question": "拘置所", "answers": [ "こうちしょ" ], "comment": "prison; detention house; detention center; jail" },
	{ "question": "拙速", "answers": [ "せっそく" ], "comment": "hasty; rough and ready" },
	{ "question": "招き", "answers": [ "まねき" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "招く", "answers": [ "まねく" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask\nto beckon; to wave someone in; to gesture to\nto call in; to send for; to summon\nto bring on oneself; to cause; to incur; to lead to; to result in" },
	{ "question": "招待", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "招致", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "invitation; summons; bidding (e.g. to host the Olympics); calling" },
	{ "question": "招請", "answers": [ "しょうせい" ], "comment": "calling together; invitation" },
	{ "question": "招集", "answers": [ "しょうしゅう" ], "comment": "call; summons; convening; convocation" },
	{ "question": "拝む", "answers": [ "おがむ" ], "comment": "to assume the posture of praying; to press the palms and fingers of both hands together; to do reverence (e.g. before a statue of the Buddha); to pay one's respects\nto beg; to make a supplication\nto see (something or someone of high status)" },
	{ "question": "拝啓", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "Dear (so and so); Dear Sir; Dear Madam; To Whom It May Concern" },
	{ "question": "拝見", "answers": [ "はいけん" ], "comment": "seeing; look at" },
	{ "question": "拠出", "answers": [ "きょしゅつ" ], "comment": "donation; contribution" },
	{ "question": "拠点", "answers": [ "きょてん" ], "comment": "position; location; base; point" },
	{ "question": "拡充", "answers": [ "かくじゅう" ], "comment": "expansion" },
	{ "question": "拡声機", "answers": [ "かくせいき" ], "comment": "megaphone; bullhorn; loudhailer" },
	{ "question": "拡大", "answers": [ "かくだい" ], "comment": "magnification; enlargement; expansion; amplification" },
	{ "question": "拡大均衡", "answers": [ "かくだいきんこう" ], "comment": "an expanded or expanding equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "拡張", "answers": [ "かくちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; extension; enlargement; escape; ESC" },
	{ "question": "拡張子", "answers": [ "かくちょうし" ], "comment": "filename extension" },
	{ "question": "拡散", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "scattering; diffusion; spread (e.g. signal across the spectrum)" },
	{ "question": "拭う", "answers": [ "ぬぐう" ], "comment": "to wipe\nto get rid of; to eliminate (e.g. one's shame); to remove (e.g. an impression); to erase" },
	{ "question": "拭く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "to wipe; to dry" },
	{ "question": "拳", "answers": [ "こぶし" ], "comment": "fist" },
	{ "question": "拷問", "answers": [ "ごうもん" ], "comment": "torture; the rack; third degree" },
	{ "question": "拾い物", "answers": [ "ひろいもの" ], "comment": "a find\nwindfall; bargain" },
	{ "question": "拾う", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "to pick up; to find; to gather" },
	{ "question": "拾得", "answers": [ "しゅうとく" ], "comment": "picking up; finding" },
	{ "question": "持ち", "answers": [ "もち" ], "comment": "hold; charge; keep possession; in charge\nwear; durability; life; draw\nusage" },
	{ "question": "持ち上げる", "answers": [ "もちあげる" ], "comment": "to elevate; to raise; to lift up\nto flatter; to extol; to praise to the sky" },
	{ "question": "持ち主", "answers": [ "もちぬし" ], "comment": "owner; proprietor; possessor (e.g. of talent, beauty, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "持ち出し", "answers": [ "もちだし" ], "comment": "taking something out; carrying out\nproviding money oneself; paying with one's own money\ncorbel\nstrengthening under a seam (clothing)" },
	{ "question": "持ち出す", "answers": [ "もちだす" ], "comment": "to take out; to carry out; to bring out from where it belongs\nto mention something; to broach a topic; to bring up (a subject); to raise (an issue); to mention" },
	{ "question": "持ち前", "answers": [ "もちまえ" ], "comment": "one's nature; characteristic; inherent; natural" },
	{ "question": "持ち合い", "answers": [ "たもちあい", "もちあい" ], "comment": "unity; even matching; interdependence\nsteadiness (of market price); holding; no change" },
	{ "question": "持ち味", "answers": [ "もちあじ" ], "comment": "inherent flavor; inherent flavour; distinctive characteristic" },
	{ "question": "持ち回り", "answers": [ "もちまわり" ], "comment": "rotation; by turns" },
	{ "question": "持ち堪える", "answers": [ "もちこたえる" ], "comment": "to hold out (e.g. against an attack); to hang on; to withstand; to endure; to last" },
	{ "question": "持ち家", "answers": [ "もちや", "もちいえ" ], "comment": "one's (own) house" },
	{ "question": "持ち帰り", "answers": [ "もちかえり" ], "comment": "takeout (i.e. food); take-out; takeaway; take-away" },
	{ "question": "持ち帰る", "answers": [ "もちかえる" ], "comment": "to bring back; to carry home; to take out (e.g. food)" },
	{ "question": "持ち株", "answers": [ "もちかぶ" ], "comment": "stock holdings; one's shares" },
	{ "question": "持ち物", "answers": [ "もちもの" ], "comment": "one's property; personal effects; one's belongings" },
	{ "question": "持ち直す", "answers": [ "もちなおす" ], "comment": "to recover; to rally; to improve; to pick up" },
	{ "question": "持ち越す", "answers": [ "もちこす" ], "comment": "to carry over; to carry forward; to keep (for later); to defer" },
	{ "question": "持ち込み", "answers": [ "もちこみ" ], "comment": "bring-your-own (e.g. food and drink); carry-on (e.g. luggage)" },
	{ "question": "持ち込む", "answers": [ "もちこむ" ], "comment": "to take something into ...; to bring in; to carry in\nto lodge (a complaint); to file (a plan); to bring (a proposal); to commence negotiations\nto bring to (a state: tied game, vote, trial, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "持っていく", "answers": [ "もってゆく", "もっていく" ], "comment": "to take; to carry (something) away; to bear" },
	{ "question": "持ってくる", "answers": [ "もってくる" ], "comment": "to bring; to take (something) along; to fetch; to get" },
	{ "question": "持って行く", "answers": [ "もってゆく", "もっていく" ], "comment": "to take; to carry (something) away; to bear" },
	{ "question": "持つ", "answers": [ "もつ" ], "comment": "to hold (in one's hand); to take; to carry\nto possess; to have; to own\nto maintain; to keep\nto last; to be durable; to keep; to survive\nto take charge of; to be in charge of" },
	{ "question": "持てる", "answers": [ "もてる" ], "comment": "to be able to possess (hold, get, etc.)\nto be well liked; to be popular; to be pampered (spoiled, doted upon, etc.); to be welcomed\nto endure (the tests of time, the elements, etc.); to last\npossessed\npossessing riches; having wealth" },
	{ "question": "持久", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "endurance; persistence" },
	{ "question": "持参", "answers": [ "じさん" ], "comment": "bringing; taking; carrying" },
	{ "question": "持堪える", "answers": [ "もちこたえる" ], "comment": "to hold out (e.g. against an attack); to hang on; to withstand; to endure; to last" },
	{ "question": "持病", "answers": [ "じびょう" ], "comment": "chronic disease" },
	{ "question": "持直す", "answers": [ "もちなおす" ], "comment": "to recover; to rally; to improve; to pick up" },
	{ "question": "持続", "answers": [ "じぞく" ], "comment": "continuation; persisting; lasting; sustaining; enduring" },
	{ "question": "持続的", "answers": [ "じぞくてき" ], "comment": "continuous; sustained; sustainable; durable; persistent" },
	{ "question": "持論", "answers": [ "じろん" ], "comment": "one's cherished opinion; pet theory" },
	{ "question": "指", "answers": [ "おゆび", "および", "ゆび" ], "comment": "finger; toe; digit" },
	{ "question": "指し示す", "answers": [ "さししめす" ], "comment": "to indicate; to show; to point to" },
	{ "question": "指す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to point\nto nominate; to select someone; to specify some person\nto identify; to indicate; to point out\nto play (a game of shogi); to move (a piece)\nto extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance)" },
	{ "question": "指令", "answers": [ "しれい" ], "comment": "orders; instructions; directive; command" },
	{ "question": "指先", "answers": [ "ゆびさき" ], "comment": "fingertip; finger\ntoe tip; toe" },
	{ "question": "指切り", "answers": [ "ゆびきり" ], "comment": "linking little fingers to confirm a promise" },
	{ "question": "指名", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "name; nominate; designate" },
	{ "question": "指名手配", "answers": [ "しめいてはい" ], "comment": "(the police) wanting (someone) for questioning; having (someone) on the wanted list" },
	{ "question": "指図", "answers": [ "さしず" ], "comment": "instruction; mandate; directions" },
	{ "question": "指定", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "designation; specification; assignment; appointment; pointing at" },
	{ "question": "指導", "answers": [ "しどう" ], "comment": "leadership; guidance; coaching\nshido (disciplinary action for a minor infringement of the rules of judo)" },
	{ "question": "指導者", "answers": [ "しどうしゃ" ], "comment": "leader; guide; mentor; coach" },
	{ "question": "指差す", "answers": [ "ゆびさす" ], "comment": "to point at" },
	{ "question": "指揮", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "command; direction" },
	{ "question": "指揮者", "answers": [ "しきしゃ" ], "comment": "(musical) conductor\ncommander; leader; director" },
	{ "question": "指摘", "answers": [ "してき" ], "comment": "pointing out; identification" },
	{ "question": "指数", "answers": [ "しすう" ], "comment": "index; index number; exponent (e.g. in floating-point representation); characteristic" },
	{ "question": "指標", "answers": [ "しひょう" ], "comment": "index; indices; indicator" },
	{ "question": "指示", "answers": [ "しし", "しじ" ], "comment": "indication; denotation; designation\ninstructions; directions" },
	{ "question": "指紋", "answers": [ "しもん" ], "comment": "fingerprint" },
	{ "question": "指輪", "answers": [ "ゆびわ" ], "comment": "(finger) ring" },
	{ "question": "指針", "answers": [ "ししん" ], "comment": "needle (compass, gauge, etc.); hand (clock); indicator; pointer; index\nguiding principle; guideline; guide" },
	{ "question": "挑戦", "answers": [ "ちょうせん" ], "comment": "challenge; defiance; dare; attempt; try" },
	{ "question": "挑発", "answers": [ "ちょうはつ" ], "comment": "provocation; stirring up; arousal" },
	{ "question": "挙がる", "answers": [ "あがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be arrested\nto turn up (of evidence, etc.)\nto be deep fried\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion" },
	{ "question": "挙党", "answers": [ "きょとう" ], "comment": "entire (political) party" },
	{ "question": "挙式", "answers": [ "きょしき" ], "comment": "holding a ceremony; wedding ceremony" },
	{ "question": "挟み撃ち", "answers": [ "はさみうち" ], "comment": "pincer attack; attack on both sides (flanks)" },
	{ "question": "挟む", "answers": [ "はさむ" ], "comment": "to interpose; to hold between; to insert\nto be on either side (e.g. road); to be across (e.g. street, river); to be beyond" },
	{ "question": "挨拶", "answers": [ "あいさつ" ], "comment": "greeting; greetings; salutation; salute; polite set phrase used when meeting or parting from somebody\npolite set phrase used to express apology, sympathy, congratulations, etc.\nspeech (congratulatory or appreciative); address\nreply; response\nrevenge; retaliation\na fine thing to say (used as part of a sarcastic response to a rude remark)\ndialoging (with another Zen practitioner to ascertain their level of enlightenment)\nrelationship (between people); connection\nintervention; mediation; mediator" },
	{ "question": "挫折", "answers": [ "ざせつ" ], "comment": "setback; failure (e.g. plans, business); frustration; discouragement" },
	{ "question": "振り付け", "answers": [ "ふりつけ" ], "comment": "choreography; dance composition; dance coaching" },
	{ "question": "振り出し", "answers": [ "ふりだし" ], "comment": "starting point; beginning; outset\ndrawing; issuing; draft; draught\nshaking out\nthrow (of dice); toss\ninfusion" },
	{ "question": "振り切る", "answers": [ "ふりきる" ], "comment": "to shake off; to shake free from\nto swing completely" },
	{ "question": "振り向く", "answers": [ "ふりむく" ], "comment": "to turn one's face; to turn around; to look over one's shoulder" },
	{ "question": "振り回す", "answers": [ "ふりまわす" ], "comment": "to wield; to brandish; to flourish; to wave (about); to swing\nto display (one's knowledge); to show off\nto abuse (one's power)\nto manipulate someone" },
	{ "question": "振り子", "answers": [ "しんし", "ふりこ" ], "comment": "pendulum" },
	{ "question": "振り込み", "answers": [ "ふりこみ" ], "comment": "payment made via bank deposit transfer\ndiscarding a tile that becomes another player's winning tile" },
	{ "question": "振り込む", "answers": [ "ふりこむ" ], "comment": "to make a payment via bank deposit transfer\nto discard another player's winning tile" },
	{ "question": "振り返る", "answers": [ "ふりかえる" ], "comment": "to turn head; to look over one's shoulder; to turn around; to look back\nto think back (on); to reminisce; to look back (on); to reflect (on)" },
	{ "question": "振る", "answers": [ "ふる" ], "comment": "to wave; to shake; to swing\nto sprinkle; to throw (dice)\nto cast (actor); to allocate (work)\nto turn down (somebody); to reject; to jilt; to dump\nto abandon; to give up; to ruin\nto add kana indicating a reading of a word\nto slightly change headings; to change directions\nto extract by broiling; to prepare an infusion of; to decoct\nto carry with great vigor (e.g. a portable shrine)\nto bring up a topic; to lead to a topic\nto replace; to substitute\nto set up a joke for somebody else" },
	{ "question": "振る舞い", "answers": [ "ふるまい" ], "comment": "behavior; behaviour; conduct" },
	{ "question": "振る舞う", "answers": [ "ふるまう" ], "comment": "to behave; to conduct oneself\nto entertain; to treat someone (to a drink); to make tea for someone (tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "振動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "oscillation; vibration" },
	{ "question": "振替", "answers": [ "ふりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer; switching over; change\nmoney transfer (usu. between accounts held by the same person)\npostal transfer" },
	{ "question": "振興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "promotion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "挽肉", "answers": [ "ひきにく" ], "comment": "minced meat; ground meat" },
	{ "question": "挿入", "answers": [ "そうにゅう" ], "comment": "insertion; incorporation; infixing" },
	{ "question": "挿絵", "answers": [ "さしえ" ], "comment": "illustration (e.g. book); picture" },
	{ "question": "捕える", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to capture; to seize; to arrest; to grab; to catch hold of\nto grasp (e.g. meaning); to perceive; to capture (e.g. features)\nto captivate; to move (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "捕まえる", "answers": [ "つかまえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to arrest; to seize" },
	{ "question": "捕らえる", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to capture; to seize; to arrest; to grab; to catch hold of\nto grasp (e.g. meaning); to perceive; to capture (e.g. features)\nto captivate; to move (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "捕る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take; to catch; to capture" },
	{ "question": "捕手", "answers": [ "ほしゅ" ], "comment": "catcher" },
	{ "question": "捕獲", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "捕虜", "answers": [ "ほりょ" ], "comment": "prisoner (of war)" },
	{ "question": "捕鯨", "answers": [ "ほげい" ], "comment": "whaling; whale fishing" },
	{ "question": "捜し物", "answers": [ "さがしもの" ], "comment": "object being sought" },
	{ "question": "捜す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "捜査", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "search (esp. in criminal investigations); investigation; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "捜査官", "answers": [ "そうさかん" ], "comment": "police investigator; investigator" },
	{ "question": "捜索", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "search (esp. for someone or something missing); manhunt\nlegally authorized search of a person, building, etc." },
	{ "question": "捧げる", "answers": [ "ささげる" ], "comment": "to lift up; to hold up; to hold above eye level\nto give; to offer; to consecrate\nto devote; to sacrifice; to dedicate" },
	{ "question": "捨てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "to throw away; to cast away; to dump; to discard\nto abandon; to desert; to leave\nto give up; to resign" },
	{ "question": "捨て子", "answers": [ "すてご", "きじ" ], "comment": "abandoned child; foundling" },
	{ "question": "据える", "answers": [ "すえる" ], "comment": "to place (in position); to fix; to set (e.g. table); to lay (foundation)\nto install; to seat (someone)\nto settle (upon something); to fix (e.g. one's gaze)\nto apply (moxa)" },
	{ "question": "据え置き", "answers": [ "すえおき" ], "comment": "deferment (e.g. of savings); leaving (a thing) as it stands\nunredeemed; unredeemable; irredeemable; deferred; stationary" },
	{ "question": "捻挫", "answers": [ "ねんざ" ], "comment": "sprain" },
	{ "question": "掃く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to sweep; to brush; to gather up" },
	{ "question": "掃海", "answers": [ "そうかい" ], "comment": "sweeping the sea for mines; dragging for mines" },
	{ "question": "掃討", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "cleaning up; sweeping up; mopping up" },
	{ "question": "掃除", "answers": [ "そうじ" ], "comment": "cleaning; sweeping; dusting; scrubbing" },
	{ "question": "掃除機", "answers": [ "そうじき" ], "comment": "cleaner (usu. vacuum cleaner)" },
	{ "question": "授ける", "answers": [ "さずける" ], "comment": "to grant; to award; to teach" },
	{ "question": "授与", "answers": [ "じゅよ" ], "comment": "award; conferment" },
	{ "question": "授受", "answers": [ "じゅじゅ" ], "comment": "giving and receiving; transferring; transfer; changing hands" },
	{ "question": "授業", "answers": [ "じゅぎょう" ], "comment": "lesson; class work; teaching; instruction" },
	{ "question": "授業参観", "answers": [ "じゅぎょうさんかん" ], "comment": "parents' day (day when parents observe their children in school)" },
	{ "question": "授業料", "answers": [ "じゅぎょうりょう" ], "comment": "tuition fee; course fee" },
	{ "question": "授賞式", "answers": [ "じゅしょうしき" ], "comment": "award ceremony" },
	{ "question": "掌", "answers": [ "たなごころ", "てのひら" ], "comment": "palm (of one's hand)" },
	{ "question": "掌握", "answers": [ "しょうあく" ], "comment": "grasping; seizing; holding; commanding; having control over" },
	{ "question": "排他", "answers": [ "はいた" ], "comment": "exclusion" },
	{ "question": "排他主義", "answers": [ "はいたしゅぎ" ], "comment": "exclusion principle" },
	{ "question": "排出", "answers": [ "はいしゅつ" ], "comment": "evacuation; emission (e.g. of CO2, etc.); ejection" },
	{ "question": "排斥", "answers": [ "はいせき" ], "comment": "rejection; expulsion; boycott; ostracism" },
	{ "question": "排日", "answers": [ "はいにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "排気", "answers": [ "はいき" ], "comment": "exhaust; ventilation" },
	{ "question": "排気ガス", "answers": [ "はいきガス" ], "comment": "exhaust fumes" },
	{ "question": "排水", "answers": [ "はいすい" ], "comment": "drainage" },
	{ "question": "排除", "answers": [ "はいじょ" ], "comment": "exclusion; removal; rejection; elimination; abatement; lifting (sanctions, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "掘る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "to dig; to excavate; to hollow\nto delve into\nto dig up (e.g. vegetables)\n(for two men) to have anal sex" },
	{ "question": "掘削", "answers": [ "くっさく" ], "comment": "digging out; excavation" },
	{ "question": "掛け声", "answers": [ "かけごえ" ], "comment": "yell used to time or encourage activity (e.g. \"Heave ho!\", \"On three ... One, two, three!\" in English); enthusiastic shout from the audience (e.g. in kabuki); shouting (in concerts)" },
	{ "question": "掛け算", "answers": [ "かけざん" ], "comment": "multiplication" },
	{ "question": "掛け金", "answers": [ "かけきん" ], "comment": "installment; instalment; premium; bill" },
	{ "question": "掛軸", "answers": [ "かけじく" ], "comment": "hanging scroll" },
	{ "question": "掟", "answers": [ "おきて" ], "comment": "law; regulation; rule; code; agreement; arrangement; compact" },
	{ "question": "採る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to adopt (measure, proposal)\nto pick (e.g. fruit); to catch (e.g. insects); to take (e.g. a sample)\nto assume (attitude)\nto take on (i.e. hire); to engage" },
	{ "question": "採取", "answers": [ "さいしゅ" ], "comment": "picking; collecting; harvesting" },
	{ "question": "採択", "answers": [ "さいたく" ], "comment": "adoption; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "採掘", "answers": [ "さいくつ" ], "comment": "mining" },
	{ "question": "採決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "vote; roll call" },
	{ "question": "採点", "answers": [ "さいてん" ], "comment": "marking; grading; scoring" },
	{ "question": "採用", "answers": [ "さいよう" ], "comment": "use; adoption; acceptance\nappointment; employment; engagement; recruitment" },
	{ "question": "採算", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "profit" },
	{ "question": "採集", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "collecting; gathering" },
	{ "question": "探し回る", "answers": [ "さがしまわる" ], "comment": "to search about for; to hunt around for; to look high and low for; to look everywhere for" },
	{ "question": "探し物", "answers": [ "さがしもの" ], "comment": "object being sought" },
	{ "question": "探す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "探る", "answers": [ "さぐる" ], "comment": "to feel around for; to fumble for; to grope for; to search for; to look for\nto investigate; to probe into; to spy on; to sound out\nto explore (parts unknown); to enjoy (natural beauty)" },
	{ "question": "探偵", "answers": [ "たんてい" ], "comment": "detective; sleuth; investigator" },
	{ "question": "探査", "answers": [ "たんさ" ], "comment": "probe; inquiry; enquiry; investigation" },
	{ "question": "探検", "answers": [ "たんけん" ], "comment": "exploration; expedition" },
	{ "question": "探求", "answers": [ "たんきゅう" ], "comment": "search; quest; pursuit" },
	{ "question": "探究", "answers": [ "たんきゅう" ], "comment": "research; investigation; enquiry; inquiry; study" },
	{ "question": "探険", "answers": [ "たんけん" ], "comment": "exploration; expedition" },
	{ "question": "接する", "answers": [ "せっする" ], "comment": "to touch; to come in contact with; to border on; to adjoin; to be adjacent; to be close\nto receive (e.g. visitor); to attend to; to serve; to take care of; to look after; to deal with; to see\nto receive (news); to get; to hear\nto encounter; to come across\nto be tangent to\nto make touch; to bring into contact with; to bring adjacent to; to bring close; to connect" },
	{ "question": "接待", "answers": [ "せったい" ], "comment": "reception; welcome; serving (food)\nwining and dining; business entertainment; corporate entertainment; entertaining politicians" },
	{ "question": "接戦", "answers": [ "せっせん" ], "comment": "close combat; close contest" },
	{ "question": "接点", "answers": [ "せってん" ], "comment": "tangent point; point of contact\ncontact (electrical, etc.)\npoint of agreement; common ground; interaction" },
	{ "question": "接着", "answers": [ "せっちゃく" ], "comment": "adhesion; glueing; gluing; bonding; binding; adhering; fastening" },
	{ "question": "接種", "answers": [ "せっしゅ" ], "comment": "inoculation; vaccination" },
	{ "question": "接続", "answers": [ "せつぞく" ], "comment": "connection; attachment; union; join; joint; link\nchanging trains\nconjunction" },
	{ "question": "接見", "answers": [ "せっけん" ], "comment": "interview" },
	{ "question": "接触", "answers": [ "せっしょく" ], "comment": "touch; contact" },
	{ "question": "接近", "answers": [ "せっきん" ], "comment": "getting closer; drawing nearer; approaching\nbeing not much different; being near (age, skill, etc.)\nbecoming close (i.e. friendly); becoming intimate" },
	{ "question": "控え", "answers": [ "ひかえ" ], "comment": "reserve; spare; backup\nnote; memorandum\nduplicate; copy; stub (of a ticket, etc.)\nwaiting one's turn" },
	{ "question": "控えめ", "answers": [ "ひかえめ" ], "comment": "moderate; reserved; conservative; humble; mild-mannered; self-effacing; unassuming; well-behaved; low-key; temperate; in small quantities" },
	{ "question": "控える", "answers": [ "ひかえる" ], "comment": "to be temperate in; to refrain; to abstain; to hold back; to restrain oneself from excessive ...\nto make notes; to jot down (e.g. phone number)\nto be in preparation for; to be in waiting for\nto be soon; to be in the offing\nto be in a close relationship (e.g. as a backer, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "控え室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "控室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "控訴", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "koso appeal (initial appeal to a higher court)" },
	{ "question": "控除", "answers": [ "こうじょ" ], "comment": "subtraction; deduction (e.g. tax); subsidy" },
	{ "question": "推す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "to recommend; to endorse (e.g. a candidate); to nominate\nto infer; to conclude; to conjecture; to surmise\nto think something through; to ponder deeply" },
	{ "question": "推奨", "answers": [ "すいしょう" ], "comment": "recommendation; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "推奨環境", "answers": [ "すいしょうかんきょう" ], "comment": "system requirements (i.e. recommended hardware and software to run a package)" },
	{ "question": "推定", "answers": [ "すいてい" ], "comment": "presumption; assumption\nestimation" },
	{ "question": "推敲", "answers": [ "すいこう" ], "comment": "polishing (e.g. essay); revision; elaboration; refinement; improvement" },
	{ "question": "推測", "answers": [ "すいそく" ], "comment": "guess; conjecture" },
	{ "question": "推理", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "reasoning; inference; mystery or detective genre (movie, novel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "推理小説", "answers": [ "すいりしょうせつ" ], "comment": "mystery novel; detective novel; whodunit" },
	{ "question": "推移", "answers": [ "すいい" ], "comment": "transition; change" },
	{ "question": "推薦", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "recommendation; referral; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "推計", "answers": [ "すいけい" ], "comment": "estimate; estimation" },
	{ "question": "推進", "answers": [ "すいしん" ], "comment": "propulsion; drive\npromotion (e.g. of a government policy); furtherance; implementation" },
	{ "question": "推量", "answers": [ "すいりょう" ], "comment": "guess; conjecture; supposition; inference" },
	{ "question": "措置", "answers": [ "そち" ], "comment": "measure; step; action" },
	{ "question": "掲げる", "answers": [ "かかげる" ], "comment": "to publish; to print; to carry (an article)\nto put up; to hang out; to hoist; to fly (a sail); to float (a flag, kite, etc.)\nto tuck up (e.g. sleeves); to roll up\nto tout (a principle, plan, etc.); to adopt (a slogan)\nto stoke a fire; to fan a flame" },
	{ "question": "掲揚", "answers": [ "けいよう" ], "comment": "hoist (flag); fly; display" },
	{ "question": "掲示", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "notice; bulletin; post; posting; placard" },
	{ "question": "掲示板", "answers": [ "けいじばん" ], "comment": "bulletin board; display board; notice board\nelectronic bulletin board; BBS" },
	{ "question": "掲載", "answers": [ "けいさい" ], "comment": "publication (e.g. article in paper); appearance; insertion\nto insert (e.g. an article); to run (e.g. in a newspaper); to carry (e.g. an article); to post (e.g. on the Web)" },
	{ "question": "掻き回す", "answers": [ "かきまわす" ], "comment": "to stir up; to churn; to ransack; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "揃う", "answers": [ "そろう" ], "comment": "to become complete; to be all present; to be a full set; to have everything at one's disposal\nto be equal; to be uniform\nto gather; to assemble" },
	{ "question": "揃える", "answers": [ "そろえる" ], "comment": "to collect; to gather; to get together; to complete (a collection)\nto arrange; to put in order; to prepare; to get ready\nto make uniform; to make even; to match" },
	{ "question": "揉む", "answers": [ "もむ" ], "comment": "to rub; to crumple\nto massage\nto argue; to have a heated discussion\nto train; to coach\nto jostle; to crowd; to shake; to rock\nto have various experiences (out in the world)" },
	{ "question": "描く", "answers": [ "えがく", "かく" ], "comment": "to draw; to paint; to sketch\nto depict; to describe\nto picture in one's mind; to imagine\nto form a certain shape (e.g. path of an action, appearance of an object, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "描写", "answers": [ "びょうしゃ" ], "comment": "depiction; description; portrayal" },
	{ "question": "提供", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "offer; tender; program sponsoring; programme sponsoring; furnishing; provisioning; supply" },
	{ "question": "提供者", "answers": [ "ていきょうしゃ" ], "comment": "donor; contributer; provider" },
	{ "question": "提出", "answers": [ "ていしゅつ" ], "comment": "to present; to submit (e.g. a report or a thesis); to hand in; to file; to turn in\npresentation; submission; filing" },
	{ "question": "提唱", "answers": [ "ていしょう" ], "comment": "advocacy; proposal" },
	{ "question": "提携", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "cooperation; tie-up; joint business; link-up; sponsorship" },
	{ "question": "提案", "answers": [ "ていあん" ], "comment": "proposal; proposition; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "提示", "answers": [ "ていじ" ], "comment": "presentation; exhibit; suggest; citation" },
	{ "question": "提言", "answers": [ "ていげん" ], "comment": "proposal; motion; recommendation" },
	{ "question": "提訴", "answers": [ "ていそ" ], "comment": "presenting a case; suing" },
	{ "question": "提起", "answers": [ "ていき" ], "comment": "raising (a question); bringing up (a problem); instituting (a lawsuit); filing (a claim); submitting (a case)\nlifting up" },
	{ "question": "揚げ", "answers": [ "あげ" ], "comment": "frying; fried food\nfried tofu; fried bean curd" },
	{ "question": "換える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "換気", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "ventilation" },
	{ "question": "換気扇", "answers": [ "かんきせん" ], "comment": "ventilation fan" },
	{ "question": "換算", "answers": [ "かんさん", "かんざん" ], "comment": "conversion (e.g. yen to dollars); change; exchange; translation (numerical)" },
	{ "question": "換金", "answers": [ "かんきん" ], "comment": "realization (of goods into money); conversion (into money); liquidation" },
	{ "question": "握らす", "answers": [ "にぎらす" ], "comment": "to let (someone) take hold of your hand" },
	{ "question": "握り", "answers": [ "にぎり" ], "comment": "grasping; gripping; grasp; grip; clutch\nhandful; fistful\nhandle; grip; knob\nrice ball\nnigirizushi; hand-formed sushi with a topping of seafood, etc." },
	{ "question": "握り寿司", "answers": [ "にぎりずし" ], "comment": "nigirizushi; hand-formed sushi with a topping of seafood, etc." },
	{ "question": "握り締める", "answers": [ "にぎりしめる" ], "comment": "to grasp tightly" },
	{ "question": "握る", "answers": [ "にぎる" ], "comment": "to clasp; to grasp; to grip; to clutch\nto make (nigirizushi, rice ball, etc.); to form; to press into shape; to mold; to mould\nto seize (power, etc.); to take hold of" },
	{ "question": "握力", "answers": [ "あくりょく" ], "comment": "grip (of hand); grip strength" },
	{ "question": "握手", "answers": [ "あくしゅ" ], "comment": "handshake" },
	{ "question": "援助", "answers": [ "えんじょ" ], "comment": "assistance; aid; support" },
	{ "question": "援助交際", "answers": [ "えんじょこうさい" ], "comment": "dating with compensation (payments, financial support, etc.)\nschoolgirl prostitution" },
	{ "question": "援護", "answers": [ "えんご" ], "comment": "covering; protection; backing; relief" },
	{ "question": "揺さぶり", "answers": [ "ゆさぶり" ], "comment": "shaking; shaking up (one's adversary)" },
	{ "question": "揺さぶる", "answers": [ "ゆさぶる" ], "comment": "to shake; to jolt; to rock; to swing" },
	{ "question": "揺らぎ", "answers": [ "ゆらぎ" ], "comment": "tremor; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "揺らぐ", "answers": [ "ゆらぐ" ], "comment": "to swing; to sway; to shake; to tremble\nto waver; to feel shaken; to become unstable" },
	{ "question": "揺る", "answers": [ "ゆる" ], "comment": "to shake; to jolt; to rock (cradle); to swing" },
	{ "question": "揺るがす", "answers": [ "ゆるがす" ], "comment": "to shake; to swing; to sway; to shock" },
	{ "question": "揺れる", "answers": [ "ゆれる" ], "comment": "to shake; to sway; to waver" },
	{ "question": "損", "answers": [ "そん" ], "comment": "loss; damage; harm; unprofitable\ndisadvantage; handicap; drawback; unfavorable" },
	{ "question": "損う", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to spoil; to mar\nto fail to ...; to miss one's opportunity to ..." },
	{ "question": "損する", "answers": [ "そんする" ], "comment": "to lose (money, etc.)\nto have wasted one's (time, etc.); to have one's efforts come to naught" },
	{ "question": "損なう", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to spoil; to mar\nto fail to ...; to miss one's opportunity to ..." },
	{ "question": "損ねる", "answers": [ "そこねる" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to wreck\nto miss one's chance to (do something); to fail to (do what one ought to have done)" },
	{ "question": "損傷", "answers": [ "そんしょう" ], "comment": "damage; injury" },
	{ "question": "損壊", "answers": [ "そんかい" ], "comment": "damage; destruction" },
	{ "question": "損失", "answers": [ "そんしつ" ], "comment": "loss (e.g. assets or profits)" },
	{ "question": "損害", "answers": [ "そんがい" ], "comment": "damage; injury; loss" },
	{ "question": "損害保険", "answers": [ "そんがいほけん" ], "comment": "damage insurance" },
	{ "question": "損得", "answers": [ "そんとく" ], "comment": "loss and gain; advantage and disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "損益", "answers": [ "そんえき" ], "comment": "profit and loss; advantage and disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "搬入", "answers": [ "はんにゅう" ], "comment": "taking in; bringing in (esp. heavy objects, artwork, furniture); carrying in" },
	{ "question": "搬送", "answers": [ "はんそう" ], "comment": "transportation; conveyance; delivery\nhospitalization; transfer to hospital" },
	{ "question": "搭乗", "answers": [ "とうじょう" ], "comment": "embarkation; boarding (an aeroplane, airplane)" },
	{ "question": "搭載", "answers": [ "とうさい" ], "comment": "loading (on board); equipping\nequipped (with); built-in" },
	{ "question": "携える", "answers": [ "たずさえる" ], "comment": "to carry in one's hand" },
	{ "question": "携わる", "answers": [ "たずさわる" ], "comment": "to engage in; to participate; to take part" },
	{ "question": "携帯ストラップ", "answers": [ "けいたいストラップ" ], "comment": "straps for mobile phone" },
	{ "question": "搾る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "to wring (towel, rag); to squeeze\nto squeeze (fruit to extract juice); to press; to extract; to milk; to express milk\nto rack (one's brains); to strain (one's voice)\nto extort; to exploit\nto chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke\nto drill into; to train\nto narrow down (one's focus); to whittle down\nto gather up (curtain, etc.); to tighten (drawstring)\nto stop down (lens)\nto turn down (e.g. radio)\nto bend (bow); to draw\nto hold down; to constrict; to immobilize" },
	{ "question": "搾取", "answers": [ "さくしゅ" ], "comment": "exploitation; squeezing; sweating" },
	{ "question": "摂取", "answers": [ "せっしゅ" ], "comment": "intake; absorption; adoption\nassimilation" },
	{ "question": "摂氏", "answers": [ "せっし" ], "comment": "Centigrade; Celsius" },
	{ "question": "摘む", "answers": [ "つむ" ], "comment": "to pluck; to pick; to trim" },
	{ "question": "摘出", "answers": [ "てきしゅつ" ], "comment": "picking out; taking out; (surgical) removal\nexposure" },
	{ "question": "摘発", "answers": [ "てきはつ" ], "comment": "exposing; unmasking; laying bare" },
	{ "question": "摩擦", "answers": [ "まさつ" ], "comment": "friction; rubbing; rubdown; chafe" },
	{ "question": "撃ち止める", "answers": [ "うちとめる" ], "comment": "to hammer into place\nto end (a performance)\nto kill; to slay; to shoot dead; to cut down" },
	{ "question": "撃つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "to shoot (at)\nto attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge" },
	{ "question": "撃墜", "answers": [ "げきつい" ], "comment": "shooting down (aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "撒く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to scatter; to sprinkle; to strew\nto distribute (handbills, etc.); to spread (rumours, etc.)\nto give the slip; to throw off; to shake off; to lose" },
	{ "question": "撤去", "answers": [ "てっきょ" ], "comment": "withdrawal; revocation; repeal\ndemolition; removal" },
	{ "question": "撤収", "answers": [ "てっしゅう" ], "comment": "removal (e.g. of a building); dismantling (e.g. a tent); striking (e.g. a stage set)\nwithdrawal (of troops); evacuation; retreating" },
	{ "question": "撤回", "answers": [ "てっかい" ], "comment": "withdrawal; retraction; revocation; repeal" },
	{ "question": "撤廃", "answers": [ "てっぱい" ], "comment": "annulment; abolition; repeal; rescission" },
	{ "question": "撤退", "answers": [ "てったい" ], "comment": "evacuation; withdrawal; revocation; repeal; retreat" },
	{ "question": "撫でる", "answers": [ "なでる" ], "comment": "to brush gently; to stroke; to caress" },
	{ "question": "撮る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take (a photo)\nto record (video, audio, etc.); to make (a film)" },
	{ "question": "撮影", "answers": [ "さつえい" ], "comment": "photography (still or motion); photographing; filming; shooting; (video) recording" },
	{ "question": "撲滅", "answers": [ "ぼくめつ" ], "comment": "eradication; extermination; destruction; suppression" },
	{ "question": "擁する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "to have; to possess" },
	{ "question": "擁立", "answers": [ "ようりつ" ], "comment": "backing (for a position); support" },
	{ "question": "擁護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "protection; advocacy; support; defence; championship; vindication\nto protect (e.g. rights, etc.); to advocate (e.g. free trade, etc.); to support" },
	{ "question": "操", "answers": [ "みさお" ], "comment": "chastity; fidelity; honour; honor; faith" },
	{ "question": "操る", "answers": [ "あやつる" ], "comment": "to manipulate; to operate; to handle; to operate (e.g. a machine); to steer (a ship)\nto have a good command of (a language); to be fluent in\nto operate a puppet; to pull the strings of a puppet\nto mastermind; to pull the strings; to control from the shadows\nto play (a musical instrument)" },
	{ "question": "操作", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "operation; management; handling\nmanipulating to one's benefit" },
	{ "question": "操業", "answers": [ "そうぎょう" ], "comment": "operation" },
	{ "question": "操縦", "answers": [ "そうじゅう" ], "comment": "steering; piloting; flying; control; operation; handling\nmanagement; handling; control; manipulation" },
	{ "question": "擦る", "answers": [ "する" ], "comment": "to rub; to chafe; to strike (match); to file; to frost (glass)\nto lose (e.g. a match); to forfeit; to squander one's money (e.g. through gambling, Pachinko, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "擬装", "answers": [ "ぎそう" ], "comment": "camouflage; disguise\npretense; feigning; masquerade" },
	{ "question": "支える", "answers": [ "ささえる" ], "comment": "to support; to prop; to sustain; to underlay; to hold up\nto hold at bay; to stem; to check" },
	{ "question": "支出", "answers": [ "ししゅつ" ], "comment": "expenditure; expenses" },
	{ "question": "支局", "answers": [ "しきょく" ], "comment": "branch office" },
	{ "question": "支店", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "branch office; branch store" },
	{ "question": "支店長", "answers": [ "してんちょう" ], "comment": "branch manager; manager of a branch office" },
	{ "question": "支度", "answers": [ "したく" ], "comment": "preparation; arrangements" },
	{ "question": "支所", "answers": [ "ししょ" ], "comment": "branch (office)" },
	{ "question": "支払い", "answers": [ "しはらい" ], "comment": "payment" },
	{ "question": "支払う", "answers": [ "しはらう" ], "comment": "to pay" },
	{ "question": "支持", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "support; holding up; propping\nsupport; backing; endorsing" },
	{ "question": "支援", "answers": [ "しえん" ], "comment": "support; backing; aid; assistance" },
	{ "question": "支柱", "answers": [ "しちゅう" ], "comment": "prop; stay; support; brace; fulcrum" },
	{ "question": "支流", "answers": [ "しりゅう" ], "comment": "tributary; branch" },
	{ "question": "支社", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "branch office" },
	{ "question": "支給", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "provision; supply; payment; allowance; grant" },
	{ "question": "支部", "answers": [ "しぶ" ], "comment": "branch; subdivision" },
	{ "question": "支配", "answers": [ "しはい" ], "comment": "domination; rule; control; direction; guidance" },
	{ "question": "支配人", "answers": [ "しはいにん" ], "comment": "manager; executive" },
	{ "question": "支配的", "answers": [ "しはいてき" ], "comment": "dominant; ruling" },
	{ "question": "支障", "answers": [ "ししょう" ], "comment": "obstacle; hindrance; impediment; difficulty" },
	{ "question": "改ざん", "answers": [ "かいざん" ], "comment": "alteration; falsification; faking" },
	{ "question": "改まる", "answers": [ "あらたまる" ], "comment": "to be renewed\nto stand on ceremony; to be formal\nto take a turn for the worse" },
	{ "question": "改めて", "answers": [ "あらためて" ], "comment": "another time; again; over again; once again; anew\nformally; especially; intentionally; deliberately" },
	{ "question": "改める", "answers": [ "あらためる" ], "comment": "to change; to alter; to revise; to replace\nto reform; to correct; to mend; to improve\nto examine; to check; to inspect\nto do properly; to do formally" },
	{ "question": "改修", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "repair; improvement" },
	{ "question": "改定", "answers": [ "かいてい", "かいじょう" ], "comment": "revision (of a rule, price, etc.); reform; alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "改憲", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "constitutional change" },
	{ "question": "改新", "answers": [ "かいしん" ], "comment": "reformation" },
	{ "question": "改札", "answers": [ "かいさつ" ], "comment": "examination of tickets\nticket gate; ticket barrier" },
	{ "question": "改札口", "answers": [ "かいさつぐち" ], "comment": "ticket barrier (gate); wicket" },
	{ "question": "改正", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "revision; amendment; alteration" },
	{ "question": "改築", "answers": [ "かいちく" ], "comment": "structural alteration of building; reconstruction" },
	{ "question": "改組", "answers": [ "かいそ" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改編", "answers": [ "かいへん" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改良", "answers": [ "かいりょう" ], "comment": "improvement; reform" },
	{ "question": "改装", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "remodelling; remodeling; reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改訂", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "revision (of text); alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "改造", "answers": [ "かいぞう" ], "comment": "remodeling; remodelling; restructuring; reconstruction; reshuffling (e.g. cabinet)\nmodding" },
	{ "question": "改選", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "re-election" },
	{ "question": "改革", "answers": [ "かいかく" ], "comment": "reform; reformation; innovation" },
	{ "question": "攻める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "to attack; to assault; to assail" },
	{ "question": "攻勢", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "offensive (movement); aggression" },
	{ "question": "攻守", "answers": [ "こうしゅ" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence; batting and fielding" },
	{ "question": "攻撃", "answers": [ "こうげき" ], "comment": "attack; strike; offensive\ncriticism; censure; denunciation; condemnation" },
	{ "question": "攻略", "answers": [ "こうりゃく" ], "comment": "capture\nstrategy guide; playing guide (e.g. for game); book of hints" },
	{ "question": "攻防", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence" },
	{ "question": "放す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to release; to let go; to free; to set free; to let loose; to turn loose\nto add (pieces of eggplant, potato, etc.) to water, broth, etc." },
	{ "question": "放つ", "answers": [ "はなつ" ], "comment": "to fire (gun, arrow, questions, etc.); to shoot; to hit (e.g. baseball); to break wind\nto set free; to release; to let loose\nto emit (e.g. light); to give off (e.g. a scent)\nto send out (a person to carry out a duty)\nto set fire to" },
	{ "question": "放る", "answers": [ "ほる", "ほうる" ], "comment": "to throw; to toss; to fling\nto throw away; to discard\nto neglect; to abandon; to leave alone; to give up on; to leave undone; to leave unfinished" },
	{ "question": "放れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "to get free; to be freed; to be released" },
	{ "question": "放任", "answers": [ "ほうにん" ], "comment": "noninterference; leaving something to take its own course; giving someone a free hand with something" },
	{ "question": "放出", "answers": [ "ほうしゅつ" ], "comment": "release; emission; ejection" },
	{ "question": "放射", "answers": [ "ほうしゃ" ], "comment": "radiation; emission" },
	{ "question": "放射性", "answers": [ "ほうしゃせい" ], "comment": "radioactive" },
	{ "question": "放射線", "answers": [ "ほうしゃせん" ], "comment": "radiation" },
	{ "question": "放射能", "answers": [ "ほうしゃのう" ], "comment": "radioactivity" },
	{ "question": "放映", "answers": [ "ほうえい" ], "comment": "televising" },
	{ "question": "放棄", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "abandonment; renunciation; resignation; abdication (responsibility, right)" },
	{ "question": "放水", "answers": [ "ほうすい" ], "comment": "hosing down; drainage; discharge of water; spraying with water" },
	{ "question": "放流", "answers": [ "ほうりゅう" ], "comment": "discharge (e.g. of water from a dam)\nliberation; stocking (e.g. a river with fish)" },
	{ "question": "放浪", "answers": [ "ほうろう" ], "comment": "wandering" },
	{ "question": "放火", "answers": [ "ほうか" ], "comment": "arson; setting fire" },
	{ "question": "放置", "answers": [ "ほうち" ], "comment": "leaving as is; leaving alone; leaving to chance; neglecting; abandoning" },
	{ "question": "放課後", "answers": [ "ほうかご" ], "comment": "after school" },
	{ "question": "放送", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "broadcast; broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "放題", "answers": [ "ほうだい" ], "comment": "as much as you would like to; as much as one likes" },
	{ "question": "政", "answers": [ "まつりごと", "せい" ], "comment": "rule; government" },
	{ "question": "政争", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "political strife" },
	{ "question": "政令", "answers": [ "せいれい" ], "comment": "government ordinance; cabinet order" },
	{ "question": "政党", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "political party" },
	{ "question": "政党政治", "answers": [ "せいとうせいじ" ], "comment": "party politics" },
	{ "question": "政務", "answers": [ "せいむ" ], "comment": "government affairs" },
	{ "question": "政務次官", "answers": [ "せいむじかん" ], "comment": "deputy minister; assistant minister" },
	{ "question": "政変", "answers": [ "せいへん" ], "comment": "political disturbance; political change; coup d'état; coup; revolution; overthrowing of a government (e.g. Jasmine Revolution)" },
	{ "question": "政局", "answers": [ "せいきょく" ], "comment": "political situation" },
	{ "question": "政庁", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "government office" },
	{ "question": "政府", "answers": [ "せいふ" ], "comment": "government; administration" },
	{ "question": "政情", "answers": [ "せいじょう" ], "comment": "political situation; political affairs" },
	{ "question": "政教", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "religion and politics; church and state" },
	{ "question": "政敵", "answers": [ "せいてき" ], "comment": "political opponent" },
	{ "question": "政権", "answers": [ "せいけん" ], "comment": "(political) administration; political power" },
	{ "question": "政治", "answers": [ "せいじ" ], "comment": "politics; government" },
	{ "question": "政治力", "answers": [ "せいじりょく" ], "comment": "political strength" },
	{ "question": "政治家", "answers": [ "せいじか" ], "comment": "politician; statesman" },
	{ "question": "政治犯", "answers": [ "せいじはん" ], "comment": "political offense; political offence; political crime\npolitical offender; political prisoner; prisoner of conscience" },
	{ "question": "政治的", "answers": [ "せいじてき" ], "comment": "political" },
	{ "question": "政界", "answers": [ "せいかい" ], "comment": "political world" },
	{ "question": "政策", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "political measures; policy" },
	{ "question": "政経", "answers": [ "せいけい" ], "comment": "politics and economics" },
	{ "question": "政見", "answers": [ "せいけん" ], "comment": "political views" },
	{ "question": "故事", "answers": [ "こじ" ], "comment": "historical event; ancient event\ntradition; folklore; legend; origin" },
	{ "question": "故人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "the deceased; the departed" },
	{ "question": "故国", "answers": [ "ここく" ], "comment": "one's native land" },
	{ "question": "故意", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "intention; purpose; bad faith\nmens rea (guilty mind)" },
	{ "question": "故障", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "breakdown; failure; fault; accident; out of order\ndamage; hurt\nobjection; protest" },
	{ "question": "敏感", "answers": [ "びんかん" ], "comment": "sensitive; alert; aware; susceptible" },
	{ "question": "救い", "answers": [ "すくい" ], "comment": "help; aid; relief; (religious) salvation; (Christian) grace; providence" },
	{ "question": "救う", "answers": [ "すくう" ], "comment": "to rescue from; to help out of; to save" },
	{ "question": "救世主", "answers": [ "きゅうせいしゅ" ], "comment": "saviour; messiah" },
	{ "question": "救出", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅつ" ], "comment": "rescue; extricate; reclaim; deliverance" },
	{ "question": "救助", "answers": [ "きゅうじょ" ], "comment": "relief; aid; rescue" },
	{ "question": "救命", "answers": [ "きゅうめい" ], "comment": "lifesaving" },
	{ "question": "救国", "answers": [ "きゅうこく" ], "comment": "patriot devoted to the salvation of his country" },
	{ "question": "救急", "answers": [ "きゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "first-aid; emergency (aid)" },
	{ "question": "救急医療", "answers": [ "きゅうきゅういりょう" ], "comment": "emergency medicine" },
	{ "question": "救急箱", "answers": [ "きゅうきゅうばこ" ], "comment": "first-aid kit" },
	{ "question": "救急車", "answers": [ "きゅうきゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "ambulance" },
	{ "question": "救援", "answers": [ "きゅうえん" ], "comment": "relief; rescue; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "救済", "answers": [ "きゅうさい" ], "comment": "relief; aid; rescue; salvation; help" },
	{ "question": "敗れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "to be defeated; to be beaten; to be unsuccessful; to lose" },
	{ "question": "敗北", "answers": [ "はいぼく" ], "comment": "defeat\nto be defeated" },
	{ "question": "敗因", "answers": [ "はいいん" ], "comment": "cause of defeat" },
	{ "question": "敗戦", "answers": [ "はいせん" ], "comment": "defeat; losing a war" },
	{ "question": "敗者", "answers": [ "はいしゃ" ], "comment": "the defeated; vanquished; loser" },
	{ "question": "敗訴", "answers": [ "はいそ" ], "comment": "loss of a court-case" },
	{ "question": "敗退", "answers": [ "はいたい" ], "comment": "being defeated; being eliminated (from competition)" },
	{ "question": "教え", "answers": [ "おしえ" ], "comment": "teaching; instruction; teachings; precept; lesson; doctrine" },
	{ "question": "教える", "answers": [ "おしえる" ], "comment": "to teach; to instruct\nto tell; to inform\nto preach" },
	{ "question": "教え子", "answers": [ "おしえご" ], "comment": "student; disciple" },
	{ "question": "教わる", "answers": [ "おそわる" ], "comment": "to be taught (by); to learn from" },
	{ "question": "教会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "church" },
	{ "question": "教務", "answers": [ "きょうむ" ], "comment": "school affairs; religious affairs" },
	{ "question": "教員", "answers": [ "きょういん" ], "comment": "teacher; instructor; teaching staff; faculty member" },
	{ "question": "教団", "answers": [ "きょうだん" ], "comment": "religious organization; religious organisation" },
	{ "question": "教壇", "answers": [ "きょうだん" ], "comment": "(teacher's) platform; podium; dais" },
	{ "question": "教官", "answers": [ "きょうかん" ], "comment": "teacher; instructor; professor" },
	{ "question": "教室", "answers": [ "きょうしつ" ], "comment": "classroom\ndepartment; laboratory\nsingle-room school; small school" },
	{ "question": "教師", "answers": [ "きょうし" ], "comment": "teacher (classroom)" },
	{ "question": "教徒", "answers": [ "きょうと" ], "comment": "believer; adherent" },
	{ "question": "教授", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "professor\nteaching; instruction" },
	{ "question": "教書", "answers": [ "きょうしょ" ], "comment": "(presidential) message" },
	{ "question": "教材", "answers": [ "きょうざい" ], "comment": "teaching materials" },
	{ "question": "教祖", "answers": [ "きょうそ" ], "comment": "founder of a religious sect" },
	{ "question": "教科", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "subject; curriculum" },
	{ "question": "教科書", "answers": [ "きょうかしょ" ], "comment": "textbook; coursebook; schoolbook" },
	{ "question": "教習", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "training; instruction" },
	{ "question": "教職員", "answers": [ "きょうしょくいん" ], "comment": "teaching staff; faculty" },
	{ "question": "教育", "answers": [ "きょういく" ], "comment": "training; education" },
	{ "question": "教育委員会", "answers": [ "きょういくいいんかい" ], "comment": "Board of Education" },
	{ "question": "教育的", "answers": [ "きょういくてき" ], "comment": "educational; instructive" },
	{ "question": "教育者", "answers": [ "きょういくしゃ" ], "comment": "educator; teacher; educationalist" },
	{ "question": "教訓", "answers": [ "きょうくん" ], "comment": "lesson; precept; teachings; moral" },
	{ "question": "教諭", "answers": [ "きょうゆ" ], "comment": "(licensed) teacher" },
	{ "question": "教頭", "answers": [ "きょうとう" ], "comment": "deputy head teacher; vice principal" },
	{ "question": "教養", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "cultivation; refinement; culture; education" },
	{ "question": "敢行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "decisive action" },
	{ "question": "敢闘", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "fighting bravely" },
	{ "question": "散々", "answers": [ "さんざん" ], "comment": "thoroughly; completely; utterly\nseverely; harshly; terribly; miserably; wretchedly; badly\nscattered; disconnected; dispersed; smashed into tiny pieces" },
	{ "question": "散らかす", "answers": [ "ちらかす" ], "comment": "to scatter around; to leave untidy" },
	{ "question": "散らかる", "answers": [ "ちらかる" ], "comment": "to be in disorder; to lie scattered around" },
	{ "question": "散らす", "answers": [ "ちらす" ], "comment": "to scatter; to cause a shower of\nto disperse; to distribute; to spread\nto resolve (a symptom, condition, etc.); to relieve; to get rid of; to cure\nto distract; to divert\nto do ... wildly (i.e. disorderly or frequently); to do ... all over the place" },
	{ "question": "散らばる", "answers": [ "ちらばる" ], "comment": "to be scattered about" },
	{ "question": "散る", "answers": [ "ちる" ], "comment": "to fall (e.g. blossoms, leaves)\nto scatter; to be dispersed\nto disappear; to dissolve; to break up\nto spread; to run; to blur\nto die a noble death" },
	{ "question": "散会", "answers": [ "さんかい" ], "comment": "adjournment" },
	{ "question": "散布", "answers": [ "さんぷ", "さっぷ" ], "comment": "dissemination; scattering; sprinkling; spraying" },
	{ "question": "散歩", "answers": [ "さんぽ" ], "comment": "walk; stroll" },
	{ "question": "散発", "answers": [ "さんぱつ" ], "comment": "sporadic; scattering" },
	{ "question": "散策", "answers": [ "さんさく" ], "comment": "walking; strolling; roaming; wandering; exploring" },
	{ "question": "散骨", "answers": [ "さんこつ" ], "comment": "scattering of ashes (cremated remains)" },
	{ "question": "散髪", "answers": [ "さんぱつ" ], "comment": "(having a) haircut; hair-cutting; hair-dressing" },
	{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "to show respect; to honour; to honor" },
	{ "question": "敬具", "answers": [ "けいぐ" ], "comment": "Yours sincerely; Yours truly; Sincerely yours" },
	{ "question": "敬意", "answers": [ "けいい" ], "comment": "respect; honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "敬称", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "title of honour; title of honor" },
	{ "question": "敬老", "answers": [ "けいろう" ], "comment": "respect for the aged" },
	{ "question": "敬語", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "honorific; term of respect; polite expression; honorific language" },
	{ "question": "敬遠", "answers": [ "けいえん" ], "comment": "pretending to respect someone while in fact staying distant; keeping at arms length; giving a wide berth\navoiding (something unpleasant); shying away from\ngiving the batter an \"intentional walk\"" },
	{ "question": "数", "answers": [ "かず", "すう" ], "comment": "number; amount /\n several; a number of\nquantity; amount\ncounting; figures; numbers\nnumber; numeral; figure\ngrammatical number\ndestiny; fate; course of events; trend" },
	{ "question": "数々", "answers": [ "かずかず" ], "comment": "many; numerous; various; large number of" },
	{ "question": "数える", "answers": [ "かぞえる" ], "comment": "to count; to enumerate" },
	{ "question": "数万", "answers": [ "すうまん" ], "comment": "tens of thousands" },
	{ "question": "数個", "answers": [ "すうこ" ], "comment": "several (objects, usu. from two to six)" },
	{ "question": "数値", "answers": [ "すうち" ], "comment": "numerical value; numerics\nreading (on a meter, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "数億年", "answers": [ "すうおくねん" ], "comment": "several hundred million years" },
	{ "question": "数多く", "answers": [ "かずおおく" ], "comment": "in great numbers" },
	{ "question": "数字", "answers": [ "すうじ" ], "comment": "numeral; figure; digit; numeric character" },
	{ "question": "数学", "answers": [ "すうがく" ], "comment": "mathematics; arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "数日", "answers": [ "すうじつ" ], "comment": "few days" },
	{ "question": "数時間", "answers": [ "すうじかん" ], "comment": "a few hours" },
	{ "question": "数次", "answers": [ "すうじ" ], "comment": "number of times" },
	{ "question": "数百", "answers": [ "すうひゃく" ], "comment": "several hundreds" },
	{ "question": "数量", "answers": [ "すうりょう" ], "comment": "quantity; volume" },
	{ "question": "整う", "answers": [ "ととのう" ], "comment": "to be ready; to be prepared; to be arranged\nto be in order; to be put in order; to be well-ordered; to be well-proportioned; to be harmonious\nto be adjusted; to be regulated; to be refined (e.g. of a face)\nto be settled (e.g. treaty, contract); to be completed" },
	{ "question": "整える", "answers": [ "ととのえる" ], "comment": "to put in order; to arrange; to adjust\nto get ready; to prepare\nto raise money" },
	{ "question": "整った", "answers": [ "ととのった" ], "comment": "well-ordered; in good order; well-featured; well-regulated" },
	{ "question": "整備", "answers": [ "せいび" ], "comment": "maintenance; servicing\nputting in place; establishment; development; preparation; provision; outfitting" },
	{ "question": "整列", "answers": [ "せいれつ" ], "comment": "standing in a row; forming a line; alignment" },
	{ "question": "整合", "answers": [ "せいごう" ], "comment": "adjustment; coordination; integration; conformity" },
	{ "question": "整形外科", "answers": [ "せいけいげか" ], "comment": "orthopaedic surgery; plastic surgery" },
	{ "question": "整数", "answers": [ "せいすう" ], "comment": "integer" },
	{ "question": "整理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "sorting; arrangement; organization; putting in order; adjustment; regulation\nliquidation; settlement; consolidation; clearance (e.g. debt); paying off\nretrenchment; curtailment; cutting down; disposal" },
	{ "question": "整頓", "answers": [ "せいとん" ], "comment": "orderliness; put in order; tidying up; arranging neatly" },
	{ "question": "敵", "answers": [ "てき" ], "comment": "opponent; rival; adversary\nmenace; danger; threat; enemy" },
	{ "question": "敵国", "answers": [ "てきこく", "てっこく" ], "comment": "enemy nation" },
	{ "question": "敵失", "answers": [ "てきしつ" ], "comment": "error made by the enemy or opposing team" },
	{ "question": "敵対", "answers": [ "てきたい" ], "comment": "hostility; antagonism; opposition" },
	{ "question": "敵意", "answers": [ "てきい" ], "comment": "hostility; animosity; enmity" },
	{ "question": "敷き布団", "answers": [ "しきぶとん" ], "comment": "(Japanese) mattress; underquilt; futon laid on the floor; sleeping mat" },
	{ "question": "敷く", "answers": [ "しく" ], "comment": "to spread out; to lay out\nto take a position\nto impose widely (e.g. over a city)" },
	{ "question": "敷地", "answers": [ "しきち" ], "comment": "site; plot; lot; grounds" },
	{ "question": "敷居", "answers": [ "しき", "しきみ", "しきい" ], "comment": "threshold (esp. one with grooves for sliding doors); sill" },
	{ "question": "敷布団", "answers": [ "しきぶとん" ], "comment": "(Japanese) mattress; underquilt; futon laid on the floor; sleeping mat" },
	{ "question": "敷設", "answers": [ "ふせつ" ], "comment": "laying (a railroad, pipes, naval mines, etc.); construction" },
	{ "question": "敷金", "answers": [ "しききん" ], "comment": "(security) deposit; caution money" },
	{ "question": "文", "answers": [ "ふみ", "ぶん" ], "comment": "letter; writings /\n sentence\ncomposition; text; writings\nthe literary arts (as opposed to the military arts); academia; literature" },
	{ "question": "文中", "answers": [ "ぶんちゅう" ], "comment": "in the document\nBunchuu era (of the Southern Court) (1372.4.?-1375.5.27)" },
	{ "question": "文体", "answers": [ "ぶんたい" ], "comment": "literary style" },
	{ "question": "文具", "answers": [ "ぶんぐ" ], "comment": "stationery" },
	{ "question": "文化", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "culture; civilization; civilisation\nBunka era (1804.2.11-1818.4.22)" },
	{ "question": "文化人", "answers": [ "ぶんかじん" ], "comment": "person of culture; cultured person" },
	{ "question": "文化勲章", "answers": [ "ぶんかくんしょう" ], "comment": "Order of Culture; Order of Cultural Merit" },
	{ "question": "文化庁", "answers": [ "ぶんかちょう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) Agency for Cultural Affairs" },
	{ "question": "文化的", "answers": [ "ぶんかてき" ], "comment": "cultural" },
	{ "question": "文化財", "answers": [ "ぶんかざい" ], "comment": "cultural assets; cultural property" },
	{ "question": "文化遺産", "answers": [ "ぶんかいさん" ], "comment": "cultural heritage" },
	{ "question": "文句", "answers": [ "もんく" ], "comment": "complaint; grumbling; objection\nphrase; words; expression" },
	{ "question": "文句なし", "answers": [ "もんくなし" ], "comment": "undisputed; entirely; perfect" },
	{ "question": "文壇", "answers": [ "ぶんだん" ], "comment": "literary world; literary circles" },
	{ "question": "文字", "answers": [ "もじ" ], "comment": "letter (of alphabet); character\nliteral" },
	{ "question": "文字通り", "answers": [ "もじどおり" ], "comment": "literal\nliterally" },
	{ "question": "文学", "answers": [ "ぶんがく" ], "comment": "literature" },
	{ "question": "文学者", "answers": [ "ぶんがくしゃ" ], "comment": "scholar of literature; literary person; man of letters\nwriter" },
	{ "question": "文庫", "answers": [ "ぶんこ" ], "comment": "library; book collection\npaperback book" },
	{ "question": "文房具", "answers": [ "ぶんぼうぐ" ], "comment": "stationery" },
	{ "question": "文教", "answers": [ "ぶんきょう" ], "comment": "education; culture" },
	{ "question": "文明", "answers": [ "ぶんめい" ], "comment": "civilization; civilisation; culture\nBummei era (1469.4.28-1487.7.20)" },
	{ "question": "文書", "answers": [ "もんじょ", "ぶんしょ" ], "comment": "document; writing; letter; paperwork; note; records; archives\ndocument addressed to someone in particular (jargon used in paleography)" },
	{ "question": "文楽", "answers": [ "ぶんらく" ], "comment": "Japanese puppet theatre (theater); bunraku" },
	{ "question": "文様", "answers": [ "もんよう" ], "comment": "pattern; design" },
	{ "question": "文民", "answers": [ "ぶんみん" ], "comment": "civilian" },
	{ "question": "文法", "answers": [ "ぶんぽう" ], "comment": "grammar; syntax" },
	{ "question": "文献", "answers": [ "ぶんけん" ], "comment": "literature; books (reference); document" },
	{ "question": "文相", "answers": [ "ぶんしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Education, Science and Culture" },
	{ "question": "文科", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "literary course\nthe arts" },
	{ "question": "文章", "answers": [ "ぶんしょう" ], "comment": "sentence; article; composition\n(writing) style" },
	{ "question": "文系", "answers": [ "ぶんけい" ], "comment": "humanities, social sciences, and fine arts; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "文脈", "answers": [ "ぶんみゃく" ], "comment": "context" },
	{ "question": "文芸", "answers": [ "ぶんげい" ], "comment": "literature; art and literature; belles-lettres" },
	{ "question": "文語", "answers": [ "ぶんご" ], "comment": "written language; literary language\nformal (or archaic) written style based on Heian-period Japanese" },
	{ "question": "文通", "answers": [ "ぶんつう" ], "comment": "correspondence; exchange of letters" },
	{ "question": "文部", "answers": [ "もんぶ" ], "comment": "Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology" },
	{ "question": "文部省", "answers": [ "もんぶしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology" },
	{ "question": "文面", "answers": [ "ぶんめん" ], "comment": "content of a letter" },
	{ "question": "斉唱", "answers": [ "せいしょう" ], "comment": "singing or chanting in unison" },
	{ "question": "斎場", "answers": [ "さいじょう" ], "comment": "funeral hall\nceremony site" },
	{ "question": "斗", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "to (measure of volume, approx. 18 litres)\nsquare bearing block (at the top of a pillar)\nChinese \"Dipper\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "料", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "fee; charge; rate\nmaterial" },
	{ "question": "料亭", "answers": [ "りょうてい" ], "comment": "ryotei; traditional Japanese restaurant (esp. a luxurious one)" },
	{ "question": "料理", "answers": [ "りょうり" ], "comment": "cooking; cookery; cuisine\ndealing with something; handling; administration; management" },
	{ "question": "料理屋", "answers": [ "りょうりや" ], "comment": "restaurant" },
	{ "question": "料金", "answers": [ "りょうきん" ], "comment": "fee; charge; fare" },
	{ "question": "斜め", "answers": [ "ななめ" ], "comment": "slanting; tilted; sloping; diagonal; oblique\nunusual; slanted (view of the world); bad (mood)" },
	{ "question": "斜体", "answers": [ "しゃたい" ], "comment": "oblique type; slanted type\ndivision ring; skew field" },
	{ "question": "斜面", "answers": [ "しゃめん" ], "comment": "slope; slanting surface; bevel" },
	{ "question": "斡旋", "answers": [ "あっせん" ], "comment": "kind offices; services; through the good offices of; influence\nintercession; mediation" },
	{ "question": "斤量", "answers": [ "きんりょう" ], "comment": "weight" },
	{ "question": "断", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "decision; judgment; resolution" },
	{ "question": "断じて", "answers": [ "だんじて" ], "comment": "absolutely; positively; decidedly" },
	{ "question": "断つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to sever; to cut off\nto suppress; to eradicate; to exterminate\nto abstain (from); to give up" },
	{ "question": "断らず", "answers": [ "ことわらず" ], "comment": "without permission" },
	{ "question": "断り", "answers": [ "ことわり" ], "comment": "notice; notification; warning\npermission; consent\nrejection; refusal; nonacceptance; declination; declining\nexcuse; plea" },
	{ "question": "断る", "answers": [ "ことわる" ], "comment": "to refuse; to reject; to dismiss; to turn down; to decline\nto inform; to give notice; to tell in advance\nto ask leave; to excuse oneself (from)" },
	{ "question": "断固", "answers": [ "だんこ" ], "comment": "firm; determined; resolute; conclusive" },
	{ "question": "断定", "answers": [ "だんてい" ], "comment": "conclusion; decision" },
	{ "question": "断層", "answers": [ "だんそう" ], "comment": "fault; dislocation\ngap; discrepancy" },
	{ "question": "断念", "answers": [ "だんねん" ], "comment": "abandoning (hope, plans); giving up" },
	{ "question": "断水", "answers": [ "だんすい" ], "comment": "suspension of water supply; water outage" },
	{ "question": "断然", "answers": [ "だんぜん" ], "comment": "firmly; absolutely; definitely; flatly; far and away; by far; by a long shot; hands down" },
	{ "question": "断熱", "answers": [ "だんねつ" ], "comment": "insulation" },
	{ "question": "断片", "answers": [ "だんぺん" ], "comment": "fragment; scrap; piece; shred" },
	{ "question": "断絶", "answers": [ "だんぜつ" ], "comment": "extinction; discontinuation; interruption\nseverance; rupture\nto become extinct; to cease to exist\nto sever; to break off; to divide (between two things)" },
	{ "question": "断続", "answers": [ "だんぞく" ], "comment": "intermittent" },
	{ "question": "断行", "answers": [ "だんこう" ], "comment": "decisive action; carry out" },
	{ "question": "断言", "answers": [ "だんげん" ], "comment": "assertion; declaration; affirmation" },
	{ "question": "断面", "answers": [ "だんめん" ], "comment": "cross-section" },
	{ "question": "断食", "answers": [ "だんじき" ], "comment": "fasting" },
	{ "question": "新", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "new; neo-\nGregorian calendar\nXin (dynasty of China)" },
	{ "question": "新しい", "answers": [ "あたらしい" ], "comment": "new; novel; fresh; recent; latest; up-to-date; modern" },
	{ "question": "新た", "answers": [ "あらた" ], "comment": "new; fresh; novel" },
	{ "question": "新世界", "answers": [ "しんせかい" ], "comment": "a new world; the New World" },
	{ "question": "新人", "answers": [ "しんじん" ], "comment": "new face; newcomer; rookie; fresh recruit\nmodern humans (from Cro-Magnon man onwards)" },
	{ "question": "新任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "inaugural; new" },
	{ "question": "新体", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "new style" },
	{ "question": "新作", "answers": [ "しんさく" ], "comment": "new work; new production" },
	{ "question": "新党", "answers": [ "しんとう" ], "comment": "new (political) party" },
	{ "question": "新入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "newly arrived; newly joined; newly entered; newcomer" },
	{ "question": "新刊", "answers": [ "しんかん" ], "comment": "new book; new publication" },
	{ "question": "新制", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "new system" },
	{ "question": "新劇", "answers": [ "しんげき" ], "comment": "new type or school of drama" },
	{ "question": "新卒", "answers": [ "しんそつ" ], "comment": "new (recent) graduate" },
	{ "question": "新品", "answers": [ "しんぴん" ], "comment": "(brand-)new article" },
	{ "question": "新型", "answers": [ "しんがた" ], "comment": "new type; new style; new model; new strain (e.g. infectious disease)" },
	{ "question": "新婚", "answers": [ "しんこん" ], "comment": "newly-wed" },
	{ "question": "新婦", "answers": [ "しんぷ" ], "comment": "bride" },
	{ "question": "新学期", "answers": [ "しんがっき" ], "comment": "new school term" },
	{ "question": "新居", "answers": [ "しんきょ" ], "comment": "new home" },
	{ "question": "新年", "answers": [ "しんねん" ], "comment": "New Year" },
	{ "question": "新幹線", "answers": [ "しんかんせん" ], "comment": "Shinkansen; bullet train" },
	{ "question": "新成人", "answers": [ "しんせいじん" ], "comment": "new adults (i.e. in Japan, 20-year-olds having their coming-of-age ceremony within that year)" },
	{ "question": "新手", "answers": [ "あらて", "しんて" ], "comment": "fresh supply of troops; newcomer\nnew method; new trick" },
	{ "question": "新政", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "new government; new administration" },
	{ "question": "新旧", "answers": [ "しんきゅう" ], "comment": "new and old; incoming and outgoing" },
	{ "question": "新星", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "nova\nnew face; new star" },
	{ "question": "新春", "answers": [ "しんしゅん" ], "comment": "New Year (Spring)" },
	{ "question": "新曲", "answers": [ "しんきょく" ], "comment": "new piece; new song" },
	{ "question": "新書", "answers": [ "しんしょ" ], "comment": "new book\n17 x 11 cm paperbook book" },
	{ "question": "新株", "answers": [ "しんかぶ" ], "comment": "new stocks or shares" },
	{ "question": "新概念", "answers": [ "しんがいねん" ], "comment": "new concept" },
	{ "question": "新橋", "answers": [ "しんばし" ], "comment": "Shinbashi (section of Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "新法", "answers": [ "しんぽう" ], "comment": "new law\nnew method" },
	{ "question": "新派", "answers": [ "しんぱ" ], "comment": "new school (of thought, etc.)\nnew drama" },
	{ "question": "新生", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "rebirth; new birth; nascent" },
	{ "question": "新生児", "answers": [ "しんせいじ" ], "comment": "newborn baby" },
	{ "question": "新田", "answers": [ "しんでん", "あらた" ], "comment": "new rice field; newly developed rice field\nwasteland or marshland newly reclaimed as a rice field (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "新発売", "answers": [ "しんはつばい" ], "comment": "new product or model" },
	{ "question": "新築", "answers": [ "しんちく" ], "comment": "new building; new construction" },
	{ "question": "新米", "answers": [ "しんまい" ], "comment": "new rice\nnovice; beginner; tyro; newcomer; newbie" },
	{ "question": "新緑", "answers": [ "しんりょく" ], "comment": "fresh verdure; new green leaves" },
	{ "question": "新聞", "answers": [ "しんぶん" ], "comment": "newspaper" },
	{ "question": "新聞社", "answers": [ "しんぶんしゃ" ], "comment": "newspaper company" },
	{ "question": "新聞紙", "answers": [ "しんぶんがみ", "しんぶんし" ], "comment": "newspaper\nnewsprint; newspaper used for wrapping, packing, etc." },
	{ "question": "新聞記事", "answers": [ "しんぶんきじ" ], "comment": "newspaper story (article, account)" },
	{ "question": "新興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "rising; developing; emergent" },
	{ "question": "新薬", "answers": [ "しんやく" ], "comment": "new medicine" },
	{ "question": "新装", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "redecoration; remodelling; remodeling; refurbishment" },
	{ "question": "新規", "answers": [ "しんき" ], "comment": "new; fresh\nnew item (e.g. customer, regulation); newly created object (orig. meaning)\nnew customer" },
	{ "question": "新設", "answers": [ "しんせつ" ], "comment": "newly organized; newly organised; newly established" },
	{ "question": "新語", "answers": [ "しんご" ], "comment": "new word; neologism; word of recent origin; recent word; modern term" },
	{ "question": "新車", "answers": [ "しんしゃ" ], "comment": "new car" },
	{ "question": "新進", "answers": [ "しんしん" ], "comment": "rising; up-and-coming" },
	{ "question": "新郎", "answers": [ "しんろう" ], "comment": "bridegroom" },
	{ "question": "新鋭", "answers": [ "しんえい" ], "comment": "young and energetic; up-and-coming; new and excellent; newly produced; up-and-comer" },
	{ "question": "新風", "answers": [ "しんぷう" ], "comment": "new style" },
	{ "question": "新鮮", "answers": [ "しんせん" ], "comment": "fresh" },
	{ "question": "方", "answers": [ "かた", "ほう" ], "comment": "direction; way\nperson; lady; gentleman\nmethod of; manner of; way of\ncare of ..\nperson in charge of ..\nside (e.g. \"on my mother's side\") /\n direction; way; side; area (in a particular direction)\nside (of an argument, etc.); one's part\ntype; category\nfield (of study, etc.)\nindicates one side of a comparison\nway; method; manner; means\nlength (of each side of a square)" },
	{ "question": "方々", "answers": [ "かたがた", "ほうぼう" ], "comment": "they (of people); gentlemen (of the ...)\nyou (usu. plural)\nvarious /\n here and there; this way and that way; everywhere; all over" },
	{ "question": "方がいい", "answers": [ "ほうがいい" ], "comment": "(after past tense verb) had better (verb); (after negative verb) had better not (verb)" },
	{ "question": "方位", "answers": [ "ほうい" ], "comment": "bearing; heading; point of the compass" },
	{ "question": "方向", "answers": [ "ほうこう" ], "comment": "direction; orientation; bearing; way\ncourse (e.g. of action)" },
	{ "question": "方向音痴", "answers": [ "ほうこうおんち" ], "comment": "(person with) no sense of direction; poor sense of locality" },
	{ "question": "方式", "answers": [ "ほうしき" ], "comment": "form; method; system; formula" },
	{ "question": "方法", "answers": [ "ほうほう" ], "comment": "method; process; manner; way; means; technique" },
	{ "question": "方法論", "answers": [ "ほうほうろん" ], "comment": "methodology" },
	{ "question": "方程式", "answers": [ "ほうていしき" ], "comment": "equation; formula\nmethod for solving a problem; set way of achieving a particular result" },
	{ "question": "方策", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "方角", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "direction; way\npoint of the compass; cardinal direction; bearing\nmethod; means; approach" },
	{ "question": "方言", "answers": [ "ほうげん" ], "comment": "dialect" },
	{ "question": "方針", "answers": [ "ほうしん" ], "comment": "objective; plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "方面", "answers": [ "ほうめん" ], "comment": "direction; district; area\nfield (e.g. of study); sphere; quarter; aspect; angle" },
	{ "question": "施す", "answers": [ "ほどこす" ], "comment": "to give (time, money, goods); to donate\nto do; to perform; to conduct\nto apply (processing, makeup, etc.); to add (e.g. ornamentation, annotation)\nto sow; to seed; to scatter (e.g. fertilizer); to sprinkle\nto spread far and wide" },
	{ "question": "施工", "answers": [ "せこう", "しこう" ], "comment": "construction; constructing; carrying out; work; formation; workmanship; execution" },
	{ "question": "施政", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "government; administration; statesmanship" },
	{ "question": "施策", "answers": [ "しさく" ], "comment": "policy; measure" },
	{ "question": "施行", "answers": [ "しこう", "せこう", "せぎょう", "しぎょう" ], "comment": "execution; enforcing; carrying out\ngiving alms; giving food to the poor or monks" },
	{ "question": "施設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "institution; establishment; facility\n(army) engineer" },
	{ "question": "旁", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "right-hand radical of a character" },
	{ "question": "旅", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "travel; trip; journey" },
	{ "question": "旅先", "answers": [ "たびさき" ], "comment": "destination; goal (of travel); place one stays during a journey" },
	{ "question": "旅券", "answers": [ "りょけん" ], "comment": "passport" },
	{ "question": "旅団", "answers": [ "りょだん" ], "comment": "brigade" },
	{ "question": "旅客", "answers": [ "りょきゃく", "りょかく" ], "comment": "passenger (transport)" },
	{ "question": "旅客機", "answers": [ "りょかっき", "りょかくき" ], "comment": "passenger plane" },
	{ "question": "旅立つ", "answers": [ "たびだつ" ], "comment": "to begin a trip; to depart; to embark\nto die; to pass away; to depart this life" },
	{ "question": "旅行", "answers": [ "りょこう" ], "comment": "travel; trip" },
	{ "question": "旅行券", "answers": [ "りょこうけん" ], "comment": "travel voucher; travel coupon" },
	{ "question": "旅行者", "answers": [ "りょこうしゃ" ], "comment": "traveller; traveler" },
	{ "question": "旅費", "answers": [ "りょひ" ], "comment": "travel expenses" },
	{ "question": "旅館", "answers": [ "りょかん" ], "comment": "ryokan; Japanese-style lodging, usu. professionally-run" },
	{ "question": "旋律", "answers": [ "せんりつ" ], "comment": "melody; tune" },
	{ "question": "旋風", "answers": [ "せんぷう", "つむじかぜ", "つじかぜ" ], "comment": "whirlwind\ncommotion; sensation; hullabaloo" },
	{ "question": "族", "answers": [ "ぞく" ], "comment": "tribe; clan; band\n(taxonomical) tribe\ngroup (of the periodic table)" },
	{ "question": "旗", "answers": [ "はた" ], "comment": "flag\npataka (banner)" },
	{ "question": "旗印", "answers": [ "はたじるし" ], "comment": "(design on a) banner; slogan; emblem (on flag); insignia" },
	{ "question": "旗手", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "standard-bearer" },
	{ "question": "旗揚げ", "answers": [ "はたあげ" ], "comment": "raising an army\nlaunching business" },
	{ "question": "既婚", "answers": [ "きこん" ], "comment": "marriage; married" },
	{ "question": "既存", "answers": [ "きそん" ], "comment": "existing" },
	{ "question": "既定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "default; established; pre-arranged; fixed; predetermined" },
	{ "question": "既得権", "answers": [ "きとくけん" ], "comment": "vested rights" },
	{ "question": "既成", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "established; completed; existing" },
	{ "question": "既成事実", "answers": [ "きせいじじつ" ], "comment": "established fact; fait accompli" },
	{ "question": "既製", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "ready-made; off the shelf" },
	{ "question": "日", "answers": [ "にち", "ひ" ], "comment": "day; days\nsun; sunshine; sunlight\ncase (esp. unfortunate); event /\n Sunday\nday (of the month)\ncounter for days\nJapan" },
	{ "question": "日々", "answers": [ "にちにち", "ひび" ], "comment": "every day; daily; day after day; days (e.g. good old days)" },
	{ "question": "日ごろ", "answers": [ "ひごろ" ], "comment": "normally; habitually" },
	{ "question": "日に日に", "answers": [ "ひにひに" ], "comment": "day by day; by the day\ndaily; every day" },
	{ "question": "日の丸", "answers": [ "ひのまる" ], "comment": "outline of the sun (esp. represented as a red circle)\nthe Japanese flag" },
	{ "question": "日の入り", "answers": [ "ひのいり" ], "comment": "sunset" },
	{ "question": "日の出", "answers": [ "ひので" ], "comment": "sunrise" },
	{ "question": "日の目", "answers": [ "ひのめ" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日ソ", "answers": [ "にっソ" ], "comment": "Japanese-Soviet" },
	{ "question": "日中", "answers": [ "にっちゅう", "ひなか" ], "comment": "daytime; during the day\nSino-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "日付", "answers": [ "ひづけ" ], "comment": "date; dating" },
	{ "question": "日付け", "answers": [ "ひづけ" ], "comment": "date; dating" },
	{ "question": "日光", "answers": [ "にっこう" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日光浴", "answers": [ "にっこうよく" ], "comment": "sunbathing" },
	{ "question": "日出", "answers": [ "にっしゅつ" ], "comment": "sunrise" },
	{ "question": "日刊", "answers": [ "にっかん" ], "comment": "daily issue" },
	{ "question": "日取り", "answers": [ "ひどり" ], "comment": "fixed date; appointed day" },
	{ "question": "日向", "answers": [ "ひなた" ], "comment": "sunny place; in the sun" },
	{ "question": "日和", "answers": [ "ひより" ], "comment": "weather; climatic conditions\nfine weather; clear day\nsituation; state of affairs\nsea conditions; good day for sailing" },
	{ "question": "日報", "answers": [ "にっぽう" ], "comment": "daily report" },
	{ "question": "日増しに", "answers": [ "ひましに" ], "comment": "day by day" },
	{ "question": "日夜", "answers": [ "にちや" ], "comment": "day and night; always" },
	{ "question": "日差し", "answers": [ "ひざし" ], "comment": "sunlight; rays of the sun" },
	{ "question": "日帰り", "answers": [ "ひがえり" ], "comment": "day trip" },
	{ "question": "日常", "answers": [ "にちじょう" ], "comment": "ordinary; regular; everyday; usual" },
	{ "question": "日常生活", "answers": [ "にちじょうせいかつ" ], "comment": "everyday life; daily life" },
	{ "question": "日当たり", "answers": [ "ひあたり" ], "comment": "exposure to the sun; sunny place\nper day" },
	{ "question": "日数", "answers": [ "ひかず", "にっすう" ], "comment": "a number of days" },
	{ "question": "日日", "answers": [ "ひにち", "ひび" ], "comment": "the number of days; date" },
	{ "question": "日時", "answers": [ "にちじ" ], "comment": "date and time" },
	{ "question": "日暮れ", "answers": [ "ひぐれ" ], "comment": "twilight; sunset; dusk; evening" },
	{ "question": "日曜", "answers": [ "にちよう" ], "comment": "Sunday" },
	{ "question": "日曜日", "answers": [ "にちようび" ], "comment": "Sunday" },
	{ "question": "日替り", "answers": [ "ひがわり" ], "comment": "changing every day" },
	{ "question": "日替わり", "answers": [ "ひがわり" ], "comment": "changing every day" },
	{ "question": "日本", "answers": [ "にっぽん", "にほん" ], "comment": "Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本一", "answers": [ "にっぽんいち", "にほんいち" ], "comment": "Japan's best; number one in Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本人", "answers": [ "にほんじん", "にっぽんじん" ], "comment": "Japanese person; Japanese people" },
	{ "question": "日本企業", "answers": [ "にほんきぎょう" ], "comment": "Japanese company (business, firm)" },
	{ "question": "日本全国", "answers": [ "にほんぜんこく" ], "comment": "all over Japan; throughout Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本学術会議", "answers": [ "にほんがくじゅつかいぎ" ], "comment": "Science Council of Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本式", "answers": [ "にほんしき" ], "comment": "Japanese style" },
	{ "question": "日本政府", "answers": [ "にほんせいふ" ], "comment": "Japanese government" },
	{ "question": "日本海", "answers": [ "にほんかい", "にっぽんかい" ], "comment": "Sea of Japan" },
	{ "question": "日本画", "answers": [ "にほんが" ], "comment": "Japanese painting" },
	{ "question": "日本社会", "answers": [ "にほんしゃかい" ], "comment": "Japanese society" },
	{ "question": "日本語", "answers": [ "にっぽんご", "にほんご" ], "comment": "Japanese (language)\nJapanese as a second language" },
	{ "question": "日本酒", "answers": [ "にほんしゅ" ], "comment": "sake; Japanese rice wine" },
	{ "question": "日本銀行", "answers": [ "にっぽんぎんこう", "にほんぎんこう" ], "comment": "Bank of Japan; BOJ; BoJ" },
	{ "question": "日没", "answers": [ "にちぼつ" ], "comment": "sunset" },
	{ "question": "日焼け", "answers": [ "ひやけ" ], "comment": "sunburn; suntan; tan\nbecoming discolored from the sun (e.g. paper); yellowing" },
	{ "question": "日焼け止め", "answers": [ "ひやけどめ" ], "comment": "sunscreen; suntan lotion; sunblock" },
	{ "question": "日照", "answers": [ "にっしょう" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日産", "answers": [ "にっさん" ], "comment": "daily output\nNissan (Japanese car company)" },
	{ "question": "日用品", "answers": [ "にちようひん" ], "comment": "daily necessities" },
	{ "question": "日程", "answers": [ "にってい" ], "comment": "schedule; program; programme; agenda" },
	{ "question": "日米", "answers": [ "にちべい" ], "comment": "Japan-America" },
	{ "question": "日系", "answers": [ "にっけい" ], "comment": "(of) Japanese descent\nnon-Japanese of Japanese descent; nikkeijin\ncompany, etc. set up with Japanese capital; company managed by Japanese or non-Japanese of Japanese descent" },
	{ "question": "日経", "answers": [ "にっけい" ], "comment": "Nikkei (newspaper, share index)" },
	{ "question": "日給", "answers": [ "にっきゅう" ], "comment": "daily wages" },
	{ "question": "日記", "answers": [ "にっき" ], "comment": "diary; journal" },
	{ "question": "日誌", "answers": [ "にっし" ], "comment": "journal; log" },
	{ "question": "日課", "answers": [ "にっか" ], "comment": "daily lesson; daily work; daily routine" },
	{ "question": "日陰", "answers": [ "ひかげ" ], "comment": "shade; shadow\nsunshine" },
	{ "question": "日韓", "answers": [ "にっかん" ], "comment": "Japan and (South) Korea\nJapanese and (South) Korean" },
	{ "question": "日食", "answers": [ "にっしょく" ], "comment": "solar eclipse" },
	{ "question": "旦那", "answers": [ "だんな" ], "comment": "master (of a house, shop, etc.)\nhusband (informal)\nsir; boss; master; governor; word used to address a male patron, customer, or person of high status\npatron of a mistress, geisha, bar or nightclub hostess; sugar daddy\nalms; almsgiving; almsgiver" },
	{ "question": "旧", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "ex-; former; old" },
	{ "question": "旧制", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "old system; old order" },
	{ "question": "旧姓", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "one's original family name; maiden name" },
	{ "question": "旧式", "answers": [ "きゅうしき" ], "comment": "old type; old style" },
	{ "question": "旧態", "answers": [ "きゅうたい" ], "comment": "old state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "旧来", "answers": [ "きゅうらい" ], "comment": "traditional; from ancient times; formerly" },
	{ "question": "旧正月", "answers": [ "きゅうしょうがつ" ], "comment": "lunisolar New Year; Chinese New Year; Vietnamese Tet" },
	{ "question": "旧派", "answers": [ "きゅうは" ], "comment": "old school; old style" },
	{ "question": "旨", "answers": [ "むね" ], "comment": "principle; aim; main purpose; central part; pillar\npurport; gist; drift; meaning\ninstructions; orders; intention; wishes" },
	{ "question": "早", "answers": [ "はや" ], "comment": "already; now; by this time" },
	{ "question": "早々", "answers": [ "そうそう", "はやばや" ], "comment": "as soon as...; just after...; immediately after...\nhurriedly; in haste; quickly; promptly; early /\n early; quickly; promptly" },
	{ "question": "早い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; hasty; brisk\nearly (in the day, etc.); premature\n(too) soon; not yet; (too) early\neasy; simple; quick" },
	{ "question": "早く", "answers": [ "はやく" ], "comment": "early; soon\nquickly; swiftly; rapidly; fast" },
	{ "question": "早まる", "answers": [ "はやまる" ], "comment": "to move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up\nto quicken; to speed up; to gather speed\nto be hasty; to be rash" },
	{ "question": "早める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "早乙女", "answers": [ "さおとめ" ], "comment": "young female rice planter; young girl" },
	{ "question": "早口", "answers": [ "はやくち", "はやぐち" ], "comment": "fast-talking; rapid talking" },
	{ "question": "早寝", "answers": [ "はやね" ], "comment": "go to bed early" },
	{ "question": "早引き", "answers": [ "はやびき" ], "comment": "leaving work (office, school) early" },
	{ "question": "早引け", "answers": [ "はやびけ" ], "comment": "leaving work (office, school) early" },
	{ "question": "早急", "answers": [ "さっきゅう", "そうきゅう" ], "comment": "immediate; prompt; quick; rapid; urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "早春", "answers": [ "そうしゅん" ], "comment": "early spring" },
	{ "question": "早朝", "answers": [ "そうちょう" ], "comment": "early morning" },
	{ "question": "早期", "answers": [ "そうき" ], "comment": "early stage" },
	{ "question": "早期治療", "answers": [ "そうきちりょう" ], "comment": "early treatment" },
	{ "question": "早瀬", "answers": [ "はやせ" ], "comment": "swift current; rapids" },
	{ "question": "早熟", "answers": [ "そうじゅく" ], "comment": "precocity; early ripening; premature development" },
	{ "question": "早起き", "answers": [ "はやおき" ], "comment": "early rising" },
	{ "question": "早退", "answers": [ "そうたい" ], "comment": "leaving early" },
	{ "question": "早速", "answers": [ "さっそく" ], "comment": "at once; immediately; without delay; promptly" },
	{ "question": "旬", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "ten-day period" },
	{ "question": "昆布", "answers": [ "こんぶ", "こぶ" ], "comment": "kombu (usu. Saccharina japonica); konbu; kelp; any edible species from the family Laminariaceae" },
	{ "question": "昆虫", "answers": [ "こんちゅう" ], "comment": "insect; bug" },
	{ "question": "昇る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "昇格", "answers": [ "しょうかく" ], "comment": "raising of status; promotion; advance" },
	{ "question": "昇給", "answers": [ "しょうきゅう" ], "comment": "salary raise" },
	{ "question": "昇進", "answers": [ "しょうしん" ], "comment": "promotion; advancement; rising in rank" },
	{ "question": "明かす", "answers": [ "あかす" ], "comment": "to pass (e.g. the night); to spend\nto reveal; to divulge" },
	{ "question": "明かり", "answers": [ "あかり" ], "comment": "light; illumination; glow; gleam\nlamp; light" },
	{ "question": "明くる", "answers": [ "あくる" ], "comment": "next; following" },
	{ "question": "明くる日", "answers": [ "あくるひ" ], "comment": "next day; following day" },
	{ "question": "明ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "to open (a door, etc.); to unwrap (e.g. parcel, package); to unlock\nto open (for business, etc.)\nto empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole)" },
	{ "question": "明け方", "answers": [ "あけがた" ], "comment": "dawn" },
	{ "question": "明け暮れ", "answers": [ "あけくれ" ], "comment": "morning and evening; all the time" },
	{ "question": "明らか", "answers": [ "あきらか" ], "comment": "obvious; evident; clear; plain" },
	{ "question": "明るい", "answers": [ "あかるい" ], "comment": "bright; colourful\ncheerful\nfamiliar (with); knowledgeable (about)\nfair (e.g. politics); clean" },
	{ "question": "明年", "answers": [ "みょうねん" ], "comment": "next year" },
	{ "question": "明後日", "answers": [ "みょうごにち", "あさって" ], "comment": "day after tomorrow" },
	{ "question": "明快", "answers": [ "めいかい" ], "comment": "clear; clear-cut; lucid; unequivocal; explicit" },
	{ "question": "明文化", "answers": [ "めいぶんか" ], "comment": "stipulation; stating clearly; documenting in writing; stating explicitly" },
	{ "question": "明日", "answers": [ "みょうにち", "あす", "あした" ], "comment": "tomorrow\nnear future" },
	{ "question": "明晩", "answers": [ "みょうばん" ], "comment": "tomorrow evening" },
	{ "question": "明暗", "answers": [ "めいあん" ], "comment": "light and darkness; light and shade" },
	{ "question": "明朗", "answers": [ "めいろう" ], "comment": "cheerful; bright\nclear; clean; honest; fair" },
	{ "question": "明朝", "answers": [ "みょうちょう" ], "comment": "tomorrow morning" },
	{ "question": "明治", "answers": [ "めいじ" ], "comment": "Meiji era (1868.9.8-1912.7.30)" },
	{ "question": "明白", "answers": [ "めいはく" ], "comment": "obvious; clear; plain; evident; apparent; explicit; overt" },
	{ "question": "明瞭", "answers": [ "めいりょう" ], "comment": "clarity; clearness" },
	{ "question": "明確", "answers": [ "めいかく" ], "comment": "clear; precise; definite; distinct" },
	{ "question": "明示", "answers": [ "めいじ" ], "comment": "elucidation; explicit statement; specification" },
	{ "question": "明細", "answers": [ "めいさい" ], "comment": "details; particulars\ndetailed statement" },
	{ "question": "明言", "answers": [ "めいげん" ], "comment": "declaration; statement" },
	{ "question": "明記", "answers": [ "めいき" ], "comment": "clear writing; specification" },
	{ "question": "昔", "answers": [ "むかし" ], "comment": "olden days; former" },
	{ "question": "昔のまま", "answers": [ "むかしのまま" ], "comment": "the way it was; the way it used be; as of old; in former times" },
	{ "question": "昔話", "answers": [ "むかしばなし" ], "comment": "old tale; folk tale; legend\nreminiscence" },
	{ "question": "星", "answers": [ "ほし" ], "comment": "star; any light-emitting (or reflecting) heavenly body (except for the sun and the moon)\noffender; perpetrator\nstar point (in go); hoshi; intersection marked with a dot\ncircular symbol (said to be shaped like a shining star)\nbullseye\none's star (out of the nine stars); the star that determines one's fate\nsmall dot; spot\npoint; score" },
	{ "question": "星座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "constellation; star sign; zodiac sign" },
	{ "question": "星空", "answers": [ "ほしぞら" ], "comment": "starry sky" },
	{ "question": "映える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to shine; to look attractive; to look pretty" },
	{ "question": "映し出す", "answers": [ "うつしだす" ], "comment": "to project; to show\nto portray; to depict; to describe; to reflect" },
	{ "question": "映す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to project; to reflect; to cast (shadow)" },
	{ "question": "映る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be reflected; to harmonize with (harmonise); to come out (photo); to be projected; to be displayed (on a screen)" },
	{ "question": "映像", "answers": [ "えいぞう" ], "comment": "reflection; image; picture (e.g. on a television); shot\nvideo; film; footage; clip; video recording\nimage in one's mind; mental picture" },
	{ "question": "映画", "answers": [ "えいが" ], "comment": "movie; film" },
	{ "question": "映画館", "answers": [ "えいがかん" ], "comment": "movie theatre; movie theater; cinema" },
	{ "question": "春", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "spring; springtime\nNew Year\nprime (of one's life, etc.)\nadolescence; puberty\nsexuality" },
	{ "question": "春休み", "answers": [ "はるやすみ" ], "comment": "spring break; spring vacation" },
	{ "question": "春先", "answers": [ "はるさき" ], "comment": "beginning of spring" },
	{ "question": "春分", "answers": [ "しゅんぶん" ], "comment": "vernal equinox; spring equinox" },
	{ "question": "春場所", "answers": [ "はるばしょ" ], "comment": "spring (March) tournament, held in Osaka" },
	{ "question": "春夏秋冬", "answers": [ "しゅんかしゅうとう" ], "comment": "spring, summer, autumn (fall) and winter; the four seasons" },
	{ "question": "春季", "answers": [ "しゅんき" ], "comment": "spring season" },
	{ "question": "春秋", "answers": [ "はるあき", "しゅんじゅう" ], "comment": "spring and autumn; spring and fall; months and years\nthe Chronicles of Lu or the Spring and Autumn Annals - one of the Five Classics" },
	{ "question": "春闘", "answers": [ "しゅんとう" ], "comment": "spring labor offensive; annual spring wage bargaining round" },
	{ "question": "昨今", "answers": [ "さっこん", "さくこん" ], "comment": "nowadays; recently" },
	{ "question": "昨夜", "answers": [ "ゆう", "ゆうべ", "さくや" ], "comment": "evening\nlast night" },
	{ "question": "昨年", "answers": [ "さくねん" ], "comment": "last year" },
	{ "question": "昨年度", "answers": [ "さくねんど" ], "comment": "previous year (fiscal, academic, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "昨年来", "answers": [ "さくねんらい" ], "comment": "since last year" },
	{ "question": "昨日", "answers": [ "さくじつ", "きのう" ], "comment": "yesterday" },
	{ "question": "昨春", "answers": [ "さくしゅん" ], "comment": "last spring; the spring of last year" },
	{ "question": "昨晩", "answers": [ "さくばん" ], "comment": "last night" },
	{ "question": "昨秋", "answers": [ "さくしゅう" ], "comment": "autumn of last year; fall of last year" },
	{ "question": "昭和", "answers": [ "しょうわ" ], "comment": "Showa era (1926.12.25-1989.1.7)" },
	{ "question": "是正", "answers": [ "ぜせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; redressing; rectifying" },
	{ "question": "是非とも", "answers": [ "ぜひとも" ], "comment": "by all means (with sense of not taking \"no\" for an answer)" },
	{ "question": "昼", "answers": [ "ひる" ], "comment": "noon; midday\ndaytime\nlunch" },
	{ "question": "昼下がり", "answers": [ "ひるさがり" ], "comment": "early afternoon" },
	{ "question": "昼休み", "answers": [ "ひるやすみ" ], "comment": "lunch break; noon recess; noon rest period" },
	{ "question": "昼前", "answers": [ "ひるまえ" ], "comment": "forenoon; just before noon" },
	{ "question": "昼夜", "answers": [ "ちゅうや" ], "comment": "day and night" },
	{ "question": "昼寝", "answers": [ "ひるね" ], "comment": "nap (afternoon); siesta" },
	{ "question": "昼過ぎ", "answers": [ "ひるすぎ" ], "comment": "just past noon; afternoon" },
	{ "question": "昼間", "answers": [ "ひるま", "ちゅうかん" ], "comment": "daytime; during the day; time from sunrise until sunset; diurnal period" },
	{ "question": "昼食", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょく", "ちゅうじき", "ひるげ" ], "comment": "lunch; midday meal\nfood served at a tea party (tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "時", "answers": [ "じ", "とき" ], "comment": "time; hour; moment\noccasion; case\nchance; opportunity; season\nthe times; the age; the day\ntense /\n hour; o'clock\n(specified) time; when ...; during ..." },
	{ "question": "時々", "answers": [ "ときどき" ], "comment": "sometimes; at times" },
	{ "question": "時として", "answers": [ "ときとして" ], "comment": "in some cases; sometimes; on occasions" },
	{ "question": "時には", "answers": [ "ときには" ], "comment": "at times; occasionally" },
	{ "question": "時は金なり", "answers": [ "ときはかねなり" ], "comment": "time is money" },
	{ "question": "時事", "answers": [ "じじ" ], "comment": "events of the day; current affairs" },
	{ "question": "時代", "answers": [ "じだい" ], "comment": "period; epoch; era; age\nthe times; those days\noldness; ancientness; antiquity\nantique; period piece" },
	{ "question": "時代劇", "answers": [ "じだいげき" ], "comment": "historical play; period drama" },
	{ "question": "時代錯誤", "answers": [ "じだいさくご" ], "comment": "anachronism" },
	{ "question": "時価", "answers": [ "じか" ], "comment": "current value; price; market value" },
	{ "question": "時刻", "answers": [ "じこく" ], "comment": "instant; time; moment" },
	{ "question": "時効", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "statute of limitations; lapse of rights after a period of time; prescription (including acquisitive and extinctive prescription)\nageing; aging" },
	{ "question": "時半", "answers": [ "じはん" ], "comment": "about an hour; short time\nhalf past (the hour)" },
	{ "question": "時報", "answers": [ "じほう" ], "comment": "announcement of time; time signal\nnews report; newsletter" },
	{ "question": "時差", "answers": [ "じさ" ], "comment": "time difference" },
	{ "question": "時折", "answers": [ "ときおり" ], "comment": "sometimes" },
	{ "question": "時期", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "time; season; period; phase; stage\nsoon; shortly" },
	{ "question": "時期尚早", "answers": [ "じきしょうそう" ], "comment": "premature" },
	{ "question": "時機", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; time; occasion" },
	{ "question": "時流", "answers": [ "じりゅう" ], "comment": "fashion (current) of the times; general drift of affairs" },
	{ "question": "時点", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "point in time; occasion" },
	{ "question": "時給", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "hourly pay; hourly wage" },
	{ "question": "時計", "answers": [ "とけい" ], "comment": "watch; clock; timepiece" },
	{ "question": "時速", "answers": [ "じそく" ], "comment": "speed (per hour)" },
	{ "question": "時間", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "time\nhours (period of)" },
	{ "question": "時間切れ", "answers": [ "じかんぎれ" ], "comment": "being out of time; passing the deadline\ntime-out" },
	{ "question": "時間割", "answers": [ "じかんわり" ], "comment": "timetable (esp. a weekly school timetable); schedule" },
	{ "question": "時間割り", "answers": [ "じかんわり" ], "comment": "timetable (esp. a weekly school timetable); schedule" },
	{ "question": "時限", "answers": [ "じげん" ], "comment": "(school) period\nperiod or division of time; time limit" },
	{ "question": "時雨", "answers": [ "しぐれ", "じう" ], "comment": "rain shower in late autumn (fall) or early winter\nseasonable rain" },
	{ "question": "晒す", "answers": [ "さらす" ], "comment": "to expose (to the sun, public, danger, etc.)\nto bleach; to refine\nto rinse (vegetables); to soak\nto sentence someone to public humiliation" },
	{ "question": "晩", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "evening\ncounter for nights" },
	{ "question": "晩婚", "answers": [ "ばんこん" ], "comment": "late marriage" },
	{ "question": "晩年", "answers": [ "ばんねん" ], "comment": "(one's) last years" },
	{ "question": "普及", "answers": [ "ふきゅう" ], "comment": "diffusion; spread; popularization; promulgation; familiarization" },
	{ "question": "普段", "answers": [ "ふだん" ], "comment": "usual; habitual; ordinary; everyday; usually; generally; always" },
	{ "question": "普段着", "answers": [ "ふだんぎ" ], "comment": "casual wear; ordinary clothes; everyday clothes; home wear" },
	{ "question": "普賢", "answers": [ "ふげん" ], "comment": "Samantabhadra (bodhisattva); Universal Compassion" },
	{ "question": "普通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "general; ordinary; usual\nnormally; generally; usually\nlocal train; train that stops at every station" },
	{ "question": "普通預金", "answers": [ "ふつうよきん" ], "comment": "ordinary bank account" },
	{ "question": "普遍", "answers": [ "ふへん" ], "comment": "universal; general; ubiquitous; omnipresent" },
	{ "question": "普遍的", "answers": [ "ふへんてき" ], "comment": "universal; omnipresent; ubiquitous" },
	{ "question": "景品", "answers": [ "けいひん" ], "comment": "gift; premium; freebie; giveaway; something additional; an extra\nprize (lottery drawing, pachinko, etc.)\nparty favor (favour)" },
	{ "question": "景気", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "business conditions; the market; economic activity; economic climate\ngood (economic) times; prosperity; boom\nliveliness; energy; vigour; vigor; spirit" },
	{ "question": "景色", "answers": [ "けいしょく", "けしき" ], "comment": "scenery; scene; landscape" },
	{ "question": "景観", "answers": [ "けいかん" ], "comment": "scenery" },
	{ "question": "晴れ", "answers": [ "はれ" ], "comment": "clear weather; fine weather\nformal; ceremonial; public\ncleared of suspicion" },
	{ "question": "晴れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "to clear up; to clear away; to be sunny; to stop raining\nto refresh (e.g. spirits)\nto be cleared (e.g. of a suspicion)\nto be dispelled; to be banished" },
	{ "question": "晴天", "answers": [ "せいてん" ], "comment": "fine weather (i.e. little or no clouds); fair weather; clear weather; clear sky; fair skies" },
	{ "question": "暁", "answers": [ "あかつき" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak\nevent (e.g. \"in the event of ...\"); occasion; occurrence" },
	{ "question": "暇", "answers": [ "いとま", "ひま" ], "comment": "spare time; free time; leisure\ntime (e.g. time it takes to do something)\ntime off; day off; vacation; holiday; leave\nquitting (one's job); firing someone; divorcing (one's spouse)\n(of one's time) free; (of one's business) slow\nleaving; departing" },
	{ "question": "暇がない", "answers": [ "ひまがない" ], "comment": "busy; having no (free) time" },
	{ "question": "暇つぶし", "answers": [ "ひまつぶし" ], "comment": "waste of time; killing time" },
	{ "question": "暇潰し", "answers": [ "ひまつぶし" ], "comment": "waste of time; killing time" },
	{ "question": "暑い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "hot (weather, etc.); warm" },
	{ "question": "暑さ", "answers": [ "あつさ" ], "comment": "heat (of the weather); hotness" },
	{ "question": "暑中見舞", "answers": [ "しょちゅうみまい" ], "comment": "summer greeting card; inquiry after someone's health in the hot season" },
	{ "question": "暑中見舞い", "answers": [ "しょちゅうみまい" ], "comment": "summer greeting card; inquiry after someone's health in the hot season" },
	{ "question": "暖かい", "answers": [ "あったかい", "あたたかい" ], "comment": "warm; mild; genial" },
	{ "question": "暖まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる", "ぬくまる", "あったまる" ], "comment": "to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm" },
	{ "question": "暖める", "answers": [ "あたためる", "あっためる" ], "comment": "to warm; to heat" },
	{ "question": "暖冬", "answers": [ "だんとう" ], "comment": "mild winter; warm winter" },
	{ "question": "暖房", "answers": [ "だんぼう" ], "comment": "(indoor) heating" },
	{ "question": "暗い", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "dark; gloomy\ndark (in colour); dull\ndepressed; dispirited\nsorrowful; bitter (as in a dark past)\nunclear; unfamiliar; unknown" },
	{ "question": "暗に", "answers": [ "あんに" ], "comment": "implicitly" },
	{ "question": "暗やみ", "answers": [ "くらやみ" ], "comment": "darkness; the dark" },
	{ "question": "暗号", "answers": [ "あんごう" ], "comment": "code; password; cipher" },
	{ "question": "暗殺", "answers": [ "あんさつ" ], "comment": "assassination" },
	{ "question": "暗礁", "answers": [ "あんしょう" ], "comment": "reef; sunken rock" },
	{ "question": "暗示", "answers": [ "あんじ" ], "comment": "hint; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "暗記", "answers": [ "あんき" ], "comment": "memorization; memorisation; learning by heart" },
	{ "question": "暗闇", "answers": [ "くらやみ" ], "comment": "darkness; the dark" },
	{ "question": "暗雲", "answers": [ "あんうん" ], "comment": "dark clouds" },
	{ "question": "暗黒", "answers": [ "あんこく" ], "comment": "darkness" },
	{ "question": "暗黙", "answers": [ "あんもく" ], "comment": "tacit; implicit" },
	{ "question": "暦", "answers": [ "れき", "こよみ" ], "comment": "calendar; almanac" },
	{ "question": "暫定", "answers": [ "ざんてい" ], "comment": "tentative; temporary" },
	{ "question": "暮らし", "answers": [ "くらし" ], "comment": "life; living; livelihood; life circumstances" },
	{ "question": "暮らす", "answers": [ "くらす" ], "comment": "to live; to get along\nto spend (time)" },
	{ "question": "暮れ", "answers": [ "くれ" ], "comment": "sunset; sundown; nightfall; dusk\nend; close\nyear-end; end of the year" },
	{ "question": "暮れる", "answers": [ "くれる" ], "comment": "to get dark\nto end; to come to an end; to close; to run out\nto be sunk (e.g. in despair); to be lost" },
	{ "question": "暴れる", "answers": [ "あばれる" ], "comment": "to act violently; to rage; to struggle; to be riotous" },
	{ "question": "暴力", "answers": [ "ぼうりょく" ], "comment": "violence; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "暴力団", "answers": [ "ぼうりょくだん" ], "comment": "gangster organization (organisation); crime syndicate; yakuza (Japanese mafia); band of thugs; group of hoodlums" },
	{ "question": "暴動", "answers": [ "ぼうどう" ], "comment": "insurrection; rebellion; revolt; riot; uprising" },
	{ "question": "暴徒", "answers": [ "ぼうと" ], "comment": "insurgent; rioter; mob" },
	{ "question": "暴挙", "answers": [ "ぼうきょ" ], "comment": "violence; reckless action" },
	{ "question": "暴落", "answers": [ "ぼうらく" ], "comment": "slump; crash; heavy fall; decline" },
	{ "question": "暴行", "answers": [ "ぼうこう" ], "comment": "assault; outrage; act of violence\nrape" },
	{ "question": "暴走", "answers": [ "ぼうそう" ], "comment": "acting rashly; running wildly; behaving recklessly; reckless driving; rampage\nrunaway (process)\nreckless baserunning" },
	{ "question": "暴露", "answers": [ "ばくろ" ], "comment": "disclosure; exposure; revelation" },
	{ "question": "暴風", "answers": [ "あらし", "ぼうふう" ], "comment": "storm; windstorm; gale" },
	{ "question": "暴風雨", "answers": [ "あらし", "ぼうふうう" ], "comment": "storm; rainstorm" },
	{ "question": "暴騰", "answers": [ "ぼうとう" ], "comment": "sudden rise; sharp rise; boom; skyrocketing" },
	{ "question": "曇り", "answers": [ "くもり" ], "comment": "cloudiness; cloudy weather; shadow" },
	{ "question": "曇る", "answers": [ "くもる" ], "comment": "to get cloudy; to cloud over; to become overcast\nto cloud up; to fog up; to mist up; to become dim\nto be gloomy; to be clouded (expression); to be downcast\nto look slightly downward (of a noh mask; indicating sadness, grief, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "曖昧", "answers": [ "あいまい" ], "comment": "vague; ambiguous; unclear\nfuzzy" },
	{ "question": "曙", "answers": [ "あけぼの" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak; beginning" },
	{ "question": "曜日", "answers": [ "ようび" ], "comment": "day of the week" },
	{ "question": "曝す", "answers": [ "さらす" ], "comment": "to expose (to the sun, public, danger, etc.)\nto bleach; to refine\nto rinse (vegetables); to soak\nto sentence someone to public humiliation" },
	{ "question": "曲", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "song; tune; composition; piece of music" },
	{ "question": "曲がり", "answers": [ "まがり" ], "comment": "curvature; warp; bend" },
	{ "question": "曲がりかど", "answers": [ "まがりかど" ], "comment": "street corner; road turn; bend in the road\nturning point; watershed" },
	{ "question": "曲がり角", "answers": [ "まがりかど" ], "comment": "street corner; road turn; bend in the road\nturning point; watershed" },
	{ "question": "曲がる", "answers": [ "まがる" ], "comment": "to bend; to curve; to warp; to wind; to twist\nto turn\nto be awry; to be askew; to be crooked" },
	{ "question": "曲げる", "answers": [ "まげる" ], "comment": "to bend; to crook; to bow; to curve; to curl\nto lean; to tilt; to incline; to slant\nto bend (the truth); to distort; to twist; to pervert\nto yield (a point); to depart (from a principle); to ignore (what one really thinks)\nto pawn" },
	{ "question": "曲折", "answers": [ "きょくせつ" ], "comment": "windings; meanderings; complications; twists and turns" },
	{ "question": "曲目", "answers": [ "きょくもく" ], "comment": "program; programme; musical selection; tunes" },
	{ "question": "曲線", "answers": [ "きょくせん" ], "comment": "curve" },
	{ "question": "更ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to get late; to advance; to wear on" },
	{ "question": "更改", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "renewal; extension; revision" },
	{ "question": "更新", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "renewal; update; innovation; improvement" },
	{ "question": "更正", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; rectification" },
	{ "question": "更生", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "rehabilitation\nrebirth; resuscitation\nreorganization; reorganisation; recycle; reuse" },
	{ "question": "更衣室", "answers": [ "こういしつ" ], "comment": "locker room; changing room; dressing room" },
	{ "question": "更迭", "answers": [ "こうてつ" ], "comment": "change; shake-up; reshuffle (e.g. of a cabinet); dismissal (e.g. of a minister); exchanging places" },
	{ "question": "書き上げる", "answers": [ "かきあげる" ], "comment": "to write out or down; to finish writing" },
	{ "question": "書き初め", "answers": [ "かきぞめ" ], "comment": "first calligraphy of the year" },
	{ "question": "書き取り", "answers": [ "かきとり" ], "comment": "writing down from other written material; writing kanji text from hiragana\ntranscription (of spoken material)" },
	{ "question": "書き取る", "answers": [ "かきとる" ], "comment": "to write down; to take dictation; to take notes" },
	{ "question": "書き換える", "answers": [ "かきかえる" ], "comment": "to rewrite; to overwrite; to renew; to transfer" },
	{ "question": "書き方", "answers": [ "かきかた" ], "comment": "way of writing; manner of writing\npenmanship (esp. used in old textbooks); calligraphy\nformat (e.g. of a report)\nstroke order of a character" },
	{ "question": "書き直す", "answers": [ "かきなおす" ], "comment": "to write out; to make a fair copy; to rewrite" },
	{ "question": "書き言葉", "answers": [ "かきことば" ], "comment": "written word; written language" },
	{ "question": "書き込み", "answers": [ "かきこみ" ], "comment": "writing\nentry (e.g. to a form)\nposting (e.g. to a blog)" },
	{ "question": "書き込む", "answers": [ "かきこむ" ], "comment": "to fill in (field, entry, etc.); to fill out (form)\nto post a message (e.g. on a bulletin-board)\nto store" },
	{ "question": "書く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "to write; to compose; to pen\nto draw; to paint" },
	{ "question": "書体", "answers": [ "しょたい" ], "comment": "calligraphic style; calligraphic styles; typeface" },
	{ "question": "書取", "answers": [ "かきとり" ], "comment": "writing down from other written material; writing kanji text from hiragana\ntranscription (of spoken material)" },
	{ "question": "書名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "book title" },
	{ "question": "書家", "answers": [ "しょか" ], "comment": "calligrapher; individual with good penmanship" },
	{ "question": "書店", "answers": [ "しょてん" ], "comment": "bookshop; bookstore" },
	{ "question": "書房", "answers": [ "しょぼう" ], "comment": "library; bookstore; bookshop" },
	{ "question": "書斎", "answers": [ "しょさい" ], "comment": "study; library; den; home office; reading room" },
	{ "question": "書物", "answers": [ "しょもつ" ], "comment": "books" },
	{ "question": "書留", "answers": [ "かきとめ" ], "comment": "registered mail\nregistration (e.g. of mail); writing down; putting on record; recording; making a note of" },
	{ "question": "書簡", "answers": [ "しょかん" ], "comment": "letter; note; epistle; correspondence" },
	{ "question": "書籍", "answers": [ "しょせき" ], "comment": "book; publication" },
	{ "question": "書記", "answers": [ "しょき" ], "comment": "clerk; secretary" },
	{ "question": "書記官", "answers": [ "しょきかん" ], "comment": "secretary" },
	{ "question": "書記局", "answers": [ "しょききょく" ], "comment": "secretariat" },
	{ "question": "書評", "answers": [ "しょひょう" ], "comment": "book review" },
	{ "question": "書道", "answers": [ "しょどう" ], "comment": "calligraphy" },
	{ "question": "書院", "answers": [ "しょいん" ], "comment": "drawing room; study; publishing house; writing alcove" },
	{ "question": "書面", "answers": [ "しょめん" ], "comment": "document; letter\nwriting; contents (e.g. of a letter)" },
	{ "question": "書類", "answers": [ "しょるい" ], "comment": "documents; official papers" },
	{ "question": "替え", "answers": [ "かえ" ], "comment": "change; alteration; substitute; spare; proxy\nrate of exchange" },
	{ "question": "替える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "替え玉", "answers": [ "かえだま" ], "comment": "substitute; double\nsecond serving (ball) of noodles (to add to previously purchased ramen)" },
	{ "question": "替わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "substitute; replacement; substituting; replacing\nstand-in; proxy; alternate; deputy; relief; successor\ncompensation; exchange; return\nsecond helping; another cup; seconds\nupcoming program; upcoming programme" },
	{ "question": "替わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to succeed; to relieve; to replace\nto take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent\nto be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch" },
	{ "question": "最も", "answers": [ "もっとも" ], "comment": "most; extremely" },
	{ "question": "最上", "answers": [ "もがみ", "さいじょう" ], "comment": "best" },
	{ "question": "最下", "answers": [ "さいか" ], "comment": "the lowest; the worst" },
	{ "question": "最中", "answers": [ "さいちゅう", "さなか" ], "comment": "in the middle of; height of; in course of; midst" },
	{ "question": "最低", "answers": [ "さいてい" ], "comment": "least; lowest; minimum\nworst\nawful; horrible; nasty; disgusting\nat the very least" },
	{ "question": "最低限", "answers": [ "さいていげん" ], "comment": "minimum\nat the very least" },
	{ "question": "最優遇", "answers": [ "さいゆうぐう" ], "comment": "most favourable treatment; most favorable treatment; very warm reception" },
	{ "question": "最先端", "answers": [ "さいせんたん" ], "comment": "cutting edge; leading edge; forefront\ntip; end" },
	{ "question": "最初", "answers": [ "さいしょ" ], "comment": "beginning; outset; first; onset" },
	{ "question": "最前列", "answers": [ "さいぜんれつ" ], "comment": "front row" },
	{ "question": "最前線", "answers": [ "さいぜんせん" ], "comment": "front line; forefront" },
	{ "question": "最古", "answers": [ "さいこ" ], "comment": "the oldest" },
	{ "question": "最善", "answers": [ "さいぜん" ], "comment": "the very best" },
	{ "question": "最多", "answers": [ "さいた" ], "comment": "most (numerous)" },
	{ "question": "最大", "answers": [ "さいだい" ], "comment": "biggest; greatest; largest; maximum" },
	{ "question": "最大限", "answers": [ "さいだいげん" ], "comment": "maximum\nto the maximum degree" },
	{ "question": "最寄り", "answers": [ "もより" ], "comment": "nearest; neighbouring; neighboring; nearby" },
	{ "question": "最小", "answers": [ "さいしょう" ], "comment": "smallest (in size, degree, etc.); least; minimum; minimal" },
	{ "question": "最小限", "answers": [ "さいしょうげん" ], "comment": "minimum; lowest" },
	{ "question": "最少", "answers": [ "さいしょう" ], "comment": "fewest; least; smallest (number); lowest; minimum\nyoungest" },
	{ "question": "最年少", "answers": [ "さいねんしょう" ], "comment": "youngest" },
	{ "question": "最強", "answers": [ "さいきょう" ], "comment": "strongest" },
	{ "question": "最後", "answers": [ "さいご" ], "comment": "last; end; conclusion; latest; most recent\nno sooner than; right after (often having negative consequences)\none's final moments" },
	{ "question": "最後の舞台", "answers": [ "さいごのぶたい" ], "comment": "final performance; swan song; last act" },
	{ "question": "最後尾", "answers": [ "さいこうび" ], "comment": "end of a line (queue)" },
	{ "question": "最恵国", "answers": [ "さいけいこく" ], "comment": "most favored nation; most favoured nation; MFN" },
	{ "question": "最悪", "answers": [ "さいあく" ], "comment": "the worst\nin the worst case" },
	{ "question": "最愛", "answers": [ "さいあい" ], "comment": "beloved; dearest" },
	{ "question": "最新", "answers": [ "さいしん" ], "comment": "latest; newest; late-breaking (news)" },
	{ "question": "最新ニュース", "answers": [ "さいしんニュース" ], "comment": "latest news; most recent news" },
	{ "question": "最新情報", "answers": [ "さいしんじょうほう" ], "comment": "the latest information" },
	{ "question": "最新研究", "answers": [ "さいしんけんきゅう" ], "comment": "the newest research" },
	{ "question": "最新鋭", "answers": [ "さいしんえい" ], "comment": "state-of-the-art; cutting-edge" },
	{ "question": "最期", "answers": [ "さいご" ], "comment": "one's last moment; one's death; one's end" },
	{ "question": "最盛期", "answers": [ "さいせいき" ], "comment": "golden age; prime; heyday; height of prosperity\nseason (for fruit, vegetables, etc.); best time" },
	{ "question": "最短", "answers": [ "さいたん" ], "comment": "shortest" },
	{ "question": "最終", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "last; final; closing" },
	{ "question": "最終的", "answers": [ "さいしゅうてき" ], "comment": "final; eventual" },
	{ "question": "最良", "answers": [ "さいりょう" ], "comment": "the best; ideal" },
	{ "question": "最近", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "most recent; these days; right now; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "最適", "answers": [ "さいてき" ], "comment": "optimum; the most suitable" },
	{ "question": "最重点", "answers": [ "さいじゅうてん" ], "comment": "very important point" },
	{ "question": "最長", "answers": [ "さいちょう" ], "comment": "longest\noldest" },
	{ "question": "最高", "answers": [ "さいこう" ], "comment": "most; highest; maximum; uppermost; supreme\nbest; wonderful; finest" },
	{ "question": "最高峰", "answers": [ "さいこうほう" ], "comment": "highest peak; highest mountain\ngreatest authority; most prominent person; pinnacle (e.g. of art); peak" },
	{ "question": "最高検", "answers": [ "さいこうけん" ], "comment": "Public Prosecutor's Office" },
	{ "question": "最高級", "answers": [ "さいこうきゅう" ], "comment": "highest grade; top class" },
	{ "question": "最高裁", "answers": [ "さいこうさい" ], "comment": "Supreme Court" },
	{ "question": "月", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "moon\nmonth" },
	{ "question": "月々", "answers": [ "つきづき" ], "comment": "every month; monthly; month by month" },
	{ "question": "月並", "answers": [ "つきなみ", "げつじ" ], "comment": "every month\ntrite; common" },
	{ "question": "月並み", "answers": [ "つきなみ", "げつじ" ], "comment": "every month\ntrite; common" },
	{ "question": "月例", "answers": [ "げつれい" ], "comment": "monthly" },
	{ "question": "月光", "answers": [ "げっこう" ], "comment": "moonlight; moonbeam" },
	{ "question": "月内", "answers": [ "げつない" ], "comment": "by the end of this month" },
	{ "question": "月刊", "answers": [ "げっかん" ], "comment": "monthly publication; monthly issue" },
	{ "question": "月初め", "answers": [ "つきはじめ" ], "comment": "beginning of month" },
	{ "question": "月収", "answers": [ "げっしゅう" ], "comment": "monthly income" },
	{ "question": "月夜", "answers": [ "つきよ" ], "comment": "moonlit night" },
	{ "question": "月日", "answers": [ "つきひ", "がっぴ" ], "comment": "time; years; days /\n (the) date" },
	{ "question": "月曜", "answers": [ "げつよう" ], "comment": "Monday" },
	{ "question": "月曜日", "answers": [ "げつようび" ], "comment": "Monday" },
	{ "question": "月末", "answers": [ "げつまつ", "つきずえ" ], "comment": "end of the month" },
	{ "question": "月産", "answers": [ "げっさん" ], "comment": "monthly output (production)" },
	{ "question": "月経", "answers": [ "げっけい" ], "comment": "menstruation; menstrual period" },
	{ "question": "月給", "answers": [ "げっきゅう" ], "comment": "monthly salary" },
	{ "question": "月見", "answers": [ "つきみ" ], "comment": "viewing the moon" },
	{ "question": "月謝", "answers": [ "げっしゃ" ], "comment": "monthly tuition fee" },
	{ "question": "月賦", "answers": [ "げっぷ" ], "comment": "monthly installment (instalment); monthly payment" },
	{ "question": "月間", "answers": [ "げっかん" ], "comment": "month-long period; (during) month" },
	{ "question": "月面", "answers": [ "げつめん" ], "comment": "moon's surface" },
	{ "question": "月額", "answers": [ "げつがく" ], "comment": "monthly amount (sum)" },
	{ "question": "月食", "answers": [ "げっしょく" ], "comment": "lunar eclipse" },
	{ "question": "有", "answers": [ "ゆう" ], "comment": "existence\npossession; having\nlimited company" },
	{ "question": "有する", "answers": [ "ゆうする" ], "comment": "to own; to be endowed with" },
	{ "question": "有り様", "answers": [ "ありさま", "ありよう" ], "comment": "state; condition; circumstances; the way things are or should be; truth" },
	{ "question": "有事", "answers": [ "ゆうじ" ], "comment": "emergency" },
	{ "question": "有人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "manned; occupied; piloted" },
	{ "question": "有価証券", "answers": [ "ゆうかしょうけん" ], "comment": "marketable securities; stocks and bonds" },
	{ "question": "有償", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; consideration\nfor profit; non-free\nonerous" },
	{ "question": "有利", "answers": [ "ゆうり" ], "comment": "advantageous; better; profitable; lucrative" },
	{ "question": "有力", "answers": [ "ゆうりょく" ], "comment": "influential; prominent\nstrong; likely; plausible; potent" },
	{ "question": "有力者", "answers": [ "ゆうりょくしゃ" ], "comment": "influential person; man of importance" },
	{ "question": "有効", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "valid; effective\nyuko (judo)" },
	{ "question": "有名", "answers": [ "ゆうめい" ], "comment": "famous\nfame" },
	{ "question": "有害", "answers": [ "ゆうがい" ], "comment": "harmful; hazardous" },
	{ "question": "有志", "answers": [ "ゆうし" ], "comment": "voluntary; volunteer; sympathizer; sympathiser" },
	{ "question": "有意義", "answers": [ "ゆういぎ" ], "comment": "significant; useful; meaningful; worthwhile; valuable; of interest" },
	{ "question": "有数", "answers": [ "ゆうすう" ], "comment": "prominent; leading; foremost; distinguished" },
	{ "question": "有料", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "toll; fee; charge; admission-paid" },
	{ "question": "有望", "answers": [ "ゆうぼう" ], "comment": "good prospects; full of hope; promising" },
	{ "question": "有様", "answers": [ "ありさま", "ありよう" ], "comment": "state; condition; circumstances; the way things are or should be; truth" },
	{ "question": "有権者", "answers": [ "ゆうけんしゃ" ], "comment": "voter; constituent; (electoral) franchise-holder; (the) electorate; eligible voters" },
	{ "question": "有機", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "organic" },
	{ "question": "有機物", "answers": [ "ゆうきぶつ" ], "comment": "organic matter" },
	{ "question": "有毒", "answers": [ "ゆうどく" ], "comment": "poisonous; toxic" },
	{ "question": "有無", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "existence or nonexistence; presence or absence\nconsent or refusal; yes or no\nflag indicator; presence or absence marker" },
	{ "question": "有用", "answers": [ "ゆうよう" ], "comment": "useful; helpful" },
	{ "question": "有益", "answers": [ "ゆうえき" ], "comment": "beneficial; profitable" },
	{ "question": "有給", "answers": [ "ゆうきゅう" ], "comment": "salaried; with pay\nvacation; (paid) holiday" },
	{ "question": "有線", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "communicate by wire" },
	{ "question": "有罪", "answers": [ "ゆうざい" ], "comment": "guilt; culpability" },
	{ "question": "有能", "answers": [ "ゆうのう" ], "comment": "able; capable; efficient; skill" },
	{ "question": "有識者", "answers": [ "ゆうしきしゃ" ], "comment": "expert; knowledgeable person" },
	{ "question": "有限", "answers": [ "ゆうげん" ], "comment": "finite; limited" },
	{ "question": "有頂天", "answers": [ "うちょうてん" ], "comment": "ecstasy" },
	{ "question": "服", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "clothes (esp. Western clothes)\ncounter for doses of medicine, gulps of tea, drags of a cigarette, etc." },
	{ "question": "服役", "answers": [ "ふくえき" ], "comment": "penal servitude; military service" },
	{ "question": "服従", "answers": [ "ふくじゅう" ], "comment": "obedience; submission; resignation" },
	{ "question": "服用", "answers": [ "ふくよう" ], "comment": "taking medicine; dosing" },
	{ "question": "服装", "answers": [ "ふくそう" ], "comment": "garments; attire" },
	{ "question": "服飾", "answers": [ "ふくしょく" ], "comment": "clothing and accessories; attire" },
	{ "question": "朗らか", "answers": [ "ほがらか" ], "comment": "bright; cheerful; melodious" },
	{ "question": "朗報", "answers": [ "ろうほう" ], "comment": "good news" },
	{ "question": "朗読", "answers": [ "ろうどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud; recitation" },
	{ "question": "望ましい", "answers": [ "のぞましい" ], "comment": "desirable; hoped for; preferable; advisable" },
	{ "question": "望み", "answers": [ "のぞみ" ], "comment": "wish; desire; hope\nprospect; expectation; (one's) hopes" },
	{ "question": "望む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "to desire\nto wish for; to expect\nto see; to command (a view of)" },
	{ "question": "望月", "answers": [ "もちづき", "ぼうげつ" ], "comment": "full moon; 15th day of the lunar calendar\nfull moon of the eighth lunar month" },
	{ "question": "望遠鏡", "answers": [ "ぼうえんきょう" ], "comment": "telescope" },
	{ "question": "朝", "answers": [ "あさ", "あした" ], "comment": "morning" },
	{ "question": "朝ご飯", "answers": [ "あさごはん" ], "comment": "breakfast" },
	{ "question": "朝一番", "answers": [ "あさいちばん" ], "comment": "first thing in the morning" },
	{ "question": "朝刊", "answers": [ "ちょうかん" ], "comment": "morning newspaper" },
	{ "question": "朝夕", "answers": [ "ちょうせき", "あさゆう" ], "comment": "morning and evening; from morning until night; constantly" },
	{ "question": "朝御飯", "answers": [ "あさごはん" ], "comment": "breakfast" },
	{ "question": "朝方", "answers": [ "あさがた" ], "comment": "early morning; early hours; toward morning" },
	{ "question": "朝日", "answers": [ "あさひ" ], "comment": "morning sun" },
	{ "question": "朝礼", "answers": [ "ちょうれい" ], "comment": "morning assembly (company, school, etc.); pep talk" },
	{ "question": "朝顔", "answers": [ "あさがお" ], "comment": "Japanese morning glory (Ipomoea nil, Pharbitis nil)\nany funnel shaped object; bell (i.e. of a trumpet); funnel-shaped urinal" },
	{ "question": "朝食", "answers": [ "あさげ", "ちょうしょく" ], "comment": "breakfast" },
	{ "question": "朝飯", "answers": [ "あさめし", "あさはん" ], "comment": "breakfast" },
	{ "question": "朝鮮", "answers": [ "ちょうせん" ], "comment": "Korea" },
	{ "question": "朝鮮半島", "answers": [ "ちょうせんはんとう" ], "comment": "Korean peninsula" },
	{ "question": "朝鮮民主主義人民共和国", "answers": [ "ちょうせんみんしゅしゅぎじんみんきょうわこく" ], "comment": "Democratic People's Republic of Korea (North Korea); DPRK" },
	{ "question": "期待", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; hope" },
	{ "question": "期待感", "answers": [ "きたいかん" ], "comment": "feeling of expectation" },
	{ "question": "期日", "answers": [ "きじつ", "きにち" ], "comment": "fixed date; settlement date" },
	{ "question": "期末", "answers": [ "きまつ" ], "comment": "end of term" },
	{ "question": "期間", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "period; term; interval" },
	{ "question": "期間限定", "answers": [ "きかんげんてい" ], "comment": "limited time\nlimited-time offer" },
	{ "question": "期限", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "term; period; time frame\ntime limit; deadline; cutoff (date)" },
	{ "question": "木", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "tree; shrub; bush\nwood; timber" },
	{ "question": "木々", "answers": [ "きぎ" ], "comment": "every tree; many trees; all kinds of trees" },
	{ "question": "木の実", "answers": [ "このみ", "きのみ" ], "comment": "nut; fruit; berry" },
	{ "question": "木の葉", "answers": [ "このは", "きのは" ], "comment": "foliage; leaves of trees" },
	{ "question": "木場", "answers": [ "きば" ], "comment": "lumberyard" },
	{ "question": "木工", "answers": [ "もっこう" ], "comment": "woodworking; woodworker; carpenter" },
	{ "question": "木戸", "answers": [ "きど" ], "comment": "wicket gate; wooden door\nentrance to an entertainment venue (i.e. sumo arena, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "木星", "answers": [ "もくせい" ], "comment": "Jupiter (planet)" },
	{ "question": "木曜", "answers": [ "もくよう" ], "comment": "Thursday" },
	{ "question": "木曜日", "answers": [ "もくようび" ], "comment": "Thursday" },
	{ "question": "木材", "answers": [ "もくざい" ], "comment": "lumber; timber; wood" },
	{ "question": "木枯し", "answers": [ "こがらし" ], "comment": "cold wintry wind" },
	{ "question": "木枯らし", "answers": [ "こがらし" ], "comment": "cold wintry wind" },
	{ "question": "木炭", "answers": [ "もくたん" ], "comment": "charcoal" },
	{ "question": "木製", "answers": [ "もくせい" ], "comment": "wooden; made of wood" },
	{ "question": "木造", "answers": [ "もくぞう" ], "comment": "wooden; made of wood" },
	{ "question": "未", "answers": [ "ひつじ" ], "comment": "eighth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Ram, 1pm-3pm, south-southwest, June)" },
	{ "question": "未亡人", "answers": [ "みぼうじん" ], "comment": "widow" },
	{ "question": "未婚", "answers": [ "みこん" ], "comment": "unmarried" },
	{ "question": "未定", "answers": [ "みてい" ], "comment": "not yet fixed; undecided; pending" },
	{ "question": "未成年", "answers": [ "みせいねん" ], "comment": "minor; not of age" },
	{ "question": "未払い", "answers": [ "みばらい", "みはらい" ], "comment": "unpaid; overdue" },
	{ "question": "未明", "answers": [ "みめい" ], "comment": "early dawn; grey of morning; gray of morning" },
	{ "question": "未来", "answers": [ "みらい" ], "comment": "the future (usually distant)\nfuture tense\nthe world to come" },
	{ "question": "未満", "answers": [ "みまん" ], "comment": "less than; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "未然", "answers": [ "みぜん" ], "comment": "before it happens; previously" },
	{ "question": "未熟", "answers": [ "みじゅく" ], "comment": "unripe; green\ninexperienced; immature; unskilled" },
	{ "question": "未熟児", "answers": [ "みじゅくじ" ], "comment": "premature baby" },
	{ "question": "未発表", "answers": [ "みはっぴょう" ], "comment": "unpublished; not yet announced" },
	{ "question": "未知", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "not yet known; unknown; strange" },
	{ "question": "未知数", "answers": [ "みちすう" ], "comment": "(an) unknown; unknown number; variable\nunknown quantity; not yet known" },
	{ "question": "未納", "answers": [ "みのう" ], "comment": "payment default; overdue on a payment" },
	{ "question": "未練", "answers": [ "みれん" ], "comment": "lingering affection; attachment; regret; regrets; reluctance; ruefulness" },
	{ "question": "未解決", "answers": [ "みかいけつ" ], "comment": "unsettled; pending; unresolved" },
	{ "question": "未遂", "answers": [ "みすい" ], "comment": "attempt (e.g. at crime)" },
	{ "question": "未開", "answers": [ "みかい" ], "comment": "savage land; backward region; uncivilized; uncivilised" },
	{ "question": "末", "answers": [ "すえ", "まつ" ], "comment": "tip; top\nend; close (e.g. close of the month)\nyoungest child\ndescendants; offspring; posterity\nfuture\nfinally\ntrivialities /\n the end of\npowder" },
	{ "question": "末っ子", "answers": [ "すえっこ" ], "comment": "youngest child" },
	{ "question": "末に", "answers": [ "すえに" ], "comment": "finally; after; following\nat the end (of)" },
	{ "question": "末広", "answers": [ "すえひろ" ], "comment": "spreading out like an open fan\nbecoming prosperous\nfolding fan; ceremonial folding fan" },
	{ "question": "末日", "answers": [ "まつじつ" ], "comment": "last day (of a month)" },
	{ "question": "末期", "answers": [ "まっき" ], "comment": "closing years (period, days); last stage; end stage; end-of-life (care, decision making, etc.)\nterminal (e.g. cancer, disease, etc.); final" },
	{ "question": "末期的", "answers": [ "まっきてき" ], "comment": "terminal; final" },
	{ "question": "末端", "answers": [ "まったん" ], "comment": "end; tip; extremities; terminal" },
	{ "question": "本", "answers": [ "ほん", "もと" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\n(somebody's) side; (somebody's) location\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\ncounter for blades of grass, tree trunks, etc., and for falcons (in falconry)\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip /\n book; volume; script\nthis; present\nmain; head\nreal; regular\ncounter for long cylindrical things; counter for films, TV shows, etc.; counter for goals, home runs, etc.; counter for telephone calls" },
	{ "question": "本予算", "answers": [ "ほんよさん" ], "comment": "main budget" },
	{ "question": "本人", "answers": [ "ほんにん" ], "comment": "the person himself" },
	{ "question": "本件", "answers": [ "ほんけん" ], "comment": "this matter; this case" },
	{ "question": "本会議", "answers": [ "ほんかいぎ" ], "comment": "plenary session; regular session" },
	{ "question": "本位", "answers": [ "ほんい" ], "comment": "standard; basis; principle" },
	{ "question": "本体", "answers": [ "ほんたい" ], "comment": "substance; real form\nmain part; main unit; body (of a machine)\nthis machine; this appliance\nobject of worship (at a shrine, temple, etc.)\nnoumenon\nbase price; pre-tax price" },
	{ "question": "本名", "answers": [ "ほんめい", "ほんみょう" ], "comment": "real name" },
	{ "question": "本命", "answers": [ "ほんめい" ], "comment": "favorite (to win); favourite; likely winner\none's heart's desire; first choice" },
	{ "question": "本因坊", "answers": [ "ほんいんぼう" ], "comment": "Honinbō; grand master of the game of go" },
	{ "question": "本国", "answers": [ "ほんごく" ], "comment": "one's own country" },
	{ "question": "本土", "answers": [ "ほんど" ], "comment": "mainland; one's home country; the country proper" },
	{ "question": "本堂", "answers": [ "ほんどう" ], "comment": "main temple building; nave" },
	{ "question": "本場", "answers": [ "ほんば" ], "comment": "home; habitat; center; centre; best place\nauthentic; genuine" },
	{ "question": "本塁", "answers": [ "ほんるい" ], "comment": "base; stronghold; main fort\nhome base; home plate" },
	{ "question": "本塁打", "answers": [ "ほんるいだ" ], "comment": "home run" },
	{ "question": "本家", "answers": [ "ほんけ" ], "comment": "head house (family); birthplace; originator" },
	{ "question": "本屋", "answers": [ "ほんや" ], "comment": "bookstore; bookshop\npublisher\nmain building" },
	{ "question": "本山", "answers": [ "ほんざん" ], "comment": "head temple; this temple" },
	{ "question": "本島", "answers": [ "ほんとう" ], "comment": "main island\nthis island" },
	{ "question": "本年", "answers": [ "ほんねん" ], "comment": "this (current) year" },
	{ "question": "本店", "answers": [ "ほんだな", "ほんてん" ], "comment": "head office; flagship store; main store\nthis store" },
	{ "question": "本当", "answers": [ "ほんとう" ], "comment": "truth; reality; actuality; fact\nproper; right; correct; official\ngenuine; authentic; natural; veritable" },
	{ "question": "本当に", "answers": [ "ほんとうに", "ホントーに", "ホントに", "ホントウに" ], "comment": "really; truly" },
	{ "question": "本心", "answers": [ "ほんしん" ], "comment": "true feelings" },
	{ "question": "本拠", "answers": [ "ほんきょ" ], "comment": "stronghold; inner citadel; base; headquarters" },
	{ "question": "本数", "answers": [ "ほんすう" ], "comment": "number of long thin objects (movies, TV programs, baseball games, etc.) (programmes)" },
	{ "question": "本文", "answers": [ "ほんもん", "ほんぶん" ], "comment": "text (of document); body (of letter)" },
	{ "question": "本日", "answers": [ "ほんじつ" ], "comment": "today" },
	{ "question": "本書", "answers": [ "ほんしょ" ], "comment": "text; script; this book" },
	{ "question": "本朝", "answers": [ "ほんちょう" ], "comment": "this land; our country; Imperial Court" },
	{ "question": "本木", "answers": [ "もとき" ], "comment": "original stock" },
	{ "question": "本来", "answers": [ "ほんらい" ], "comment": "originally; primarily\nessentially; naturally; by nature; in (and of) itself\nproper; legal" },
	{ "question": "本格", "answers": [ "ほんかく" ], "comment": "original method or procedure\nserious; orthodox; classical; genuine" },
	{ "question": "本格化", "answers": [ "ほんかくか" ], "comment": "regularization; regularisation; getting up speed; proceeding at full tilt" },
	{ "question": "本格的", "answers": [ "ほんかくてき" ], "comment": "genuine; real; regular; normal; typical; standard; orthodox\nfull-scale; full-blown; all-out\nfull-fledged; professional" },
	{ "question": "本棚", "answers": [ "ほんだな" ], "comment": "bookshelves; bookshelf; bookcase" },
	{ "question": "本業", "answers": [ "ほんぎょう" ], "comment": "principal occupation; core business" },
	{ "question": "本欄", "answers": [ "ほんらん" ], "comment": "this column" },
	{ "question": "本気", "answers": [ "ほんき" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness; truth; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "本流", "answers": [ "ほんりゅう" ], "comment": "main course (of a river)\nmainstream; main current (e.g. of thought)" },
	{ "question": "本物", "answers": [ "ほんもの" ], "comment": "genuine article; real thing; real deal" },
	{ "question": "本番", "answers": [ "ほんばん" ], "comment": "performance; take; going before an audience or on-air\ngame; season; crucial moment\nactual sexual intercourse (i.e. not simulated); penetration" },
	{ "question": "本省", "answers": [ "ほんしょう" ], "comment": "this ministry; the home office" },
	{ "question": "本社", "answers": [ "ほんしゃ" ], "comment": "head office; main office; headquarters; parent company\nmain shrine\nthis company; this shrine" },
	{ "question": "本箱", "answers": [ "ほんばこ" ], "comment": "bookcase" },
	{ "question": "本籍", "answers": [ "ほんせき" ], "comment": "one's registered domicile (as recorded in the family register); one's legal domicile (as opposed to where one lives)" },
	{ "question": "本紙", "answers": [ "ほんし" ], "comment": "this newspaper" },
	{ "question": "本線", "answers": [ "ほんせん" ], "comment": "main line" },
	{ "question": "本職", "answers": [ "ほんしょく" ], "comment": "principal occupation; main job\nprofessional; an expert; specialist\nI (of a government official, etc.); me" },
	{ "question": "本能", "answers": [ "ほんのう" ], "comment": "instinct" },
	{ "question": "本腰", "answers": [ "ほんごし" ], "comment": "strenuous effort; earnestness; seriousness" },
	{ "question": "本調子", "answers": [ "ほんちょうし" ], "comment": "normal condition\nkeynote; proper key" },
	{ "question": "本質", "answers": [ "ほんしつ" ], "comment": "essence; true nature; substance; reality" },
	{ "question": "本部", "answers": [ "ほんぶ" ], "comment": "headquarters; head office; main office" },
	{ "question": "本隊", "answers": [ "ほんたい" ], "comment": "main body (of an army); main force\nthese troops" },
	{ "question": "本音", "answers": [ "ほんね" ], "comment": "real intention; motive; true opinion; what one really thinks" },
	{ "question": "本領", "answers": [ "ほんりょう" ], "comment": "speciality; specialty; characteristic\nproper function; duty\noriginal fief" },
	{ "question": "本願", "answers": [ "ほんがん" ], "comment": "Amida Buddha's original vow; long-cherished desire" },
	{ "question": "本館", "answers": [ "ほんかん" ], "comment": "main building" },
	{ "question": "札", "answers": [ "さつ", "ふだ" ], "comment": "note; paper money /\n ticket; token; check; receipt\nlabel; tag\nsign; card; plate\nplaying card\ncharm; talisman\nslips of paper posted on shrine pillars by pilgrims" },
	{ "question": "札束", "answers": [ "さつたば" ], "comment": "roll of banknotes" },
	{ "question": "朱", "answers": [ "しゅ", "あけ" ], "comment": "scarlet; red\nblood" },
	{ "question": "机", "answers": [ "つくえ" ], "comment": "desk" },
	{ "question": "机上", "answers": [ "きじょう" ], "comment": "on the desk\ntheoretical; academic" },
	{ "question": "杉", "answers": [ "すぎ" ], "comment": "Japanese cedar (Cryptomeria japonica)" },
	{ "question": "材料", "answers": [ "ざいりょう" ], "comment": "ingredients; material\nmaterial (for a novel, experiment, etc.); subject matter; data\nbasis (for a decision); grounds; evidence\n(market) factor" },
	{ "question": "材木", "answers": [ "ざいもく" ], "comment": "lumber; timber" },
	{ "question": "材質", "answers": [ "ざいしつ" ], "comment": "material\nmaterial properties; quality of material" },
	{ "question": "村", "answers": [ "むら" ], "comment": "village" },
	{ "question": "村人", "answers": [ "むらびと" ], "comment": "villager" },
	{ "question": "村民", "answers": [ "そんみん" ], "comment": "villager" },
	{ "question": "村議会", "answers": [ "そんぎかい" ], "comment": "village assembly" },
	{ "question": "村長", "answers": [ "むらおさ", "そんちょう" ], "comment": "village headman; village mayor" },
	{ "question": "杖", "answers": [ "つえ" ], "comment": "cane; walking stick; staff; wand" },
	{ "question": "束", "answers": [ "たば" ], "comment": "bundle; bunch; sheaf" },
	{ "question": "束ねる", "answers": [ "たばねる", "つかねる" ], "comment": "to tie up in a bundle (e.g. straw, hair, bills, letters); to bundle; to sheathe\nto govern; to manage; to control; to administer\nto fold (one's arms)" },
	{ "question": "束の間", "answers": [ "つかのま" ], "comment": "moment; brief time; brief; transient" },
	{ "question": "束縛", "answers": [ "そくばく" ], "comment": "restraint; restriction; fetters; yoke; shackles\nbinding; confinement with rope" },
	{ "question": "条件", "answers": [ "じょうけん" ], "comment": "condition; conditions; term; terms; requirement; requirements" },
	{ "question": "条件付き", "answers": [ "じょうけんつき" ], "comment": "conditionally; with conditions attached" },
	{ "question": "条例", "answers": [ "じょうれい" ], "comment": "regulations; rules\n(local) regulation; ordinance; bylaw; law" },
	{ "question": "条文", "answers": [ "じょうぶん" ], "comment": "text; provisions (act, treaty)" },
	{ "question": "条約", "answers": [ "じょうやく" ], "comment": "treaty; pact" },
	{ "question": "条項", "answers": [ "じょうこう" ], "comment": "clause; article; stipulations" },
	{ "question": "来", "answers": [ "らい" ], "comment": "next (year, etc.)\nsince (last month, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "来る", "answers": [ "くる", "きたる" ], "comment": "to come (spatially or temporally); to approach; to arrive\nto come back; to do ... and come back\nto come to be; to become; to get; to grow; to continue\nto come from; to be caused by; to derive from\nto come to (i.e. \"when it comes to spinach ...\")" },
	{ "question": "来客", "answers": [ "らいかく", "らいきゃく" ], "comment": "visitor; caller" },
	{ "question": "来年", "answers": [ "らいねん" ], "comment": "next year" },
	{ "question": "来店", "answers": [ "らいてん" ], "comment": "coming to the store" },
	{ "question": "来日", "answers": [ "らいにち" ], "comment": "arrival in Japan; coming to Japan; visit to Japan" },
	{ "question": "来春", "answers": [ "らいはる", "らいしゅん" ], "comment": "next spring" },
	{ "question": "来月", "answers": [ "らいげつ" ], "comment": "next month" },
	{ "question": "来訪", "answers": [ "らいほう" ], "comment": "visit; call" },
	{ "question": "来賓", "answers": [ "らいひん" ], "comment": "guest; visitor; visitor's arrival" },
	{ "question": "来週", "answers": [ "らいしゅう" ], "comment": "next week" },
	{ "question": "杯", "answers": [ "さかづき", "さかずき", "うき" ], "comment": "sake cup; cup for alcoholic beverages" },
	{ "question": "東", "answers": [ "ひがし" ], "comment": "east" },
	{ "question": "東亜", "answers": [ "とうあ" ], "comment": "East Asia; the Orient" },
	{ "question": "東京", "answers": [ "とうきょう" ], "comment": "Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "東京証券取引所", "answers": [ "とうきょうしょうけんとりひきじょ" ], "comment": "Tokyo Stock Exchange; TSE" },
	{ "question": "東側", "answers": [ "とうそく", "ひがしがわ" ], "comment": "east side; east bank" },
	{ "question": "東北", "answers": [ "とうほく", "ひがしきた" ], "comment": "north-east\nTohoku (northernmost six prefectures of Honshu)" },
	{ "question": "東南", "answers": [ "ひがしみなみ", "とうなん" ], "comment": "south-east" },
	{ "question": "東口", "answers": [ "ひがしぐち" ], "comment": "east entrance" },
	{ "question": "東宮", "answers": [ "とうぐう" ], "comment": "crown prince" },
	{ "question": "東方", "answers": [ "とうほう", "ひがしかた", "ひがしがた" ], "comment": "eastern direction\nthe Orient\neastern fighter in a match (e.g. sumo wrestling)" },
	{ "question": "東欧", "answers": [ "とうおう" ], "comment": "Eastern Europe" },
	{ "question": "東洋", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "Orient" },
	{ "question": "東海", "answers": [ "とうかい" ], "comment": "region south of Tokyo on Pacific Ocean side of Japan; eastern sea\nEast Sea (controversial name for the Sea of Japan proposed by Korea)" },
	{ "question": "東独", "answers": [ "とうどく" ], "comment": "East Germany (1949-1990)" },
	{ "question": "東経", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "east longitude" },
	{ "question": "東西", "answers": [ "とうざい" ], "comment": "east and west\nOrient and Occident; East and West\nLadies and Gentlemen!; Your attention, please!; roll-up, roll-up" },
	{ "question": "東邦", "answers": [ "とうほう" ], "comment": "Oriental country; the Orient" },
	{ "question": "東部", "answers": [ "とうぶ" ], "comment": "eastern part; the east (of a region)" },
	{ "question": "東都", "answers": [ "とうと" ], "comment": "the Eastern Capital (now Tokyo); Yedo; Edo" },
	{ "question": "松", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "pine tree (Pinus spp.)\nhighest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "松原", "answers": [ "まつばら" ], "comment": "pine grove" },
	{ "question": "松葉", "answers": [ "まつば" ], "comment": "pine needle" },
	{ "question": "板", "answers": [ "いた" ], "comment": "board; plank\nsheet (of metal); plate (of glass); pane; slab\ncutting board; chopping board\nchef (esp. of high-end Japanese cuisine); cook\nstage (i.e. at a theatre)" },
	{ "question": "板ガラス", "answers": [ "いたガラス" ], "comment": "plate glass; sheet glass" },
	{ "question": "板門店", "answers": [ "はんもんてん" ], "comment": "Panmunjon" },
	{ "question": "枕", "answers": [ "まくら" ], "comment": "pillow; bolster\nintroduction (e.g. to a rakugo story); lead-in" },
	{ "question": "林", "answers": [ "はやし" ], "comment": "woods; forest; copse; thicket\nbunch; line (of something); collection" },
	{ "question": "林業", "answers": [ "りんぎょう" ], "comment": "forestry" },
	{ "question": "林立", "answers": [ "りんりつ" ], "comment": "standing close together; bristling (with)" },
	{ "question": "林道", "answers": [ "りんどう" ], "comment": "path through forest; woodland path\nlogging road" },
	{ "question": "林野", "answers": [ "りんや" ], "comment": "forests and fields" },
	{ "question": "林野庁", "answers": [ "りんやちょう" ], "comment": "Forestry Agency" },
	{ "question": "枚", "answers": [ "まい" ], "comment": "counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper)" },
	{ "question": "枚数", "answers": [ "まいすう" ], "comment": "the number of flat things\nwin-loss difference which influences the ranking of wrestlers" },
	{ "question": "果たして", "answers": [ "はたして" ], "comment": "as was expected; just as one thought; sure enough; as a result\nreally? (in questions); ever?" },
	{ "question": "果たす", "answers": [ "はたす" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out; to fulfill; to fulfil; to realize; to execute; to perform; to do\nto do ... completely; to do ... entirely" },
	{ "question": "果て", "answers": [ "はて" ], "comment": "the end; the extremity; the limit; the limits; the result" },
	{ "question": "果てしない", "answers": [ "はてしない" ], "comment": "endless; boundless; everlasting" },
	{ "question": "果実", "answers": [ "かじつ" ], "comment": "fruit; nut; berry" },
	{ "question": "果敢", "answers": [ "かかん" ], "comment": "resolute; determined; bold" },
	{ "question": "果樹", "answers": [ "かじゅ" ], "comment": "fruit tree" },
	{ "question": "果汁", "answers": [ "かじゅう" ], "comment": "fruit juice" },
	{ "question": "果物", "answers": [ "かぶつ", "くだもの" ], "comment": "fruit" },
	{ "question": "枝", "answers": [ "えだ" ], "comment": "branch; bow; bough; twig; limb" },
	{ "question": "枝葉", "answers": [ "しよう", "えだは" ], "comment": "branches and leaves; foliage\nunimportant details; nonessentials; side issue; digression" },
	{ "question": "枠", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "frame; framework\nborder; box\nlimit; restriction; quota" },
	{ "question": "枠内", "answers": [ "わくない" ], "comment": "within the limits (framework, boundaries, price, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "枠外", "answers": [ "わくがい" ], "comment": "beyond (the) limits" },
	{ "question": "枠組み", "answers": [ "わくぐみ" ], "comment": "frame\nframework; outline" },
	{ "question": "枯れる", "answers": [ "かれる" ], "comment": "to wither (of a plant); to be blasted; to die\nto mature (of one's personality, abilities, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "枯れ木", "answers": [ "かれき" ], "comment": "dead tree; dry wood" },
	{ "question": "枯れ葉", "answers": [ "かれは" ], "comment": "dead leaf; dry leaves" },
	{ "question": "枯木", "answers": [ "かれき" ], "comment": "dead tree; dry wood" },
	{ "question": "枯葉", "answers": [ "かれは" ], "comment": "dead leaf; dry leaves" },
	{ "question": "架橋", "answers": [ "かきょう" ], "comment": "bridge building; bridge\ncross-linking" },
	{ "question": "架空", "answers": [ "かくう" ], "comment": "aerial; overhead\nfictitious; imaginary; fanciful; fabricated" },
	{ "question": "柄", "answers": [ "え", "がら" ], "comment": "handle; grip\nstalk (of a mushroom, leaf, etc.) /\n pattern; design\nbody build; figure; physique\nessential qualities; character; nature\nappropriate to; fitting of; suitable for" },
	{ "question": "柏", "answers": [ "かしわ" ], "comment": "oak; daimyo oak; Japanese emperor oak; Quercus dentata" },
	{ "question": "柏木", "answers": [ "かしわぎ" ], "comment": "oak-tree" },
	{ "question": "染まる", "answers": [ "そまる" ], "comment": "to be dyed\nto be tainted; to be infected; to be stained; to be steeped" },
	{ "question": "染め", "answers": [ "そめ" ], "comment": "dyeing; printing" },
	{ "question": "染める", "answers": [ "そめる" ], "comment": "to dye; to colour; to color" },
	{ "question": "染色", "answers": [ "せんしょく" ], "comment": "staining; stain; dyeing" },
	{ "question": "染色体", "answers": [ "せんしょくたい" ], "comment": "chromosome" },
	{ "question": "柔らか", "answers": [ "やわらか" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; subdued (colour or light) (color); gentle; meek" },
	{ "question": "柔らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; limber\ngentle; mild\ninformal; lighter" },
	{ "question": "柔軟", "answers": [ "じゅうなん" ], "comment": "flexible; lithe; soft; pliable" },
	{ "question": "柔道", "answers": [ "じゅうどう" ], "comment": "judo" },
	{ "question": "柱", "answers": [ "はしら" ], "comment": "pillar; post\nsupport; prop; mainstay\ncounter for buddhas, gods, nobles, etc." },
	{ "question": "柳", "answers": [ "ようりゅう", "やなぎ" ], "comment": "willow (any tree of genus Salix)\nweeping willow (Salix babylonica)" },
	{ "question": "柴", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "brushwood; firewood" },
	{ "question": "査定", "answers": [ "さてい" ], "comment": "assessment; investigation; audit; revision" },
	{ "question": "査察", "answers": [ "ささつ" ], "comment": "inspection (for compliance); investigation (tax, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "査証", "answers": [ "さしょう" ], "comment": "visa" },
	{ "question": "柿", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "kaki; Japanese persimmon (Diospyros kaki)" },
	{ "question": "栄える", "answers": [ "さかえる", "はえる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto shine; to look attractive; to look pretty" },
	{ "question": "栄光", "answers": [ "えいこう" ], "comment": "glory" },
	{ "question": "栄冠", "answers": [ "えいかん" ], "comment": "laurels; garland" },
	{ "question": "栄誉", "answers": [ "えいよ" ], "comment": "honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "栄養", "answers": [ "えいよう" ], "comment": "nutrition; nourishment" },
	{ "question": "栄養士", "answers": [ "えいようし" ], "comment": "nutritionist" },
	{ "question": "栄養失調", "answers": [ "えいようしっちょう" ], "comment": "malnutrition" },
	{ "question": "栄養学", "answers": [ "えいようがく" ], "comment": "dietetics; nutritional science" },
	{ "question": "栄養素", "answers": [ "えいようそ" ], "comment": "nutrient" },
	{ "question": "栓", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "stopper; cork; stopcock" },
	{ "question": "栓抜き", "answers": [ "せんぬき" ], "comment": "bottle opener; corkscrew" },
	{ "question": "校内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "within a school" },
	{ "question": "校則", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "school regulations" },
	{ "question": "校庭", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "schoolyard; campus" },
	{ "question": "校歌", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "school song" },
	{ "question": "校舎", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "school building" },
	{ "question": "校長", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "principal; headmaster" },
	{ "question": "校門", "answers": [ "こうもん" ], "comment": "school gate" },
	{ "question": "株", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "stock; share\nstump\nroot; rootstock\nstrain (of bacteria, etc.)\ntradeable rank; goodwill\none's forte" },
	{ "question": "株主", "answers": [ "かぶぬし" ], "comment": "shareholder; stockholder" },
	{ "question": "株価", "answers": [ "かぶか" ], "comment": "stock prices" },
	{ "question": "株券", "answers": [ "かぶけん" ], "comment": "stock certificate" },
	{ "question": "株式", "answers": [ "かぶしき" ], "comment": "stock (company)" },
	{ "question": "株式会社", "answers": [ "かぶしきがいしゃ" ], "comment": "public company; corporation; KK; formula for an incorporated public company" },
	{ "question": "核", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "pit (of a fruit); stone\ncore\nnucleus; nuclear\nnuclear weaponry" },
	{ "question": "核兵器", "answers": [ "かくへいき" ], "comment": "nuclear weapon" },
	{ "question": "核分裂", "answers": [ "かくぶんれつ" ], "comment": "nuclear fission\nkaryokinesis (division of a cell nucleus during mitosis or meiosis)" },
	{ "question": "核実験", "answers": [ "かくじっけん" ], "comment": "nuclear (bomb) test" },
	{ "question": "核家族", "answers": [ "かくかぞく" ], "comment": "nuclear family" },
	{ "question": "核弾頭", "answers": [ "かくだんとう" ], "comment": "nuclear warhead" },
	{ "question": "核心", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "core; heart (of the matter); point; crux; kernel" },
	{ "question": "核武装", "answers": [ "かくぶそう" ], "comment": "nuclear arms" },
	{ "question": "核燃料", "answers": [ "かくねんりょう" ], "comment": "atomic fuel; nuclear fuel" },
	{ "question": "核融合", "answers": [ "かくゆうごう" ], "comment": "nuclear fusion" },
	{ "question": "核酸", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "nucleic acid" },
	{ "question": "根", "answers": [ "ね" ], "comment": "root (of a plant)\nroot (of a tooth, hair, etc.); center (of a pimple, etc.)\nroot (of all evil, etc.); source; origin; cause; basis\none's true nature\n(fishing) reef" },
	{ "question": "根ざす", "answers": [ "ねざす" ], "comment": "to come from; to have roots in" },
	{ "question": "根っこ", "answers": [ "ねっこ" ], "comment": "root; stub; stump" },
	{ "question": "根っ子", "answers": [ "ねっこ" ], "comment": "root; stub; stump" },
	{ "question": "根元", "answers": [ "こんげん", "ねもと", "こんぽん" ], "comment": "root; source; origin; foundation; base; principle" },
	{ "question": "根回し", "answers": [ "ねまわし" ], "comment": "making necessary arrangements; laying the groundwork\ndigging around the roots of a tree (before transplanting)" },
	{ "question": "根幹", "answers": [ "こんかん" ], "comment": "foundation; root; basis; core; fundamentals\nroot and trunk" },
	{ "question": "根底", "answers": [ "こんてい" ], "comment": "root; basis; foundation" },
	{ "question": "根性", "answers": [ "こんじょう" ], "comment": "willpower; guts; determination; grit; spirit\ncharacter; nature; disposition; personality" },
	{ "question": "根拠", "answers": [ "こんきょ" ], "comment": "basis; foundation" },
	{ "question": "根掘り葉掘り", "answers": [ "ねほりはほり" ], "comment": "inquisitively; pryingly; nosily; thoroughly; persistently; through-and-through" },
	{ "question": "根本", "answers": [ "こんげん", "ねもと", "こんぽん" ], "comment": "root; source; origin; foundation; base; principle" },
	{ "question": "根本的", "answers": [ "こんぽんてき" ], "comment": "fundamental; basic" },
	{ "question": "根気", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "patience; perseverance; persistence; tenacity; energy" },
	{ "question": "根源", "answers": [ "こんげん", "ねもと", "こんぽん" ], "comment": "root; source; origin; foundation; base; principle" },
	{ "question": "根絶", "answers": [ "こんぜつ" ], "comment": "eradication; extermination" },
	{ "question": "格", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "status; position; rank\nmethod; way; style\nrule; regulation; law\ngrammatical case\nfigure (syllogism)" },
	{ "question": "格上げ", "answers": [ "かくあげ" ], "comment": "status elevation" },
	{ "question": "格付け", "answers": [ "かくづけ" ], "comment": "rating; classification; allocation; grading" },
	{ "question": "格別", "answers": [ "かくべつ" ], "comment": "particular; special; exceptional; especial\nparticularly; especially; exceptionally" },
	{ "question": "格好", "answers": [ "かっこう", "かっこ" ], "comment": "shape; form; figure; posture; pose\nappearance\nstate; situation\nsuitable; fit; reasonable\nabout" },
	{ "question": "格子", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "lattice; latticework; window bars; grid; grating" },
	{ "question": "格安", "answers": [ "かくやす" ], "comment": "cheap; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "格安航空券", "answers": [ "かくやすこうくうけん" ], "comment": "discount airline ticket" },
	{ "question": "格差", "answers": [ "かくさ" ], "comment": "qualitative difference; disparity" },
	{ "question": "格段", "answers": [ "かくだん" ], "comment": "special; exceptional; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "格闘", "answers": [ "かくとう" ], "comment": "hand-to-hand fighting; grappling; scuffling" },
	{ "question": "栽培", "answers": [ "さいばい" ], "comment": "cultivation" },
	{ "question": "桁", "answers": [ "けた" ], "comment": "column; beam; girder; crossbeam; spar; yard\ndigit; decade; order of magnitude" },
	{ "question": "桂", "answers": [ "かつら" ], "comment": "katsura (Cercidiphyllum japonicum); Japanese Judas tree" },
	{ "question": "桃", "answers": [ "もも" ], "comment": "peach (Prunus persica)" },
	{ "question": "案", "answers": [ "あん" ], "comment": "idea; plan; thought\ndraft plan; motion; rough copy\nexpectation" },
	{ "question": "案の定", "answers": [ "あんのじょう" ], "comment": "just as one thought; as usual; sure enough" },
	{ "question": "案件", "answers": [ "あんけん" ], "comment": "matter in question; subject; case; item" },
	{ "question": "案内", "answers": [ "あんない" ], "comment": "information; guidance; leading\nto guide; to show (around); to conduct" },
	{ "question": "案外", "answers": [ "あんがい" ], "comment": "unexpectedly; surprisingly\nunexpected; unanticipated; unforeseen; surprising" },
	{ "question": "桐", "answers": [ "きり" ], "comment": "paulownia tree; Paulownia tomentosa" },
	{ "question": "桑", "answers": [ "くわ" ], "comment": "mulberry (tree)" },
	{ "question": "桑原", "answers": [ "くわばら" ], "comment": "mulberry field" },
	{ "question": "桑田", "answers": [ "そうでん" ], "comment": "mulberry plantation" },
	{ "question": "桜", "answers": [ "さくら" ], "comment": "cherry tree; cherry blossom\ndecoy; fake buyer; shill\nhired applauder\nhorse meat" },
	{ "question": "桟橋", "answers": [ "さんきょう", "さんばし" ], "comment": "wharf; bridge; jetty; pier" },
	{ "question": "桶", "answers": [ "おけ" ], "comment": "bucket" },
	{ "question": "梁", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "beam; joist" },
	{ "question": "梅", "answers": [ "うめ" ], "comment": "Japanese apricot (Prunus mume); Chinese plum\nlowest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "梅干", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "umeboshi; pickled ume; pickled plum" },
	{ "question": "梅干し", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "umeboshi; pickled ume; pickled plum" },
	{ "question": "梅雨", "answers": [ "つゆ", "ばいう" ], "comment": "rainy season (in Japan from early June to mid-July)\nrain during the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "梅雨入り", "answers": [ "つゆいり", "にゅうばい" ], "comment": "entering the rainy season; beginning of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "梅雨明け", "answers": [ "つゆあけ" ], "comment": "the end of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "棄却", "answers": [ "ききゃく" ], "comment": "rejection; dismissal; abandoning; renunciation; waiver" },
	{ "question": "棄権", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "abstention (from voting); renunciation (of a right); withdrawal (from a contest)" },
	{ "question": "棋士", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "shogi player; go player" },
	{ "question": "棋聖", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "great master of go; great master of shogi" },
	{ "question": "棋院", "answers": [ "きいん" ], "comment": "go institution; go club; go hall" },
	{ "question": "棒", "answers": [ "ぼう" ], "comment": "pole; rod; stick" },
	{ "question": "棘", "answers": [ "とげ" ], "comment": "thorn; spine; prickle\nsplinter (esp. lodged in one's flesh); hard sharp item (esp. lodged in one's throat, e.g. fish bone)\nbiting words" },
	{ "question": "棚", "answers": [ "たな" ], "comment": "shelf; shelves; ledge; rack\ntrellis" },
	{ "question": "棚上げ", "answers": [ "たなあげ" ], "comment": "shelving; pigeonholing" },
	{ "question": "棟", "answers": [ "むね" ], "comment": "ridge (of roof)\nback of a sword\ncounter for buildings, apartments, etc." },
	{ "question": "森", "answers": [ "もり" ], "comment": "forest\nshrine grove" },
	{ "question": "森林", "answers": [ "しんりん" ], "comment": "forest; woods" },
	{ "question": "棺", "answers": [ "かん", "ひつぎ" ], "comment": "coffin; casket" },
	{ "question": "椀", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "bowl (wooden)" },
	{ "question": "椅子", "answers": [ "いす" ], "comment": "chair; stool\npost; office; position" },
	{ "question": "植える", "answers": [ "うえる" ], "comment": "to plant; to grow; to raise\nto insert; to transplant; to implant; to set (type)\nto inoculate (e.g. an infectious agent)\nto instill (idea, value, etc.); to instil; to inculcate" },
	{ "question": "植木", "answers": [ "うえき" ], "comment": "garden shrubs; trees; potted plant" },
	{ "question": "植林", "answers": [ "しょくりん" ], "comment": "afforestation" },
	{ "question": "植樹", "answers": [ "しょくじゅ" ], "comment": "tree-planting" },
	{ "question": "植民地", "answers": [ "しょくみんち" ], "comment": "colony\ncolonial" },
	{ "question": "植物", "answers": [ "しょくぶつ" ], "comment": "plant; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "植物園", "answers": [ "しょくぶつえん" ], "comment": "botanical garden" },
	{ "question": "検事", "answers": [ "けんじ" ], "comment": "public prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "検事正", "answers": [ "けんじせい" ], "comment": "chief public prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "検出", "answers": [ "けんしゅつ" ], "comment": "detection; sense (e.g. sensor)" },
	{ "question": "検問", "answers": [ "けんもん" ], "comment": "inspection; examination; check" },
	{ "question": "検定", "answers": [ "けんてい" ], "comment": "official certification; approval; inspection\ncertification examination; licensing examination; licensure examination" },
	{ "question": "検察", "answers": [ "けんさつ" ], "comment": "examination; investigation; prosecution" },
	{ "question": "検察官", "answers": [ "けんさつかん" ], "comment": "public prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "検察庁", "answers": [ "けんさつちょう" ], "comment": "Public Prosecutor's Office" },
	{ "question": "検挙", "answers": [ "けんきょ" ], "comment": "arrest; roundup" },
	{ "question": "検査", "answers": [ "けんさ" ], "comment": "inspection (e.g. customs, factory); examination; scan (e.g. MRI, PET, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "検疫", "answers": [ "けんえき" ], "comment": "quarantine; medical inspection" },
	{ "question": "検索", "answers": [ "けんさく" ], "comment": "looking up (e.g. a word in a dictionary); retrieval (e.g. data); searching for; referring to" },
	{ "question": "検索条件", "answers": [ "けんさくじょうけん" ], "comment": "search criteria" },
	{ "question": "検視", "answers": [ "けんし" ], "comment": "autopsy; inquest; investigation of death" },
	{ "question": "検討", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "consideration; examination; investigation; study; scrutiny; discussion; analysis; review" },
	{ "question": "検診", "answers": [ "けんしん" ], "comment": "physical examination; medical examination; health checkup; health screening" },
	{ "question": "検証", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "verification; inspection" },
	{ "question": "検閲", "answers": [ "けんえつ" ], "comment": "censorship; inspection; examination" },
	{ "question": "楕円形", "answers": [ "だえんけい" ], "comment": "elliptical shape" },
	{ "question": "業", "answers": [ "ごう", "わざ", "ぎょう" ], "comment": "karma (i.e. actions committed in a former life)\ndeed; act; work; performance\nwork; business; company; agency\nstudy" },
	{ "question": "業務", "answers": [ "ぎょうむ" ], "comment": "business; affairs; duties; work; procedure; task; action; function; (business) operations; operational" },
	{ "question": "業界", "answers": [ "ぎょうかい" ], "comment": "business world; business circles; (the) industry" },
	{ "question": "業種", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゅ" ], "comment": "type of industry" },
	{ "question": "業績", "answers": [ "ぎょうせき" ], "comment": "achievement; performance; results; work; contribution" },
	{ "question": "業者", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゃ" ], "comment": "trader; merchant; vendor; supplier\nmanufacturer; contractor" },
	{ "question": "楯突く", "answers": [ "たてつく" ], "comment": "to oppose; to resist; to defy" },
	{ "question": "極まる", "answers": [ "きわまる" ], "comment": "to reach an extreme; to reach a limit; to terminate; to come to an end\nextremely\nto be stuck; to be in a dilemma; to be at a loss\nto be decided; to be settled" },
	{ "question": "極めて", "answers": [ "きわめて" ], "comment": "exceedingly; extremely; decisively" },
	{ "question": "極める", "answers": [ "きわめる" ], "comment": "to carry to extremes; to go to the end of something\nto investigate thoroughly; to master" },
	{ "question": "極力", "answers": [ "きょくりょく" ], "comment": "to the utmost; to the best of one's ability" },
	{ "question": "極右", "answers": [ "きょくう" ], "comment": "far right (in politics); extreme right; ultraconservative" },
	{ "question": "極度", "answers": [ "きょくど" ], "comment": "maximum; extreme; utmost; curvature" },
	{ "question": "極東", "answers": [ "きょくとう" ], "comment": "Far East" },
	{ "question": "極楽", "answers": [ "ごくらく" ], "comment": "Sukhavati (Amitabha's Pure Land)\nparadise" },
	{ "question": "極秘", "answers": [ "ごくひ" ], "comment": "absolute secrecy" },
	{ "question": "極端", "answers": [ "きょくたん" ], "comment": "extreme; extremity" },
	{ "question": "極限", "answers": [ "きょくげん" ], "comment": "utmost limits; extremity\nlimit" },
	{ "question": "楷書", "answers": [ "かいしょ" ], "comment": "square style of handwriting; printed style of handwriting; block style; standard style" },
	{ "question": "楼閣", "answers": [ "ろうかく" ], "comment": "multistoried building" },
	{ "question": "楽", "answers": [ "らく" ], "comment": "comfort; ease\nraku pottery" },
	{ "question": "楽しい", "answers": [ "たのしい" ], "comment": "enjoyable; fun" },
	{ "question": "楽しみ", "answers": [ "たのしみ" ], "comment": "enjoyment; pleasure; diversion; amusement; hobby\nanticipation; looking forward to" },
	{ "question": "楽しむ", "answers": [ "たのしむ" ], "comment": "to enjoy (oneself)" },
	{ "question": "楽器", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "musical instrument" },
	{ "question": "楽団", "answers": [ "がくだん" ], "comment": "orchestra; band" },
	{ "question": "楽園", "answers": [ "らくえん" ], "comment": "pleasure garden; paradise" },
	{ "question": "楽天的", "answers": [ "らくてんてき" ], "comment": "optimistic" },
	{ "question": "楽屋", "answers": [ "がくや" ], "comment": "dressing room; green room; backstage\nbehind the scenes; the inside; inside affairs" },
	{ "question": "楽曲", "answers": [ "がっきょく" ], "comment": "musical composition; tune" },
	{ "question": "楽章", "answers": [ "がくしょう" ], "comment": "(musical) movement" },
	{ "question": "楽観", "answers": [ "らっかん" ], "comment": "optimism" },
	{ "question": "楽観的", "answers": [ "らっかんてき" ], "comment": "optimistic; hopeful" },
	{ "question": "楽譜", "answers": [ "がくふ" ], "comment": "score; sheet music" },
	{ "question": "概念", "answers": [ "がいねん" ], "comment": "general idea; concept; notion" },
	{ "question": "概算", "answers": [ "がいさん" ], "comment": "approximation; rough estimate" },
	{ "question": "概要", "answers": [ "がいよう" ], "comment": "outline; summary; overview; abridgment; synopsis" },
	{ "question": "概論", "answers": [ "がいろん" ], "comment": "introduction; outline; general remarks" },
	{ "question": "構える", "answers": [ "かまえる" ], "comment": "to set up (a house, store, etc.); to build; to establish; to run; to maintain\nto have at the ready (e.g. a gun); to hold in preparation (e.g. a camera); to prepare in advance (e.g. a meal)\nto adopt a posture; to assume a stance; to stand ready; to be poised for\nto put on an air; to assume an attitude\nto stiffen; to tense up; to become formal\nto fabricate in order to deceive; to make up; to feign\nto plan; to scheme" },
	{ "question": "構内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "premises; grounds; campus; in-house" },
	{ "question": "構図", "answers": [ "こうず" ], "comment": "composition" },
	{ "question": "構想", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "plan; plot; idea; conception" },
	{ "question": "構成", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "organization; organisation; configuration; composition" },
	{ "question": "構築", "answers": [ "こうちく" ], "comment": "construction; building; putting up; erecting; creation; formulation; architecture (systems, agreement, etc)" },
	{ "question": "構造", "answers": [ "こうぞう" ], "comment": "structure; construction; makeup; framework; organization; pattern" },
	{ "question": "構造物", "answers": [ "こうぞうぶつ" ], "comment": "structure" },
	{ "question": "槍", "answers": [ "やり" ], "comment": "spear; lance\njavelin\nlance\njeering" },
	{ "question": "様", "answers": [ "さま" ], "comment": "Mr.; Mrs.; Miss; Ms.\nmakes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)\nstate; situation; appearance" },
	{ "question": "様々", "answers": [ "さまざま" ], "comment": "varied; various" },
	{ "question": "様変わり", "answers": [ "さまがわり" ], "comment": "changing completely" },
	{ "question": "様子", "answers": [ "ようす" ], "comment": "state; state of affairs; situation; circumstances\nappearance; look; aspect\nsign; indication" },
	{ "question": "様式", "answers": [ "ようしき" ], "comment": "style; form; pattern" },
	{ "question": "様相", "answers": [ "ようそう" ], "comment": "aspect; phase; condition\nmodality (philosophy)" },
	{ "question": "標本", "answers": [ "ひょうほん" ], "comment": "example; specimen; sample" },
	{ "question": "標準", "answers": [ "ひょうじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; level; norm" },
	{ "question": "標的", "answers": [ "ひょうてき" ], "comment": "target" },
	{ "question": "標語", "answers": [ "ひょうご" ], "comment": "motto; slogan; catchword" },
	{ "question": "標識", "answers": [ "ひょうしき" ], "comment": "sign; mark; flag" },
	{ "question": "標題", "answers": [ "ひょうだい" ], "comment": "title; index; heading; headline; caption" },
	{ "question": "標高", "answers": [ "ひょうこう" ], "comment": "elevation; height above sea level" },
	{ "question": "模倣", "answers": [ "もほう" ], "comment": "imitation; copying" },
	{ "question": "模型", "answers": [ "もけい" ], "comment": "model; dummy; maquette" },
	{ "question": "模擬", "answers": [ "もぎ" ], "comment": "imitation; sham; mock\nsimulation" },
	{ "question": "模擬試験", "answers": [ "もぎしけん" ], "comment": "trial examination; mock examination" },
	{ "question": "模様", "answers": [ "もよう" ], "comment": "pattern; figure; design\nstate; condition\nconjecture of the current situation; the way it seems\nmodel; pattern; example\nindicates that that noun seems likely (e.g. rain or storm)\nframework (in go); territorial framework; moyo" },
	{ "question": "模範", "answers": [ "もはん" ], "comment": "exemplar; exemplification; exemplum; model; example" },
	{ "question": "模索", "answers": [ "もさく" ], "comment": "groping (for); exploring for a solution" },
	{ "question": "権", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "right (to do something)\nauthority; power" },
	{ "question": "権利", "answers": [ "けんり" ], "comment": "right; privilege" },
	{ "question": "権力", "answers": [ "けんりょく" ], "comment": "(political) power; authority; influence" },
	{ "question": "権威", "answers": [ "けんい" ], "comment": "authority; power; influence" },
	{ "question": "権益", "answers": [ "けんえき" ], "comment": "(one's) interests" },
	{ "question": "権限", "answers": [ "けんげん" ], "comment": "power; authority; jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "横", "answers": [ "よこ" ], "comment": "horizontal (as opposed to vertical); lying down\nside-to-side (as opposed to front-to-back); width; breadth\nside (of a box, etc.)\nbeside; aside; next to\nunconnected" },
	{ "question": "横たわる", "answers": [ "よこたわる" ], "comment": "to lie down; to stretch out\nto lie ahead (of danger, difficulty, etc.); to lie in wait" },
	{ "question": "横切る", "answers": [ "よこぎる" ], "comment": "to cross (e.g. road); to traverse" },
	{ "question": "横取り", "answers": [ "よこどり" ], "comment": "usurpation; snatching; seizure" },
	{ "question": "横手", "answers": [ "よこて", "よこで" ], "comment": "side; beside\nfeature of a sword blade" },
	{ "question": "横文字", "answers": [ "よこもじ" ], "comment": "European writing; cross-wise writing\nWestern language" },
	{ "question": "横断", "answers": [ "おうだん" ], "comment": "crossing; traversing\ntraversing horizontally; passing west to east (or east to west)\ncutting horizontally" },
	{ "question": "横断幕", "answers": [ "おうだんまく" ], "comment": "horizontal banner" },
	{ "question": "横断歩道", "answers": [ "おうだんほどう" ], "comment": "pedestrian crossing" },
	{ "question": "横暴", "answers": [ "おうぼう" ], "comment": "violence; oppression; high-handedness; tyranny; despotism" },
	{ "question": "横書き", "answers": [ "よこがき" ], "comment": "writing horizontally" },
	{ "question": "横目", "answers": [ "よこめ" ], "comment": "sidelong glance" },
	{ "question": "横着", "answers": [ "おうちゃく" ], "comment": "laziness; shirking\nimpudent; brazenly dishonest" },
	{ "question": "横綱", "answers": [ "よこづな" ], "comment": "yokozuna (highest rank in sumo); grand champion\nbest in its field; crème de la crème; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "横線", "answers": [ "よこせん", "おうせん" ], "comment": "horizontal line; abscissa" },
	{ "question": "横行", "answers": [ "おうこう" ], "comment": "walking sideways; staggering; striding\nbeing rampant; being widespread; being prevalent" },
	{ "question": "横転", "answers": [ "おうてん" ], "comment": "toppling sideways; turning sideways; falling over sideways\nbarrel roll" },
	{ "question": "横道", "answers": [ "よこみち" ], "comment": "byway; side street; cross street\nwrong way; digression" },
	{ "question": "横領", "answers": [ "おうりょう" ], "comment": "embezzlement; misappropriation; usurpation" },
	{ "question": "横顔", "answers": [ "よこがお" ], "comment": "face in profile; profile; face seen from the side" },
	{ "question": "樹木", "answers": [ "じゅもく" ], "comment": "tree; trees and shrubs" },
	{ "question": "樹立", "answers": [ "じゅりつ" ], "comment": "establish; create" },
	{ "question": "樹脂", "answers": [ "じゅし" ], "comment": "resin; rosin" },
	{ "question": "樹齢", "answers": [ "じゅれい" ], "comment": "age of a tree" },
	{ "question": "樽", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "cask; barrel" },
	{ "question": "橋", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "bridge" },
	{ "question": "橋渡し", "answers": [ "はしわたし" ], "comment": "bridge building; mediation; go-between; intermediary; (through the) good offices (of someone)" },
	{ "question": "橋脚", "answers": [ "きょうきゃく" ], "comment": "bridge pier; pontoon bridge" },
	{ "question": "橘", "answers": [ "たちばな" ], "comment": "tachibana (inedible citrus, Citrus tachibana)" },
	{ "question": "橙色", "answers": [ "とうしょく", "だいだいいろ" ], "comment": "orange color; orange colour" },
	{ "question": "機会", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "chance; opportunity" },
	{ "question": "機体", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "fuselage; airframe" },
	{ "question": "機動", "answers": [ "きどう" ], "comment": "maneuver (usu. of military force); manoeuvre\nmobile; nimble; agile; quick to respond" },
	{ "question": "機動隊", "answers": [ "きどうたい" ], "comment": "riot police; riot squad" },
	{ "question": "機器", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "device; equipment; machinery; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "機嫌", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "humour; humor; temper; mood; spirits\nsafety; health; well-being; one's situation\nin a good mood; in high spirits; happy; cheery; merry; chipper" },
	{ "question": "機密", "answers": [ "きみつ" ], "comment": "secrecy; highly classified information" },
	{ "question": "機敏", "answers": [ "きびん" ], "comment": "clever; shrewd; canny; smart; quick; prompt" },
	{ "question": "機材", "answers": [ "きざい" ], "comment": "machine parts; machinery; equipment" },
	{ "question": "機械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "machine; mechanism\ninstrument; appliance; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "機械化", "answers": [ "きかいか" ], "comment": "mechanization; mechanisation\ncomputerization" },
	{ "question": "機構", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "mechanism; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "機種", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "type of equipment; model" },
	{ "question": "機能", "answers": [ "きのう" ], "comment": "function; facility; faculty; feature" },
	{ "question": "機運", "answers": [ "きうん" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; good time (to do)\ntrend; tendency; momentum" },
	{ "question": "機長", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "captain (of an aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "機関", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "engine\nagency; organisation; organization; institution; organ; body\nsystem; facility; facilities" },
	{ "question": "機関紙", "answers": [ "きかんし" ], "comment": "bulletin; (party) organ" },
	{ "question": "機関車", "answers": [ "きかんしゃ" ], "comment": "locomotive; engine" },
	{ "question": "機関銃", "answers": [ "きかんじゅう" ], "comment": "machine gun" },
	{ "question": "機雷", "answers": [ "きらい" ], "comment": "(sea) mine" },
	{ "question": "機首", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "nose (of plane)" },
	{ "question": "檻", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "cage; pen; jail cell; gaol cell" },
	{ "question": "櫛", "answers": [ "くし" ], "comment": "comb" },
	{ "question": "欄", "answers": [ "らん" ], "comment": "column of text (e.g. in a newspaper)\nfield (in a form, web page, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "欠かす", "answers": [ "かかす" ], "comment": "to miss (doing); to fail (to do)" },
	{ "question": "欠く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "to chip; to nick; to break; to crack\nto lack" },
	{ "question": "欠ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to be chipped; to be damaged; to be broken\nto be lacking; to be missing\nto be insufficient; to be short; to be deficient; to be negligent toward\n(of the moon) to wane; to go into eclipse" },
	{ "question": "欠乏", "answers": [ "けつぼう" ], "comment": "want; shortage; famine" },
	{ "question": "欠員", "answers": [ "けついん" ], "comment": "vacancy; vacant position" },
	{ "question": "欠場", "answers": [ "けつじょう" ], "comment": "absence; not taking part" },
	{ "question": "欠如", "answers": [ "けつじょ" ], "comment": "lack; privation; deficiency" },
	{ "question": "欠席", "answers": [ "けっせき" ], "comment": "absence; non-attendance" },
	{ "question": "欠損", "answers": [ "けっそん" ], "comment": "deficit; shortage; loss; damage" },
	{ "question": "欠点", "answers": [ "けってん" ], "comment": "fault; defect; flaw; weak point; weakness; shortcoming; drawback\nfailure (in an examination); failing grade" },
	{ "question": "欠陥", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "defect; fault; deficiency; deformity\nshortage; gap" },
	{ "question": "次", "answers": [ "つぎ" ], "comment": "next; following; subsequent\nstage; station" },
	{ "question": "次々", "answers": [ "つぎつぎ" ], "comment": "in succession; one by one" },
	{ "question": "次々に", "answers": [ "つぎつぎに" ], "comment": "one by one; one after another; successively" },
	{ "question": "次いで", "answers": [ "ついで" ], "comment": "next; secondly; subsequently" },
	{ "question": "次ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "to rank next to; to come after" },
	{ "question": "次のように", "answers": [ "つぎのように" ], "comment": "in the following manner; as follows" },
	{ "question": "次代", "answers": [ "じだい" ], "comment": "the next era" },
	{ "question": "次元", "answers": [ "じげん" ], "comment": "dimension\nperspective; point of reference; level (of something)" },
	{ "question": "次回", "answers": [ "じかい" ], "comment": "next time (occasion)" },
	{ "question": "次女", "answers": [ "じじょ" ], "comment": "second daughter" },
	{ "question": "次官", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "vice-minister; undersecretary" },
	{ "question": "次席", "answers": [ "じせき" ], "comment": "associate; junior; assistant; runner-up" },
	{ "question": "次期", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "next term; next period\nnext version; next release" },
	{ "question": "次点", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "runner-up" },
	{ "question": "次男", "answers": [ "じなん" ], "comment": "second son" },
	{ "question": "次第", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "depending on\nas soon as; immediately (upon)\nin accordance with\norder; program; programme; precedence\ncircumstances; course of events; reason" },
	{ "question": "次第に", "answers": [ "しだいに" ], "comment": "gradually (progress into a state)\nin sequence; in order; in turn" },
	{ "question": "次長", "answers": [ "じちょう" ], "comment": "vice-chief; vice-director; assistant director; deputy manager" },
	{ "question": "欧州", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "Europe" },
	{ "question": "欧米", "answers": [ "おうべい" ], "comment": "Europe and America; the West" },
	{ "question": "欲", "answers": [ "よく" ], "comment": "greed; craving; desire; avarice; wants" },
	{ "question": "欲しがる", "answers": [ "ほしがる" ], "comment": "to desire; to want; to wish for; to covet" },
	{ "question": "欲する", "answers": [ "ほっする" ], "comment": "to want; to desire" },
	{ "question": "欲張り", "answers": [ "よくばり" ], "comment": "greed; avarice; covetousness; greedy person" },
	{ "question": "欲張る", "answers": [ "よくばる" ], "comment": "to covet; to lust for" },
	{ "question": "欲望", "answers": [ "よくぼう" ], "comment": "desire; appetite; lust" },
	{ "question": "欲求", "answers": [ "よっきゅう" ], "comment": "desire" },
	{ "question": "欲深", "answers": [ "よくぶか", "よくふか" ], "comment": "avarice; covetousness; greed" },
	{ "question": "欺く", "answers": [ "あざむく" ], "comment": "to deceive; to delude; to trick; to fool\nto be as ... as ... (e.g. \"as bright as day\", \"as beautiful as a rose\")" },
	{ "question": "歌", "answers": [ "うた" ], "comment": "song\nclassical Japanese poetry (esp. tanka)\nmodern poetry" },
	{ "question": "歌う", "answers": [ "うたう" ], "comment": "to sing\nto sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.); to compose a poem; to recite a poem" },
	{ "question": "歌人", "answers": [ "かじん" ], "comment": "poet (of tanka poems)" },
	{ "question": "歌劇", "answers": [ "かげき" ], "comment": "opera" },
	{ "question": "歌合", "answers": [ "うたあわせ" ], "comment": "poetry contest" },
	{ "question": "歌唱", "answers": [ "かしょう" ], "comment": "song; singing" },
	{ "question": "歌声", "answers": [ "かせい", "うたごえ" ], "comment": "singing voice; (sound of) singing" },
	{ "question": "歌手", "answers": [ "かしゅ" ], "comment": "singer" },
	{ "question": "歌曲", "answers": [ "かきょく" ], "comment": "melody; tune; song" },
	{ "question": "歌舞伎", "answers": [ "かぶき" ], "comment": "kabuki; Japanese classical drama" },
	{ "question": "歌詞", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "song lyrics; words of a song; libretto" },
	{ "question": "歌謡", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "song; ballad" },
	{ "question": "歌謡曲", "answers": [ "かようきょく" ], "comment": "popular song" },
	{ "question": "歌集", "answers": [ "かしゅう" ], "comment": "anthology; book of poetry" },
	{ "question": "歓喜", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "delight; great joy" },
	{ "question": "歓声", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "cheer; shout of joy" },
	{ "question": "歓迎", "answers": [ "かんげい" ], "comment": "welcome; reception" },
	{ "question": "止まる", "answers": [ "とまる", "とどまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on" },
	{ "question": "止む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "to cease; to stop; to be over" },
	{ "question": "止める", "answers": [ "とめる", "やめる", "とどめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to turn off\nto park\nto prevent; to suppress (a cough); to hold back (tears); to hold (one's breath); to relieve (pain)\nto stop (someone from doing something); to dissuade; to forbid; to prohibit\nto notice; to be aware of; to concentrate on; to pay attention to; to remember; to bear in mind\nto fix (in place); to fasten; to tack; to pin; to nail; to button; to staple\nto detain; to keep in custody" },
	{ "question": "止め金", "answers": [ "とめがね" ], "comment": "clasp; snap fastener" },
	{ "question": "正", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(logical) true; regular\n10^40; ten thousand undecillion\noriginal\npositive; greater than zero" },
	{ "question": "正しい", "answers": [ "ただしい" ], "comment": "right; correct\nproper; righteous; just; honest; truthful; lawful" },
	{ "question": "正す", "answers": [ "ただす" ], "comment": "to correct; to reform; to amend; to redress\nto adjust; to straighten\nto ascertain; to confirm; to verify; to make sure of\nto enquire of someone about something (inquire); to question" },
	{ "question": "正体", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "true character; true form; true colors; true colours; identity\nconsciousness; one's senses" },
	{ "question": "正則", "answers": [ "せいそく" ], "comment": "correct; proper; formal; regular; systematic; normal" },
	{ "question": "正午", "answers": [ "しょうご" ], "comment": "noon; mid-day" },
	{ "question": "正反対", "answers": [ "せいはんたい" ], "comment": "exactly opposite (of)" },
	{ "question": "正常", "answers": [ "せいじょう" ], "comment": "normalcy; normality; normal" },
	{ "question": "正常化", "answers": [ "せいじょうか" ], "comment": "normalization; normalisation" },
	{ "question": "正座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "seiza; kneeling with the tops of the feet flat on the floor, and sitting on the soles" },
	{ "question": "正式", "answers": [ "せいしき" ], "comment": "due form; official; formality" },
	{ "question": "正式名称", "answers": [ "せいしきめいしょう" ], "comment": "official name; formal name" },
	{ "question": "正当", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "just; justifiable; right; due; proper; equitable; reasonable; legitimate; legal; lawful" },
	{ "question": "正当防衛", "answers": [ "せいとうぼうえい" ], "comment": "legitimate self-defence; legitimate self-defense" },
	{ "question": "正念場", "answers": [ "しょうねんば" ], "comment": "critical moment; do-or-die situation" },
	{ "question": "正教", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "orthodoxy; (Greek) orthodox church" },
	{ "question": "正方形", "answers": [ "せいほうけい" ], "comment": "square" },
	{ "question": "正月", "answers": [ "しょうがつ" ], "comment": "New Year (esp. first three days)\nthe first month of the year; January" },
	{ "question": "正直", "answers": [ "しょうじき" ], "comment": "honesty; integrity; frankness\nhonestly; frankly" },
	{ "question": "正確", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "accurate; punctual; exact; authentic; veracious; correct" },
	{ "question": "正統", "answers": [ "しょうとう", "せいとう" ], "comment": "legitimate; orthodox; traditional" },
	{ "question": "正義", "answers": [ "せいぎ" ], "comment": "justice; right; righteousness; correct meaning" },
	{ "question": "正装", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "full dress; formal dress; uniform" },
	{ "question": "正規", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "regular; normal; formal; legal; established; legitimate" },
	{ "question": "正解", "answers": [ "せいかい" ], "comment": "correct; right; correct interpretation (answer, solution)" },
	{ "question": "正論", "answers": [ "せいろん" ], "comment": "sound argument; fair argument; just reasoning" },
	{ "question": "正道", "answers": [ "せいどう", "しょうどう" ], "comment": "path of righteousness; path of duty; right track; correct path" },
	{ "question": "正門", "answers": [ "せいもん" ], "comment": "main gate; main entrance" },
	{ "question": "正面", "answers": [ "しょうめん" ], "comment": "front; frontage; facade; main" },
	{ "question": "此の前", "answers": [ "このまえ" ], "comment": "some time ago; recently; lately\nlast (Sunday, etc.); previous" },
	{ "question": "武力", "answers": [ "ぶりょく" ], "comment": "armed might; military power; the sword; force" },
	{ "question": "武器", "answers": [ "ぶき" ], "comment": "weapon; arms; ordnance\nweapon (something used to gain an advantage); asset" },
	{ "question": "武士", "answers": [ "もののふ", "ぶふ", "ぶし" ], "comment": "warrior; samurai" },
	{ "question": "武将", "answers": [ "ぶしょう" ], "comment": "military commander" },
	{ "question": "武者", "answers": [ "むしゃ" ], "comment": "warrior" },
	{ "question": "武装", "answers": [ "ぶそう" ], "comment": "arms; armament" },
	{ "question": "武道", "answers": [ "ぶどう" ], "comment": "martial arts; military arts; Bushido" },
	{ "question": "歩", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "step; stride\ncounter for steps" },
	{ "question": "歩き回る", "answers": [ "あるきまわる" ], "comment": "to walk about; to walk to and fro; to pace around" },
	{ "question": "歩く", "answers": [ "あるく" ], "comment": "to walk" },
	{ "question": "歩み", "answers": [ "あゆみ" ], "comment": "walking\nprogress; advance" },
	{ "question": "歩み寄り", "answers": [ "あゆみより" ], "comment": "compromise; concession" },
	{ "question": "歩み寄る", "answers": [ "あゆみよる" ], "comment": "to compromise; to meet halfway\nto step up to; to walk up to; to approach" },
	{ "question": "歩む", "answers": [ "あゆむ" ], "comment": "to walk; to go on foot" },
	{ "question": "歩兵", "answers": [ "ほへい" ], "comment": "infantry; infantryman; foot soldier" },
	{ "question": "歩合", "answers": [ "ぶあい" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; percentage\ncommission; poundage; percentage" },
	{ "question": "歩行", "answers": [ "ほこう" ], "comment": "walk" },
	{ "question": "歩行者", "answers": [ "ほこうしゃ" ], "comment": "pedestrian; walker" },
	{ "question": "歩行者天国", "answers": [ "ほこうしゃてんごく" ], "comment": "pedestrian mall; car-free mall; pedestrian paradise" },
	{ "question": "歩調", "answers": [ "ほちょう" ], "comment": "pace; step; cadence" },
	{ "question": "歩道", "answers": [ "ほどう" ], "comment": "footpath; walkway; sidewalk" },
	{ "question": "歪む", "answers": [ "ゆがむ", "いがむ", "ひずむ" ], "comment": "to warp; to swerve; to deflect; to be crooked; to be distorted; to be bent; to incline; to slant; to be perverted; to be gross-grained; to get bent; to be strained" },
	{ "question": "歯", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "tooth" },
	{ "question": "歯ごたえ", "answers": [ "はごたえ" ], "comment": "feel (consistency) of food while being chewed" },
	{ "question": "歯ブラシ", "answers": [ "はブラシ" ], "comment": "toothbrush" },
	{ "question": "歯切れ", "answers": [ "はぎれ" ], "comment": "feel when biting\nmanner of enunciation" },
	{ "question": "歯医者", "answers": [ "はいしゃ" ], "comment": "dentist" },
	{ "question": "歯向う", "answers": [ "はむかう" ], "comment": "to strike back at; to bite back; to turn on; to rise against; to oppose; to defy" },
	{ "question": "歯向かう", "answers": [ "はむかう" ], "comment": "to strike back at; to bite back; to turn on; to rise against; to oppose; to defy" },
	{ "question": "歯止め", "answers": [ "はどめ" ], "comment": "brake; skid; pawl\nrestraint; curtailment; self-imposed limit; check" },
	{ "question": "歯痒い", "answers": [ "はがゆい" ], "comment": "impatient; tantalized; tantalised; irritated; chagrined; chagrinned; vexed" },
	{ "question": "歯磨き", "answers": [ "はみがき" ], "comment": "dental brushing; brushing one's teeth\ndentifrice; toothpaste; tooth powder" },
	{ "question": "歯科", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "dentistry" },
	{ "question": "歯科医", "answers": [ "しかい" ], "comment": "dentist" },
	{ "question": "歯科医師", "answers": [ "しかいし" ], "comment": "dentist" },
	{ "question": "歯科衛生士", "answers": [ "しかえいせいし" ], "comment": "dental hygienist" },
	{ "question": "歯車", "answers": [ "はぐるま" ], "comment": "gear; cog-wheel" },
	{ "question": "歳", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "-years-old\nability; gift; talent; aptitude; genius" },
	{ "question": "歳入", "answers": [ "さいにゅう" ], "comment": "annual revenue (government); annual income (government); budget receipts" },
	{ "question": "歳出", "answers": [ "さいしゅつ" ], "comment": "annual expenditure" },
	{ "question": "歳暮", "answers": [ "せいぼ" ], "comment": "year-end gift\nend of the year; year end" },
	{ "question": "歳月", "answers": [ "さいげつ", "としつき" ], "comment": "time; years" },
	{ "question": "歳末", "answers": [ "さいまつ" ], "comment": "year end" },
	{ "question": "歴代", "answers": [ "れきだい" ], "comment": "successive generations; successive emperors" },
	{ "question": "歴史", "answers": [ "れきし" ], "comment": "history" },
	{ "question": "歴史的", "answers": [ "れきしてき" ], "comment": "historic; historical; traditional" },
	{ "question": "歴然", "answers": [ "れきぜん" ], "comment": "evident; plain; distinct; clear" },
	{ "question": "歴訪", "answers": [ "れきほう" ], "comment": "round of calls; tour of visitation" },
	{ "question": "死", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "death; decease\ndeath penalty (by strangulation or decapitation)\n(an) out" },
	{ "question": "死に体", "answers": [ "しにたい" ], "comment": "losing posture; falling position from which it is impossible to recover\nlame duck\nhopeless situation" },
	{ "question": "死ぬ", "answers": [ "しぬ" ], "comment": "to die; to pass away\nto lose spirit; to lose vigor; to look dead\nto cease; to stop" },
	{ "question": "死亡", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "death; mortality\nto die; to pass away" },
	{ "question": "死亡率", "answers": [ "しぼうりつ" ], "comment": "death rate; mortality" },
	{ "question": "死亡者", "answers": [ "しぼうしゃ" ], "comment": "the deceased; deaths; persons killed" },
	{ "question": "死人", "answers": [ "しびと", "しにん" ], "comment": "corpse; dead person" },
	{ "question": "死体", "answers": [ "したい" ], "comment": "dead body; corpse; cadaver" },
	{ "question": "死傷者", "answers": [ "ししょうしゃ" ], "comment": "casualties; killed and wounded" },
	{ "question": "死刑", "answers": [ "しけい" ], "comment": "death penalty; capital punishment" },
	{ "question": "死刑囚", "answers": [ "しけいしゅう" ], "comment": "criminal condemned to death; convict on death row" },
	{ "question": "死去", "answers": [ "しきょ" ], "comment": "death" },
	{ "question": "死因", "answers": [ "しいん" ], "comment": "cause of death" },
	{ "question": "死後", "answers": [ "しご" ], "comment": "after death" },
	{ "question": "死活", "answers": [ "しかつ" ], "comment": "life and death; life or death" },
	{ "question": "死球", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "pitch that hits the batter" },
	{ "question": "死者", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "casualty; deceased" },
	{ "question": "殊に", "answers": [ "ことに" ], "comment": "especially; particularly; unusually; above all\nadditionally" },
	{ "question": "殊勲", "answers": [ "しゅくん" ], "comment": "meritorious deeds" },
	{ "question": "残す", "answers": [ "のこす" ], "comment": "to leave (behind, over); to bequeath; to save; to reserve" },
	{ "question": "残った分", "answers": [ "のこったぶん" ], "comment": "amount left over; remaining portion" },
	{ "question": "残らず", "answers": [ "のこらず" ], "comment": "all; entirely; completely; without exception" },
	{ "question": "残り", "answers": [ "のこり" ], "comment": "remnant; residue; remaining; left-over" },
	{ "question": "残る", "answers": [ "のこる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left" },
	{ "question": "残塁", "answers": [ "ざんるい" ], "comment": "left on base\nremnant fort" },
	{ "question": "残存", "answers": [ "ざんぞん", "ざんそん" ], "comment": "remaining; survival; residual" },
	{ "question": "残念", "answers": [ "ざんねん" ], "comment": "deplorable; bad luck; regret; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "残暑", "answers": [ "ざんしょ" ], "comment": "late summer heat; lingering summer heat" },
	{ "question": "残業", "answers": [ "ざんぎょう" ], "comment": "overtime (work)" },
	{ "question": "残留", "answers": [ "ざんりゅう" ], "comment": "staying behind; remaining; residual" },
	{ "question": "残虐", "answers": [ "ざんぎゃく" ], "comment": "cruelty; brutality" },
	{ "question": "残酷", "answers": [ "ざんこく" ], "comment": "cruelty; harshness" },
	{ "question": "残高", "answers": [ "ざんだか" ], "comment": "(bank) balance; remainder" },
	{ "question": "殖える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "殖やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "to increase; to add to; to augment" },
	{ "question": "殴る", "answers": [ "なぐる" ], "comment": "to strike; to hit; to beat; to punch" },
	{ "question": "殴打", "answers": [ "おうだ" ], "comment": "hit; strike; blow" },
	{ "question": "段", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "step; stair; (flight of) steps; (row of) stitches; columns (of print)\ngrade; rank; level\ncounter for breaks in written language (or speech, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "段ボール", "answers": [ "ダンボール", "だんボール" ], "comment": "(corrugated) cardboard" },
	{ "question": "段取り", "answers": [ "だんどり" ], "comment": "programme; program; plans; arrangements" },
	{ "question": "段落", "answers": [ "だんらく" ], "comment": "paragraph\nend; stopping place; conclusion" },
	{ "question": "段階", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "grade; level; stage; class; phase; steps; order; gradation" },
	{ "question": "殺し", "answers": [ "ころし" ], "comment": "murder; killing; murderer" },
	{ "question": "殺す", "answers": [ "ころす" ], "comment": "to kill" },
	{ "question": "殺人", "answers": [ "さつじん" ], "comment": "murder" },
	{ "question": "殺傷", "answers": [ "さっしょう" ], "comment": "killing and wounding; casualties; bloodshed" },
	{ "question": "殺到", "answers": [ "さっとう" ], "comment": "rush; flood; deluge" },
	{ "question": "殺害", "answers": [ "さつがい" ], "comment": "killing; murder" },
	{ "question": "殺意", "answers": [ "さつい" ], "comment": "intent to kill; intent to murder; urge to kill; murderous impulse" },
	{ "question": "殺気", "answers": [ "さっき" ], "comment": "thirst for blood; bloodlust; determination to kill" },
	{ "question": "殺菌", "answers": [ "さっきん" ], "comment": "sterilization; sterilisation; disinfection" },
	{ "question": "殺虫剤", "answers": [ "さっちゅうざい" ], "comment": "insecticide; pesticide" },
	{ "question": "殻", "answers": [ "から" ], "comment": "shell; husk; hull; pod; chaff" },
	{ "question": "殿", "answers": [ "どの", "との", "しんがり" ], "comment": "form of address used for official letters and business letters, and in letters to inferiors; Mr." },
	{ "question": "殿下", "answers": [ "でんか" ], "comment": "your Highness; his Highness; her Highness" },
	{ "question": "殿堂", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "palace; hall; shrine; temple; sanctuary\nhall of fame" },
	{ "question": "殿様", "answers": [ "とのさま" ], "comment": "feudal lord; daimyo" },
	{ "question": "母", "answers": [ "はは" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "母さん", "answers": [ "かあさん" ], "comment": "mother\nwife (used when speaking to or about one's own wife)" },
	{ "question": "母乳", "answers": [ "ぼにゅう" ], "comment": "mother's milk" },
	{ "question": "母体", "answers": [ "ぼたい" ], "comment": "mother's body, esp. when pregnant or after giving birth\nparent body; parent organization; heartland" },
	{ "question": "母国", "answers": [ "ぼこく" ], "comment": "one's homeland" },
	{ "question": "母国語", "answers": [ "ぼこくご" ], "comment": "language of one's country; mother tongue; native language" },
	{ "question": "母子", "answers": [ "ぼし" ], "comment": "mother and child" },
	{ "question": "母性", "answers": [ "ぼせい" ], "comment": "motherhood; maternity" },
	{ "question": "母校", "answers": [ "ぼこう" ], "comment": "alma mater" },
	{ "question": "母親", "answers": [ "ははおや" ], "comment": "mother" },
	{ "question": "毎", "answers": [ "まい" ], "comment": "every (usu. with events, e.g. every weekend); each" },
	{ "question": "毎回", "answers": [ "まいかい" ], "comment": "every time; each round" },
	{ "question": "毎年", "answers": [ "まいねん", "まいとし" ], "comment": "every year; yearly; annually" },
	{ "question": "毎度", "answers": [ "まいど" ], "comment": "each time; always; often\nthank you for your continued patronage" },
	{ "question": "毎日", "answers": [ "まいにち" ], "comment": "every day" },
	{ "question": "毎晩", "answers": [ "まいばん" ], "comment": "every night" },
	{ "question": "毎月", "answers": [ "まいげつ", "まいつき" ], "comment": "every month; each month; monthly" },
	{ "question": "毎朝", "answers": [ "まいあさ", "まいちょう" ], "comment": "every morning" },
	{ "question": "毎週", "answers": [ "まいしゅう" ], "comment": "every week" },
	{ "question": "毒", "answers": [ "どく" ], "comment": "poison; toxicant\nharm; evil influence\nill will; spite; malice\nabusive language" },
	{ "question": "毒ガス", "answers": [ "どくガス" ], "comment": "poison gas" },
	{ "question": "毒性", "answers": [ "どくせい" ], "comment": "toxicity; virulence\ntoxic; virulent; poisonous" },
	{ "question": "毒薬", "answers": [ "どくやく" ], "comment": "poison" },
	{ "question": "比", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "ratio; proportion\nmatch; equal\nexplicit comparison (style of the Shi Jing)\nPhilippines\nin comparison with ..." },
	{ "question": "比べる", "answers": [ "くらべる" ], "comment": "to compare; to make a comparison\nto compete; to vie" },
	{ "question": "比例", "answers": [ "ひれい" ], "comment": "proportion" },
	{ "question": "比喩", "answers": [ "ひゆ" ], "comment": "simile; metaphor; allegory; parable" },
	{ "question": "比率", "answers": [ "ひりつ" ], "comment": "ratio; proportion; percentage" },
	{ "question": "比較", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "comparison" },
	{ "question": "比較的", "answers": [ "ひかくてき" ], "comment": "comparative; relative" },
	{ "question": "比重", "answers": [ "ひじゅう" ], "comment": "specific gravity; weight; part\nrelative weight; relative importance" },
	{ "question": "毛", "answers": [ "け" ], "comment": "hair\nfur; wool\ndown; plumage; feathers" },
	{ "question": "毛布", "answers": [ "もうふ" ], "comment": "blanket" },
	{ "question": "毛皮", "answers": [ "けがわ", "もうひ" ], "comment": "fur; skin; pelt\nkanji \"fur\" radical" },
	{ "question": "毛糸", "answers": [ "けいと" ], "comment": "knitting wool; woollen yarn" },
	{ "question": "氏", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "Mr; Mrs; Ms; Miss\nclan\nhe; him\ncounter for people" },
	{ "question": "氏名", "answers": [ "しめい", "うじな" ], "comment": "full name; identity" },
	{ "question": "氏族", "answers": [ "しぞく" ], "comment": "clan; family" },
	{ "question": "民", "answers": [ "たみ" ], "comment": "nation; people" },
	{ "question": "民主", "answers": [ "みんしゅ" ], "comment": "democracy; popular sovereignty\ndemocratic" },
	{ "question": "民主主義", "answers": [ "みんしゅしゅぎ" ], "comment": "democracy" },
	{ "question": "民主党", "answers": [ "みんしゅとう" ], "comment": "Democratic Party (esp. DPJ or US Democratic Party)" },
	{ "question": "民主国", "answers": [ "みんしゅこく" ], "comment": "democratic state" },
	{ "question": "民主的", "answers": [ "みんしゅてき" ], "comment": "democratic" },
	{ "question": "民事", "answers": [ "みんじ" ], "comment": "civil affairs; civil case" },
	{ "question": "民俗", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "folk customs; folkways; ethnic customs" },
	{ "question": "民兵", "answers": [ "みんぺい" ], "comment": "militia; militiaman" },
	{ "question": "民営", "answers": [ "みんえい" ], "comment": "private management" },
	{ "question": "民営化", "answers": [ "みんえいか" ], "comment": "privatization; privatisation" },
	{ "question": "民家", "answers": [ "みんか" ], "comment": "private house" },
	{ "question": "民宿", "answers": [ "みんしゅく" ], "comment": "pension; guesthouse; bed and breakfast; private home providing lodging for travelers (travellers)" },
	{ "question": "民意", "answers": [ "みんい" ], "comment": "popular will" },
	{ "question": "民放", "answers": [ "みんぽう" ], "comment": "commercial broadcast" },
	{ "question": "民政", "answers": [ "みんせい" ], "comment": "democracy; civil government" },
	{ "question": "民族", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "people; race; nation; ethnic group; ethnos" },
	{ "question": "民族主義", "answers": [ "みんぞくしゅぎ" ], "comment": "nationalism" },
	{ "question": "民族自決", "answers": [ "みんぞくじけつ" ], "comment": "self-determination of peoples" },
	{ "question": "民法", "answers": [ "みんぽう" ], "comment": "civil law; civil code" },
	{ "question": "民生", "answers": [ "みんせい" ], "comment": "consumer\ncivilian\npeople's welfare or livelihood" },
	{ "question": "民社党", "answers": [ "みんしゃとう" ], "comment": "Democratic Socialist Party" },
	{ "question": "民芸", "answers": [ "みんげい" ], "comment": "folk craft; folk art" },
	{ "question": "民衆", "answers": [ "みんしゅう" ], "comment": "people; populace; masses" },
	{ "question": "民話", "answers": [ "みんわ" ], "comment": "folk tale; folktale; folk story; folklore" },
	{ "question": "民謡", "answers": [ "みんよう" ], "comment": "folk song; popular song" },
	{ "question": "民間", "answers": [ "みんかん" ], "comment": "private; civilian; civil; popular; folk; unofficial" },
	{ "question": "民間放送", "answers": [ "みんかんほうそう" ], "comment": "commercial broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "民需", "answers": [ "みんじゅ" ], "comment": "private demand" },
	{ "question": "気", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "spirit; mind; heart\nnature; disposition\nmotivation; intention\nmood; feelings\nambience; atmosphere; mood" },
	{ "question": "気づかれ", "answers": [ "きづかれ" ], "comment": "mental fatigue; worry; boredom" },
	{ "question": "気づく", "answers": [ "きづく" ], "comment": "to notice; to recognize; to recognise; to become aware of; to perceive; to realize; to realise" },
	{ "question": "気に入り", "answers": [ "きにいり" ], "comment": "favorite; favourite; pet" },
	{ "question": "気に入る", "answers": [ "きにいる" ], "comment": "to be pleased with; to suit" },
	{ "question": "気のせい", "answers": [ "きのせい" ], "comment": "in one's imagination" },
	{ "question": "気の向くままに", "answers": [ "きのむくままに" ], "comment": "at one's fancy (whim)" },
	{ "question": "気の毒", "answers": [ "きのどく" ], "comment": "pitiful; unfortunate; (a) pity" },
	{ "question": "気まぐれ", "answers": [ "きまぐれ" ], "comment": "whim; caprice; whimsy; fickle; moody; uneven temper" },
	{ "question": "気まま", "answers": [ "きまま" ], "comment": "willful; wilful; selfish; self-centered; egoistic\ncarefree; do-as-you-please; freewheeling; free spirited" },
	{ "question": "気を付ける", "answers": [ "きをつける" ], "comment": "to be careful; to pay attention; to take care" },
	{ "question": "気付く", "answers": [ "きづく" ], "comment": "to notice; to recognize; to recognise; to become aware of; to perceive; to realize; to realise" },
	{ "question": "気体", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "vapour; vapor; gas" },
	{ "question": "気候", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "climate" },
	{ "question": "気兼ね", "answers": [ "きがね" ], "comment": "constraint; reserve; feeling hesitant; being afraid of troubling someone" },
	{ "question": "気分", "answers": [ "きぶん" ], "comment": "feeling; mood" },
	{ "question": "気分転換", "answers": [ "きぶんてんかん" ], "comment": "change of pace; change of mood; (mental) break (e.g. going for a walk); refreshment" },
	{ "question": "気前", "answers": [ "きまえ" ], "comment": "generosity" },
	{ "question": "気力", "answers": [ "きりょく" ], "comment": "willpower; energy; vitality" },
	{ "question": "気勢", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "fervour; fervor; vigour; vigor; ardour; ardor; spirit" },
	{ "question": "気取る", "answers": [ "きどる" ], "comment": "to affect; to put on airs" },
	{ "question": "気合", "answers": [ "きあい" ], "comment": "scream; yell; fighting spirit" },
	{ "question": "気味", "answers": [ "きみ", "きび" ], "comment": "sensation; feeling\ntendency; propensity" },
	{ "question": "気圧", "answers": [ "きあつ" ], "comment": "atmospheric pressure" },
	{ "question": "気心", "answers": [ "きごころ" ], "comment": "temper; disposition" },
	{ "question": "気性", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "disposition; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気持ち", "answers": [ "きもち" ], "comment": "feeling; sensation; mood\npreparedness; readiness; attitude\nthanks; solicitude; sympathy\njust a little; somewhat; slightly" },
	{ "question": "気持ちいい", "answers": [ "きもちいい" ], "comment": "good feeling; feeling good" },
	{ "question": "気持ち悪い", "answers": [ "きもちわるい" ], "comment": "bad feeling; feeling bad; disagreeable; unpleasant; revolting; gross; disgusting" },
	{ "question": "気掛かり", "answers": [ "きがかり" ], "comment": "anxiety; concern; worry" },
	{ "question": "気楽", "answers": [ "きらく" ], "comment": "carefree; comfortable; at ease\neasygoing; happy-go-lucky" },
	{ "question": "気概", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "strong spirit; mettle; backbone; guts; fighting spirit" },
	{ "question": "気温", "answers": [ "きおん" ], "comment": "atmospheric temperature" },
	{ "question": "気球", "answers": [ "ききゅう" ], "comment": "balloon; blimp" },
	{ "question": "気筒", "answers": [ "きとう" ], "comment": "cylinder" },
	{ "question": "気管支", "answers": [ "きかんし" ], "comment": "bronchial tube" },
	{ "question": "気絶", "answers": [ "きぜつ" ], "comment": "faint; swoon" },
	{ "question": "気象", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "weather; climate\ndisposition; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気象予報士", "answers": [ "きしょうよほうし" ], "comment": "weather forecaster" },
	{ "question": "気象台", "answers": [ "きしょうだい" ], "comment": "meteorological observatory" },
	{ "question": "気象庁", "answers": [ "きしょうちょう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) Meteorological Agency; JMA" },
	{ "question": "気負い", "answers": [ "きおい" ], "comment": "eagerness; enthusiasm; fervor; excitement; fighting spirit; fighting mood" },
	{ "question": "気質", "answers": [ "かたぎ", "きしつ" ], "comment": "spirit; character; trait; temperament; turn of mind; disposition" },
	{ "question": "気軽", "answers": [ "きがる" ], "comment": "carefree; buoyant; lighthearted; sprightly\nease" },
	{ "question": "気迫", "answers": [ "きはく" ], "comment": "spirit; soul; drive; vigor; vigour" },
	{ "question": "気遣い", "answers": [ "きづかい" ], "comment": "consideration; concern; fear; worry; solicitude" },
	{ "question": "気配", "answers": [ "けはい", "きはい" ], "comment": "indication; sign; hint; presence; trend\nquotation (esp. stock market)" },
	{ "question": "気配り", "answers": [ "きくばり" ], "comment": "care; attentiveness; attention; consideration (for others); solicitude" },
	{ "question": "気鋭", "answers": [ "きえい" ], "comment": "spirited; energetic" },
	{ "question": "気難しい", "answers": [ "きむづかしい", "きむずかしい" ], "comment": "hard to please; moody; crusty; fastidious" },
	{ "question": "水", "answers": [ "みず", "み" ], "comment": "water (esp. cool, fresh water, e.g. drinking water)\nfluid (esp. in an animal tissue); liquid\nflood; floodwaters\nwater offered to wrestlers just prior to a bout\nbreak granted to wrestlers engaged in a prolonged bout" },
	{ "question": "水上", "answers": [ "すいじょう" ], "comment": "aquatic; on the water" },
	{ "question": "水中", "answers": [ "すいちゅう" ], "comment": "underwater" },
	{ "question": "水位", "answers": [ "すいい" ], "comment": "water level" },
	{ "question": "水俣病", "answers": [ "みなまたびょう" ], "comment": "Minamata disease" },
	{ "question": "水入らず", "answers": [ "みずいらず" ], "comment": "(being) by oneself; with no outsiders present" },
	{ "question": "水分", "answers": [ "すいぶん" ], "comment": "water; liquid; fluid; moisture; humidity; sap; juice" },
	{ "question": "水利", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "water supply; irrigation; water transportation" },
	{ "question": "水割り", "answers": [ "みずわり" ], "comment": "alcohol (usu. whiskey or shochu) diluted with water\nwatered" },
	{ "question": "水力", "answers": [ "すいりょく" ], "comment": "hydraulic power; water power" },
	{ "question": "水口", "answers": [ "みずぐち" ], "comment": "spout" },
	{ "question": "水域", "answers": [ "すいいき" ], "comment": "waters; water area" },
	{ "question": "水増し", "answers": [ "みずまし" ], "comment": "dilution; watering down\ninflation (of budget, claim, etc.); padding" },
	{ "question": "水害", "answers": [ "すいがい" ], "comment": "water damage; flood disaster" },
	{ "question": "水平", "answers": [ "すいへい" ], "comment": "level; horizontality" },
	{ "question": "水平線", "answers": [ "すいへいせん" ], "comment": "horizon (related to sea or lakes)" },
	{ "question": "水彩画", "answers": [ "すいさいが" ], "comment": "watercolor painting; watercolour painting" },
	{ "question": "水揚げ", "answers": [ "みずあげ" ], "comment": "landing; unloading (e.g. a ship)\ncatch (of fish); takings\nsales (of a shop)\ndefloration (e.g. of a geisha)\npreservation (of cut flowers, in ikebana)" },
	{ "question": "水族館", "answers": [ "すいぞっかん", "すいぞくかん" ], "comment": "aquarium" },
	{ "question": "水曜", "answers": [ "すいよう" ], "comment": "Wednesday" },
	{ "question": "水曜日", "answers": [ "すいようび" ], "comment": "Wednesday" },
	{ "question": "水槽", "answers": [ "すいそう" ], "comment": "water tank; cistern\nfish tank; aquarium" },
	{ "question": "水死", "answers": [ "すいし" ], "comment": "death by drowning" },
	{ "question": "水気", "answers": [ "すいき", "みずけ" ], "comment": "moisture; dampness; vapor; vapour\ndropsy; edema; oedema" },
	{ "question": "水泳", "answers": [ "すいえい" ], "comment": "swimming" },
	{ "question": "水洗", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "rinsing with water; flushing" },
	{ "question": "水深", "answers": [ "すいしん" ], "comment": "depth of water" },
	{ "question": "水温", "answers": [ "すいおん" ], "comment": "water temperature" },
	{ "question": "水源", "answers": [ "すいげん" ], "comment": "source of river; fountainhead" },
	{ "question": "水準", "answers": [ "すいじゅん" ], "comment": "level; standard\nwater level" },
	{ "question": "水滴", "answers": [ "すいてき" ], "comment": "drop of water\nvessel for replenishing inkstone water" },
	{ "question": "水爆", "answers": [ "すいばく" ], "comment": "hydrogen bomb" },
	{ "question": "水産", "answers": [ "すいさん" ], "comment": "aquatic products; fisheries" },
	{ "question": "水産庁", "answers": [ "すいさんちょう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) Fisheries Agency" },
	{ "question": "水産業", "answers": [ "すいさんぎょう" ], "comment": "fisheries industry" },
	{ "question": "水産物", "answers": [ "すいさんぶつ" ], "comment": "marine products" },
	{ "question": "水田", "answers": [ "すいでん" ], "comment": "(water-filled) paddy field" },
	{ "question": "水着", "answers": [ "みずぎ" ], "comment": "bathing suit; swimsuit; swimmers" },
	{ "question": "水稲", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "wet-land rice" },
	{ "question": "水筒", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "canteen; flask; water bottle; thermos" },
	{ "question": "水系", "answers": [ "すいけい" ], "comment": "water system; river system; drainage system" },
	{ "question": "水素", "answers": [ "すいそ" ], "comment": "hydrogen (H)" },
	{ "question": "水臭い", "answers": [ "みずくさい" ], "comment": "stand-offish; distant; not frank; reserved\nwatery (alcohol, coffee, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "水色", "answers": [ "みずいろ" ], "comment": "light blue; pale blue; aqua" },
	{ "question": "水蒸気", "answers": [ "すいじょうき" ], "comment": "water vapour; water vapor; steam" },
	{ "question": "水質", "answers": [ "すいしつ" ], "comment": "water quality" },
	{ "question": "水路", "answers": [ "すいろ" ], "comment": "waterway; canal; channel; watercourse; aqueduct\nswimming pool lane" },
	{ "question": "水辺", "answers": [ "すいへん", "みずべ" ], "comment": "waterside; waterfront" },
	{ "question": "水道", "answers": [ "すいどう" ], "comment": "water service; water supply" },
	{ "question": "水道水", "answers": [ "すいどうすい" ], "comment": "tap-water" },
	{ "question": "水量", "answers": [ "すいりょう" ], "comment": "quantity or volume of water" },
	{ "question": "水銀", "answers": [ "すいぎん" ], "comment": "mercury (Hg)" },
	{ "question": "水面", "answers": [ "すいめん", "みなも" ], "comment": "water's surface" },
	{ "question": "水鳥", "answers": [ "みずとり", "すいちょう", "みずどり" ], "comment": "waterfowl; water bird; shorebird" },
	{ "question": "氷", "answers": [ "こおり" ], "comment": "ice\nshaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup)" },
	{ "question": "氷山", "answers": [ "ひょうざん" ], "comment": "iceberg" },
	{ "question": "氷河", "answers": [ "ひょうが" ], "comment": "glacier" },
	{ "question": "永久", "answers": [ "えいきゅう", "とわ", "とこしえ" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity; immortality\nEikyuu era (1113.7.13-1118.4.3)" },
	{ "question": "永代", "answers": [ "えいたい" ], "comment": "permanence; eternity" },
	{ "question": "永住", "answers": [ "えいじゅう" ], "comment": "permanent residence" },
	{ "question": "永続", "answers": [ "えいぞく" ], "comment": "permanence; continuation" },
	{ "question": "永遠", "answers": [ "えいえん" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity; immortality; permanence" },
	{ "question": "氾濫", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "overflowing; flood; inundation; deluge\noversupply; plethora" },
	{ "question": "汁", "answers": [ "つゆ", "しる" ], "comment": "juice; sap\nsoup; broth\n(dipping) sauce" },
	{ "question": "求める", "answers": [ "もとめる" ], "comment": "to want; to wish for\nto request; to demand\nto seek; to search for; to pursue (pleasure); to hunt (a job)\nto purchase; to buy" },
	{ "question": "求人", "answers": [ "きゅうじん" ], "comment": "offer of job (situation)" },
	{ "question": "求刑", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "recommended sentence; prosecution's demand for punishment" },
	{ "question": "求心力", "answers": [ "きゅうしんりょく" ], "comment": "centripetal force\nunifying force; cohesive power" },
	{ "question": "求職", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "job hunting; seeking employment" },
	{ "question": "汎", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "pan-" },
	{ "question": "汎用", "answers": [ "はんよう" ], "comment": "generic; general purpose; all-purpose" },
	{ "question": "汗", "answers": [ "あせ" ], "comment": "sweat; perspiration\nmoisture; condensation" },
	{ "question": "汚い", "answers": [ "きたない" ], "comment": "dirty; filthy; foul; unclean\ndisordered; messy; untidy; poor (e.g. handwriting)\nindecent (language, etc.); dirty; vulgar; coarse\ndastardly; mean; base; underhanded\nstingy; greedy" },
	{ "question": "汚す", "answers": [ "よごす", "けがす" ], "comment": "to pollute; to contaminate; to soil; to make dirty; to stain\nto disgrace; to dishonour; to dishonor; to defile" },
	{ "question": "汚れ", "answers": [ "よごれ" ], "comment": "dirt; filth; stain; blot; spot" },
	{ "question": "汚れる", "answers": [ "よごれる" ], "comment": "to get dirty; to become dirty\nto become sullied; to become corrupted; to lose one's chastity" },
	{ "question": "汚名", "answers": [ "おめい" ], "comment": "stigma; dishonour; dishonor; infamy" },
	{ "question": "汚染", "answers": [ "おせん" ], "comment": "pollution; contamination" },
	{ "question": "汚水", "answers": [ "おすい" ], "comment": "filthy water; sewage" },
	{ "question": "汚濁", "answers": [ "おだく" ], "comment": "pollution; contamination; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "汚職", "answers": [ "おしょく" ], "comment": "corruption" },
	{ "question": "江", "answers": [ "え" ], "comment": "inlet; bay" },
	{ "question": "江戸", "answers": [ "えど" ], "comment": "old name of Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "江戸っ子", "answers": [ "えどっこ" ], "comment": "true Tokyoite; person born and raised in Edo" },
	{ "question": "池", "answers": [ "いけ" ], "comment": "pond" },
	{ "question": "汲み取る", "answers": [ "くみとる" ], "comment": "to scoop out; to pump out\nto understand; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "汲む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "to draw (water); to fetch (water); to ladle; to dip; to scoop; to pump\nto have a drink together\nto consider; to sympathize with; to sympathise with" },
	{ "question": "決", "answers": [ "けつ" ], "comment": "decision; vote" },
	{ "question": "決して", "answers": [ "けっして" ], "comment": "never; by no means; not in the least; in no way" },
	{ "question": "決する", "answers": [ "けっする" ], "comment": "to decide; to determine" },
	{ "question": "決まって", "answers": [ "きまって" ], "comment": "always; without fail; invariably; usually; regularly" },
	{ "question": "決まり", "answers": [ "きまり" ], "comment": "rule; regulation\nsettlement; conclusion; end; agreement; arrangement\nhabit; custom; habitual way\ncountenance in front of another person; face\nlove relationship between a customer and a prostitute" },
	{ "question": "決まる", "answers": [ "きまる" ], "comment": "to be decided; to be settled\nto look good in (clothes)" },
	{ "question": "決め", "answers": [ "きめ" ], "comment": "agreement; rule" },
	{ "question": "決める", "answers": [ "きめる" ], "comment": "to decide; to choose; to determine; to make up one's mind; to resolve; to set one's heart on; to settle; to arrange; to set; to appoint; to fix\nto clinch (a victory); to decide (the outcome of a match)\nto persist in doing; to go through with\nto always do; to have made a habit of\nto take for granted; to assume\nto dress up; to dress to kill; to dress to the nines\nto carry out successfully (a move in sports, a pose in dance, etc.); to succeed in doing\nto immobilize with a double-arm lock (in sumo, judo, etc.)\nto eat or drink something; to take illegal drugs" },
	{ "question": "決め付ける", "answers": [ "きめつける" ], "comment": "to fix upon (one-sidedly); to (ignore somebody's position and) arbitrarily decide something is the case\nto scold; to take (a person) to task" },
	{ "question": "決め手", "answers": [ "きめて" ], "comment": "decider; person who decides\ndeciding factor; clincher; trump card; winning move" },
	{ "question": "決め球", "answers": [ "きめだま" ], "comment": "winning pitch" },
	{ "question": "決別", "answers": [ "けつべつ" ], "comment": "separation; farewell; parting" },
	{ "question": "決勝", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "decision of a contest; finals (in sports)" },
	{ "question": "決勝点", "answers": [ "けっしょうてん" ], "comment": "winning point; winning goal; game point (tennis, etc.); finishing line" },
	{ "question": "決定", "answers": [ "けってい" ], "comment": "decision; determination" },
	{ "question": "決定的", "answers": [ "けっていてき" ], "comment": "definite; final; decisive; conclusive" },
	{ "question": "決心", "answers": [ "けっしん" ], "comment": "determination; resolution" },
	{ "question": "決意", "answers": [ "けつい" ], "comment": "decision; determination; resolution" },
	{ "question": "決戦", "answers": [ "けっせん" ], "comment": "decisive battle; deciding match; play-off" },
	{ "question": "決断", "answers": [ "けつだん" ], "comment": "decision; determination" },
	{ "question": "決済", "answers": [ "けっさい" ], "comment": "settlement; payment of account" },
	{ "question": "決着", "answers": [ "けっちゃく" ], "comment": "conclusion; decision; end; settlement" },
	{ "question": "決算", "answers": [ "けっさん" ], "comment": "settlement of accounts; closing accounts; financial results; reporting (of accounts)" },
	{ "question": "決裁", "answers": [ "けっさい" ], "comment": "sanction; approval" },
	{ "question": "決裂", "answers": [ "けつれつ" ], "comment": "breakdown; rupture" },
	{ "question": "決議", "answers": [ "けつぎ" ], "comment": "resolution; vote; decision" },
	{ "question": "決起", "answers": [ "けっき" ], "comment": "rising to action; standing up against; jumping to one's feet" },
	{ "question": "決選投票", "answers": [ "けっせんとうひょう" ], "comment": "final vote; run-off ballot" },
	{ "question": "汽笛", "answers": [ "きてき" ], "comment": "steam whistle" },
	{ "question": "汽船", "answers": [ "きせん" ], "comment": "steamship; steamboat; steamer" },
	{ "question": "汽車", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "train (sometimes specifically a steam train)" },
	{ "question": "沈む", "answers": [ "しずむ" ], "comment": "to sink; to go under; to submerge\nto go down (e.g. sun); to set; to descend\nto feel depressed" },
	{ "question": "沈める", "answers": [ "しずめる" ], "comment": "to sink; to submerge\nto floor (an opponent)" },
	{ "question": "沈下", "answers": [ "ちんか" ], "comment": "sinking; subsidence" },
	{ "question": "沈没", "answers": [ "ちんぼつ" ], "comment": "sinking; foundering; going down; submersion\ngetting dead drunk\nhaving too much fun (esp. in a red-light district, etc.) and missing work or neglecting one's duties\nstaying in one place for a long time" },
	{ "question": "沈着", "answers": [ "ちんちゃく" ], "comment": "settling or depositing (at the bottom of something); deposition; pigmentation\ncomposure; calmness" },
	{ "question": "沈黙", "answers": [ "ちんもく" ], "comment": "silence; being silent; quiet; hush\nreticence; inaction" },
	{ "question": "沖", "answers": [ "おき" ], "comment": "open sea" },
	{ "question": "沖合", "answers": [ "おきあい" ], "comment": "coast; offing; offshore" },
	{ "question": "沖合い", "answers": [ "おきあい" ], "comment": "coast; offing; offshore" },
	{ "question": "沖縄", "answers": [ "おきなわ" ], "comment": "Okinawa (prefecture); region comprising most of Japan's southwestern archipelago (esp. Okinawa Island)\nOkinawa (city)" },
	{ "question": "沖縄開発庁長官", "answers": [ "おきなわかいはつちょうちょうかん" ], "comment": "Director General of Okinawa Development Agency" },
	{ "question": "没収", "answers": [ "ぼっしゅう" ], "comment": "forfeiture; seizure; confiscation; impounding" },
	{ "question": "没後", "answers": [ "ぼつご" ], "comment": "after death; posthumously" },
	{ "question": "没落", "answers": [ "ぼつらく" ], "comment": "ruin; fall; collapse" },
	{ "question": "没頭", "answers": [ "ぼっとう" ], "comment": "immersing oneself; devoting oneself; giving oneself up entirely to" },
	{ "question": "沢", "answers": [ "さわ" ], "comment": "swamp; marsh\nmountain stream; valley; dale" },
	{ "question": "河", "answers": [ "がわ", "かわ" ], "comment": "river; stream\nthe .... river; (suffix used with the names of rivers)" },
	{ "question": "河原", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "dry river bed; river beach" },
	{ "question": "河口", "answers": [ "かこう", "かわぐち" ], "comment": "mouth of river; estuary" },
	{ "question": "河岸", "answers": [ "かがん", "かし", "かわぎし" ], "comment": "riverbank; riverside\nfish market" },
	{ "question": "河川", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "rivers" },
	{ "question": "河川敷", "answers": [ "かせんしき", "かせんじき" ], "comment": "flood plain; river terrace; area between river and river bank" },
	{ "question": "沸かす", "answers": [ "わかす" ], "comment": "to boil; to heat\nto excite\nto melt (metal)" },
	{ "question": "沸く", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "to grow hot (e.g. water); to boil\nto get excited (at); to erupt (in applause, cheering, etc.); to be in a ferment; to take place energetically\nto ferment\nto melt (of metal)" },
	{ "question": "沸騰", "answers": [ "ふっとう" ], "comment": "boiling; seething\nbecoming heated (e.g. debate); excitement; agitation; fermentation\nsoaring (prices); shooting up" },
	{ "question": "油", "answers": [ "あぶら" ], "comment": "oil" },
	{ "question": "油井", "answers": [ "ゆせい" ], "comment": "oil well" },
	{ "question": "油彩", "answers": [ "ゆさい" ], "comment": "oil painting" },
	{ "question": "油断", "answers": [ "ゆだん" ], "comment": "negligence; carelessness; inattention; unpreparedness" },
	{ "question": "油田", "answers": [ "ゆでん" ], "comment": "oil field" },
	{ "question": "油絵", "answers": [ "あぶらえ" ], "comment": "oil painting" },
	{ "question": "治す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "to cure; to heal\nto fix; to correct; to repair\nto do over again (after -masu base of verb)\nto replace; to put back as it was\nto convert (into a different state); to transform" },
	{ "question": "治まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be at peace; to clamp down; to lessen (storm, terror, anger)" },
	{ "question": "治める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to govern; to manage\nto subdue" },
	{ "question": "治る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "to be cured; to get well; to be healed\nto get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed" },
	{ "question": "治安", "answers": [ "ちあん" ], "comment": "public order" },
	{ "question": "治水", "answers": [ "ちすい" ], "comment": "flood control" },
	{ "question": "治療", "answers": [ "じりょう", "ちりょう" ], "comment": "medical treatment; cure" },
	{ "question": "治癒", "answers": [ "ちゆ" ], "comment": "healing; cure; recovery" },
	{ "question": "治験", "answers": [ "ちけん" ], "comment": "clinical trial" },
	{ "question": "沼", "answers": [ "ぬま" ], "comment": "marsh; swamp; wetland; bog; pond" },
	{ "question": "沿い", "answers": [ "ぞい" ], "comment": "along" },
	{ "question": "沿う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to run along; to run beside\nto follow (a plan, etc.); to act in accordance with" },
	{ "question": "沿って", "answers": [ "そって" ], "comment": "along; by; parallel to" },
	{ "question": "沿岸", "answers": [ "えんがん" ], "comment": "coast; shore; littoral" },
	{ "question": "沿海", "answers": [ "えんかい" ], "comment": "coast; shore; inshore; coastal waters" },
	{ "question": "沿海州", "answers": [ "えんかいしゅう" ], "comment": "(Russian) maritime provinces" },
	{ "question": "沿線", "answers": [ "えんせん" ], "comment": "along railway line" },
	{ "question": "沿道", "answers": [ "えんどう" ], "comment": "route; course; roadside" },
	{ "question": "泉", "answers": [ "いずみ" ], "comment": "spring; fountain" },
	{ "question": "泊まり", "answers": [ "とまり" ], "comment": "overnight stay; stopover\ninn; hotel\nanchorage\nnight duty" },
	{ "question": "泊まる", "answers": [ "とまる" ], "comment": "to stay at (e.g. hotel)\nto be docked; to be berthed; to be moored" },
	{ "question": "泊める", "answers": [ "とめる" ], "comment": "to give shelter to; to lodge; to put up; to accommodate" },
	{ "question": "法", "answers": [ "ほう" ], "comment": "law; act; principle\nmethod\nmood\ndharma" },
	{ "question": "法人", "answers": [ "ほうじん" ], "comment": "corporate body; corporation; (legal) person; (juridical) person" },
	{ "question": "法令", "answers": [ "ほうれい" ], "comment": "laws and ordinances; acts (of parliament, congress, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "法制", "answers": [ "ほうせい" ], "comment": "legislation; laws" },
	{ "question": "法制局", "answers": [ "ほうせいきょく" ], "comment": "Cabinet Legislation Bureau" },
	{ "question": "法則", "answers": [ "ほうそく" ], "comment": "law; rule" },
	{ "question": "法務", "answers": [ "ほうむ" ], "comment": "judicial affairs\nclerical duty (in a temple)" },
	{ "question": "法務省", "answers": [ "ほうむしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Justice" },
	{ "question": "法医学", "answers": [ "ほういがく" ], "comment": "forensic medicine; forensic pathology; forensics\nmedical jurisprudence; legal medicine" },
	{ "question": "法外", "answers": [ "ほうがい" ], "comment": "exorbitant; outrageous; ridiculous; absurd; excessive; inordinate; extravagant; immoderate" },
	{ "question": "法学", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "law; jurisprudence" },
	{ "question": "法学部", "answers": [ "ほうがくぶ" ], "comment": "law department; law school" },
	{ "question": "法定", "answers": [ "ほうてい" ], "comment": "legal; designated by law" },
	{ "question": "法師", "answers": [ "ほうし" ], "comment": "Buddhist priest; bonze" },
	{ "question": "法廷", "answers": [ "ほうてい" ], "comment": "courtroom" },
	{ "question": "法律", "answers": [ "ほうりつ" ], "comment": "law" },
	{ "question": "法律事務所", "answers": [ "ほうりつじむしょ" ], "comment": "law office; law firm" },
	{ "question": "法文", "answers": [ "ほうぶん" ], "comment": "text of the law" },
	{ "question": "法案", "answers": [ "ほうあん" ], "comment": "bill (law); measure" },
	{ "question": "法治国", "answers": [ "ほうちこく" ], "comment": "constitutional state" },
	{ "question": "法王", "answers": [ "ほうおう" ], "comment": "Pope" },
	{ "question": "法的", "answers": [ "ほうてき" ], "comment": "legal" },
	{ "question": "法相", "answers": [ "ほうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Justice" },
	{ "question": "法要", "answers": [ "ほうよう" ], "comment": "Buddhist memorial service" },
	{ "question": "法規", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "the law; laws and regulations" },
	{ "question": "泡", "answers": [ "あわ", "あぶく" ], "comment": "bubble; foam; froth; head on beer" },
	{ "question": "波", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "wave" },
	{ "question": "波乱", "answers": [ "はらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; trouble; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "波及", "answers": [ "はきゅう" ], "comment": "spread; extension; influence; aftereffect; ripple" },
	{ "question": "波紋", "answers": [ "はもん" ], "comment": "ripple; ring on the water\nrepercussions\nJapanese slit drum; instrument made of iron with slits on top; makes a rippling sound" },
	{ "question": "波長", "answers": [ "はちょう" ], "comment": "wavelength" },
	{ "question": "泣き", "answers": [ "なき" ], "comment": "weeping; lamenting" },
	{ "question": "泣き声", "answers": [ "なきごえ" ], "comment": "cry; crying voice" },
	{ "question": "泣き顔", "answers": [ "なきがお" ], "comment": "tear-stained face" },
	{ "question": "泣く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "to cry; to weep; to sob; to howl" },
	{ "question": "泥", "answers": [ "どろ" ], "comment": "mud; slush; (wet) dirt; mire\nthief" },
	{ "question": "泥棒", "answers": [ "どろぼう" ], "comment": "thief; burglar; robber; theft" },
	{ "question": "泥沼", "answers": [ "どろぬま", "ドロぬま", "でいしょう" ], "comment": "bog; marsh; swamp; quagmire; morass\nquandary; dire situation from which one cannot extricate oneself; imbroglio" },
	{ "question": "注", "answers": [ "ちゅう" ], "comment": "annotation; explanatory note; comment" },
	{ "question": "注ぎ込む", "answers": [ "つぎこむ", "そそぎこむ" ], "comment": "to pour into (liquids); to pump into /\n to invest in; to sink money into; to put into; to lay out (funds); to inject; to impregnate; to infuse; to instill; to implant; to imbue; to focus (attention, efforts)" },
	{ "question": "注ぐ", "answers": [ "そそぐ" ], "comment": "to pour (into); to fill\nto sprinkle on from above; to shed (e.g. tears)\nto concentrate one's spirit (strength, attention) on\nto fall onto (of rain, snow)" },
	{ "question": "注す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks)\nto put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye\nto light (a fire); to burn" },
	{ "question": "注入", "answers": [ "ちゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "pouring; injection" },
	{ "question": "注射", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "injection" },
	{ "question": "注意", "answers": [ "ちゅうい" ], "comment": "caution; being careful; attention (heed); warning; advice" },
	{ "question": "注意報", "answers": [ "ちゅういほう" ], "comment": "warning (e.g. for a storm); advisory" },
	{ "question": "注意深い", "answers": [ "ちゅういぶかい" ], "comment": "careful" },
	{ "question": "注文", "answers": [ "ちゅうもん" ], "comment": "order; request" },
	{ "question": "注目", "answers": [ "ちゅうもく" ], "comment": "notice; attention; observation" },
	{ "question": "泳ぎ", "answers": [ "およぎ" ], "comment": "swimming" },
	{ "question": "泳ぐ", "answers": [ "およぐ" ], "comment": "to swim" },
	{ "question": "洋上", "answers": [ "ようじょう" ], "comment": "on the sea or ocean" },
	{ "question": "洋室", "answers": [ "ようしつ" ], "comment": "Western-style room" },
	{ "question": "洋式", "answers": [ "ようしき" ], "comment": "Western style; foreign style" },
	{ "question": "洋書", "answers": [ "ようしょ" ], "comment": "Western book" },
	{ "question": "洋服", "answers": [ "ようふく" ], "comment": "Western-style clothes (cf traditional Japanese clothes)" },
	{ "question": "洋楽", "answers": [ "ようがく" ], "comment": "Western music; European music" },
	{ "question": "洋画", "answers": [ "ようが" ], "comment": "Western painting\nWestern film; Western movie" },
	{ "question": "洋裁", "answers": [ "ようさい" ], "comment": "(Western) dressmaking" },
	{ "question": "洋酒", "answers": [ "ようしゅ" ], "comment": "Western wine and spirits; Western liquor" },
	{ "question": "洋間", "answers": [ "ようま" ], "comment": "Western-style room" },
	{ "question": "洋風", "answers": [ "ようふう" ], "comment": "Western style" },
	{ "question": "洋食", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "Western cooking; Western-style meal; Western-style food\nJapanized Western cuisine" },
	{ "question": "洒落", "answers": [ "しゃれ" ], "comment": "joke; pun; witticism\nsmartly dressed; stylish; fashion-conscious; refined" },
	{ "question": "洒落る", "answers": [ "しゃれる" ], "comment": "to dress stylishly\nto joke; to play on words" },
	{ "question": "洗い上げる", "answers": [ "あらいあげる" ], "comment": "to finish washing; to wash well; to investigate thoroughly" },
	{ "question": "洗い物", "answers": [ "あらいもの" ], "comment": "washing (esp. dishes and laundry)" },
	{ "question": "洗う", "answers": [ "あらう" ], "comment": "to wash; to cleanse; to rinse\nto inquire into; investigate\nto purify (one's heart)\nto lave (e.g. shore); to wash over (e.g. deck); to sweep" },
	{ "question": "洗剤", "answers": [ "せんざい" ], "comment": "detergent; washing material" },
	{ "question": "洗浄", "answers": [ "せんじょう" ], "comment": "washing; cleaning; laundering" },
	{ "question": "洗浄剤", "answers": [ "せんじょうざい" ], "comment": "detergent; washing material" },
	{ "question": "洗濯", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "washing; laundry" },
	{ "question": "洗濯機", "answers": [ "せんたっき", "せんたくき" ], "comment": "washing machine (laundry)" },
	{ "question": "洗礼", "answers": [ "せんれい" ], "comment": "baptism" },
	{ "question": "洗練", "answers": [ "せんれん" ], "comment": "polish; refinement" },
	{ "question": "洗面", "answers": [ "せんめん" ], "comment": "wash up (one's face); have a wash" },
	{ "question": "洗面器", "answers": [ "せんめんき" ], "comment": "wash basin; wash bowl (incl. portable bowl in a public bath)" },
	{ "question": "洗面所", "answers": [ "せんめんじょ" ], "comment": "washroom; bathroom" },
	{ "question": "洞", "answers": [ "ほら" ], "comment": "cave; den; grotto" },
	{ "question": "洞察", "answers": [ "どうさつ" ], "comment": "discernment; insight" },
	{ "question": "津波", "answers": [ "つなみ" ], "comment": "tsunami; tidal wave" },
	{ "question": "洪水", "answers": [ "こうずい" ], "comment": "flood" },
	{ "question": "活力", "answers": [ "かつりょく" ], "comment": "vitality; energy; dynamism" },
	{ "question": "活動", "answers": [ "かつどう" ], "comment": "action; activity\nmovie (esp. during the silent movie period)" },
	{ "question": "活動家", "answers": [ "かつどうか" ], "comment": "activist" },
	{ "question": "活字", "answers": [ "かつじ" ], "comment": "printing type; movable type\nprinted text; print" },
	{ "question": "活性", "answers": [ "かっせい" ], "comment": "activity" },
	{ "question": "活気", "answers": [ "かっき" ], "comment": "energy; liveliness" },
	{ "question": "活況", "answers": [ "かっきょう" ], "comment": "activity; briskness; prosperity" },
	{ "question": "活用", "answers": [ "かつよう" ], "comment": "practical use; application\nconjugation; declension; inflection" },
	{ "question": "活発", "answers": [ "かっぱつ" ], "comment": "lively; active; vigorous; animated; brisk" },
	{ "question": "活路", "answers": [ "かつろ" ], "comment": "means of survival; means of escape" },
	{ "question": "活躍", "answers": [ "かつやく" ], "comment": "activity (esp. energetic); great efforts; conspicuous service\nto flourish; to participate actively; to play an active role" },
	{ "question": "派", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "clique; faction; school" },
	{ "question": "派兵", "answers": [ "はへい" ], "comment": "dispatch of troops; despatch of troops" },
	{ "question": "派出所", "answers": [ "はしゅつしょ", "はしゅつじょ" ], "comment": "local police station" },
	{ "question": "派手", "answers": [ "はで" ], "comment": "showy; loud; gay; flashy; gaudy" },
	{ "question": "派生", "answers": [ "はせい" ], "comment": "derivation" },
	{ "question": "派遣", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "dispatch; despatch; deployment\ntemporary employee (esp. from an agency); temporary worker; agency temp" },
	{ "question": "派閥", "answers": [ "はばつ" ], "comment": "clique; faction" },
	{ "question": "流", "answers": [ "りゅう" ], "comment": "fashion; way; style; manner\nschool (of thought)\nclass; rank; rate\ncurrent (electrical, water, etc.); flow; stream" },
	{ "question": "流し", "answers": [ "ながし" ], "comment": "sink (e.g. kitchen)\ncruising (e.g. taxi); strolling (entertainer, musician, etc.)\nwashing area in a Japanese-style bath\nback-washing service (in a public bath)\nfloating (something on water); setting adrift; washing away" },
	{ "question": "流す", "answers": [ "ながす" ], "comment": "to drain; to pour; to spill; to shed (blood, tears)\nto wash away\nto distribute (e.g. electricity over wires, music over a PA system, etc.); to circulate; to broadcast; to beam\nto cruise (e.g. taxi)\nto float; to set adrift\nto call off (a meeting, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "流れ", "answers": [ "ながれ" ], "comment": "stream; current; flow\ncourse of events" },
	{ "question": "流れる", "answers": [ "ながれる" ], "comment": "to stream; to flow (liquid, time, etc.); to run (ink)\nto be washed away; to be carried\nto drift; to float (e.g. clouds); to wander; to stray\nto sweep (e.g. rumour, fire); to spread; to circulate\nto be heard (e.g. music); to be played\nto lapse (e.g. into indolence, despair)\nto pass; to elapse; to be transmitted\nto be called off; to be forfeited\nto disappear; to be removed" },
	{ "question": "流れ込む", "answers": [ "ながれこむ" ], "comment": "to flow into; to pour into; to stream into" },
	{ "question": "流入", "answers": [ "りゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "afflux; influx" },
	{ "question": "流出", "answers": [ "りゅうしゅつ" ], "comment": "discharge; outward flow; efflux; effluence; haemorrhage; hemorrhage; bleeding (e.g. ink into paper)\nleak of (private) information or pictures" },
	{ "question": "流動", "answers": [ "りゅうどう" ], "comment": "flow" },
	{ "question": "流動的", "answers": [ "りゅうどうてき" ], "comment": "fluid; unsettled" },
	{ "question": "流域", "answers": [ "りゅういき" ], "comment": "(river) basin" },
	{ "question": "流暢", "answers": [ "りゅうちょう" ], "comment": "fluent (language skill); flowing" },
	{ "question": "流派", "answers": [ "りゅうは" ], "comment": "school (e.g. of ikebana)" },
	{ "question": "流用", "answers": [ "りゅうよう" ], "comment": "diversion; appropriation (e.g. of funds); misappropriation\nre-use (e.g. old computer parts); recycling" },
	{ "question": "流血", "answers": [ "りゅうけつ" ], "comment": "bloodshed" },
	{ "question": "流行", "answers": [ "りゅうこう", "はやり" ], "comment": "fashion; fad; vogue; craze\nprevalence (e.g. of a disease)" },
	{ "question": "流行る", "answers": [ "はやる" ], "comment": "to be popular; to come into fashion\nto be prevalent; to spread widely (e.g. disease); to be endemic\nto flourish; to thrive" },
	{ "question": "流行歌", "answers": [ "りゅうこうか" ], "comment": "popular song; hit song" },
	{ "question": "流通", "answers": [ "りゅうつう" ], "comment": "circulation (e.g.money, goods); flow (water, air); distribution\nnegotiable (e.g. shares); distributional; circulating" },
	{ "question": "浄化", "answers": [ "じょうか" ], "comment": "purification; cleanup" },
	{ "question": "浄化槽", "answers": [ "じょうかそう" ], "comment": "septic tank; tank for purifying water" },
	{ "question": "浄土", "answers": [ "じょうど" ], "comment": "Pure Land (esp. the Western Pure Land paradise of Amitabha)\nPure Land Buddhism" },
	{ "question": "浄土真宗", "answers": [ "じょうどしんしゅう" ], "comment": "Jōdo Shinshū (offshoot of the Jōdo sect); True Pure Land School" },
	{ "question": "浄水", "answers": [ "じょうすい" ], "comment": "clean water" },
	{ "question": "浅い", "answers": [ "あさい" ], "comment": "shallow; superficial\nslight (wound); light (sleep); pale (colour); inadequate (knowledge)\nshort (time); early; young" },
	{ "question": "浅はか", "answers": [ "あさはか" ], "comment": "shallow; superficial; thoughtless; short-sighted; foolish; silly" },
	{ "question": "浚う", "answers": [ "さらう" ], "comment": "to sweep away; to wash away; to dredge" },
	{ "question": "浜辺", "answers": [ "はまべ" ], "comment": "beach; foreshore" },
	{ "question": "浦", "answers": [ "うら" ], "comment": "inlet\nseashore; beach" },
	{ "question": "浪人", "answers": [ "ろうにん" ], "comment": "ronin; wandering samurai without a master to serve\nout of work\nwaiting for another chance to enter a university" },
	{ "question": "浪費", "answers": [ "ろうひ" ], "comment": "waste; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "浮かび上がる", "answers": [ "うかびあがる" ], "comment": "to rise to the surface\nto come to the front; to emerge (e.g. from obscurity)\nto stand out (e.g. against a dark background)" },
	{ "question": "浮かぶ", "answers": [ "うかぶ" ], "comment": "to float; to be suspended\nto rise to surface\nto come to mind; to have inspiration" },
	{ "question": "浮かべる", "answers": [ "うかべる" ], "comment": "to float; to set afloat; to launch\nto show on one's face (smile, sadness, etc.)\nto recall; to call to mind; to imagine; to think of" },
	{ "question": "浮かれる", "answers": [ "うかれる" ], "comment": "to make merry; to be festive" },
	{ "question": "浮き", "answers": [ "うき" ], "comment": "floating; buoyancy\nfishing float; bobber\nbuoy\nlifebuoy; life belt; float; rubber ring" },
	{ "question": "浮き彫り", "answers": [ "うきぼり" ], "comment": "relief; embossed carving\nbringing to the fore; throwing something into relief" },
	{ "question": "浮く", "answers": [ "うく" ], "comment": "to float\nto become merry; to be cheerful\nto become loose; to become unsteady\nto feel out of it; to be cut off (e.g. from those around you); to feel out of place\nto be frivolous; to be uncertain\nto have (time, money, etc.) left over; to be saved (e.g. money)\nto have no basis; to be unreliable" },
	{ "question": "浮上", "answers": [ "ふじょう" ], "comment": "surfacing; rising to the surface; emerging; leaping into prominence; levitation" },
	{ "question": "浮世絵", "answers": [ "うきよえ" ], "comment": "ukiyoe (color print of everyday life in the Edo period) (colour)" },
	{ "question": "浮動票", "answers": [ "ふどうひょう" ], "comment": "swing vote" },
	{ "question": "浮揚", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "floating (in the air)" },
	{ "question": "浮気", "answers": [ "うわき" ], "comment": "extramarital sex; affair; fooling around\ninfidelity; wantonness; unfaithfulness; inconstancy; fickleness; caprice" },
	{ "question": "浮沈", "answers": [ "ふちん" ], "comment": "floating and sinking; rise and fall; ebb and flow; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "浮浪者", "answers": [ "ふろうしゃ" ], "comment": "vagrant" },
	{ "question": "浮遊", "answers": [ "ふゆう" ], "comment": "floating; wandering; suspension" },
	{ "question": "浴びせる", "answers": [ "あびせる" ], "comment": "to pour on" },
	{ "question": "浴びる", "answers": [ "あびる" ], "comment": "to dash over oneself (e.g. water); to take (e.g. shower); to bask in (e.g. the sun); to bathe in; to be flooded with (e.g. light); to be covered in\nto suffer (e.g. an attack); to draw (e.g. criticism, attention, praise); to have heaped upon; to be showered with" },
	{ "question": "浴場", "answers": [ "よくじょう" ], "comment": "bath; bathhouse; bathroom" },
	{ "question": "浴室", "answers": [ "よくしつ" ], "comment": "bathroom" },
	{ "question": "浴槽", "answers": [ "よくそう" ], "comment": "bathtub" },
	{ "question": "浴衣", "answers": [ "よくい", "ゆかた" ], "comment": "yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe)" },
	{ "question": "海", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "sea; ocean; waters" },
	{ "question": "海上", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "(by, at, on) sea; maritime; marine" },
	{ "question": "海上保安庁", "answers": [ "かいじょうほあんちょう" ], "comment": "Japan Coast Guard (formerly Maritime Safety Agency)" },
	{ "question": "海上自衛隊", "answers": [ "かいじょうじえいたい" ], "comment": "Maritime Self Defense Forces (Defence)" },
	{ "question": "海中", "answers": [ "かいちゅう" ], "comment": "in the sea" },
	{ "question": "海兵隊", "answers": [ "かいへいたい" ], "comment": "Marine Corps; Royal Marines" },
	{ "question": "海域", "answers": [ "かいいき" ], "comment": "area of ocean" },
	{ "question": "海外", "answers": [ "かいがい" ], "comment": "foreign; abroad; overseas" },
	{ "question": "海外出張", "answers": [ "かいがいしゅっちょう" ], "comment": "overseas business trip" },
	{ "question": "海岸", "answers": [ "かいがん" ], "comment": "coast; beach" },
	{ "question": "海岸線", "answers": [ "かいがんせん" ], "comment": "coastline; shoreline\ncoastal railway" },
	{ "question": "海峡", "answers": [ "かいきょう" ], "comment": "channel (e.g. between two land masses); strait" },
	{ "question": "海底", "answers": [ "かいてい", "うなぞこ" ], "comment": "bottom of the ocean\nundersea; submarine" },
	{ "question": "海戦", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "naval battle" },
	{ "question": "海抜", "answers": [ "かいばつ" ], "comment": "height above sea level" },
	{ "question": "海水", "answers": [ "かいすい" ], "comment": "ocean water" },
	{ "question": "海水浴", "answers": [ "かいすいよく" ], "comment": "swimming in the ocean; sea bathing; seawater bath; going for a dip in the ocean" },
	{ "question": "海水浴場", "answers": [ "かいすいよくじょう" ], "comment": "swimming area (in the ocean); swimming beach; seawater baths" },
	{ "question": "海洋", "answers": [ "かいよう" ], "comment": "ocean" },
	{ "question": "海流", "answers": [ "かいりゅう" ], "comment": "ocean current" },
	{ "question": "海浜", "answers": [ "かいひん" ], "comment": "seaside; beachside" },
	{ "question": "海王星", "answers": [ "かいおうせい" ], "comment": "Neptune (planet)" },
	{ "question": "海産物", "answers": [ "かいさんぶつ" ], "comment": "marine products" },
	{ "question": "海老", "answers": [ "えび" ], "comment": "prawn; shrimp; lobster; crayfish" },
	{ "question": "海藻", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "seaweed" },
	{ "question": "海賊", "answers": [ "かいぞく" ], "comment": "pirate; sea robber" },
	{ "question": "海軍", "answers": [ "かいぐん" ], "comment": "navy" },
	{ "question": "海辺", "answers": [ "かいへん", "うみべ" ], "comment": "beach; seashore; seaside; coast" },
	{ "question": "海運", "answers": [ "かいうん" ], "comment": "maritime; marine transportation" },
	{ "question": "海道", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "sea route" },
	{ "question": "海難", "answers": [ "かいなん" ], "comment": "accident at sea; sea disaster; shipwreck" },
	{ "question": "海面", "answers": [ "かいめん" ], "comment": "sea level; (surface of) sea" },
	{ "question": "浸す", "answers": [ "ひたす" ], "comment": "to soak; to dip; to steep; to immerse\nto moisten; to wet" },
	{ "question": "浸る", "answers": [ "ひたる" ], "comment": "to be soaked in; to be flooded; to be submerged\nto be immersed in (joy, memories, alcohol, etc.); to give oneself over to; to bask in" },
	{ "question": "浸水", "answers": [ "しんすい" ], "comment": "inundation; submersion; flood" },
	{ "question": "浸透", "answers": [ "しんとう" ], "comment": "permeation; penetration; soaking\nosmosis" },
	{ "question": "消える", "answers": [ "きえる" ], "comment": "to go out; to vanish; to disappear" },
	{ "question": "消しゴム", "answers": [ "けしゴム" ], "comment": "eraser; India rubber" },
	{ "question": "消す", "answers": [ "けす" ], "comment": "to erase; to delete; to cross out\nto turn off power\nto extinguish; to put out\nto bump off" },
	{ "question": "消化", "answers": [ "しょうか" ], "comment": "digestion\nthorough understanding\nselling accumulated (excess) products; dealing with a large amount of work\nlosing one's form and turning into something else" },
	{ "question": "消化器", "answers": [ "しょうかき" ], "comment": "digestive organs" },
	{ "question": "消印", "answers": [ "けしいん" ], "comment": "postmark; (postal) cancellation mark" },
	{ "question": "消息", "answers": [ "しょうそく" ], "comment": "news (from somebody); letter; contact\n(somebody's) whereabouts; (somebody's) movements" },
	{ "question": "消息筋", "answers": [ "しょうそくすじ" ], "comment": "informed circles" },
	{ "question": "消極", "answers": [ "しょうきょく" ], "comment": "negative; conservative\ndepolarization" },
	{ "question": "消極的", "answers": [ "しょうきょくてき" ], "comment": "negative; passive; half-hearted; unmotivated" },
	{ "question": "消毒", "answers": [ "しょうどく" ], "comment": "disinfection; sterilization; sterilisation" },
	{ "question": "消滅", "answers": [ "しょうめつ" ], "comment": "extinction; extinguishment; disappearance; vanishing; termination; lapse\nannihilation" },
	{ "question": "消火", "answers": [ "しょうか" ], "comment": "fire fighting; extinguishing a fire" },
	{ "question": "消火器", "answers": [ "しょうかき" ], "comment": "fire extinguisher" },
	{ "question": "消灯", "answers": [ "しょうとう" ], "comment": "putting out the light; switching off the light" },
	{ "question": "消耗", "answers": [ "しょうこう", "しょうもう" ], "comment": "exhaustion; consumption; waste; dissipation" },
	{ "question": "消費", "answers": [ "しょうひ" ], "comment": "consumption; expenditure" },
	{ "question": "消費税", "answers": [ "しょうひぜい" ], "comment": "consumption tax (incl. sales tax, VAT, excise duty, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "消費者", "answers": [ "しょうひしゃ" ], "comment": "consumer" },
	{ "question": "消費財", "answers": [ "しょうひざい" ], "comment": "consumer goods" },
	{ "question": "消防", "answers": [ "しょうぼう" ], "comment": "fire fighting\nfire department; fire brigade" },
	{ "question": "消防庁", "answers": [ "しょうぼうちょう" ], "comment": "Fire and Disaster Management Agency (formerly: Fire Defense Agency) (Defence)" },
	{ "question": "消防署", "answers": [ "しょうぼうしょ" ], "comment": "fire station" },
	{ "question": "消防車", "answers": [ "しょうぼうしゃ" ], "comment": "fire engine; fire truck" },
	{ "question": "涙", "answers": [ "なみだ" ], "comment": "tear; tears; lachrymal secretion\nsympathy" },
	{ "question": "液", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "liquid; fluid" },
	{ "question": "液体", "answers": [ "えきたい" ], "comment": "liquid; fluid" },
	{ "question": "液化", "answers": [ "えきか" ], "comment": "liquefaction" },
	{ "question": "液晶", "answers": [ "えきしょう" ], "comment": "liquid crystal" },
	{ "question": "涼しい", "answers": [ "すずしい" ], "comment": "cool; refreshing\nclear (e.g. eyes); bright\nclear; distinct\ncomposed (facial expression); unruffled; unconcerned\npure; upright; innocent" },
	{ "question": "涼む", "answers": [ "すずむ" ], "comment": "to cool oneself; to cool off; to enjoy the cool air" },
	{ "question": "涼風", "answers": [ "すずかぜ", "りょうふう" ], "comment": "cool breeze; refreshing breeze" },
	{ "question": "淡々", "answers": [ "たんたん" ], "comment": "uninterested; unconcerned; indifferent; dispassionate; matter-of-fact; detached\nplain; light; simple; bland\nflowing gently" },
	{ "question": "淡水", "answers": [ "たんすい" ], "comment": "fresh water (i.e. not salt water)" },
	{ "question": "淡泊", "answers": [ "たんぱく" ], "comment": "light (color, colour, taste); simple; plain\nfrank; candid; ingenuous; indifferent" },
	{ "question": "深い", "answers": [ "ふかい" ], "comment": "deep\nprofound\ndense; thick\nclose (relationship)\nintense; strong\nlate" },
	{ "question": "深さ", "answers": [ "ふかさ" ], "comment": "depth; profundity" },
	{ "question": "深まる", "answers": [ "ふかまる" ], "comment": "to deepen; to heighten; to intensify" },
	{ "question": "深み", "answers": [ "ふかみ" ], "comment": "depth; deep place" },
	{ "question": "深める", "answers": [ "ふかめる" ], "comment": "to deepen; to heighten; to intensify" },
	{ "question": "深刻", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "serious; severe; grave; acute" },
	{ "question": "深刻化", "answers": [ "しんこくか" ], "comment": "becoming more serious or severe; aggravation; intensification" },
	{ "question": "深夜", "answers": [ "しんや" ], "comment": "late at night" },
	{ "question": "深層", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "depths; deep level" },
	{ "question": "深山", "answers": [ "しんざん", "みやま" ], "comment": "mountain recess; deep in the mountains" },
	{ "question": "深海", "answers": [ "しんかい" ], "comment": "deep sea; depths of the sea; ocean depths" },
	{ "question": "淵", "answers": [ "ふち" ], "comment": "deep pool; deep water; abyss\ndepths (e.g. of despair, etc.); grip (e.g. of death)" },
	{ "question": "混ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join" },
	{ "question": "混じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join" },
	{ "question": "混ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to stir; to blend" },
	{ "question": "混ぜ合わす", "answers": [ "まぜあわす" ], "comment": "to mix together; to blend; to compound" },
	{ "question": "混む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded; to be packed\nto be complex\nto go into; to put into; to remain (seated); to be plunged into (silence); to do thoroughly\nto do intently\nto continue in the same state" },
	{ "question": "混乱", "answers": [ "こんらん" ], "comment": "disorder; chaos; confusion; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "混入", "answers": [ "こんにゅう" ], "comment": "mixing; adding; adulteration" },
	{ "question": "混合", "answers": [ "こんごう" ], "comment": "mixing; mixture; meld\nmiscegenation" },
	{ "question": "混同", "answers": [ "こんどう" ], "comment": "confusion; mixing; merger" },
	{ "question": "混成", "answers": [ "こんせい" ], "comment": "mixed (e.g. team, chorus)" },
	{ "question": "混戦", "answers": [ "こんせん" ], "comment": "free-for-all fight" },
	{ "question": "混血", "answers": [ "こんけつ" ], "comment": "mixed race; mixed parentage" },
	{ "question": "混迷", "answers": [ "こんめい" ], "comment": "turmoil; chaos; confusion" },
	{ "question": "混雑", "answers": [ "こんざつ" ], "comment": "congestion; crush; crowding; jam\nconfusion; disorder" },
	{ "question": "添う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to meet (one's expectations, etc.); to satisfy; to comply with\nto accompany; to stay by one's side\nto marry; to wed\nto be added" },
	{ "question": "添える", "answers": [ "そえる" ], "comment": "to garnish; to accompany (as a card does a gift)\nto add to as support; to prop up\nto accompany (as an aid, guide, translator, etc.)\nto mimic; to imitate\nto draw something near to oneself; to approach nearby" },
	{ "question": "添乗", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "accompanying; escorting" },
	{ "question": "添付", "answers": [ "てんぷ" ], "comment": "attachment (e.g. email); appendix (e.g. of a report, document, etc); annex; appendage; annexure" },
	{ "question": "添削", "answers": [ "てんさく" ], "comment": "correction; looking over; touching up" },
	{ "question": "添加", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "addition; annexing" },
	{ "question": "添加物", "answers": [ "てんかぶつ" ], "comment": "additive" },
	{ "question": "清い", "answers": [ "きよい" ], "comment": "clear; pure; noble" },
	{ "question": "清らか", "answers": [ "きよらか" ], "comment": "clean; pure; chaste" },
	{ "question": "清掃", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "cleaning; clean-up; garbage collection; scavenging" },
	{ "question": "清新", "answers": [ "せいしん" ], "comment": "fresh; new" },
	{ "question": "清書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "clean copy" },
	{ "question": "清流", "answers": [ "せいりゅう" ], "comment": "clear stream" },
	{ "question": "清浄", "answers": [ "せいじょう", "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "pure; clean; purity" },
	{ "question": "清涼", "answers": [ "せいりょう" ], "comment": "cool; refreshing" },
	{ "question": "清潔", "answers": [ "せいけつ" ], "comment": "clean; hygienic; sanitary\npure; virtuous; immaculate" },
	{ "question": "清算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "settlement (financial); squaring accounts; clearing debts\nliquidation\nending (a relationship); breaking up (with); burying (the past); redeeming (one's faults)" },
	{ "question": "清貧", "answers": [ "せいひん" ], "comment": "honourable poverty; honorable poverty" },
	{ "question": "清酒", "answers": [ "せいしゅ" ], "comment": "refined sake" },
	{ "question": "渇き", "answers": [ "かわき" ], "comment": "thirst" },
	{ "question": "渇く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "to be thirsty; to feel thirsty\nto thirst for; to crave" },
	{ "question": "渇水", "answers": [ "かっすい" ], "comment": "water shortage" },
	{ "question": "済ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "to finish; to get it over with; to conclude\nto settle; to pay back\nto get along (without something); to make do with (without)" },
	{ "question": "済ませる", "answers": [ "すませる" ], "comment": "to finish; to make an end of; to get through with; to let end" },
	{ "question": "済む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to finish; to end; to be completed\nto merely result in something less severe than expected\nto feel at ease\nto feel unease or guilt for troubling someone; to be sorry" },
	{ "question": "渉外", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "public relations; client liaison; client relations" },
	{ "question": "渋い", "answers": [ "しぶい" ], "comment": "astringent; bitter; puckery; rough; harsh; tart\naustere; elegant (and unobtrusive); refined; quiet (and simple); sober; sombre; subdued; tasteful (in a quiet way); understated\nsour (look); glum; grim; sullen; sulky\nstingy; tight-fisted" },
	{ "question": "渋る", "answers": [ "しぶる" ], "comment": "to hesitate; to hold back; to balk; to falter\nto be reluctant; to be unwilling; to begrudge\nto have loose painful bowel movement; to suffer from tenesmus" },
	{ "question": "渋滞", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "congestion (e.g. traffic); delay; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "渋面", "answers": [ "じゅうめん", "しぶづら", "しぶつら" ], "comment": "grimace; sullen face" },
	{ "question": "渓谷", "answers": [ "けいこく" ], "comment": "valley; ravine; canyon" },
	{ "question": "渚", "answers": [ "なぎさ" ], "comment": "water's edge; beach; shore" },
	{ "question": "減らす", "answers": [ "へらす" ], "comment": "to abate; to decrease; to diminish; to shorten" },
	{ "question": "減る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "to decrease (in size or number); to diminish; to abate" },
	{ "question": "減価償却", "answers": [ "げんかしょうきゃく" ], "comment": "depreciation" },
	{ "question": "減免", "answers": [ "げんめん" ], "comment": "reduction and exemption (e.g. taxes); mitigation and remission (e.g. in criminal law)" },
	{ "question": "減反", "answers": [ "げんたん" ], "comment": "reduction (of crop size); reduction of acreage (under cultivation)" },
	{ "question": "減収", "answers": [ "げんしゅう" ], "comment": "fall; decrease (in income)" },
	{ "question": "減員", "answers": [ "げんいん" ], "comment": "reduction of staff" },
	{ "question": "減少", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "decrease; reduction; decline" },
	{ "question": "減点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "subtract; give a demerit" },
	{ "question": "減産", "answers": [ "げんさん" ], "comment": "reduction in production" },
	{ "question": "減益", "answers": [ "げんえき" ], "comment": "decrease in profits" },
	{ "question": "減税", "answers": [ "げんぜい" ], "comment": "tax reduction" },
	{ "question": "減給", "answers": [ "げんきゅう" ], "comment": "pay cut; salary cut" },
	{ "question": "減退", "answers": [ "げんたい" ], "comment": "decline; ebb; failure; decay; decrease; loss" },
	{ "question": "減速", "answers": [ "げんそく" ], "comment": "deceleration" },
	{ "question": "減量", "answers": [ "げんりょう" ], "comment": "loss in weight, esp. body weight\nloss in quantity; reducing quantity; reducing doses" },
	{ "question": "減額", "answers": [ "げんがく" ], "comment": "reduction; diminution; abatement" },
	{ "question": "渡し", "answers": [ "わたし" ], "comment": "ferry (crossing); ferry(boat)\ndelivery" },
	{ "question": "渡す", "answers": [ "わたす" ], "comment": "to ferry across (e.g. a river); to carry across; to traverse\nto lay across; to build across\nto hand over; to hand in; to pass; to give; to transfer" },
	{ "question": "渡り", "answers": [ "わたり" ], "comment": "ferry" },
	{ "question": "渡り鳥", "answers": [ "わたりどり" ], "comment": "migratory bird; bird of passage" },
	{ "question": "渡る", "answers": [ "わたる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to go across\nto extend; to cover; to range; to span" },
	{ "question": "渡航", "answers": [ "とこう" ], "comment": "voyage" },
	{ "question": "渦", "answers": [ "うず" ], "comment": "whirlpool; swirl; eddy; vortex; maelstrom" },
	{ "question": "渦中", "answers": [ "かちゅう" ], "comment": "vortex; maelstrom; whirlpool; convulsions; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "渦巻き", "answers": [ "うずまき" ], "comment": "whirlpool; eddy; coil" },
	{ "question": "温かい", "answers": [ "あったかい", "あたたかい" ], "comment": "warm; mild; genial" },
	{ "question": "温まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる", "ぬくまる", "あったまる" ], "comment": "to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm" },
	{ "question": "温める", "answers": [ "あたためる", "あっためる" ], "comment": "to warm; to heat" },
	{ "question": "温厚", "answers": [ "おんこう" ], "comment": "gentle" },
	{ "question": "温和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; moderate" },
	{ "question": "温存", "answers": [ "おんぞん" ], "comment": "preservation; retainment; keeping" },
	{ "question": "温室", "answers": [ "おんしつ" ], "comment": "greenhouse; hothouse; conservatory; glasshouse" },
	{ "question": "温帯", "answers": [ "おんたい" ], "comment": "temperate zone" },
	{ "question": "温床", "answers": [ "おんしょう" ], "comment": "hotbed; breeding ground" },
	{ "question": "温度", "answers": [ "おんど" ], "comment": "temperature" },
	{ "question": "温暖", "answers": [ "おんだん" ], "comment": "warm; mild; temperate; warmth" },
	{ "question": "温泉", "answers": [ "おんせん" ], "comment": "spa; hot spring; onsen" },
	{ "question": "測る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "測候所", "answers": [ "そっこうじょ" ], "comment": "weather measurement station" },
	{ "question": "測定", "answers": [ "そくてい" ], "comment": "measurement" },
	{ "question": "測量", "answers": [ "そくりょう" ], "comment": "measurement; surveying" },
	{ "question": "港", "answers": [ "みなと" ], "comment": "harbour; harbor; port" },
	{ "question": "港内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "inside the harbour; inside the harbor" },
	{ "question": "港湾", "answers": [ "こうわん" ], "comment": "harbours; harbors" },
	{ "question": "渾名", "answers": [ "あだな", "こんめい" ], "comment": "nickname" },
	{ "question": "湖", "answers": [ "みずうみ" ], "comment": "lake" },
	{ "question": "湖沼", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "lakes and marshes" },
	{ "question": "湖畔", "answers": [ "こはん" ], "comment": "lake shore" },
	{ "question": "湧く", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "to well (up); to gush forth (of water); to spring out; to surge\nto appear (esp. suddenly) (sweat, tears, etc.)\nto feel emotions form (joy, bravery, etc.)\nto hatch (esp. of parasitic insects, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "湧水", "answers": [ "ゆうすい" ], "comment": "spring; welling of water" },
	{ "question": "湯", "answers": [ "ゆ" ], "comment": "hot water\nhot bath; hot spring\nmolten iron" },
	{ "question": "湯気", "answers": [ "ゆげ" ], "comment": "steam; vapour; vapor" },
	{ "question": "湯飲み", "answers": [ "ゆのみ" ], "comment": "teacup" },
	{ "question": "湾", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "bay; gulf; inlet" },
	{ "question": "湾岸", "answers": [ "わんがん" ], "comment": "gulf coast; bay coast" },
	{ "question": "湿っぽい", "answers": [ "しめっぽい" ], "comment": "damp; humid; wet\ngloomy; melancholy" },
	{ "question": "湿る", "answers": [ "しめる", "しとる" ], "comment": "to be wet; to become wet; to be damp; to be moist\nto be in low spirits; to feel depressed" },
	{ "question": "湿原", "answers": [ "しつげん" ], "comment": "marshy grassland; wetlands" },
	{ "question": "湿地", "answers": [ "しっち" ], "comment": "wetland; wetlands" },
	{ "question": "湿度", "answers": [ "しつど" ], "comment": "level of humidity" },
	{ "question": "湿気", "answers": [ "しっけ", "しっき" ], "comment": "moisture; humidity; dampness" },
	{ "question": "湿疹", "answers": [ "しっしん" ], "comment": "eczema; rash" },
	{ "question": "満々", "answers": [ "まんまん" ], "comment": "full of; brimming with" },
	{ "question": "満たす", "answers": [ "みたす" ], "comment": "to satisfy; to fulfill; to appease\nto fill (e.g. a cup); to pack\nto reach (a certain number)" },
	{ "question": "満ちる", "answers": [ "みちる" ], "comment": "to be full\nto wax (e.g. moon)\nto rise (e.g. tide)\nto mature; to expire" },
	{ "question": "満了", "answers": [ "まんりょう" ], "comment": "expiration; termination" },
	{ "question": "満員", "answers": [ "まんいん" ], "comment": "full house; no vacancy; sold out; standing room only; full (of people); crowded" },
	{ "question": "満員電車", "answers": [ "まんいんでんしゃ" ], "comment": "crowded train" },
	{ "question": "満喫", "answers": [ "まんきつ" ], "comment": "having enough of (food, drink, etc.); having one's fill\nfully enjoying" },
	{ "question": "満場", "answers": [ "まんじょう" ], "comment": "whole house; whole audience" },
	{ "question": "満場一致", "answers": [ "まんじょういっち" ], "comment": "unanimity" },
	{ "question": "満塁", "answers": [ "まんるい" ], "comment": "bases loaded" },
	{ "question": "満席", "answers": [ "まんせき" ], "comment": "full house; all seats occupied; fully occupied" },
	{ "question": "満月", "answers": [ "まんげつ" ], "comment": "full moon" },
	{ "question": "満期", "answers": [ "まんき" ], "comment": "expiration (of a term); maturity (e.g. investment)" },
	{ "question": "満杯", "answers": [ "まんぱい" ], "comment": "full" },
	{ "question": "満点", "answers": [ "まんてん" ], "comment": "perfect score; full marks\nextremely; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "満足", "answers": [ "まんぞく" ], "comment": "satisfaction; contentment; complacency\nsufficient; enough; adequate; proper" },
	{ "question": "満開", "answers": [ "まんかい" ], "comment": "full bloom" },
	{ "question": "満面", "answers": [ "まんめん" ], "comment": "(the) whole face" },
	{ "question": "源", "answers": [ "みなもと" ], "comment": "source (of a river); fountainhead\nsource; origin; root" },
	{ "question": "源氏", "answers": [ "げんじ" ], "comment": "Genji (the character in the Genji Monogatari)\nthe Minamoto family" },
	{ "question": "源泉", "answers": [ "げんせん" ], "comment": "source" },
	{ "question": "源流", "answers": [ "げんりゅう" ], "comment": "source (e.g. of a river); headwaters\norigin of something continuous (language, culture, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "準える", "answers": [ "なずらえる", "なぞらえる" ], "comment": "to pattern after; to liken to; to imitate" },
	{ "question": "準じる", "answers": [ "じゅんじる" ], "comment": "to follow; to conform; to apply to" },
	{ "question": "準ずる", "answers": [ "じゅんずる" ], "comment": "to apply correspondingly; to correspond to; to be proportionate to; to conform to" },
	{ "question": "準備", "answers": [ "じゅんび" ], "comment": "preparation; setup; arrangements; provision; reserve" },
	{ "question": "準急", "answers": [ "じゅんきゅう" ], "comment": "semi-express train; local express train; sub-express train; slower than an express (more stops)" },
	{ "question": "準決勝", "answers": [ "じゅんけっしょう" ], "comment": "semifinal" },
	{ "question": "溜める", "answers": [ "ためる" ], "comment": "to amass; to accumulate; to store\nto leave unpaid" },
	{ "question": "溜め息", "answers": [ "ためいき" ], "comment": "sigh" },
	{ "question": "溝", "answers": [ "みぞ", "どぶ" ], "comment": "ditch; drain; gutter; trench\ngroove; tread\ngap (between people, countries, etc.); gulf" },
	{ "question": "溶かす", "answers": [ "とかす" ], "comment": "to melt; to dissolve" },
	{ "question": "溶く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "to dissolve (paint); to scramble (eggs); to melt (metal, etc.); to mix (water with flour, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "溶ける", "answers": [ "とける" ], "comment": "to melt; to thaw; to fuse; to dissolve" },
	{ "question": "溶け込む", "answers": [ "とけこむ" ], "comment": "to melt into; to merge into\nto fit in; to adapt; to blend" },
	{ "question": "溶岩", "answers": [ "ようがん" ], "comment": "lava" },
	{ "question": "溶接", "answers": [ "ようせつ" ], "comment": "weld; welding" },
	{ "question": "溶液", "answers": [ "ようえき" ], "comment": "solution (liquid)" },
	{ "question": "滅びる", "answers": [ "ほろびる" ], "comment": "to be ruined; to go under; to perish; to be destroyed" },
	{ "question": "滅亡", "answers": [ "めつぼう" ], "comment": "downfall; ruin; collapse; destruction" },
	{ "question": "滅多に", "answers": [ "めったに" ], "comment": "rarely; seldom" },
	{ "question": "滑らか", "answers": [ "すべらか", "なめらか" ], "comment": "smooth (of a surface); glassy; velvety; soft\nsmooth (of an action, proceedings, etc.); fluent (speech); fluid; trouble-free" },
	{ "question": "滑る", "answers": [ "すべる" ], "comment": "to glide; to slide (e.g. on skis); to slip\nto fail (an examination); to bomb (when telling a joke)\nto drop; to go down; to come down; to fall (e.g. in status)" },
	{ "question": "滑稽", "answers": [ "こっけい" ], "comment": "funny; humorous; humourous; comical; laughable; ridiculous; joking" },
	{ "question": "滑走", "answers": [ "かっそう" ], "comment": "gliding; sliding; skating (on ice); glide; slide\ntaxiing (aircraft); making a takeoff run" },
	{ "question": "滑走路", "answers": [ "かっそうろ" ], "comment": "runway" },
	{ "question": "滑降", "answers": [ "かっこう" ], "comment": "descent (esp. in skiing); sliding down" },
	{ "question": "滝", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "waterfall\nrapids" },
	{ "question": "滝川", "answers": [ "たきがわ" ], "comment": "rapids" },
	{ "question": "滞在", "answers": [ "たいざい" ], "comment": "stay; sojourn" },
	{ "question": "滞納", "answers": [ "たいのう" ], "comment": "falling behind (with a payment); being in arrears; non-payment; default; delinquency" },
	{ "question": "滴", "answers": [ "しずく" ], "comment": "drop (of water); drip" },
	{ "question": "漁", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "fishing; gathering seafood (e.g. clams, seaweed)\ncatch (e.g. of fish); haul" },
	{ "question": "漁る", "answers": [ "あさる" ], "comment": "to fish\nto look for; to search for; to hunt for; to scavenge; to scrounge; to look through; to rummage through\nto go on a spree (spending, reading, etc.); to binge" },
	{ "question": "漁場", "answers": [ "りょうば", "ぎょば", "ぎょじょう" ], "comment": "fishing grounds; permitted fishing zone" },
	{ "question": "漁師", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "fisherman" },
	{ "question": "漁村", "answers": [ "ぎょそん" ], "comment": "fishing village" },
	{ "question": "漁業", "answers": [ "ぎょぎょう" ], "comment": "fishing (industry)" },
	{ "question": "漁民", "answers": [ "ぎょみん" ], "comment": "fishermen" },
	{ "question": "漁港", "answers": [ "ぎょこう" ], "comment": "fishing harbour; fishing harbor" },
	{ "question": "漁獲", "answers": [ "ぎょかく" ], "comment": "fishing; catch; haul" },
	{ "question": "漁船", "answers": [ "ぎょせん" ], "comment": "fishing boat" },
	{ "question": "漂う", "answers": [ "ただよう" ], "comment": "to drift; to float\nto waft (e.g. a scent); to hang in the air\nto be in the air (e.g. a feeling or mood)\nto wander; to walk around aimlessly\nto be unsteady; to be unstable\nto falter; to flinch; to wince\nto live in unreliable circumstances" },
	{ "question": "漂流", "answers": [ "ひょうりゅう" ], "comment": "drifting; drift; being adrift" },
	{ "question": "漏らす", "answers": [ "もらす" ], "comment": "to let leak; to reveal\nto wet one's pants\nto give utterance; to vent; to express\nto omit; to leave out" },
	{ "question": "漏る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "to leak; to run out" },
	{ "question": "漏れる", "answers": [ "もれる" ], "comment": "to leak out; to escape; to come through; to shine through; to filter out\nto find expression; to give vent\nto leak out; to be divulged; to be disclosed\nto be omitted; to be left out; to be excluded; to be not included" },
	{ "question": "演じる", "answers": [ "えんじる" ], "comment": "to perform (a play); to play (a part); to act (a part); to commit (a blunder)" },
	{ "question": "演ずる", "answers": [ "えんずる" ], "comment": "to perform; to play" },
	{ "question": "演出", "answers": [ "えんしゅつ" ], "comment": "production (e.g. play); direction" },
	{ "question": "演出家", "answers": [ "えんしゅつか" ], "comment": "producer; director" },
	{ "question": "演劇", "answers": [ "えんげき" ], "comment": "drama; theatre; theater; play" },
	{ "question": "演壇", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "rostrum; platform" },
	{ "question": "演奏", "answers": [ "えんそう" ], "comment": "musical performance" },
	{ "question": "演技", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "acting; performance" },
	{ "question": "演技力", "answers": [ "えんぎりょく" ], "comment": "acting ability; talent as a performer" },
	{ "question": "演歌", "answers": [ "えんか" ], "comment": "enka; traditional-style Japanese popular ballad\ntroubadour" },
	{ "question": "演目", "answers": [ "えんもく" ], "comment": "program (musical, concert, theatrical, etc.); programme" },
	{ "question": "演算", "answers": [ "えんざん" ], "comment": "operation; calculation" },
	{ "question": "演習", "answers": [ "えんしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising\nexercises; manoeuvres; maneuvers\nseminar (student debates, presentations, etc.); practicum" },
	{ "question": "演舞", "answers": [ "えんぶ" ], "comment": "dance performance" },
	{ "question": "演芸", "answers": [ "えんげい" ], "comment": "entertainment; performance" },
	{ "question": "演説", "answers": [ "えんぜつ" ], "comment": "speech; address" },
	{ "question": "漠然", "answers": [ "ばくぜん" ], "comment": "obscure; vague; equivocal" },
	{ "question": "漢和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "China and Japan\nChinese and Japanese (languages)\nChinese Character-Japanese dictionary" },
	{ "question": "漢字", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "Chinese characters; kanji" },
	{ "question": "漢文", "answers": [ "かんぶん" ], "comment": "Chinese classical literature\nliterature written entirely in kanji" },
	{ "question": "漢方", "answers": [ "かんぽう" ], "comment": "traditional Chinese medicine" },
	{ "question": "漢方薬", "answers": [ "かんぽうやく" ], "comment": "Chinese herbal medicine" },
	{ "question": "漢語", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "Chinese word; Sino-Japanese word" },
	{ "question": "漫才", "answers": [ "まんざい" ], "comment": "two-person comedy act (usu. presented as a fast-paced dialogue, occ. presented as a skit); comic dialogue" },
	{ "question": "漫画", "answers": [ "まんが" ], "comment": "cartoon; comic; comic strip" },
	{ "question": "漫画家", "answers": [ "まんがか" ], "comment": "cartoonist; manga artist" },
	{ "question": "漬ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to soak; to seep; to dip in\nto pickle" },
	{ "question": "漬け物", "answers": [ "つけもの" ], "comment": "tsukemono; Japanese pickled vegetables" },
	{ "question": "漬物", "answers": [ "つけもの" ], "comment": "tsukemono; Japanese pickled vegetables" },
	{ "question": "潔い", "answers": [ "いさぎよい" ], "comment": "manly; sportsmanlike; gracious; gallant; resolute; brave\npure (heart, actions, etc.); upright; blameless\nunsullied (e.g. scenery or object); pure; clean" },
	{ "question": "潔白", "answers": [ "けっぱく" ], "comment": "innocence (i.e. not guilty); purity; uprightness" },
	{ "question": "潜む", "answers": [ "ひそむ" ], "comment": "to lurk; to lie dormant; to be hidden; to be concealed; to be stashed" },
	{ "question": "潜在", "answers": [ "せんざい" ], "comment": "potentiality; dormancy; latency" },
	{ "question": "潜水", "answers": [ "せんすい" ], "comment": "diving; submerging; going underwater" },
	{ "question": "潜水艦", "answers": [ "せんすいかん" ], "comment": "submarine" },
	{ "question": "潤い", "answers": [ "うるおい" ], "comment": "moisture; damp; wetness\nrichness; warmth; gain; profit\nfinancial leeway" },
	{ "question": "潤う", "answers": [ "うるおう" ], "comment": "to be moist; to be damp; to get wet; to be watered\nto profit by; to receive benefits; to receive favors (favours)\nto become rich; to become at ease financially" },
	{ "question": "潤滑油", "answers": [ "じゅんかつゆ" ], "comment": "lubricating oil; lubricant; lube" },
	{ "question": "潤色", "answers": [ "じゅんしょく" ], "comment": "rhetorical flourishes" },
	{ "question": "潮", "answers": [ "しお", "うしお" ], "comment": "tide; current\nsalt water\nopportunity" },
	{ "question": "潮流", "answers": [ "ちょうりゅう" ], "comment": "tide; tidal current\ntendency; drift; trend" },
	{ "question": "潰す", "answers": [ "つぶす" ], "comment": "to smash; to crush\nto shut down\nto thwart; to block\nto kill (time)\nto waste (e.g. talents)" },
	{ "question": "潰れる", "answers": [ "つぶれる" ], "comment": "to be crushed; to be smashed; to be broken; to collapse\nto become useless; to cease functioning; to be wasted (e.g. time)\nto go bankrupt; to go out of business; to fail" },
	{ "question": "澄む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to clear (e.g. weather); to become transparent" },
	{ "question": "澱む", "answers": [ "よどむ" ], "comment": "to stagnate; to be stagnant; to settle; to deposit; to be sedimented; to be precipitated; to hesitate; to be sluggish; to stammer; to stumble; to falter" },
	{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "violent; furious; tempestuous\nextreme; intense; fierce; strong\nfervent; vehement\nincessant; relentless\nprecipitous; steep" },
	{ "question": "激励", "answers": [ "げきれい" ], "comment": "encouragement" },
	{ "question": "激動", "answers": [ "げきどう" ], "comment": "terrible shock; agitation; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "激化", "answers": [ "げきか", "げっか" ], "comment": "intensification; aggravation" },
	{ "question": "激変", "answers": [ "げきへん" ], "comment": "sudden change; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "激怒", "answers": [ "げきど" ], "comment": "rage; indignation; exasperation" },
	{ "question": "激戦", "answers": [ "げきせん" ], "comment": "fierce battle; hard-fought battle; hot contest; severe fight" },
	{ "question": "激減", "answers": [ "げきげん" ], "comment": "dropping sharply; decreasing rapidly" },
	{ "question": "激突", "answers": [ "げきとつ" ], "comment": "crash into; clash" },
	{ "question": "激論", "answers": [ "げきろん" ], "comment": "heated discussion" },
	{ "question": "濁す", "answers": [ "にごす" ], "comment": "to make muddy (a liquid); to make cloudy; to make turbid; to roil\nto prevaricate; to speak ambiguously" },
	{ "question": "濁る", "answers": [ "にごる" ], "comment": "to become muddy; to become cloudy; to get impure (of a liquid, gas, etc.)\nto become dull (of a sound, color, etc.); to become hoarse\nto become impure (of a heart, society, etc.); to be corrupted; to be polluted\nto become voiced; to add voiced consonant marks" },
	{ "question": "濃い", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "deep (colour); dark\nstrong (flavour, smell, etc.)\nthick (consistency); dense\nstrong (possibility, etc.)\nthick (i.e. \"as thick as thieves\"); close; deep (love, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "濃厚", "answers": [ "のうこう" ], "comment": "rich (in flavor, color, smell, etc.); thick; dense; strong\nvery likely; highly possible\npassionate; hot" },
	{ "question": "濃度", "answers": [ "のうど" ], "comment": "concentration; thickness; density\ncardinality" },
	{ "question": "濃淡", "answers": [ "のうたん" ], "comment": "light and shade; shade (of colour, color)\ndepth (of flavor); complexity; strength and weakness (of flavor)" },
	{ "question": "濃縮", "answers": [ "のうしゅく" ], "comment": "concentration (e.g. of a solution); enrichment; condensation" },
	{ "question": "濡らす", "answers": [ "ぬらす" ], "comment": "to wet; to soak; to dip" },
	{ "question": "濡れる", "answers": [ "ぬれる" ], "comment": "to get wet" },
	{ "question": "瀬", "answers": [ "せ" ], "comment": "shallows; shoal\nrapids; current; torrent\nposition; place\nchance; opportunity" },
	{ "question": "瀬戸", "answers": [ "せと" ], "comment": "strait; channel" },
	{ "question": "瀬戸物", "answers": [ "せともの" ], "comment": "earthenware; porcelain; china; pottery; crockery" },
	{ "question": "瀬戸際", "answers": [ "せとぎわ" ], "comment": "brink; critical moment" },
	{ "question": "灌漑", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "irrigation" },
	{ "question": "灘", "answers": [ "なだ" ], "comment": "open sea" },
	{ "question": "火", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "fire; flame; blaze" },
	{ "question": "火事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "fire; conflagration" },
	{ "question": "火付け役", "answers": [ "ひつけやく" ], "comment": "instigator; troublemaker" },
	{ "question": "火力", "answers": [ "かりょく" ], "comment": "heating power; thermal power\nfirepower" },
	{ "question": "火口", "answers": [ "ひぐち" ], "comment": "burner; nozzle; origin of a fire" },
	{ "question": "火器", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "firearms; guns" },
	{ "question": "火山", "answers": [ "かざん" ], "comment": "volcano" },
	{ "question": "火山灰", "answers": [ "かざんばい" ], "comment": "volcanic ash" },
	{ "question": "火星", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "Mars (planet)" },
	{ "question": "火曜", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "Tuesday" },
	{ "question": "火曜日", "answers": [ "かようび" ], "comment": "Tuesday" },
	{ "question": "火災", "answers": [ "かさい" ], "comment": "conflagration; fire" },
	{ "question": "火災保険", "answers": [ "かさいほけん" ], "comment": "fire insurance" },
	{ "question": "火炎瓶", "answers": [ "かえんびん" ], "comment": "Molotov cocktail" },
	{ "question": "火砕流", "answers": [ "かさいりゅう" ], "comment": "pyroclastic flow (type of volcanic eruption); stone wind" },
	{ "question": "火種", "answers": [ "ひだね" ], "comment": "live coals (for firelighting); remains of fire\ncause (of disturbance, conflict, etc.); trigger" },
	{ "question": "火花", "answers": [ "ひばな" ], "comment": "spark" },
	{ "question": "火葬", "answers": [ "かそう" ], "comment": "cremation" },
	{ "question": "火薬", "answers": [ "かやく" ], "comment": "gunpowder; powder" },
	{ "question": "灯", "answers": [ "とうか", "ひ", "ともしび" ], "comment": "light; lamp; torch" },
	{ "question": "灯す", "answers": [ "ともす", "とぼす" ], "comment": "to light; to turn on" },
	{ "question": "灯り", "answers": [ "あかり" ], "comment": "light; illumination; glow; gleam\nlamp; light" },
	{ "question": "灯台", "answers": [ "とうだい" ], "comment": "lighthouse\nold-fashioned interior light fixture comprising a wooden pole with an oil-filled dish and a wick atop it" },
	{ "question": "灯油", "answers": [ "とうゆ" ], "comment": "lamp oil; kerosene" },
	{ "question": "灰", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "ash; ashes" },
	{ "question": "灰皿", "answers": [ "はいざら" ], "comment": "ashtray" },
	{ "question": "灰色", "answers": [ "はいいろ" ], "comment": "grey; gray; ashen" },
	{ "question": "災い", "answers": [ "わざわい" ], "comment": "calamity; catastrophe; misfortune" },
	{ "question": "災害", "answers": [ "さいがい" ], "comment": "calamity; disaster; misfortune" },
	{ "question": "災難", "answers": [ "さいなん" ], "comment": "calamity; misfortune; disaster" },
	{ "question": "炉心", "answers": [ "ろしん" ], "comment": "nuclear reactor core" },
	{ "question": "炊く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "to cook (grains, e.g. rice)\nto boil; to simmer; to stew; to seethe" },
	{ "question": "炊事", "answers": [ "すいじ" ], "comment": "cooking; culinary arts" },
	{ "question": "炊出し", "answers": [ "たきだし" ], "comment": "emergency rice feeding; distribution of rice after an emergency" },
	{ "question": "炊飯器", "answers": [ "すいはんき" ], "comment": "rice cooker" },
	{ "question": "炎", "answers": [ "ほむら", "ほのお" ], "comment": "flame; blaze\nflames (of intense emotion, e.g. love, jealousy, anger); passion" },
	{ "question": "炎上", "answers": [ "えんじょう" ], "comment": "blazing up\ndestruction of a large building by fire\nflood of comments to a blog, exceeding what the blog's owner can answer" },
	{ "question": "炎天", "answers": [ "えんてん" ], "comment": "blazing heat; scorching sun" },
	{ "question": "炎症", "answers": [ "えんしょう" ], "comment": "inflammation; irritation" },
	{ "question": "炒める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to fry; to saute; to stir-fry" },
	{ "question": "炭", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "charcoal\ncharred remains" },
	{ "question": "炭田", "answers": [ "たんでん" ], "comment": "coalfield; coal field" },
	{ "question": "炭素", "answers": [ "たんそ" ], "comment": "carbon (C)" },
	{ "question": "炭鉱", "answers": [ "たんこう" ], "comment": "coal mine; coal pit" },
	{ "question": "点", "answers": [ "てん" ], "comment": "spot; mark\npoint; dot\nmark (e.g. in exam); score; points\ncomma\naspect; matter; respect\ncounter for goods, items, articles of clothing, works of art, etc." },
	{ "question": "点す", "answers": [ "ともす", "とぼす" ], "comment": "to light; to turn on" },
	{ "question": "点在", "answers": [ "てんざい" ], "comment": "being dotted with; being scattered" },
	{ "question": "点字", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "Braille" },
	{ "question": "点差", "answers": [ "てんさ" ], "comment": "point spread" },
	{ "question": "点数", "answers": [ "てんすう" ], "comment": "marks; points; score; runs; number of items; credits" },
	{ "question": "点検", "answers": [ "てんけん" ], "comment": "inspection; examination; checking" },
	{ "question": "点滅", "answers": [ "てんめつ" ], "comment": "switching on and off; flashing; blinking; flickering" },
	{ "question": "点滴", "answers": [ "てんてき" ], "comment": "raindrops; falling drop of water\nintravenous drip; IV; drip-feed" },
	{ "question": "点火", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "ignition; lighting; set fire to" },
	{ "question": "点訳", "answers": [ "てんやく" ], "comment": "translating into Braille" },
	{ "question": "為替", "answers": [ "かわせ" ], "comment": "money order; draft\nexchange (e.g. foreign)" },
	{ "question": "為替相場", "answers": [ "かわせそうば" ], "comment": "exchange rates" },
	{ "question": "焚く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "to burn; to kindle; to build a fire\nto heat (a bath, stove, etc.)\nto use (a camera flash)" },
	{ "question": "無事", "answers": [ "ぶじ" ], "comment": "safety; peace; quietness" },
	{ "question": "無人", "answers": [ "むじん", "むにん", "ぶにん", "ぶじん" ], "comment": "lack of help\nunmanned; uninhabited" },
	{ "question": "無休", "answers": [ "むきゅう" ], "comment": "without a holiday; nonstop" },
	{ "question": "無作為", "answers": [ "むさくい" ], "comment": "at random; unintentional" },
	{ "question": "無修正", "answers": [ "むしゅうせい" ], "comment": "unaltered; uncensored; unexpurgated" },
	{ "question": "無傷", "answers": [ "むきず" ], "comment": "unhurt; uninjured; unwounded; flawless; spotless; sound; perfect" },
	{ "question": "無償", "answers": [ "むしょう" ], "comment": "no compensation; without payment\nfree of charge" },
	{ "question": "無免許", "answers": [ "むめんきょ" ], "comment": "unlicensed; without a license (licence)" },
	{ "question": "無党派層", "answers": [ "むとうはそう" ], "comment": "unaffiliated voters; floating voters; swinging voters" },
	{ "question": "無利子", "answers": [ "むりし" ], "comment": "(earning or paying) no interest" },
	{ "question": "無制限", "answers": [ "むせいげん" ], "comment": "limitless" },
	{ "question": "無力", "answers": [ "むりょく" ], "comment": "powerlessness; helplessness; incompetent" },
	{ "question": "無力感", "answers": [ "むりょくかん" ], "comment": "sense of helplessness; feeling of powerlessness" },
	{ "question": "無効", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "invalid; no effect; unavailable; illegal" },
	{ "question": "無口", "answers": [ "むくち" ], "comment": "reticence; taciturnity; silent person\nreticent; taciturn; silent" },
	{ "question": "無名", "answers": [ "むめい" ], "comment": "unsigned; nameless; anonymous; anonymity" },
	{ "question": "無地", "answers": [ "むじ" ], "comment": "plain; unfigured" },
	{ "question": "無実", "answers": [ "むじつ" ], "comment": "absence of the fact; insubstantiality; innocence; guiltlessness\ninnocent; guiltless\nfalse; untrue" },
	{ "question": "無害", "answers": [ "むがい" ], "comment": "harmless" },
	{ "question": "無差別", "answers": [ "むさべつ" ], "comment": "indiscrimination; without discrimination\nindiscriminate" },
	{ "question": "無形", "answers": [ "むけい" ], "comment": "abstract; immaterial; moral; spiritual; intangible" },
	{ "question": "無形文化財", "answers": [ "むけいぶんかざい" ], "comment": "intangible cultural asset" },
	{ "question": "無得点", "answers": [ "むとくてん" ], "comment": "scoreless (game or competition)" },
	{ "question": "無心", "answers": [ "むしん" ], "comment": "innocence\ninsentient (i.e. plants, inanimate objects, etc.)\nfree from obstructive thoughts\nto pester someone (for cash, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "無念", "answers": [ "むねん" ], "comment": "regret; chagrin; mortification\nfreedom from obstructive thoughts" },
	{ "question": "無性に", "answers": [ "むしょうに" ], "comment": "excessively; very much" },
	{ "question": "無恥", "answers": [ "むち" ], "comment": "shameless" },
	{ "question": "無情", "answers": [ "むじょう" ], "comment": "heartlessness; hardness; cruelty; ruthless" },
	{ "question": "無意味", "answers": [ "むいみ" ], "comment": "nonsense; no meaning; meaningless" },
	{ "question": "無意識", "answers": [ "むいしき" ], "comment": "unconsciousness\nthe unconscious" },
	{ "question": "無所属", "answers": [ "むしょぞく" ], "comment": "independent (esp. in politics); non-partisan" },
	{ "question": "無投票", "answers": [ "むとうひょう" ], "comment": "without a vote" },
	{ "question": "無政府", "answers": [ "むせいふ" ], "comment": "anarchy" },
	{ "question": "無数", "answers": [ "むすう" ], "comment": "countless number; infinite number; innumerable" },
	{ "question": "無料", "answers": [ "むりょう" ], "comment": "free; no charge" },
	{ "question": "無断", "answers": [ "むだん" ], "comment": "without permission; without notice" },
	{ "question": "無期", "answers": [ "むき" ], "comment": "indefinite" },
	{ "question": "無期限", "answers": [ "むきげん" ], "comment": "indefinite" },
	{ "question": "無条件", "answers": [ "むじょうけん" ], "comment": "unconditional" },
	{ "question": "無機物", "answers": [ "むきぶつ" ], "comment": "inorganic substance" },
	{ "question": "無欲", "answers": [ "むよく" ], "comment": "unselfish; disinterested; unavaricious; free of avarice" },
	{ "question": "無死", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "no outs" },
	{ "question": "無残", "answers": [ "むざん" ], "comment": "cruel; merciless; atrocious; ruthless; cold-blooded\npitiful; tragic; horrible; miserable\nbreaking a religious precept without shame" },
	{ "question": "無気力", "answers": [ "むきりょく" ], "comment": "apathy; lassitude; lethargy; languor" },
	{ "question": "無法", "answers": [ "むほう" ], "comment": "lawlessness; injustice; wrong; outrage\noutrageous; lawless; disorderly; unjust; unreasonable" },
	{ "question": "無理", "answers": [ "むり" ], "comment": "unreasonable; unnatural; unjustifiable\nimpossible\nforcible; forced; compulsory\nexcessive (work, etc.); immoderate\nto work too hard; to try too hard\nirrational" },
	{ "question": "無理やり", "answers": [ "むりやり" ], "comment": "forcibly; against one's will" },
	{ "question": "無理矢理", "answers": [ "むりやり" ], "comment": "forcibly; against one's will" },
	{ "question": "無生物", "answers": [ "むせいぶつ" ], "comment": "inanimate object" },
	{ "question": "無用", "answers": [ "むよう" ], "comment": "useless; futile\nunnecessary; needless\nnot on business; unrelated; unauthorised; unauthorized\nprohibited; banned; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "無益", "answers": [ "むえき" ], "comment": "useless; futile; vain" },
	{ "question": "無知", "answers": [ "むち" ], "comment": "ignorance; innocence; stupidity" },
	{ "question": "無礼", "answers": [ "ぶれい" ], "comment": "impolite; rude" },
	{ "question": "無神経", "answers": [ "むしんけい" ], "comment": "insensitive; inconsiderate; callous; thick-skinned" },
	{ "question": "無秩序", "answers": [ "むちつじょ" ], "comment": "disorder; chaos; confusion" },
	{ "question": "無策", "answers": [ "むさく" ], "comment": "lacking means or measures or policies" },
	{ "question": "無精", "answers": [ "ぶしょう" ], "comment": "indolence; laziness; sloth" },
	{ "question": "無給", "answers": [ "むきゅう" ], "comment": "unpaid; nonsalaried" },
	{ "question": "無線", "answers": [ "むせん" ], "comment": "wireless; radio" },
	{ "question": "無線ＬＡＮ", "answers": [ "むせんラン" ], "comment": "wireless local area network; wireless LAN; WLAN" },
	{ "question": "無縁", "answers": [ "むえん" ], "comment": "unrelated; irrelevant; indifferent\nwithout relations (esp. of a deceased person); having no surviving relatives\nunrelated to the teachings of Buddha; unable to be saved by Buddha" },
	{ "question": "無罪", "answers": [ "むざい" ], "comment": "innocence" },
	{ "question": "無職", "answers": [ "むしょく" ], "comment": "without an occupation" },
	{ "question": "無能", "answers": [ "むのう" ], "comment": "inefficiency; incompetence\nincompetent person" },
	{ "question": "無色", "answers": [ "むしょく" ], "comment": "colourless; colorless; achromatic" },
	{ "question": "無茶", "answers": [ "むちゃ", "むっちゃ" ], "comment": "absurd; unreasonable; excessive; rash\nvery; extremely; excessively" },
	{ "question": "無視", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "disregarding; ignoring" },
	{ "question": "無言", "answers": [ "むごん" ], "comment": "silence" },
	{ "question": "無記名", "answers": [ "むきめい" ], "comment": "unsigned; unregistered" },
	{ "question": "無論", "answers": [ "むろん" ], "comment": "of course; naturally" },
	{ "question": "無謀", "answers": [ "むぼう" ], "comment": "reckless; thoughtless; rash; ill-advised; impulsive; mad (scheme, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "無責任", "answers": [ "むせきにん" ], "comment": "irresponsibility" },
	{ "question": "無資格", "answers": [ "むしかく" ], "comment": "unqualified; unlicensed; uncertified" },
	{ "question": "無造作", "answers": [ "むぞうさ" ], "comment": "easy; simple; ready\ncasual; off-hand; easy-going; careless; artless" },
	{ "question": "無邪気", "answers": [ "むじゃき" ], "comment": "innocence; simple-mindedness" },
	{ "question": "無配", "answers": [ "むはい" ], "comment": "without dividend" },
	{ "question": "無重量", "answers": [ "むじゅうりょう" ], "comment": "weightlessness; zero gravity" },
	{ "question": "無量", "answers": [ "むりょう" ], "comment": "immeasurable" },
	{ "question": "無関係", "answers": [ "むかんけい" ], "comment": "unrelated" },
	{ "question": "無関心", "answers": [ "むかんしん" ], "comment": "apathetic; indifferent" },
	{ "question": "無限", "answers": [ "むげん" ], "comment": "infinity; infinitude; eternity\ninfinite; limitless" },
	{ "question": "無難", "answers": [ "ぶなん" ], "comment": "safe; secure\nacceptable; passable; faultless; innocuous" },
	{ "question": "無風", "answers": [ "むふう" ], "comment": "calm; windless" },
	{ "question": "無駄", "answers": [ "むだ" ], "comment": "futility; uselessness; pointlessness" },
	{ "question": "無駄遣い", "answers": [ "むだづかい" ], "comment": "wasting ... on (e.g. money); squandering; waste; frittering away" },
	{ "question": "焦げる", "answers": [ "こげる" ], "comment": "to burn; to scorch; to char; to singe" },
	{ "question": "焦り", "answers": [ "あせり" ], "comment": "impatience" },
	{ "question": "焦る", "answers": [ "あせる" ], "comment": "to be in a hurry; to be impatient; to be flustered; to lose one's presence of mind; to be surprised" },
	{ "question": "焦点", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "focus (e.g. photographic); focal point" },
	{ "question": "焼きそば", "answers": [ "やきそば" ], "comment": "yakisoba; fried noodles, usu. with with vegetables and meat" },
	{ "question": "焼き肉", "answers": [ "やきにく" ], "comment": "yakiniku; Japanese dish of grilled meat similar to Korean barbecue\nroasted meat; grill" },
	{ "question": "焼き芋", "answers": [ "やきいも" ], "comment": "roasted sweet potato; baked sweet potato" },
	{ "question": "焼き鳥", "answers": [ "やきとり" ], "comment": "yakitori; chicken pieces (or sometimes beef or pork offal) grilled on a skewer" },
	{ "question": "焼く", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "to burn\nto roast; to broil; to grill; to bake; to toast; to barbecue\nto heat; to heat up\nto make (charcoal, pottery, bricks, etc.); to bake; to fire; to burn\nto tan (i.e. suntan); to burn\nto print (a photo); to burn (an optical disc)\nto be jealous of; to be envious of; to envy" },
	{ "question": "焼ける", "answers": [ "やける" ], "comment": "to burn; to be roasted; to be heated; to be sunburnt; to fade (in the sun); to glow red (i.e. of the sky at sunset)\nto be jealous; to be envious" },
	{ "question": "焼け跡", "answers": [ "やけあと" ], "comment": "ruins of a fire; fire-devastated area" },
	{ "question": "焼そば", "answers": [ "やきそば" ], "comment": "yakisoba; fried noodles, usu. with with vegetables and meat" },
	{ "question": "焼却", "answers": [ "しょうきゃく" ], "comment": "incineration; destroy by fire" },
	{ "question": "焼死", "answers": [ "しょうし" ], "comment": "death by fire" },
	{ "question": "焼肉", "answers": [ "やきにく" ], "comment": "yakiniku; Japanese dish of grilled meat similar to Korean barbecue\nroasted meat; grill" },
	{ "question": "焼芋", "answers": [ "やきいも" ], "comment": "roasted sweet potato; baked sweet potato" },
	{ "question": "焼酎", "answers": [ "しょうちゅう" ], "comment": "shochu; Japanese spirit distilled from sweet potatoes, rice, etc." },
	{ "question": "焼鳥", "answers": [ "やきとり" ], "comment": "yakitori; chicken pieces (or sometimes beef or pork offal) grilled on a skewer" },
	{ "question": "煎餅", "answers": [ "せんべい" ], "comment": "rice cracker; Japanese cracker; rice cookie; wafer" },
	{ "question": "煙", "answers": [ "けむり", "けむ", "けぶり", "けぶ" ], "comment": "smoke; fumes" },
	{ "question": "煙い", "answers": [ "けぶい", "けむい" ], "comment": "smoky" },
	{ "question": "煙たい", "answers": [ "けぶたい", "けむたい" ], "comment": "smoky\nawkward; ill at ease" },
	{ "question": "煙る", "answers": [ "けむる", "けぶる" ], "comment": "to smoke (e.g. fire)\nto be hazy" },
	{ "question": "煙突", "answers": [ "えんとつ" ], "comment": "chimney; smokestack; funnel (of a ship); stovepipe\ncarrying a passenger without turning on the taximeter" },
	{ "question": "照らす", "answers": [ "てらす" ], "comment": "to shine on; to illuminate\nto compare (with); to refer to" },
	{ "question": "照る", "answers": [ "てる" ], "comment": "to shine\nto look slightly upward (of a noh mask; indicating joy, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "照れる", "answers": [ "てれる" ], "comment": "to be shy; to be bashful; to feel awkward; to feel embarrassed" },
	{ "question": "照会", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "inquiry; enquiry; query; reference" },
	{ "question": "照射", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "radiation; beaming; irradiation" },
	{ "question": "照明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "illumination; lighting" },
	{ "question": "照準", "answers": [ "しょうじゅん" ], "comment": "sight (e.g. of a gun); aim; alignment" },
	{ "question": "煩う", "answers": [ "わずらう" ], "comment": "to be ill; to suffer from\nto worry about; to be concerned about\nto have trouble doing ...; to be unable to ...; to fail to ..." },
	{ "question": "煩わしい", "answers": [ "わずらわしい" ], "comment": "troublesome; annoying; complicated" },
	{ "question": "煩忙", "answers": [ "はんぼう" ], "comment": "pressure of business; busy" },
	{ "question": "煩雑", "answers": [ "はんざつ" ], "comment": "complex; intricate; complicated; confused; troublesome; vexatious; cumbersome" },
	{ "question": "煮える", "answers": [ "にえる" ], "comment": "to be boiled; to be cooked" },
	{ "question": "煮る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "to boil; to simmer; to stew; to seethe" },
	{ "question": "煮物", "answers": [ "にもの" ], "comment": "food cooked by boiling or stewing" },
	{ "question": "煮詰める", "answers": [ "につめる" ], "comment": "to boil down; to concentrate (soup, milk, stock, etc.)\nto reach a conclusion; to conclude a discussion" },
	{ "question": "煮込む", "answers": [ "にこむ" ], "comment": "to cook together; to boil well" },
	{ "question": "煽る", "answers": [ "あおる" ], "comment": "to fan (oneself, flames, etc.)\nto flap; to be shaken (by wind)\nto instigate; to stir up; to agitate; to induce\nto buy a large amount in order to cause prices to rise\nto take a photo from a low angle\nto tailgate" },
	{ "question": "熊", "answers": [ "くま" ], "comment": "bear (any mammal of family Ursidae)" },
	{ "question": "熟知", "answers": [ "じゅくち" ], "comment": "being familiar with; having a thorough knowledge of; being well-informed about" },
	{ "question": "熟練", "answers": [ "じゅくれん" ], "comment": "skill; dexterity; proficiency" },
	{ "question": "熟語", "answers": [ "じゅくご" ], "comment": "kanji compound\nidiom; idiomatic phrase" },
	{ "question": "熱", "answers": [ "ねつ" ], "comment": "heat\nfever; temperature\nzeal; passion; enthusiasm\nmania; craze; rage" },
	{ "question": "熱々", "answers": [ "あつあつ" ], "comment": "piping hot; scalding\nmadly in love" },
	{ "question": "熱い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "hot (thing)\npassionate (feelings, etc.); ardent; hot (e.g. gaze)\nhot (e.g. temper)\nzealous; enthusiastic; fired up\nintense; severe; extreme\nhot (topic); of interest" },
	{ "question": "熱する", "answers": [ "ねっする" ], "comment": "to heat; to heat up" },
	{ "question": "熱中", "answers": [ "ねっちゅう" ], "comment": "going nuts (over something); enthusiasm; zeal; mania" },
	{ "question": "熱帯", "answers": [ "ねったい" ], "comment": "tropics" },
	{ "question": "熱帯魚", "answers": [ "ねったいぎょ" ], "comment": "tropical fish" },
	{ "question": "熱弁", "answers": [ "ねつべん" ], "comment": "fervent speech" },
	{ "question": "熱心", "answers": [ "ねっしん" ], "comment": "zeal; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "熱意", "answers": [ "ねつい" ], "comment": "zeal; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "熱戦", "answers": [ "ねっせん" ], "comment": "fierce fighting; close contest" },
	{ "question": "熱気", "answers": [ "ねっき" ], "comment": "heat; hot air; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "熱湯", "answers": [ "ねっとう" ], "comment": "boiling water" },
	{ "question": "熱烈", "answers": [ "ねつれつ" ], "comment": "ardent; passionate; vehement" },
	{ "question": "熱狂", "answers": [ "ねっきょう" ], "comment": "wild enthusiasm; being crazy about" },
	{ "question": "燃える", "answers": [ "もえる" ], "comment": "to burn; to get fired up" },
	{ "question": "燃やす", "answers": [ "もやす", "もす" ], "comment": "to burn" },
	{ "question": "燃料", "answers": [ "ねんりょう" ], "comment": "fuel" },
	{ "question": "燃焼", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "burning; combustion" },
	{ "question": "燃費", "answers": [ "ねんぴ" ], "comment": "fuel consumption; gas mileage" },
	{ "question": "爆撃", "answers": [ "ばくげき" ], "comment": "bombing (raid)" },
	{ "question": "爆発", "answers": [ "ばくはつ" ], "comment": "explosion; detonation; eruption" },
	{ "question": "爆破", "answers": [ "ばくは" ], "comment": "destructive blast; explosion; blow up" },
	{ "question": "爆竹", "answers": [ "ばくちく" ], "comment": "firecracker" },
	{ "question": "爆笑", "answers": [ "ばくしょう" ], "comment": "roar of laughter (from several people)\nlaughing hard (single person)" },
	{ "question": "爆音", "answers": [ "ばくおん" ], "comment": "(sound of an) explosion or detonation; roar (of a machine)" },
	{ "question": "爪", "answers": [ "つめ" ], "comment": "nail (e.g. fingernail, toenail); claw; talon; hoof\nplectrum; pick\nhook; clasp" },
	{ "question": "爪切り", "answers": [ "つめきり" ], "comment": "nail clippers" },
	{ "question": "爪楊枝", "answers": [ "つまようじ" ], "comment": "toothpick" },
	{ "question": "父", "answers": [ "ちち", "ちゃん", "とと" ], "comment": "father" },
	{ "question": "父さん", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "father; dad; papa; pa; pop; daddy; dada" },
	{ "question": "父兄", "answers": [ "ふけい" ], "comment": "guardians; parents and older brothers" },
	{ "question": "父子", "answers": [ "ふし" ], "comment": "father and child (son)" },
	{ "question": "父母", "answers": [ "ちちはは", "ふぼ" ], "comment": "father and mother; parents" },
	{ "question": "父親", "answers": [ "ちちおや" ], "comment": "father" },
	{ "question": "片付く", "answers": [ "かたづく" ], "comment": "to be put in order; to be put to rights\nto be disposed of; to be solved\nto be finished\nto be married (off)" },
	{ "question": "片付ける", "answers": [ "かたづける" ], "comment": "to tidy up; to put in order; to straighten up; to put away\nto settle (problem); to clear (dispute)\nto finish; to bring something to an end\nto marry off (e.g. a daughter)\nto do away with someone; to bump someone off" },
	{ "question": "片側", "answers": [ "かたがわ" ], "comment": "one side" },
	{ "question": "片寄る", "answers": [ "かたよる" ], "comment": "to be one-sided; to incline; to be partial; to be prejudiced; to lean; to be biased; to be biassed" },
	{ "question": "片思い", "answers": [ "かたおもい" ], "comment": "unrequited love" },
	{ "question": "片手", "answers": [ "かたて" ], "comment": "one hand" },
	{ "question": "片方", "answers": [ "かたほう" ], "comment": "one side; one party; counterpart; the other side; the other party\none of a pair; fellow; mate" },
	{ "question": "片道", "answers": [ "かたみち" ], "comment": "one-way (trip)\none-way ticket" },
	{ "question": "片隅", "answers": [ "かたすみ" ], "comment": "corner; nook" },
	{ "question": "版", "answers": [ "ばん", "はん" ], "comment": "edition; version; printing; impression; implementation (e.g. software)\nplate; block; cast\neditions of a publication" },
	{ "question": "版権", "answers": [ "はんけん" ], "comment": "copyright" },
	{ "question": "版画", "answers": [ "はんが" ], "comment": "woodcut; woodblock print; art print" },
	{ "question": "牛", "answers": [ "ぎゅう", "うし" ], "comment": "cattle (Bos taurus); cow; bull; ox; calf\nbeef\nChinese \"Ox\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "牛丼", "answers": [ "ぎゅうどん" ], "comment": "rice covered with beef and vegetables" },
	{ "question": "牛乳", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(cow's) milk" },
	{ "question": "牛歩", "answers": [ "ぎゅうほ" ], "comment": "snail's pace; slow progress" },
	{ "question": "牛肉", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにく" ], "comment": "beef" },
	{ "question": "牧場", "answers": [ "まきば", "ぼくじょう" ], "comment": "farm (livestock); ranch (US); station (Aus, NZ)\npasture land; meadow; grazing land" },
	{ "question": "牧師", "answers": [ "ぼくし" ], "comment": "pastor; minister; clergyman; reverend" },
	{ "question": "牧畜", "answers": [ "ぼくちく" ], "comment": "stock-farming" },
	{ "question": "牧草", "answers": [ "ぼくそう" ], "comment": "pasture; grass" },
	{ "question": "牧野", "answers": [ "ぼくや" ], "comment": "pasture land; ranch" },
	{ "question": "物事", "answers": [ "ものごと" ], "comment": "things; everything" },
	{ "question": "物件", "answers": [ "ぶっけん" ], "comment": "article; thing; object; property (real estate)" },
	{ "question": "物体", "answers": [ "ぶったい" ], "comment": "body; object" },
	{ "question": "物価", "answers": [ "ぶっか" ], "comment": "prices of commodities; prices (in general); cost-of-living" },
	{ "question": "物価指数", "answers": [ "ぶっかしすう" ], "comment": "a price index" },
	{ "question": "物別れ", "answers": [ "ものわかれ" ], "comment": "failure to reach agreement" },
	{ "question": "物品", "answers": [ "ぶっぴん" ], "comment": "goods; articles" },
	{ "question": "物好き", "answers": [ "ものずき" ], "comment": "(idle) curiosity; fancifulness; whimsy; (having) strange tastes" },
	{ "question": "物差", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "ruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "物差し", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "ruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "物干し", "answers": [ "ものほし" ], "comment": "frame for drying clothes; clotheshorse" },
	{ "question": "物心", "answers": [ "ものごころ" ], "comment": "awareness of things around one; ability to understand what is going on around oneself; judgment; judgement; discretion" },
	{ "question": "物指", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "ruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "物指し", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "ruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "物流", "answers": [ "ぶつりゅう" ], "comment": "(physical) distribution; distribution of goods; logistics" },
	{ "question": "物理", "answers": [ "ぶつり" ], "comment": "physics; law of nature" },
	{ "question": "物理学", "answers": [ "ぶつりがく" ], "comment": "physics" },
	{ "question": "物産", "answers": [ "ぶっさん" ], "comment": "product" },
	{ "question": "物的", "answers": [ "ぶってき" ], "comment": "material; physical" },
	{ "question": "物置", "answers": [ "ものおき" ], "comment": "storage room; storeroom; lumber room" },
	{ "question": "物覚え", "answers": [ "ものおぼえ" ], "comment": "memory; ability to learn" },
	{ "question": "物言い", "answers": [ "ものいい" ], "comment": "manner of speaking\nverbal argument\nobjection; protesting a decision (esp. that of a sumo referee)\nrumor; rumour" },
	{ "question": "物証", "answers": [ "ぶっしょう" ], "comment": "evidence; exhibit" },
	{ "question": "物語", "answers": [ "ものがたり" ], "comment": "tale; story; legend" },
	{ "question": "物語る", "answers": [ "ものがたる" ], "comment": "to tell; to indicate" },
	{ "question": "物議", "answers": [ "ぶつぎ" ], "comment": "public discussion; public criticism; controversy" },
	{ "question": "物販", "answers": [ "ぶっぱん" ], "comment": "sale of goods (as opposed to services)" },
	{ "question": "物資", "answers": [ "ぶっし" ], "comment": "goods; materials" },
	{ "question": "物質", "answers": [ "ぶっしつ" ], "comment": "material; substance\nmatter" },
	{ "question": "物質的", "answers": [ "ぶっしつてき" ], "comment": "material; physical" },
	{ "question": "物足りない", "answers": [ "ものたりない" ], "comment": "unsatisfied; unsatisfactory; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "物陰", "answers": [ "ものかげ" ], "comment": "cover; under cover; shelter; hiding" },
	{ "question": "物音", "answers": [ "ものおと" ], "comment": "sounds" },
	{ "question": "物騒", "answers": [ "ぶっそう" ], "comment": "dangerous; unsettled; troubled; disturbed; insecure" },
	{ "question": "特に", "answers": [ "とくに" ], "comment": "particularly; especially" },
	{ "question": "特使", "answers": [ "とくし" ], "comment": "special envoy" },
	{ "question": "特例", "answers": [ "とくれい" ], "comment": "special case; exception" },
	{ "question": "特典", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "privilege; special favor; special favour; benefit; prerogative; perk; amenity" },
	{ "question": "特別", "answers": [ "とくべつ" ], "comment": "special" },
	{ "question": "特別区", "answers": [ "とくべつく" ], "comment": "special ward (esp. of Tokyo)\nspecial economic zone (China)\nspecial administrative region of China (e.g. Hong Kong)" },
	{ "question": "特効薬", "answers": [ "とっこうやく" ], "comment": "specific medicine; wonder drug; silver bullet" },
	{ "question": "特売", "answers": [ "とくばい" ], "comment": "special sale" },
	{ "question": "特大", "answers": [ "とくだい" ], "comment": "extra-large" },
	{ "question": "特定", "answers": [ "とくてい" ], "comment": "specific; particular; designated; special\nspecifying; designating; identifying; pinpointing" },
	{ "question": "特徴", "answers": [ "とくちょう" ], "comment": "feature; trait; characteristic; peculiarity; distinction" },
	{ "question": "特急", "answers": [ "とっきゅう" ], "comment": "limited express (train, faster than an express)\ngreat hurry" },
	{ "question": "特性", "answers": [ "とくせい" ], "comment": "special characteristic; special quality; trait; idiosyncrasy; peculiarity" },
	{ "question": "特技", "answers": [ "とくぎ" ], "comment": "special skill" },
	{ "question": "特捜", "answers": [ "とくそう" ], "comment": "special investigation" },
	{ "question": "特攻隊", "answers": [ "とっこうたい" ], "comment": "special attack unit; kamikaze unit; suicide squad" },
	{ "question": "特有", "answers": [ "とくゆう" ], "comment": "characteristic (of); peculiar (to)" },
	{ "question": "特権", "answers": [ "とっけん" ], "comment": "privilege; special right" },
	{ "question": "特殊", "answers": [ "とくしゅ" ], "comment": "special; particular; peculiar; unique" },
	{ "question": "特殊法人", "answers": [ "とくしゅほうじん" ], "comment": "semigovernmental corporation" },
	{ "question": "特段", "answers": [ "とくだん" ], "comment": "special" },
	{ "question": "特派員", "answers": [ "とくはいん" ], "comment": "(special) correspondent (e.g. for a newspaper)\nrepresentative; delegate" },
	{ "question": "特産", "answers": [ "とくさん" ], "comment": "specialty; special product" },
	{ "question": "特異", "answers": [ "とくい" ], "comment": "unique; singular" },
	{ "question": "特筆", "answers": [ "とくひつ" ], "comment": "special mention" },
	{ "question": "特約", "answers": [ "とくやく" ], "comment": "special contract; special agreement; rider (insurance)" },
	{ "question": "特色", "answers": [ "とくしょく" ], "comment": "characteristic; feature; idiosyncrasy; personal colour\nspot color (in printing)" },
	{ "question": "特製", "answers": [ "とくせい" ], "comment": "special make; deluxe" },
	{ "question": "特訓", "answers": [ "とっくん" ], "comment": "special training; intensive training; crash course" },
	{ "question": "特設", "answers": [ "とくせつ" ], "comment": "setting up specially; special installation" },
	{ "question": "特許", "answers": [ "とっきょ" ], "comment": "patent; special permission; licence (license); concession; franchise; charter\nproprietary" },
	{ "question": "特許庁", "answers": [ "とっきょちょう" ], "comment": "Patent Office; Patent Agency" },
	{ "question": "特質", "answers": [ "とくしつ" ], "comment": "characteristic; feature; special quality" },
	{ "question": "特選", "answers": [ "とくせん" ], "comment": "specially selection; special approval; special prize; high honour" },
	{ "question": "特集", "answers": [ "とくしゅう" ], "comment": "feature (e.g. newspaper); special edition; report" },
	{ "question": "犠打", "answers": [ "ぎだ" ], "comment": "sacrifice fly; bunt" },
	{ "question": "犠牲", "answers": [ "ぎせい" ], "comment": "victim; sacrifice; scapegoat" },
	{ "question": "犠牲者", "answers": [ "ぎせいしゃ" ], "comment": "victim" },
	{ "question": "犠飛", "answers": [ "ぎひ" ], "comment": "sacrifice fly" },
	{ "question": "犬", "answers": [ "いぬ" ], "comment": "dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)\nsnoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)\nloser; asshole\ncounterfeit; inferior; useless; wasteful" },
	{ "question": "犯す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to commit (e.g. crime); to perpetrate; to make (e.g. mistake)\nto break (e.g. rule); to violate; to transgress; to contravene\nto rape; to violate; to ravish; to deflower" },
	{ "question": "犯人", "answers": [ "はんにん" ], "comment": "offender; criminal" },
	{ "question": "犯罪", "answers": [ "はんざい" ], "comment": "crime; offence; offense" },
	{ "question": "犯行", "answers": [ "はんこう" ], "comment": "crime; criminal act; offence; offense" },
	{ "question": "状", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "shape; state\nletter; correspondence" },
	{ "question": "状態", "answers": [ "じょうたい" ], "comment": "current status; condition; situation; circumstances; state" },
	{ "question": "状況", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "state of affairs (around you); situation; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "状況報告", "answers": [ "じょうきょうほうこく" ], "comment": "situation report" },
	{ "question": "狂う", "answers": [ "くるう" ], "comment": "to go mad\nto get out of order; to go amiss" },
	{ "question": "狂乱", "answers": [ "きょうらん" ], "comment": "fury; frenzy; madness" },
	{ "question": "狂気", "answers": [ "きょうき" ], "comment": "madness; insanity" },
	{ "question": "狂言", "answers": [ "きょうげん" ], "comment": "kyogen; farce presented between noh plays or during the interlude of a noh play\nkabuki play; kabuki performance\nmake-believe; ruse; trick" },
	{ "question": "狙い", "answers": [ "ねらい" ], "comment": "aim" },
	{ "question": "狙う", "answers": [ "ねらう" ], "comment": "to aim at" },
	{ "question": "狩り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "hunting\nharvesting (e.g. berries, fruit); picking; gathering" },
	{ "question": "狩猟", "answers": [ "しゅりょう" ], "comment": "hunting" },
	{ "question": "独り", "answers": [ "いちにん", "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "独りで", "answers": [ "ひとりで" ], "comment": "alone; by oneself; voluntarily; spontaneously; automatically" },
	{ "question": "独り占め", "answers": [ "ひとりじめ" ], "comment": "monopolising; monopolizing; hogging; having all to oneself" },
	{ "question": "独り歩き", "answers": [ "ひとりあるき" ], "comment": "walking alone; walking unaided; going alone; standing on one's own" },
	{ "question": "独り言", "answers": [ "ひとりごと" ], "comment": "soliloquy; monologue; speaking to oneself" },
	{ "question": "独創", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "originality" },
	{ "question": "独創的", "answers": [ "どくそうてき" ], "comment": "creative; original" },
	{ "question": "独占", "answers": [ "どくせん" ], "comment": "monopoly; monopolization\nhogging; keeping to oneself" },
	{ "question": "独学", "answers": [ "どくがく" ], "comment": "self-education; self-instruction; self-study" },
	{ "question": "独断", "answers": [ "どくだん" ], "comment": "one's own judgement (judgment); dogmatic; arbitrary" },
	{ "question": "独特", "answers": [ "どくとく" ], "comment": "peculiarity; uniqueness; characteristic\nunderstood only by oneself" },
	{ "question": "独禁法", "answers": [ "どっきんほう" ], "comment": "antitrust law; Antitrust Act" },
	{ "question": "独立", "answers": [ "どくりつ" ], "comment": "independence (e.g. Independence Day); self-support" },
	{ "question": "独立国", "answers": [ "どくりつこく" ], "comment": "independent state or nation" },
	{ "question": "独自", "answers": [ "どくじ" ], "comment": "original; unique; distinctive; characteristic; peculiar\nindependent; one's own; personal" },
	{ "question": "独裁", "answers": [ "どくさい" ], "comment": "dictatorship; despotism" },
	{ "question": "独走", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "running alone; running solo\nhaving a large lead (over the others); being far ahead (of everyone else)\nhaving one's own way; ignoring others' opinions and acting as one wishes; arbitrary action" },
	{ "question": "独身", "answers": [ "どくしん" ], "comment": "bachelorhood; single; unmarried; celibate" },
	{ "question": "狭い", "answers": [ "せまい" ], "comment": "narrow; confined; small" },
	{ "question": "狭まる", "answers": [ "せばまる" ], "comment": "to narrow; to contract" },
	{ "question": "狭める", "answers": [ "せばめる" ], "comment": "to narrow; to reduce; to contract" },
	{ "question": "狭心症", "answers": [ "きょうしんしょう" ], "comment": "heart attack; angina pectoris" },
	{ "question": "猛威", "answers": [ "もうい" ], "comment": "fury; power; menace" },
	{ "question": "猛打", "answers": [ "もうだ" ], "comment": "heavy blow; heavy hit" },
	{ "question": "猛攻", "answers": [ "もうこう" ], "comment": "fierce attack" },
	{ "question": "猛暑", "answers": [ "もうしょ" ], "comment": "heat wave; fierce heat" },
	{ "question": "猛烈", "answers": [ "もうれつ" ], "comment": "violent; vehement; raging; stout; intense; spirited; stormy" },
	{ "question": "猟", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "hunting; game" },
	{ "question": "猫背", "answers": [ "ねこぜ" ], "comment": "bent back; hunchback; stoop" },
	{ "question": "猫舌", "answers": [ "ねこじた" ], "comment": "dislike of very hot food or drink; inability to take hot food" },
	{ "question": "献上", "answers": [ "けんじょう" ], "comment": "presenting to" },
	{ "question": "献立", "answers": [ "こんだて" ], "comment": "menu; bill of fare\nprogram; programme; schedule" },
	{ "question": "献花", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "flower offering" },
	{ "question": "献血", "answers": [ "けんけつ" ], "comment": "blood donation" },
	{ "question": "献金", "answers": [ "けんきん" ], "comment": "donation; contribution; offering" },
	{ "question": "猶予", "answers": [ "ゆうよ" ], "comment": "postponement; deferment; extension (of time)" },
	{ "question": "獄中", "answers": [ "ごくちゅう" ], "comment": "during imprisonment; while in jail (gaol)" },
	{ "question": "獅子", "answers": [ "しし" ], "comment": "lion\nleft-hand guardian dog at a Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "獣", "answers": [ "じゅう", "けだもの", "けもの" ], "comment": "beast; brute; animal" },
	{ "question": "獣医", "answers": [ "じゅうい" ], "comment": "veterinarian" },
	{ "question": "獲得", "answers": [ "かくとく" ], "comment": "acquisition; possession" },
	{ "question": "獲物", "answers": [ "えもの" ], "comment": "game; spoils; trophy; prey" },
	{ "question": "玄人", "answers": [ "くろと", "くろうと" ], "comment": "expert; professional; master\nwoman in the nightlife business; demimondaine; geisha and prostitutes" },
	{ "question": "玄米", "answers": [ "げんまい" ], "comment": "unpolished rice; unmilled rice; brown rice" },
	{ "question": "玄関", "answers": [ "げんかん" ], "comment": "entranceway; entry hall; vestibule; foyer; entryway; mud room" },
	{ "question": "率", "answers": [ "りつ" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; proportion; percentage" },
	{ "question": "率いる", "answers": [ "ひきいる" ], "comment": "to lead; to spearhead (a group); to command (troops)" },
	{ "question": "率先", "answers": [ "そっせん" ], "comment": "taking the initiative" },
	{ "question": "率直", "answers": [ "そっちょく" ], "comment": "frankness; candour; candor; openheartedness; directness" },
	{ "question": "玉", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "ball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent" },
	{ "question": "玉虫色", "answers": [ "たまむしいろ" ], "comment": "iridescent\nequivocal; ambivalent\nvariable meaning; weasel-word; chameleonic interpretation" },
	{ "question": "王", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "king; ruler; sovereign; monarch\ntycoon; magnate; champion; master\nking (of the senior player)" },
	{ "question": "王位", "answers": [ "おうい" ], "comment": "the throne; the crown" },
	{ "question": "王国", "answers": [ "おうこく" ], "comment": "kingdom; monarchy" },
	{ "question": "王女", "answers": [ "おうじょ" ], "comment": "princess" },
	{ "question": "王妃", "answers": [ "おうひ" ], "comment": "queen" },
	{ "question": "王子", "answers": [ "おうじ" ], "comment": "prince\nsubordinate Kumano shrine" },
	{ "question": "王室", "answers": [ "おうしつ" ], "comment": "royal family" },
	{ "question": "王宮", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "royal palace" },
	{ "question": "王将", "answers": [ "おうしょう" ], "comment": "king (of the senior player)" },
	{ "question": "王座", "answers": [ "おうざ" ], "comment": "throne" },
	{ "question": "王手", "answers": [ "おうて" ], "comment": "check" },
	{ "question": "王族", "answers": [ "おうぞく" ], "comment": "royalty" },
	{ "question": "王朝", "answers": [ "おうちょう" ], "comment": "dynasty" },
	{ "question": "王様", "answers": [ "おうさま" ], "comment": "king" },
	{ "question": "王立", "answers": [ "おうりつ" ], "comment": "royal" },
	{ "question": "王者", "answers": [ "おうしゃ", "おうじゃ" ], "comment": "king; monarch; ruler\nreigning champion" },
	{ "question": "珍", "answers": [ "ちん" ], "comment": "rare; curious; strange" },
	{ "question": "珍しい", "answers": [ "めずらしい" ], "comment": "unusual; rare; curious\nnew; novel\nfine (e.g. gift)" },
	{ "question": "班", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "group; party; team\nsquad; section" },
	{ "question": "現す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known" },
	{ "question": "現に", "answers": [ "げんに" ], "comment": "actually; really" },
	{ "question": "現れ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "embodiment; manifestation; materialization; materialisation; expression; indication" },
	{ "question": "現れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "現わす", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known" },
	{ "question": "現われ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "embodiment; manifestation; materialization; materialisation; expression; indication" },
	{ "question": "現われる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "現代", "answers": [ "げんだい" ], "comment": "nowadays; modern era; modern times; present-day" },
	{ "question": "現代的", "answers": [ "げんだいてき" ], "comment": "modernistic" },
	{ "question": "現代社会", "answers": [ "げんだいしゃかい" ], "comment": "modern society" },
	{ "question": "現住所", "answers": [ "げんじゅうしょ" ], "comment": "(present) address" },
	{ "question": "現像", "answers": [ "げんぞう" ], "comment": "developing (film)" },
	{ "question": "現在", "answers": [ "げんざい" ], "comment": "now; current; present; present time; as of" },
	{ "question": "現地", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "actual place; local; on-site" },
	{ "question": "現場", "answers": [ "げんば", "げんじょう" ], "comment": "actual spot; scene; scene of the crime; site; location; setting\nshop floor; factory floor; (on) site" },
	{ "question": "現実", "answers": [ "げんじつ" ], "comment": "reality; actuality; hard fact" },
	{ "question": "現役", "answers": [ "げんえき" ], "comment": "active duty; active service\nstudent taking (university) entrance exams while still enrolled in school; student who passed their university entrance exams on the first try" },
	{ "question": "現時点", "answers": [ "げんじてん" ], "comment": "present point (i.e. in history); at the present time" },
	{ "question": "現有", "answers": [ "げんゆう" ], "comment": "present; existing" },
	{ "question": "現段階", "answers": [ "げんだんかい" ], "comment": "present stage; current phase\ncurrent rank; present grade" },
	{ "question": "現況", "answers": [ "げんきょう" ], "comment": "present condition" },
	{ "question": "現物", "answers": [ "げんぶつ" ], "comment": "actual article or goods\nspots (stocks, foreign exchange, commodities, etc.)\n(in) kind (income, benefit, rent, taxes, investment, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "現状", "answers": [ "げんじょう" ], "comment": "present condition; existing state; status quo; current state" },
	{ "question": "現職", "answers": [ "げんしょく" ], "comment": "present post; current office; (an) incumbent" },
	{ "question": "現行", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "present; current; in operation" },
	{ "question": "現行犯", "answers": [ "げんこうはん" ], "comment": "flagrante delicto; caught red-handed" },
	{ "question": "現象", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "phenomenon" },
	{ "question": "現金", "answers": [ "げんきん" ], "comment": "cash; ready money; money on hand; currency\nmercenary; self-interested; calculating" },
	{ "question": "球", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "sphere\ncounter for balls" },
	{ "question": "球団", "answers": [ "きゅうだん" ], "comment": "baseball team" },
	{ "question": "球場", "answers": [ "きゅうじょう" ], "comment": "baseball stadium" },
	{ "question": "球威", "answers": [ "きゅうい" ], "comment": "(pitcher's) stuff" },
	{ "question": "球技", "answers": [ "きゅうぎ" ], "comment": "ball game (e.g. baseball, tennis, soccer)" },
	{ "question": "球界", "answers": [ "きゅうかい" ], "comment": "the baseball world" },
	{ "question": "球菌", "answers": [ "きゅうきん" ], "comment": "coccus" },
	{ "question": "理", "answers": [ "り" ], "comment": "reason; principle; logic\ngeneral principle (as opposed to individual concrete phenomenon)\n(in neo-Confucianism) the underlying principles of the cosmos" },
	{ "question": "理不尽", "answers": [ "りふじん" ], "comment": "unreasonable; irrational; outrageous; absurd" },
	{ "question": "理事", "answers": [ "りじ" ], "comment": "director; board of directors" },
	{ "question": "理学", "answers": [ "りがく" ], "comment": "physical science; natural science\nphysics\nlixue (Song-era Chinese philosophy)\nphilosophy" },
	{ "question": "理学部", "answers": [ "りがくぶ" ], "comment": "department of science" },
	{ "question": "理屈", "answers": [ "りくつ" ], "comment": "theory; reason" },
	{ "question": "理工", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "science and technology" },
	{ "question": "理工学部", "answers": [ "りこうがくぶ" ], "comment": "department of science and engineering" },
	{ "question": "理念", "answers": [ "りねん" ], "comment": "(Platonic) ideal (of how things ought to be, e.g. human rights); foundational principle; idea; conception (e.g. of the university); doctrine; ideology" },
	{ "question": "理性", "answers": [ "りせい" ], "comment": "reason; reasoning power; (one's) sense" },
	{ "question": "理想", "answers": [ "りそう" ], "comment": "ideal; ideals" },
	{ "question": "理想的", "answers": [ "りそうてき" ], "comment": "ideal" },
	{ "question": "理由", "answers": [ "りゆう" ], "comment": "reason; pretext; motive" },
	{ "question": "理科", "answers": [ "りか" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "理系", "answers": [ "りけい" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "理解", "answers": [ "りかい" ], "comment": "understanding; comprehension; appreciation; sympathy" },
	{ "question": "理論", "answers": [ "りろん" ], "comment": "theory" },
	{ "question": "理髪", "answers": [ "りはつ" ], "comment": "haircut" },
	{ "question": "琢磨", "answers": [ "たくま" ], "comment": "polish (jewels); cultivation" },
	{ "question": "琴", "answers": [ "こと", "そう" ], "comment": "koto (13-stringed Japanese zither)\nstringed instrument\nzheng (Chinese zither); guzheng" },
	{ "question": "琵琶", "answers": [ "びわ" ], "comment": "biwa (Japanese lute)" },
	{ "question": "環境", "answers": [ "かんきょう" ], "comment": "environment; circumstance" },
	{ "question": "環境庁", "answers": [ "かんきょうちょう" ], "comment": "Environment Agency" },
	{ "question": "環状", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "annulation; ring-forming" },
	{ "question": "瓦", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "roof tile" },
	{ "question": "瓶", "answers": [ "びん" ], "comment": "bottle; jar; decanter; flagon; phial; vial" },
	{ "question": "瓶詰", "answers": [ "びんづめ" ], "comment": "bottling; bottled" },
	{ "question": "瓶詰め", "answers": [ "びんづめ" ], "comment": "bottling; bottled" },
	{ "question": "甘い", "answers": [ "あまい" ], "comment": "sweet-tasting; sweet; sugary; sugared\nfragrant (smelling); sweet (music)\nlightly salted; light in salt; not spicy\nnaive; overly optimistic; soft on; generous; indulgent; easy-going; lenient\nhalf-hearted; not finished properly\ninsufficient; not satisfactory; inadequate; loose\nmild\ntempting; enticing; luring" },
	{ "question": "甘え", "answers": [ "あまえ" ], "comment": "lack of self-reliance; depending on others" },
	{ "question": "甘える", "answers": [ "あまえる" ], "comment": "to behave like a spoiled child; to fawn on\nto take advantage of; to presume upon (e.g. another's benevolence); to depend on" },
	{ "question": "甘み", "answers": [ "うまみ", "かんみ", "あまみ" ], "comment": "sweetness; sugary taste\nsweets; dessert; cake\ncharm; appeal\ntaste; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "甘やかす", "answers": [ "あまやかす" ], "comment": "to pamper; to spoil" },
	{ "question": "甘味", "answers": [ "うまみ", "かんみ", "あまみ" ], "comment": "sweetness; sugary taste\nsweets; dessert; cake\ncharm; appeal\ntaste; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "甚だしい", "answers": [ "はなはだしい" ], "comment": "extreme; excessive; terrible; intense; severe; serious; tremendous; heavy (damage)" },
	{ "question": "生", "answers": [ "なま" ], "comment": "raw; uncooked; fresh\nnatural; as it is; unedited; unprocessed\nunprotected (i.e. not wearing a condom)\nlive (i.e. not recorded)\ninexperienced; unpolished; green; crude\nimpudence; sauciness\nunpasteurized beer; draft beer; draught beer\njust a little; somehow; vaguely; partially; somewhat; half-; semi-\nirresponsibly; half-baked\ncash\ntipsiness" },
	{ "question": "生々しい", "answers": [ "なまなましい" ], "comment": "lively; green; fresh; raw; vivid; graphic" },
	{ "question": "生い立ち", "answers": [ "おいたち" ], "comment": "growth; development\none's early life; upbringing; personal history" },
	{ "question": "生える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to grow; to spring up; to sprout\nto cut (teeth)" },
	{ "question": "生え抜き", "answers": [ "はえぬき" ], "comment": "native-born; trueborn" },
	{ "question": "生かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc)\nto let live; to keep alive\nto revive; to resuscitate" },
	{ "question": "生きる", "answers": [ "いきる" ], "comment": "to live; to exist\nto make a living; to subsist\nto be in effect; to be in use; to function\nto come to life; to be enlivened\nto be safe (in baseball, go, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "生き埋め", "answers": [ "いきうめ" ], "comment": "burying alive" },
	{ "question": "生き方", "answers": [ "いきかた" ], "comment": "way of life; how to live" },
	{ "question": "生き残り", "answers": [ "いきのこり" ], "comment": "survival\nsurvivor; relic" },
	{ "question": "生き物", "answers": [ "いきもの" ], "comment": "living thing; animal" },
	{ "question": "生き生き", "answers": [ "いきいき" ], "comment": "vividly; lively" },
	{ "question": "生き甲斐", "answers": [ "いきがい" ], "comment": "something one lives for; purpose in life; raison d'être" },
	{ "question": "生き返る", "answers": [ "いきかえる" ], "comment": "to revive; to come to oneself; to be restored to life" },
	{ "question": "生け花", "answers": [ "いけばな", "せいか" ], "comment": "ikebana; Japanese art of flower arrangement\nfresh flower; natural flower" },
	{ "question": "生じる", "answers": [ "しょうじる" ], "comment": "to produce; to yield; to cause\nto result from; to arise; to be generated" },
	{ "question": "生ずる", "answers": [ "しょうずる" ], "comment": "to produce; to yield; to cause\nto result from; to arise; to be generated" },
	{ "question": "生ぬるい", "answers": [ "なまぬるい" ], "comment": "lukewarm; tepid\nhalf-hearted; vague; weak\nlenient; mild; soft" },
	{ "question": "生まれ", "answers": [ "うまれ" ], "comment": "birth; birthplace\nborn in (country, month, imperial era, zodiac year, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "生まれつき", "answers": [ "うまれつき" ], "comment": "by nature; by birth; naturally; natural; innate" },
	{ "question": "生まれる", "answers": [ "うまれる" ], "comment": "to be born" },
	{ "question": "生まれ育つ", "answers": [ "うまれそだつ" ], "comment": "to be born and raised (in one particular place)" },
	{ "question": "生み", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "production; bringing into the world; (physical) birth" },
	{ "question": "生みの親", "answers": [ "うみのおや" ], "comment": "biological parent\nfounder; creator" },
	{ "question": "生み出す", "answers": [ "うみだす" ], "comment": "to create; to bring forth; to produce\nto invent; to think up and bring into being\nto give birth to; to bear" },
	{ "question": "生む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to give birth; to bear (child); to lay (eggs)\nto produce; to yield; to give rise to; to deliver" },
	{ "question": "生やす", "answers": [ "はやす" ], "comment": "to grow; to cultivate; to wear a beard" },
	{ "question": "生中継", "answers": [ "なまちゅうけい" ], "comment": "(on TV) \"live\" broadcast" },
	{ "question": "生体", "answers": [ "せいたい" ], "comment": "organism; living body" },
	{ "question": "生保", "answers": [ "せいほ" ], "comment": "life insurance\nlivelihood protection; public assistance; welfare" },
	{ "question": "生前", "answers": [ "せいぜん" ], "comment": "while alive; during one's lifetime" },
	{ "question": "生化学", "answers": [ "せいかがく" ], "comment": "biochemistry" },
	{ "question": "生協", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "cooperative association; co-op store" },
	{ "question": "生命", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "life; existence" },
	{ "question": "生命保険", "answers": [ "せいめいほけん" ], "comment": "life insurance" },
	{ "question": "生命力", "answers": [ "せいめいりょく" ], "comment": "vitality; (one's) life force" },
	{ "question": "生地", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "cloth; fabric; material; texture\none's true character\nunglazed pottery\nuncooked dough; batter" },
	{ "question": "生存", "answers": [ "せいぞん" ], "comment": "existence; being; survival\nto exist; to live; to survive" },
	{ "question": "生家", "answers": [ "しょうか", "せいか" ], "comment": "house where one was born\nparents' house" },
	{ "question": "生年月日", "answers": [ "せいねんがっぴ" ], "comment": "birth date; date of birth; DOB" },
	{ "question": "生後", "answers": [ "せいご" ], "comment": "post-natal; since birth" },
	{ "question": "生徒", "answers": [ "せいと" ], "comment": "pupil" },
	{ "question": "生息", "answers": [ "せいそく" ], "comment": "inhabiting; living" },
	{ "question": "生息地", "answers": [ "せいそくち" ], "comment": "habitat; home (e.g. of the tiger)" },
	{ "question": "生意気", "answers": [ "なまいき" ], "comment": "impertinent; saucy; cheeky; conceit; audacious; brazen; feisty" },
	{ "question": "生態", "answers": [ "せいたい" ], "comment": "mode of life; ecology\n(animal) territory" },
	{ "question": "生態学", "answers": [ "せいたいがく" ], "comment": "ecology" },
	{ "question": "生態系", "answers": [ "せいたいけい" ], "comment": "ecosystem" },
	{ "question": "生成", "answers": [ "せいせい" ], "comment": "creation; generation; formation; derivation" },
	{ "question": "生死", "answers": [ "せいし", "しょうじ", "しょうし" ], "comment": "life and death\nsamsara (cycle of death and rebirth)\ndeath" },
	{ "question": "生殖", "answers": [ "せいしょく" ], "comment": "reproduction" },
	{ "question": "生活", "answers": [ "せいかつ" ], "comment": "living; life (one's daily existence); livelihood" },
	{ "question": "生活費", "answers": [ "せいかつひ" ], "comment": "living expenses" },
	{ "question": "生涯", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "one's lifetime (i.e. one's existence until death); one's career" },
	{ "question": "生物", "answers": [ "せいぶつ", "なまもの" ], "comment": "living things; creature\nbiology /\n raw food; perishables" },
	{ "question": "生物学", "answers": [ "せいぶつがく" ], "comment": "biology" },
	{ "question": "生理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "physiology\nmenstruation; one's period; menses" },
	{ "question": "生理学", "answers": [ "せいりがく" ], "comment": "physiology" },
	{ "question": "生産", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "production; manufacture" },
	{ "question": "生産性", "answers": [ "せいさんせい" ], "comment": "productivity" },
	{ "question": "生産者", "answers": [ "せいさんしゃ" ], "comment": "manufacturer; producer" },
	{ "question": "生育", "answers": [ "せいいく" ], "comment": "birth and growth; giving birth and raising; development; breeding" },
	{ "question": "生臭い", "answers": [ "なまぐさい" ], "comment": "smelling of fish; fishy; smelling of blood; bloody\ndegenerate (of a monk); depraved; corrupt; fallen\nworldly; mundane; secular; common; ordinary\nfishy; suspicious; questionable" },
	{ "question": "生花", "answers": [ "いけばな", "せいか" ], "comment": "ikebana; Japanese art of flower arrangement\nfresh flower; natural flower" },
	{ "question": "生計", "answers": [ "せいけい" ], "comment": "livelihood; living" },
	{ "question": "生誕", "answers": [ "せいたん" ], "comment": "birth; nativity" },
	{ "question": "生返る", "answers": [ "いきかえる" ], "comment": "to revive; to come to oneself; to be restored to life" },
	{ "question": "生還", "answers": [ "せいかん" ], "comment": "returning alive\nreaching the home plate" },
	{ "question": "生長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "growth; increment" },
	{ "question": "生鮮", "answers": [ "せいせん" ], "comment": "fresh" },
	{ "question": "産む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to give birth; to bear (child); to lay (eggs)\nto produce; to yield; to give rise to; to deliver" },
	{ "question": "産別", "answers": [ "さんべつ" ], "comment": "industrial union" },
	{ "question": "産卵", "answers": [ "さんらん" ], "comment": "egg-laying; spawning" },
	{ "question": "産品", "answers": [ "さんぴん" ], "comment": "products" },
	{ "question": "産地", "answers": [ "さんち" ], "comment": "producing area" },
	{ "question": "産婦人科", "answers": [ "さんふじんか" ], "comment": "maternity and gynaecology department (gynecology); department of obstetrics and gynaecology (gynecology)" },
	{ "question": "産業", "answers": [ "さんぎょう" ], "comment": "industry\nlivelihood; occupation" },
	{ "question": "産業界", "answers": [ "さんぎょうかい" ], "comment": "the industrial world" },
	{ "question": "産油国", "answers": [ "さんゆこく" ], "comment": "oil-producing countries (nations)" },
	{ "question": "産物", "answers": [ "さんぶつ" ], "comment": "product; produce\nresult; fruit" },
	{ "question": "産科", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "obstetrics" },
	{ "question": "産量", "answers": [ "さんりょう" ], "comment": "output" },
	{ "question": "甥", "answers": [ "おい" ], "comment": "nephew" },
	{ "question": "甦る", "answers": [ "よみがえる" ], "comment": "to be resurrected; to be resuscitated; to be rehabilitated; to be revived; to be refreshed; to be restored\nto be recalled (e.g. memories); to be brought back" },
	{ "question": "用", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "business; task; errand; engagement\nuse; purpose\nfor the use of ...; used for ...; made for ...\ncall of nature; excretion" },
	{ "question": "用いる", "answers": [ "もちいる" ], "comment": "to use; to make use of; to utilize; to utilise" },
	{ "question": "用事", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "tasks; things to do; errand; business (to take care of); affairs; engagement" },
	{ "question": "用件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "business; thing to be done; something that should be performed; information that should be conveyed" },
	{ "question": "用例", "answers": [ "ようれい" ], "comment": "example; illustration" },
	{ "question": "用具", "answers": [ "ようぐ" ], "comment": "tools; implements" },
	{ "question": "用品", "answers": [ "ようひん" ], "comment": "articles; supplies; parts" },
	{ "question": "用地", "answers": [ "ようち" ], "comment": "site" },
	{ "question": "用心", "answers": [ "ようじん" ], "comment": "care; precaution; guarding; caution" },
	{ "question": "用心棒", "answers": [ "ようじんぼう" ], "comment": "bodyguard; bouncer; guard\nbar (e.g. on a door); bolt\nstick or pole used for self-defence" },
	{ "question": "用心深い", "answers": [ "ようじんぶかい" ], "comment": "wary; watchful" },
	{ "question": "用意", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "preparation; arrangements; provision; getting ready; laying out (e.g. a meal)" },
	{ "question": "用水", "answers": [ "ようすい" ], "comment": "irrigation water; water for fire; city water; cistern water" },
	{ "question": "用紙", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "blank form\nsheets of paper; sheet of paper" },
	{ "question": "用語", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "term; terminology\nwording; choice of words; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "用途", "answers": [ "ようと" ], "comment": "use; usefulness; utility; service; purpose" },
	{ "question": "田", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "rice field" },
	{ "question": "田んぼ", "answers": [ "でんぽ", "たんぼ" ], "comment": "paddy field; farm" },
	{ "question": "田園", "answers": [ "でんえん" ], "comment": "the country; countryside; rural districts\ncultivated land; fields" },
	{ "question": "田植え", "answers": [ "たうえ" ], "comment": "rice planting" },
	{ "question": "田畑", "answers": [ "たはた", "でんぱた", "たはたけ" ], "comment": "fields (of rice and other crops)" },
	{ "question": "田舎", "answers": [ "いなか" ], "comment": "rural area; countryside; the sticks\nhometown" },
	{ "question": "由", "answers": [ "よし" ], "comment": "reason; significance; cause\npiece of information that one has heard; I hear that ...; it is said that ..." },
	{ "question": "由来", "answers": [ "ゆらい" ], "comment": "origin; source; history; derivation; reason; destiny" },
	{ "question": "由緒", "answers": [ "ゆいしょ" ], "comment": "history; pedigree; lineage" },
	{ "question": "甲", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "carapace; shell\n1st in rank; grade A\ninstep; back of hand\nthe A party (e.g. in a contract); the first party; plaintiff (label in legal documents)" },
	{ "question": "甲子", "answers": [ "きのえね", "こうし", "かっし" ], "comment": "first of the sexagenary cycle" },
	{ "question": "甲斐", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "effect; result; worth; use; avail" },
	{ "question": "甲板", "answers": [ "こうはん", "かんぱん" ], "comment": "deck (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "甲状腺", "answers": [ "こうじょうせん" ], "comment": "thyroid gland" },
	{ "question": "申", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "ninth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Monkey, 3pm-5pm, west-southwest, July)" },
	{ "question": "申し上げる", "answers": [ "もうしあげる" ], "comment": "to say; to tell; to state; to express; to offer; to extend (greetings, congratulations, etc.)\nto do" },
	{ "question": "申し入れ", "answers": [ "もうしいれ" ], "comment": "proposal; offer; report; proposition; notice; request" },
	{ "question": "申し入れる", "answers": [ "もうしいれる" ], "comment": "to propose; to suggest" },
	{ "question": "申し出", "answers": [ "もうしいで", "もうしで" ], "comment": "proposal; request; claim; report; notice; offer" },
	{ "question": "申し出る", "answers": [ "もうしでる" ], "comment": "to report to; to tell; to suggest; to submit; to request; to make an offer; to come forward with information" },
	{ "question": "申し分無い", "answers": [ "もうしぶんない" ], "comment": "no objection; nothing to criticize; nothing to criticise" },
	{ "question": "申し合わせ", "answers": [ "もうしあわせ" ], "comment": "arrangement; appointment" },
	{ "question": "申し立て", "answers": [ "もうしたて" ], "comment": "statement; account (of something); declaration; allegation" },
	{ "question": "申し訳", "answers": [ "もうしわけ" ], "comment": "apology; excuse" },
	{ "question": "申し訳ありません", "answers": [ "もうしわけありません" ], "comment": "I'm sorry; (it's) inexcusable\nthank you very much (for help, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "申し訳ない", "answers": [ "もうしわけない" ], "comment": "I'm sorry; (it's) inexcusable; I feel regretful; I feel guilty\nthank you very much (for help, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "申し込み", "answers": [ "もうしこみ" ], "comment": "application; entry; request; subscription; offer; proposal; overture; challenge" },
	{ "question": "申し込む", "answers": [ "もうしこむ" ], "comment": "to apply for; to make an application; to propose (marriage); to offer (mediation); to make an overture (of peace); to challenge; to lodge (objections); to request (an interview); to subscribe for; to book; to reserve" },
	{ "question": "申す", "answers": [ "もうす" ], "comment": "to say; to be called\nto do" },
	{ "question": "申告", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "report; statement; filing a return; notification" },
	{ "question": "申請", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "application; request; petition" },
	{ "question": "申込", "answers": [ "もうしこみ" ], "comment": "application; entry; request; subscription; offer; proposal; overture; challenge" },
	{ "question": "申込み", "answers": [ "もうしこみ" ], "comment": "application; entry; request; subscription; offer; proposal; overture; challenge" },
	{ "question": "申込書", "answers": [ "もうしこみしょ" ], "comment": "application form; written application" },
	{ "question": "男", "answers": [ "おとこ" ], "comment": "man; male\nfellow; guy; chap; bloke\nmale lover; boyfriend; man\nmanliness; manly honor; manly honour; manly reputation" },
	{ "question": "男のコ", "answers": [ "おとこのこ", "おとこのコ" ], "comment": "boy; male child; baby boy" },
	{ "question": "男の人", "answers": [ "おとこのひと" ], "comment": "man" },
	{ "question": "男の子", "answers": [ "おとこのこ", "おとこのコ" ], "comment": "boy; male child; baby boy" },
	{ "question": "男らしい", "answers": [ "おとこらしい" ], "comment": "manly; masculine" },
	{ "question": "男優", "answers": [ "だんゆう" ], "comment": "actor (male)" },
	{ "question": "男児", "answers": [ "だんじ" ], "comment": "boy; son; man" },
	{ "question": "男前", "answers": [ "おとこまえ" ], "comment": "handsome man" },
	{ "question": "男女", "answers": [ "だんじょ", "なんにょ" ], "comment": "men and women; man and woman; both sexes; both genders" },
	{ "question": "男子", "answers": [ "だんし" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "男性", "answers": [ "だんせい" ], "comment": "man; male\nmasculine gender" },
	{ "question": "男性的", "answers": [ "だんせいてき" ], "comment": "manly" },
	{ "question": "町", "answers": [ "まち", "ちょう" ], "comment": "town; block; neighbourhood; neighborhood\nstreet; road\n109.09 m\n0.99 hectares\ndowntown; main street" },
	{ "question": "町並", "answers": [ "まちなみ" ], "comment": "townscape; street (of stores and houses); (look of) stores and houses on street" },
	{ "question": "町並み", "answers": [ "まちなみ" ], "comment": "townscape; street (of stores and houses); (look of) stores and houses on street" },
	{ "question": "町中", "answers": [ "まちなか" ], "comment": "downtown" },
	{ "question": "町内", "answers": [ "ちょうない" ], "comment": "neighborhood; neighbourhood; street; block; town" },
	{ "question": "町外れ", "answers": [ "まちはずれ" ], "comment": "outskirts (of a town)" },
	{ "question": "町役場", "answers": [ "まちやくば" ], "comment": "town hall" },
	{ "question": "町村", "answers": [ "ちょうそん" ], "comment": "towns and villages" },
	{ "question": "町民", "answers": [ "ちょうみん" ], "comment": "townspeople" },
	{ "question": "町角", "answers": [ "まちかど" ], "comment": "street corner" },
	{ "question": "町議会", "answers": [ "ちょうぎかい" ], "comment": "town council" },
	{ "question": "町長", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう" ], "comment": "town headman; town mayor" },
	{ "question": "画", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "stroke (of a kanji, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "画する", "answers": [ "かくする" ], "comment": "to draw (a line)\nto demarcate; to mark; to divide; to map out\nto plan" },
	{ "question": "画一", "answers": [ "かくいつ" ], "comment": "uniformity; standardization; standardisation" },
	{ "question": "画像", "answers": [ "がぞう" ], "comment": "image; picture; portrait" },
	{ "question": "画商", "answers": [ "がしょう" ], "comment": "picture dealer; commercial art gallery" },
	{ "question": "画家", "answers": [ "がか" ], "comment": "painter; artist" },
	{ "question": "画廊", "answers": [ "がろう" ], "comment": "art gallery (esp. artworks for sale); picture gallery" },
	{ "question": "画数", "answers": [ "かくすう" ], "comment": "stroke count" },
	{ "question": "画期的", "answers": [ "かっきてき" ], "comment": "ground-breaking; revolutionary; unprecedented; epoch-making" },
	{ "question": "画用紙", "answers": [ "がようし" ], "comment": "drawing paper" },
	{ "question": "画面", "answers": [ "がめん" ], "comment": "terminal screen; scene; picture; the field (in TV); photo" },
	{ "question": "畑", "answers": [ "はた", "はたけ" ], "comment": "field (for fruits, vegetables, etc.); cultivated land; vegetable plot; kitchen garden; plantation\nfield (of specialization); sphere; area\nwomb; birth; birthplace" },
	{ "question": "留まる", "answers": [ "とまる", "とどまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on" },
	{ "question": "留める", "answers": [ "とどめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to stay (e.g. the night); to cease; to put an end to\nto contain; to keep (in position, in place); to limit\nto record (e.g. a fact); to retain" },
	{ "question": "留め金", "answers": [ "とめがね" ], "comment": "clasp; snap fastener" },
	{ "question": "留任", "answers": [ "りゅうにん" ], "comment": "remaining (staying) in office; remaining at one's post" },
	{ "question": "留保", "answers": [ "りゅうほ" ], "comment": "reserving; withholding" },
	{ "question": "留学", "answers": [ "りゅうがく" ], "comment": "studying abroad (usu. at university level)" },
	{ "question": "留学生", "answers": [ "りゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "overseas student; exchange student" },
	{ "question": "留守", "answers": [ "るす" ], "comment": "absence; being away from home\nhouse-sitting; house-sitter\nbeing left unattended to (of one's studies, etc.); neglecting" },
	{ "question": "留守番", "answers": [ "るすばん" ], "comment": "care-taking; house-sitting; house-watching; staying at home\ncaretaker; house-sitter" },
	{ "question": "留年", "answers": [ "りゅうねん" ], "comment": "repeating a year (at school); staying in the same class for another year" },
	{ "question": "留置", "answers": [ "りゅうち" ], "comment": "detention (usu. during investigation); imprisonment; poundage; custody" },
	{ "question": "留置場", "answers": [ "りゅうちじょう" ], "comment": "police cell; place of detention" },
	{ "question": "畜生", "answers": [ "ちくしょう", "ちきしょう" ], "comment": "beast (i.e. any animal other than man)\nperson reborn into the animal realm\nbrute (i.e. a contemptible human being)\nson of a bitch; for Christ's sake; damn it" },
	{ "question": "畜産", "answers": [ "ちくさん" ], "comment": "animal husbandry" },
	{ "question": "略", "answers": [ "りゃく" ], "comment": "abbreviation; omission" },
	{ "question": "略す", "answers": [ "りゃくす" ], "comment": "to abbreviate; to omit\nto take; to capture" },
	{ "question": "略奪", "answers": [ "りゃくだつ" ], "comment": "pillage; plunder; looting; robbery" },
	{ "question": "略式", "answers": [ "りゃくしき" ], "comment": "informal; simplified" },
	{ "question": "略歴", "answers": [ "りゃくれき" ], "comment": "brief personal record; short curriculum vitae; short CV" },
	{ "question": "略称", "answers": [ "りゃくしょう" ], "comment": "abbreviation" },
	{ "question": "略語", "answers": [ "りゃくご" ], "comment": "abbreviation; acronym" },
	{ "question": "番", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "number (in a series)\n(one's) turn\nwatch; guard; lookout\nbout; match" },
	{ "question": "番付", "answers": [ "ばんづけ" ], "comment": "ranked list (entertainers, sumo wrestlers, millionaires, etc.)\nprogram (e.g. theatre)" },
	{ "question": "番号", "answers": [ "ばんごう" ], "comment": "number; series of digits" },
	{ "question": "番地", "answers": [ "ばんち" ], "comment": "house number; address" },
	{ "question": "番手", "answers": [ "ばんて" ], "comment": "(yarn) count\nn-th place (e.g. in a race); n-th in position (e.g. a starting lineup)" },
	{ "question": "番目", "answers": [ "ばんめ" ], "comment": "indicates position in a sequence\ndivisions of a kabuki performance" },
	{ "question": "番組", "answers": [ "ばんぐみ" ], "comment": "program (e.g. TV); programme" },
	{ "question": "異なる", "answers": [ "ことなる" ], "comment": "to differ; to vary; to disagree" },
	{ "question": "異例", "answers": [ "いれい" ], "comment": "exceptional; unusual; extraordinary; unprecedented; singular" },
	{ "question": "異動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "change (personnel); transfer; reshuffle" },
	{ "question": "異口同音", "answers": [ "いくどうおん" ], "comment": "in concert; with one voice; unanimously" },
	{ "question": "異名", "answers": [ "いみょう", "いめい" ], "comment": "another name; nickname; alias" },
	{ "question": "異国", "answers": [ "いこく" ], "comment": "foreign country" },
	{ "question": "異変", "answers": [ "いへん" ], "comment": "unusual phenomenon; unusual event; abnormal event; accident" },
	{ "question": "異常", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "strangeness; abnormality; disorder" },
	{ "question": "異性", "answers": [ "いせい" ], "comment": "the opposite sex\nisomerism" },
	{ "question": "異文", "answers": [ "いぶん" ], "comment": "variant (in a manuscript or book); part of a text that differs from other versions" },
	{ "question": "異様", "answers": [ "いよう" ], "comment": "bizarre; strange; eccentric; odd; queer" },
	{ "question": "異物", "answers": [ "いぶつ" ], "comment": "foreign substance; foreign body; foreign contamination\nstrange object; unusual object\ndead body; corpse; remains" },
	{ "question": "異状", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "something wrong; accident; change; abnormality; aberration" },
	{ "question": "異端", "answers": [ "いたん" ], "comment": "heresy" },
	{ "question": "異色", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "unique; distinctive; novel; singular; unusual; special\ndifferent color (colour)" },
	{ "question": "異論", "answers": [ "いろん" ], "comment": "different opinion; objection" },
	{ "question": "異議", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "objection; dissent; protest" },
	{ "question": "異質", "answers": [ "いしつ" ], "comment": "different (quality, nature); heterogeneous" },
	{ "question": "畳", "answers": [ "じょう", "たたみ" ], "comment": "counter for tatami mats\nmeasure of room size (in mat units) /\n tatami mat; Japanese straw floor coverings" },
	{ "question": "疎外", "answers": [ "そがい" ], "comment": "estrangement; neglect; alienation; casting out" },
	{ "question": "疎通", "answers": [ "そつう" ], "comment": "(mutual) understanding; communication\nremoval of blockage (esp. medical); drainage" },
	{ "question": "疎遠", "answers": [ "そえん" ], "comment": "estrangement; neglect; silence" },
	{ "question": "疎開", "answers": [ "そかい" ], "comment": "dispersal; evacuation; deployment" },
	{ "question": "疑い", "answers": [ "うたがい" ], "comment": "doubt; question; uncertainty; skepticism; scepticism; suspicion; distrust" },
	{ "question": "疑う", "answers": [ "うたがう" ], "comment": "to doubt; to distrust; to be suspicious of; to suspect" },
	{ "question": "疑わしい", "answers": [ "うたがわしい" ], "comment": "doubtful; questionable; uncertain; disputable; suspicious" },
	{ "question": "疑似", "answers": [ "ぎじ" ], "comment": "suspected; pseudo; sham; quasi; false; mock" },
	{ "question": "疑問", "answers": [ "ぎもん" ], "comment": "question; problem; doubt; guess" },
	{ "question": "疑問点", "answers": [ "ぎもんてん" ], "comment": "point of uncertainty; unclarified issue; doubt" },
	{ "question": "疑問符", "answers": [ "ぎもんふ" ], "comment": "question mark" },
	{ "question": "疑心", "answers": [ "ぎしん" ], "comment": "doubt; suspicion; fear; apprehension" },
	{ "question": "疑念", "answers": [ "ぎねん" ], "comment": "doubt; suspicion; misgivings; scruples" },
	{ "question": "疑惑", "answers": [ "ぎわく" ], "comment": "doubt; misgivings; distrust; suspicion" },
	{ "question": "疑獄", "answers": [ "ぎごく" ], "comment": "scandal; graft case" },
	{ "question": "疑義", "answers": [ "ぎぎ" ], "comment": "doubt" },
	{ "question": "疲れ", "answers": [ "つかれ" ], "comment": "tiredness; fatigue" },
	{ "question": "疲れる", "answers": [ "つかれる" ], "comment": "to get tired; to tire\nto be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)\nto starve" },
	{ "question": "疲労", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "fatigue; weariness" },
	{ "question": "疲弊", "answers": [ "ひへい" ], "comment": "exhaustion; fatigue\nimpoverishment; (financial) exhaustion; ruin" },
	{ "question": "疾患", "answers": [ "しっかん" ], "comment": "disease; ailment; illness" },
	{ "question": "疾病", "answers": [ "しっぺい" ], "comment": "illness; disease" },
	{ "question": "病", "answers": [ "やまい" ], "comment": "illness; disease\nbad habit; weakness; fault" },
	{ "question": "病む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "to fall ill; to suffer from; to have something wrong with" },
	{ "question": "病人", "answers": [ "びょうにん" ], "comment": "sick person; patient; invalid" },
	{ "question": "病名", "answers": [ "びょうめい" ], "comment": "name of a disease" },
	{ "question": "病室", "answers": [ "びょうしつ" ], "comment": "sickroom; hospital room" },
	{ "question": "病床", "answers": [ "びょうしょう" ], "comment": "sickbed" },
	{ "question": "病弱", "answers": [ "びょうじゃく" ], "comment": "weak (constitution); sickly; feeble; in poor health" },
	{ "question": "病棟", "answers": [ "びょうとう" ], "comment": "(hospital) ward" },
	{ "question": "病死", "answers": [ "びょうし" ], "comment": "death from disease; death from illness" },
	{ "question": "病気", "answers": [ "びょうき" ], "comment": "illness; disease; sickness" },
	{ "question": "病状", "answers": [ "びょうじょう" ], "comment": "patient's condition; pathology" },
	{ "question": "病理", "answers": [ "びょうり" ], "comment": "pathology" },
	{ "question": "病院", "answers": [ "びょういん" ], "comment": "hospital" },
	{ "question": "症", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "illness" },
	{ "question": "症例", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "case" },
	{ "question": "症候群", "answers": [ "しょうこうぐん" ], "comment": "syndrome" },
	{ "question": "症状", "answers": [ "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "symptoms; condition" },
	{ "question": "痕跡", "answers": [ "こんせき" ], "comment": "trace; traces; vestige; vestiges" },
	{ "question": "痛い", "answers": [ "いたい" ], "comment": "painful; sore\nexceeding" },
	{ "question": "痛ましい", "answers": [ "いたましい" ], "comment": "pitiful; heartbreaking; tragical" },
	{ "question": "痛み", "answers": [ "いたみ" ], "comment": "pain; ache; soreness; grief; distress\ndamage; injury; wear; bruise; break" },
	{ "question": "痛む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to hurt; to ache; to feel a pain\nto be injured; to be spoiled (e.g. food); to be damaged" },
	{ "question": "痛める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket" },
	{ "question": "痛恨", "answers": [ "つうこん" ], "comment": "regretful; sorrowful; bitter\ncontrition" },
	{ "question": "痛感", "answers": [ "つうかん" ], "comment": "feeling keenly; fully realizing" },
	{ "question": "痛手", "answers": [ "いたで" ], "comment": "serious wound\nhard blow" },
	{ "question": "痛烈", "answers": [ "つうれつ" ], "comment": "severe; bitter; scathing" },
	{ "question": "痩せる", "answers": [ "やせる" ], "comment": "to become thin; to lose weight; to reduce (one's) weight; to slim\nto be barren; to be infertile; to be sterile" },
	{ "question": "痴呆", "answers": [ "ちほう" ], "comment": "dementia" },
	{ "question": "痴女", "answers": [ "ちじょ" ], "comment": "female pervert" },
	{ "question": "痴漢", "answers": [ "ちかん" ], "comment": "masher; molester; pervert" },
	{ "question": "療法", "answers": [ "りょうほう" ], "comment": "therapy; treatment; remedy; cure" },
	{ "question": "療養", "answers": [ "りょうよう" ], "comment": "recuperation; medical treatment" },
	{ "question": "療養所", "answers": [ "りょうようしょ", "りょうようじょ" ], "comment": "sanatorium" },
	{ "question": "癒着", "answers": [ "ゆちゃく" ], "comment": "adhesion; conglutination\ncollusion; collusive relationship" },
	{ "question": "癖", "answers": [ "くせ", "へき" ], "comment": "habit (often a bad habit, i.e. vice); tendency\npeculiarity; idiosyncrasy; mannerism\ncrease; wrinkle; curl; kink" },
	{ "question": "発", "answers": [ "はつ" ], "comment": "departure; departing (from ...); departing (at time ...)\nsending; sent (by ...); sent (at ...)\nengine\ngreen dragon tile\ncounter for gunshots, bursts of gas, etc.; counter for bullets, bombs, etc.; counter for blows (punches)" },
	{ "question": "発する", "answers": [ "はっする" ], "comment": "to fire (a gun); to emit; to give forth" },
	{ "question": "発令", "answers": [ "はつれい" ], "comment": "official announcement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "発作", "answers": [ "ほっさ" ], "comment": "fit; spasm; attack; seizure" },
	{ "question": "発信", "answers": [ "はっしん" ], "comment": "dispatch; despatch; transmission; submission" },
	{ "question": "発光", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "luminescence; radiation" },
	{ "question": "発刊", "answers": [ "はっかん" ], "comment": "publish; start (new) publication" },
	{ "question": "発効", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "coming into effect" },
	{ "question": "発動", "answers": [ "はつどう" ], "comment": "putting into operation\ninvocation" },
	{ "question": "発声", "answers": [ "はっせい" ], "comment": "utterance; speaking; vocalization; vocalisation; enunciation; pronouncing\nleading a group of people (in cheering, singing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "発売", "answers": [ "はつばい" ], "comment": "sale; offering for sale; release (for sale); launch (product)" },
	{ "question": "発射", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "firing; shooting; discharge; catapult\nejaculation" },
	{ "question": "発展", "answers": [ "はってん" ], "comment": "development; growth; advancement; unfurling\nexpansion; extension; enlargement\nplaying around; having an active sex life" },
	{ "question": "発展途上国", "answers": [ "はってんとじょうこく" ], "comment": "developing country" },
	{ "question": "発想", "answers": [ "はっそう" ], "comment": "idea; conception; way of thinking\nexpression" },
	{ "question": "発掘", "answers": [ "はっくつ" ], "comment": "excavation; exhumation\ndiscovery (e.g. new talent)" },
	{ "question": "発揮", "answers": [ "はっき" ], "comment": "exhibition; demonstration; show; display; manifestation" },
	{ "question": "発散", "answers": [ "はっさん" ], "comment": "emission; emanation; radiation; diffusion; dispersion\nletting out (feelings); venting\ndivergence (of light)\ndivergence" },
	{ "question": "発明", "answers": [ "はつめい" ], "comment": "invention\nintelligent; clever\nbeing enlightened; having the meaning of everything become clear" },
	{ "question": "発案", "answers": [ "はつあん" ], "comment": "idea; suggestion; initiation of a proposal" },
	{ "question": "発泡スチロール", "answers": [ "はっぽうスチロール" ], "comment": "styrofoam; styrene foam; expanded polystyrene" },
	{ "question": "発注", "answers": [ "はっちゅう" ], "comment": "ordering (materials); placing an order; order" },
	{ "question": "発火", "answers": [ "はっか" ], "comment": "ignition; catching fire\nfiring (e.g. gun); discharging" },
	{ "question": "発熱", "answers": [ "はつねつ" ], "comment": "generation of heat\n(attack of) fever; pyrexia" },
	{ "question": "発生", "answers": [ "はっせい" ], "comment": "outbreak; spring forth; occurrence; incidence\ngeneration (e.g. of power or heat); genesis; origin\nontogeny; development of complex multicellular structures from cell(s) in a simple state" },
	{ "question": "発病", "answers": [ "はつびょう" ], "comment": "attack (disease)" },
	{ "question": "発症", "answers": [ "はっしょう" ], "comment": "outbreak of an illness; onset of an illness; appearance of symptoms" },
	{ "question": "発着", "answers": [ "はっちゃく" ], "comment": "arrival and departure" },
	{ "question": "発砲", "answers": [ "はっぽう" ], "comment": "firing; discharge of gun" },
	{ "question": "発祥", "answers": [ "はっしょう" ], "comment": "origin\nappearance of auspicious omen" },
	{ "question": "発端", "answers": [ "ほったん" ], "comment": "origin; genesis; opening; start; beginning" },
	{ "question": "発給", "answers": [ "はっきゅう" ], "comment": "issuance (e.g. of a passport); issuing" },
	{ "question": "発育", "answers": [ "はついく" ], "comment": "(physical) growth; development" },
	{ "question": "発芽", "answers": [ "はつが" ], "comment": "germination; sprouting; budding" },
	{ "question": "発行", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "issue (publications); publishing\nraising an event (software)" },
	{ "question": "発表", "answers": [ "はっぴょう" ], "comment": "announcement; publication; presenting; statement; communique; making known; breaking (news story); expressing (one's opinion); releasing; unveiling" },
	{ "question": "発見", "answers": [ "はっけん" ], "comment": "discovery; detection; finding" },
	{ "question": "発覚", "answers": [ "はっかく" ], "comment": "detection; coming to light" },
	{ "question": "発言", "answers": [ "はつげん" ], "comment": "statement; remark; observation; utterance; speech; proposal" },
	{ "question": "発言権", "answers": [ "はつげんけん" ], "comment": "right to speak" },
	{ "question": "発起人", "answers": [ "ほっきにん" ], "comment": "originator; promoter" },
	{ "question": "発足", "answers": [ "ほっそく", "はっそく" ], "comment": "starting; inauguration; launch; founding; establishment; start-up" },
	{ "question": "発車", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "departure of a vehicle" },
	{ "question": "発送", "answers": [ "はっそう" ], "comment": "sending; forwarding; shipping" },
	{ "question": "発達", "answers": [ "はったつ" ], "comment": "development; growth" },
	{ "question": "発酵", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "fermentation; zymosis" },
	{ "question": "発電", "answers": [ "はつでん" ], "comment": "generation (e.g. power)\nsending a telegram; telegraphing" },
	{ "question": "発電所", "answers": [ "はつでんしょ" ], "comment": "power plant; power station" },
	{ "question": "発電機", "answers": [ "はつでんき" ], "comment": "dynamo; power generator" },
	{ "question": "発音", "answers": [ "はつおん" ], "comment": "pronunciation" },
	{ "question": "登る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "to ascend; to go up; to climb\nto ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise\nto go to (the capital)\nto be promoted\nto add up to\nto advance (in price)\nto swim up (a river); to sail up\nto come up (on the agenda)" },
	{ "question": "登場", "answers": [ "とうじょう" ], "comment": "entry (on stage); appearance (on screen)\nentrance; introduction (into a market)" },
	{ "question": "登山", "answers": [ "とざん" ], "comment": "mountain climbing" },
	{ "question": "登板", "answers": [ "とうばん" ], "comment": "taking the mound; pitching a game" },
	{ "question": "登校", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "attendance (at school); going to school" },
	{ "question": "登用", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "appointment; assignment; promotion" },
	{ "question": "登竜門", "answers": [ "とうりゅうもん" ], "comment": "gateway to success; opening to honours; opening to honors" },
	{ "question": "登記", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "registry; registration" },
	{ "question": "登載", "answers": [ "とうさい" ], "comment": "register; record; printing" },
	{ "question": "登録", "answers": [ "とうろく" ], "comment": "registration; accession; register; entry; record" },
	{ "question": "登録商標", "answers": [ "とうろくしょうひょう" ], "comment": "registered trademark" },
	{ "question": "登録番号", "answers": [ "とうろくばんごう" ], "comment": "registration number" },
	{ "question": "登録者", "answers": [ "とうろくしゃ" ], "comment": "registrant; subscriber; enrollee" },
	{ "question": "登頂", "answers": [ "とうちょう" ], "comment": "climbing to the summit; summiting" },
	{ "question": "白", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "white\ninnocence; innocent person\nblank space\nwhite go stone\nwhite dragon tile\nskewered grilled pig intestine" },
	{ "question": "白い", "answers": [ "しろい" ], "comment": "white" },
	{ "question": "白バイ", "answers": [ "しろバイ" ], "comment": "motorcycle police\nwhite-colored police motorcycle" },
	{ "question": "白人", "answers": [ "はくじん" ], "comment": "white person; Caucasian" },
	{ "question": "白内障", "answers": [ "はくないしょう" ], "comment": "cataract (opacity in lens of eye)" },
	{ "question": "白地", "answers": [ "しろじ", "しらじ" ], "comment": "white background\nblank\nfemale virgin" },
	{ "question": "白星", "answers": [ "しろぼし" ], "comment": "white circle; white star\nvictory mark" },
	{ "question": "白書", "answers": [ "はくしょ" ], "comment": "white paper" },
	{ "question": "白樺", "answers": [ "しらかば", "しらかんば" ], "comment": "Japanese white birch (Betula platyphylla var. japonica)" },
	{ "question": "白熱", "answers": [ "はくねつ" ], "comment": "white heat; incandescence\nclimax" },
	{ "question": "白状", "answers": [ "はくじょう" ], "comment": "confession" },
	{ "question": "白粉", "answers": [ "おしろい" ], "comment": "(face) powder" },
	{ "question": "白紙", "answers": [ "はくし", "しらかみ" ], "comment": "white paper; flyleaf\nblank paper\nclean slate; lack of prior opinion, positions, etc.\nscratch; beginning" },
	{ "question": "白線", "answers": [ "はくせん" ], "comment": "white line\nlinea alba (anot.)" },
	{ "question": "白羽", "answers": [ "しらは" ], "comment": "white feather" },
	{ "question": "白色", "answers": [ "はくしょく" ], "comment": "white" },
	{ "question": "白菜", "answers": [ "はくさい", "パクチョイ" ], "comment": "Chinese cabbage (Brassica campestris var. amplexicaulis); white rape; bok choy; pak choi" },
	{ "question": "白血球", "answers": [ "はっけっきゅう" ], "comment": "leukocyte; leucocyte; white blood cell" },
	{ "question": "白血病", "answers": [ "はっけつびょう" ], "comment": "leukemia" },
	{ "question": "白衣", "answers": [ "はくい", "びゃくい", "びゃくえ" ], "comment": "white robe; (doctor's) white gown" },
	{ "question": "白馬", "answers": [ "しろうま", "はくば" ], "comment": "white horse\nunrefined sake" },
	{ "question": "白骨", "answers": [ "はっこつ" ], "comment": "white (bleached) bone; skeleton" },
	{ "question": "白髪", "answers": [ "はくはつ", "しらが" ], "comment": "white hair; grey hair; gray hair" },
	{ "question": "白鳥", "answers": [ "しらとり", "はくちょう", "しろとり" ], "comment": "swan (Cygnus spp.)\nwhite-feathered bird" },
	{ "question": "白黒", "answers": [ "しろくろ" ], "comment": "black and white; monochrome\ngood and evil; right and wrong; guilt and innocence" },
	{ "question": "百", "answers": [ "はく", "ひゃく", "もも" ], "comment": "100; hundred" },
	{ "question": "百万", "answers": [ "ひゃくまん" ], "comment": "1,000,000; one million; million\nmany" },
	{ "question": "百億", "answers": [ "ひゃくおく" ], "comment": "10,000,000,000; ten billion (American); (obs) ten milliard (British)" },
	{ "question": "百八十度", "answers": [ "ひゃくはちじゅうど" ], "comment": "180 degrees; complete change" },
	{ "question": "百合", "answers": [ "ゆり" ], "comment": "lily (Lilium spp.)\ncomics and novels about female homosexuality" },
	{ "question": "百姓", "answers": [ "ひゃくしょう" ], "comment": "farmer; peasant; country bumpkin\nfarming\nthe common people" },
	{ "question": "百科事典", "answers": [ "ひゃっかじてん" ], "comment": "encyclopedia; encyclopaedia" },
	{ "question": "百科辞典", "answers": [ "ひゃっかじてん" ], "comment": "encyclopedia; encyclopaedia" },
	{ "question": "百貨店", "answers": [ "ひゃっかてん" ], "comment": "(department) store; (department) stores" },
	{ "question": "的", "answers": [ "まと", "てき" ], "comment": "-like; typical /\n mark; target" },
	{ "question": "的中", "answers": [ "てきちゅう" ], "comment": "striking home; hitting the mark\ncoming true; proving to be right; becoming realized" },
	{ "question": "的確", "answers": [ "てきかく", "てっかく" ], "comment": "precise; accurate; appropriate; exactly the right" },
	{ "question": "皆さん", "answers": [ "みなさん" ], "comment": "all; everyone; everybody" },
	{ "question": "皆様", "answers": [ "みなさま" ], "comment": "everyone" },
	{ "question": "皆無", "answers": [ "かいむ" ], "comment": "nonexistent; nil; none; nothing (at all); bugger-all" },
	{ "question": "皇后", "answers": [ "こうごう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) empress; queen" },
	{ "question": "皇太后", "answers": [ "こうたいごう", "こうたいこう" ], "comment": "Queen Mother; Empress Dowager" },
	{ "question": "皇太子", "answers": [ "こうたいし" ], "comment": "crown prince" },
	{ "question": "皇太子妃", "answers": [ "こうたいしひ" ], "comment": "crown princess" },
	{ "question": "皇室", "answers": [ "こうしつ" ], "comment": "Imperial household" },
	{ "question": "皇居", "answers": [ "こうきょ" ], "comment": "Imperial Palace (of Japan); imperial residence" },
	{ "question": "皇帝", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "emperor" },
	{ "question": "皇族", "answers": [ "こうぞく" ], "comment": "imperial family; royalty" },
	{ "question": "皇民党", "answers": [ "こうみんとう" ], "comment": "Imperialist Party" },
	{ "question": "皮", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "skin; hide; pelt; fur\nrind; peel; husk; bark\nshell; sheath; wrapping\nmask (hiding one's true nature); seeming" },
	{ "question": "皮切り", "answers": [ "かわきり" ], "comment": "beginning; start" },
	{ "question": "皮肉", "answers": [ "ひにく" ], "comment": "cynicism; sarcasm; irony; satire" },
	{ "question": "皮膚", "answers": [ "ひふ", "ひフ" ], "comment": "skin" },
	{ "question": "皮膚科", "answers": [ "ひふか", "ヒフか", "ひフか" ], "comment": "dermatology" },
	{ "question": "皮革", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "leather; hide" },
	{ "question": "皿", "answers": [ "さら" ], "comment": "plate; dish; platter; disc\nserving; helping; course\nkanji radical 108 (at the bottom)" },
	{ "question": "盆", "answers": [ "ぼん" ], "comment": "tray\nfamily; household\nO-Bon; Bon Festival; Lantern Festival; Festival of the Dead" },
	{ "question": "盆地", "answers": [ "ぼんち" ], "comment": "basin (e.g. between mountains)" },
	{ "question": "盆栽", "answers": [ "ぼんさい" ], "comment": "bonsai; miniature potted plant" },
	{ "question": "盆踊り", "answers": [ "ぼんおどり" ], "comment": "Bon Festival dance; Lantern Festival dance" },
	{ "question": "益", "answers": [ "やく", "よう", "えき" ], "comment": "benefit; use; good; advantage; gain\nprofit; gains" },
	{ "question": "盗み", "answers": [ "ぬすみ" ], "comment": "stealing" },
	{ "question": "盗む", "answers": [ "ぬすむ" ], "comment": "to steal" },
	{ "question": "盗塁", "answers": [ "とうるい" ], "comment": "base stealing; steal; stolen base" },
	{ "question": "盗聴", "answers": [ "とうちょう" ], "comment": "interception (email); wiretap; bug" },
	{ "question": "盗賊", "answers": [ "とうぞく" ], "comment": "thief; robber; burglar; bandit" },
	{ "question": "盗難", "answers": [ "とうなん" ], "comment": "theft; robbery" },
	{ "question": "盛り", "answers": [ "さかり", "もり" ], "comment": "peak (e.g. of cherry blossom season); height (e.g. of summer)\nprime (of one's life); one's best days\nrutting; being in heat" },
	{ "question": "盛り上がり", "answers": [ "もりあがり" ], "comment": "climax; uprush\nbulge" },
	{ "question": "盛り上がる", "answers": [ "もりあがる" ], "comment": "to swell; to rise; to bulge; to be piled up\nto rouse; to get excited" },
	{ "question": "盛り上げる", "answers": [ "もりあげる" ], "comment": "to pile up; to heap up\nto stir up; to enliven; to bring to a climax" },
	{ "question": "盛り付け", "answers": [ "もりつけ" ], "comment": "arrangement of food (on a dish); serving of (arranged) food" },
	{ "question": "盛り込む", "answers": [ "もりこむ" ], "comment": "to incorporate; to include" },
	{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "もる", "さかる" ], "comment": "to serve (food, etc.); to dish out\nto fill up; to pile up; to heap\nto prescribe; to administer; to dose out\nto put into (e.g. information in a report)\nto mark out (e.g. scale); to graduate (e.g. thermometer)\nto exaggerate; to apply heavy makeup" },
	{ "question": "盛ん", "answers": [ "さかん" ], "comment": "popular\nprosperous\nenthusiastic\nenergetic; vigorous" },
	{ "question": "盛大", "answers": [ "せいだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; lavish; large scale; prosperous; thriving; lively\nforceful; powerful; vigorous" },
	{ "question": "盛況", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "success; prosperity; boom" },
	{ "question": "盟主", "answers": [ "めいしゅ" ], "comment": "leader; leading power" },
	{ "question": "盟友", "answers": [ "めいゆう" ], "comment": "sworn friend" },
	{ "question": "監修", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "(editorial) supervision; general editorship\nsupervising director (of anime, TV series etc.)" },
	{ "question": "監察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "inspection; inspector" },
	{ "question": "監査", "answers": [ "かんさ" ], "comment": "inspection; audit; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "監査役", "answers": [ "かんさやく" ], "comment": "auditor; inspector" },
	{ "question": "監獄", "answers": [ "かんごく" ], "comment": "prison" },
	{ "question": "監理", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "superintendence; supervision; administration" },
	{ "question": "監督", "answers": [ "かんとく" ], "comment": "supervision; control; superintendence; direction\ndirector; superintendent; supervisor; coach; foreman; manager; overseer; controller; boss" },
	{ "question": "監禁", "answers": [ "かんきん" ], "comment": "confinement" },
	{ "question": "監視", "answers": [ "かんし" ], "comment": "monitoring; watching; observation; surveillance; guarding; inspection" },
	{ "question": "盤", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "disk; disc; record; clock face\ntray; shallow bowl\ngrid; board (e.g. in shogi)" },
	{ "question": "目", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "eye; eyeball\neyesight; sight; vision\nlook; stare; glance\nan experience\nviewpoint\nstitch; texture; weave\nordinal number suffix\nsomewhat; -ish" },
	{ "question": "目が覚める", "answers": [ "めがさめる" ], "comment": "to awaken; to perk up; to snap out (of something)" },
	{ "question": "目つき", "answers": [ "めつき" ], "comment": "look; expression of the eyes; eyes" },
	{ "question": "目の前", "answers": [ "めのまえ" ], "comment": "before one's eyes; in front of one; under one's nose\nimmediate; imminent; around the corner" },
	{ "question": "目を通す", "answers": [ "めをとおす" ], "comment": "to scan; to look over" },
	{ "question": "目上", "answers": [ "めうえ" ], "comment": "superior; superiors; senior" },
	{ "question": "目下", "answers": [ "めした", "もっか" ], "comment": "subordinate; subordinates; inferior; inferiors; junior /\n at present; now" },
	{ "question": "目付き", "answers": [ "めつき" ], "comment": "look; expression of the eyes; eyes" },
	{ "question": "目先", "answers": [ "めさき" ], "comment": "before one's eyes; under one's nose\nimmediate (e.g. interests); present; at hand; short-run\nforesight; near future\nappearance" },
	{ "question": "目前", "answers": [ "もくぜん" ], "comment": "before one's very eyes; under one's nose; imminence; close at hand" },
	{ "question": "目印", "answers": [ "めじるし" ], "comment": "mark; sign; landmark; benchmark" },
	{ "question": "目安", "answers": [ "めやす" ], "comment": "criterion; standard; yardstick; reference; aim\nrough estimate; approximation" },
	{ "question": "目当て", "answers": [ "めあて" ], "comment": "mark; guide; landmark\npurpose; aim; goal; intention; end\nsight (on a firearm)" },
	{ "question": "目抜き", "answers": [ "めぬき" ], "comment": "principal; main; important; fashionable" },
	{ "question": "目指す", "answers": [ "めざす" ], "comment": "to aim at; to have an eye on\nto go toward; to head for" },
	{ "question": "目撃", "answers": [ "もくげき" ], "comment": "witnessing; observing; sighting" },
	{ "question": "目方", "answers": [ "めかた" ], "comment": "weight" },
	{ "question": "目標", "answers": [ "もくひょう" ], "comment": "mark; objective; target" },
	{ "question": "目次", "answers": [ "もくじ" ], "comment": "table of contents" },
	{ "question": "目減り", "answers": [ "めべり" ], "comment": "loss (of weight or volume); decrease; reduction; diminishment; erosion; shrinkage; ullage" },
	{ "question": "目玉", "answers": [ "めだま" ], "comment": "eyeball\nspecial feature; centerpiece; showpiece; drawcard\nspecial program; loss leader\nsunny-side-up fried eggs" },
	{ "question": "目玉商品", "answers": [ "めだましょうひん" ], "comment": "bargain goods; eye-catching goods; featured product; loss leader" },
	{ "question": "目白押し", "answers": [ "めじろおし" ], "comment": "jostling; milling about; crush; being jammed together\npacked with (activities, products, etc.); teeming with" },
	{ "question": "目的", "answers": [ "もくてき" ], "comment": "purpose; goal; aim; objective; intention" },
	{ "question": "目的地", "answers": [ "もくてきち" ], "comment": "place of destination" },
	{ "question": "目盛り", "answers": [ "めもり" ], "comment": "scale; gradations" },
	{ "question": "目立つ", "answers": [ "めだつ" ], "comment": "to be conspicuous; to stand out" },
	{ "question": "目薬", "answers": [ "めぐすり" ], "comment": "eye drops; eyewash" },
	{ "question": "目覚まし", "answers": [ "めざまし" ], "comment": "alarm clock\nopening one's eyes; keeping one's eyes open\ntype of candy given to a child after it wakes up from a nap" },
	{ "question": "目覚ましい", "answers": [ "めざましい" ], "comment": "brilliant; splendid; striking; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "目覚まし時計", "answers": [ "めざましどけい", "めざましとけい" ], "comment": "alarm clock" },
	{ "question": "目覚める", "answers": [ "めざめる" ], "comment": "to wake up; to awake\nto awaken to (instinct, ability, perception, etc.); to become aware of; to become conscious of; to realize\nto come to one's senses" },
	{ "question": "目録", "answers": [ "もくろく" ], "comment": "catalogue; catalog; inventory; index; list\ncertificate indicating an impending gift" },
	{ "question": "目頭", "answers": [ "まがしら", "めがしら" ], "comment": "inner canthus; inner corner of the eye" },
	{ "question": "盲人", "answers": [ "もうじん" ], "comment": "blind person" },
	{ "question": "盲学校", "answers": [ "もうがっこう" ], "comment": "school for the blind" },
	{ "question": "盲導犬", "answers": [ "もうどうけん" ], "comment": "guide dog for the blind; seeing eye dog" },
	{ "question": "盲点", "answers": [ "もうてん" ], "comment": "blind spot" },
	{ "question": "盲目", "answers": [ "もうもく" ], "comment": "blindness" },
	{ "question": "盲腸", "answers": [ "もうちょう" ], "comment": "cecum; caecum; blind gut\n(vermiform) appendix\nappendicitis" },
	{ "question": "直", "answers": [ "ちょく", "じき" ], "comment": "soon; in a moment; before long; shortly\nnearby; close\ndirect\nspot transaction; cash transaction /\n direct; in person; frankness; honesty; simplicity; cheerfulness; correctness; being straight\nnight duty; shift (e.g. in a factory)" },
	{ "question": "直し", "answers": [ "なおし" ], "comment": "correction; rectification\nmending; repair" },
	{ "question": "直す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "to cure; to heal\nto fix; to correct; to repair\nto do over again (after -masu base of verb)\nto replace; to put back as it was\nto convert (into a different state); to transform" },
	{ "question": "直ちに", "answers": [ "ただちに" ], "comment": "at once; immediately; directly; in person; automatically" },
	{ "question": "直に", "answers": [ "じきに" ], "comment": "immediately; directly; soon; shortly; before long\neasily; readily" },
	{ "question": "直る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "to be cured; to get well; to be healed\nto get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed" },
	{ "question": "直下", "answers": [ "ちょっか" ], "comment": "directly under\nfalling perpendicularly" },
	{ "question": "直列", "answers": [ "ちょくれつ" ], "comment": "series (e.g. electrical)\nserial" },
	{ "question": "直前", "answers": [ "ちょくぜん" ], "comment": "just before" },
	{ "question": "直営", "answers": [ "ちょくえい" ], "comment": "direct management" },
	{ "question": "直属", "answers": [ "ちょくぞく" ], "comment": "direct control; direct supervision" },
	{ "question": "直径", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "diameter" },
	{ "question": "直後", "answers": [ "ちょくご" ], "comment": "immediately following" },
	{ "question": "直感", "answers": [ "ちょっかん" ], "comment": "intuition; instinct; insight; hunch; immediacy" },
	{ "question": "直接", "answers": [ "ちょくせつ" ], "comment": "direct; immediate; personal; firsthand" },
	{ "question": "直接的", "answers": [ "ちょくせつてき" ], "comment": "direct" },
	{ "question": "直接税", "answers": [ "ちょくせつぜい" ], "comment": "direct tax" },
	{ "question": "直接選挙", "answers": [ "ちょくせつせんきょ" ], "comment": "direct election" },
	{ "question": "直撃", "answers": [ "ちょくげき" ], "comment": "direct hit" },
	{ "question": "直球", "answers": [ "ちょくきゅう", "ちょっきゅう" ], "comment": "straight ball (pitch)\nstraight; frank" },
	{ "question": "直系", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "direct descent; direct line" },
	{ "question": "直線", "answers": [ "ちょくせん" ], "comment": "straight line" },
	{ "question": "直行", "answers": [ "ちょっこう" ], "comment": "through; non-stop; direct" },
	{ "question": "直視", "answers": [ "ちょくし" ], "comment": "looking someone in the eyes; taking a straight look at something" },
	{ "question": "直観", "answers": [ "ちょっかん" ], "comment": "intuition; instinct; insight; hunch; immediacy" },
	{ "question": "直角", "answers": [ "ちょっかく" ], "comment": "right angle; perpendicular" },
	{ "question": "直轄", "answers": [ "ちょっかつ" ], "comment": "direct control" },
	{ "question": "直通", "answers": [ "ちょくつう" ], "comment": "direct line; direct communication; connecting directly; through service" },
	{ "question": "直進", "answers": [ "ちょくしん" ], "comment": "going right on; going straight ahead" },
	{ "question": "直面", "answers": [ "ちょくめん" ], "comment": "confrontation\nto face; to confront; to encounter" },
	{ "question": "相まって", "answers": [ "あいまって" ], "comment": "coupled with; together" },
	{ "question": "相乗", "answers": [ "そうじょう" ], "comment": "multiplication; synergism" },
	{ "question": "相乗り", "answers": [ "あいのり" ], "comment": "riding together" },
	{ "question": "相互", "answers": [ "そうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal" },
	{ "question": "相互交流", "answers": [ "そうごこうりゅう" ], "comment": "mutual exchange" },
	{ "question": "相互銀行", "answers": [ "そうごぎんこう" ], "comment": "mutual savings bank" },
	{ "question": "相場", "answers": [ "そうば" ], "comment": "market price\nspeculation (e.g. on stocks)\nreputation (according to conventional wisdom); estimation; esteem" },
	{ "question": "相変わらず", "answers": [ "あいかわらず" ], "comment": "as ever; as usual; the same; still" },
	{ "question": "相対", "answers": [ "あいたい", "そうたい" ], "comment": "confrontation; facing; between ourselves; no third party; tete-a-tete /\n relativity\nrelative" },
	{ "question": "相対的", "answers": [ "そうたいてき" ], "comment": "relative" },
	{ "question": "相当", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "befitting; becoming; worthy of; proportionate; in keeping with; suitable\nconsiderable; substantial\nto be worthy of; to be proportionate to\nto correspond to (in meaning, function, etc.); to be equivalent\nextremely; considerably" },
	{ "question": "相応", "answers": [ "そうおう" ], "comment": "suitability; fitness" },
	{ "question": "相性", "answers": [ "あいしょう" ], "comment": "affinity; compatibility" },
	{ "question": "相手", "answers": [ "あいて" ], "comment": "companion; partner; company\nother party; addressee\nopponent (sports, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "相手取る", "answers": [ "あいてどる" ], "comment": "to challenge (esp. in a lawsuit); to take on an opponent (in negotiations, contest, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "相手方", "answers": [ "あいてかた", "あいてがた" ], "comment": "other (opposite) party" },
	{ "question": "相撲", "answers": [ "すもう" ], "comment": "sumo wrestling\nwrestler; rikishi" },
	{ "question": "相槌", "answers": [ "あいづち" ], "comment": "aizuchi; back-channeling; interjections indicating that one is paying attention\ntwo smiths hammering at an object in turn" },
	{ "question": "相次ぐ", "answers": [ "あいつぐ" ], "comment": "to follow in succession; to happen one after another" },
	{ "question": "相殺", "answers": [ "そうさい", "そうさつ" ], "comment": "offset; offsetting each other; cancelling each other out; counterbalancing\nset-off; setoff" },
	{ "question": "相続", "answers": [ "そうぞく" ], "comment": "succession; inheritance" },
	{ "question": "相続税", "answers": [ "そうぞくぜい" ], "comment": "inheritance tax; death duty" },
	{ "question": "相談", "answers": [ "そうだん" ], "comment": "consultation; discussion" },
	{ "question": "相談役", "answers": [ "そうだんやく" ], "comment": "counselor; counsellor; adviser; advisor" },
	{ "question": "相談所", "answers": [ "そうだんじょ" ], "comment": "consultation office; bureau" },
	{ "question": "相違", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "difference; discrepancy; variation" },
	{ "question": "相関", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "correlation; interrelation" },
	{ "question": "相関関係", "answers": [ "そうかんかんけい" ], "comment": "correlation; interrelation; intertwining" },
	{ "question": "盾", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "shield; buckler; escutcheon; pretext" },
	{ "question": "省く", "answers": [ "はぶく" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to exclude; to eliminate\nto curtail; to save; to cut down; to economize; to economise" },
	{ "question": "省みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "省エネルギー", "answers": [ "しょうエネルギー" ], "comment": "energy conservation; economical use of energy; energy-saving" },
	{ "question": "省令", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "ministerial ordinance" },
	{ "question": "省力", "answers": [ "しょうりょく" ], "comment": "labor saving; labour saving" },
	{ "question": "省庁", "answers": [ "しょうちょう" ], "comment": "ministries and government offices; the authorities" },
	{ "question": "省略", "answers": [ "しょうりゃく" ], "comment": "omission; abbreviation; abridgment; abridgement" },
	{ "question": "眉", "answers": [ "まゆ" ], "comment": "eyebrow; eyebrows" },
	{ "question": "眉毛", "answers": [ "まゆげ" ], "comment": "eyebrows" },
	{ "question": "看る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "to look after (often medically); to take care of" },
	{ "question": "看板", "answers": [ "かんばん" ], "comment": "signboard; sign; billboard; hoarding; doorplate\ndraw; attraction; feature; highlight; spokesman; figurehead\nreputation (of a shop)\nappearance; look\nclosing time" },
	{ "question": "看病", "answers": [ "かんびょう" ], "comment": "nursing (a patient)" },
	{ "question": "看護", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "nursing; (army) nurse" },
	{ "question": "看護婦", "answers": [ "かんごふ" ], "comment": "(female) nurse" },
	{ "question": "看護師", "answers": [ "かんごし" ], "comment": "(hospital) nurse; registered nurse; RN" },
	{ "question": "看過", "answers": [ "かんか" ], "comment": "overlooking; turning a blind eye" },
	{ "question": "県", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "prefecture (of Japan)\ncounty (of China)" },
	{ "question": "県下", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "in the prefecture; prefectural" },
	{ "question": "県内", "answers": [ "けんない" ], "comment": "within the prefecture" },
	{ "question": "県営", "answers": [ "けんえい" ], "comment": "prefectural; under prefectural management" },
	{ "question": "県外", "answers": [ "けんがい" ], "comment": "outside the prefecture" },
	{ "question": "県庁", "answers": [ "けんちょう" ], "comment": "prefectural office" },
	{ "question": "県民", "answers": [ "けんみん" ], "comment": "citizen of a prefecture; prefectural citizen" },
	{ "question": "県知事", "answers": [ "けんちじ" ], "comment": "prefectural governor" },
	{ "question": "県立", "answers": [ "けんりつ" ], "comment": "prefectural (institution)" },
	{ "question": "県警", "answers": [ "けんけい" ], "comment": "prefectural police" },
	{ "question": "県議", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "prefectural assembly" },
	{ "question": "県道", "answers": [ "けんどう" ], "comment": "prefectural road" },
	{ "question": "真", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "truth; reality; genuineness\nseriousness\nlogical TRUE\nprinted style writing\nstar performer" },
	{ "question": "真っ二つ", "answers": [ "まっぷたつ" ], "comment": "in two equal parts" },
	{ "question": "真っ先", "answers": [ "まっさき" ], "comment": "the head; the foremost; beginning; the very front" },
	{ "question": "真っ向", "answers": [ "まっこう" ], "comment": "directly opposite; right in front\nmiddle of the forehead\nhelmet front" },
	{ "question": "真っ暗", "answers": [ "まっくら" ], "comment": "total darkness; pitch dark\nbleak future; poor prospects" },
	{ "question": "真っ最中", "answers": [ "まっさいちゅう" ], "comment": "midst; middle of; height of" },
	{ "question": "真っ白", "answers": [ "まっしろ" ], "comment": "pure white\nblank (e.g. mind, paper)" },
	{ "question": "真っ赤", "answers": [ "まっか" ], "comment": "bright red; deep red; flushed (of face)\ndownright (e.g. lie); complete; utter" },
	{ "question": "真っ青", "answers": [ "まっさお" ], "comment": "deep blue; bright blue\nghastly pale; pallid; white as a sheet" },
	{ "question": "真っ黒", "answers": [ "まっくろ" ], "comment": "pitch black" },
	{ "question": "真の", "answers": [ "しんの" ], "comment": "true; real; genuine; proper; utter" },
	{ "question": "真ん中", "answers": [ "まなか", "まんなか" ], "comment": "middle; centre; center; mid-way" },
	{ "question": "真ん丸", "answers": [ "まんまる" ], "comment": "perfect circle\ncute" },
	{ "question": "真上", "answers": [ "まうえ" ], "comment": "just above; right overhead" },
	{ "question": "真似", "answers": [ "まね" ], "comment": "imitating; copying; mimicry\nbehavior; behaviour; action; conduct" },
	{ "question": "真似る", "answers": [ "まねる" ], "comment": "to mimic; to imitate" },
	{ "question": "真価", "answers": [ "しんか" ], "comment": "true value; real worth" },
	{ "question": "真偽", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "truth or error; authenticity; veracity" },
	{ "question": "真剣", "answers": [ "しんけん" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness\nreal sword (as opposed to unsharpened or wooden practice weapon)" },
	{ "question": "真四角", "answers": [ "ましかく" ], "comment": "square" },
	{ "question": "真夏", "answers": [ "まなつ" ], "comment": "midsummer" },
	{ "question": "真夜中", "answers": [ "まよなか" ], "comment": "dead of night; midnight" },
	{ "question": "真実", "answers": [ "さね", "しんじつ", "さな" ], "comment": "truth; reality" },
	{ "question": "真心", "answers": [ "まこころ", "まごころ" ], "comment": "sincerity; devotion" },
	{ "question": "真意", "answers": [ "しんい" ], "comment": "real intention; true motive; true meaning" },
	{ "question": "真摯", "answers": [ "しんし" ], "comment": "sincere; earnest" },
	{ "question": "真新しい", "answers": [ "まあたらしい" ], "comment": "brand new" },
	{ "question": "真正面", "answers": [ "ましょうめん" ], "comment": "directly opposite; right in front" },
	{ "question": "真珠", "answers": [ "しんじゅ" ], "comment": "pearl" },
	{ "question": "真理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "truth" },
	{ "question": "真相", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "truth; real situation" },
	{ "question": "真空", "answers": [ "しんくう" ], "comment": "vacuum; hollow; empty" },
	{ "question": "真面目", "answers": [ "まじめ" ], "comment": "diligent; serious; honest; sober; grave; earnest; steady" },
	{ "question": "真顔", "answers": [ "まがお" ], "comment": "serious look" },
	{ "question": "真髄", "answers": [ "しんずい" ], "comment": "essence; quintessence; spirit; soul; heart; pith; pith and marrow" },
	{ "question": "眠い", "answers": [ "ねむい" ], "comment": "sleepy; drowsy; somnolent" },
	{ "question": "眠たい", "answers": [ "ねぶたい", "ねむたい" ], "comment": "sleepy; drowsy" },
	{ "question": "眠り", "answers": [ "ねむり" ], "comment": "sleep; sleeping\ninactivity\ndeath" },
	{ "question": "眠る", "answers": [ "ねむる" ], "comment": "to sleep (not necessarily lying down)\nto die\nto lie idle (e.g. of resources); to be dormant; to be unused\nto close one's eyes" },
	{ "question": "眠気", "answers": [ "ねむけ" ], "comment": "sleepiness; drowsiness" },
	{ "question": "眩しい", "answers": [ "まぶしい", "まぼしい" ], "comment": "dazzling; radiant" },
	{ "question": "眺め", "answers": [ "ながめ" ], "comment": "scene; view; prospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "眺める", "answers": [ "ながめる" ], "comment": "to view; to gaze at" },
	{ "question": "眼", "answers": [ "め", "まなこ" ], "comment": "eye; eyeball\neyesight; sight; vision\nlook; stare; glance\nan experience\nviewpoint\nstitch; texture; weave\nordinal number suffix\nsomewhat; -ish /\n eye; eyeball\npupil and (dark) iris of the eye\ninsight; perceptivity; power of observation\nlook; field of vision\ncore; center; centre; essence" },
	{ "question": "眼差し", "answers": [ "まなざし" ], "comment": "(a) look; gaze" },
	{ "question": "眼科", "answers": [ "がんか" ], "comment": "ophthalmology" },
	{ "question": "眼鏡", "answers": [ "めがね", "がんきょう" ], "comment": "spectacles; glasses\njudgement; discrimination; discernment; insight" },
	{ "question": "着", "answers": [ "ちゃく" ], "comment": "counter for suits of clothing\narriving at ..." },
	{ "question": "着々", "answers": [ "ちゃくちゃく" ], "comment": "steadily" },
	{ "question": "着く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to arrive at; to reach\nto sit on; to sit at (e.g. the table)" },
	{ "question": "着ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment)\nto furnish (a house with)\nto wear; to put on\nto keep a diary; to make an entry\nto appraise; to set (a price)\nto allot; to budget; to assign\nto bring alongside\nto place (under guard or doctor)\nto follow; to shadow\nto load; to give (courage to)\nto keep (an eye on)\nto establish (relations or understanding)\nto turn on (light)\nto produce flowers; to produce fruit" },
	{ "question": "着せる", "answers": [ "きせる" ], "comment": "to put clothes on (someone)\nto plate; to gild; to veneer\nto accuse (of some crime); to give (a bad name)" },
	{ "question": "着る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down); to put on\nto bear (guilt, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "着地", "answers": [ "ちゃくち" ], "comment": "landing" },
	{ "question": "着実", "answers": [ "ちゃくじつ" ], "comment": "steady; sound; trustworthy; solid" },
	{ "question": "着工", "answers": [ "ちゃっこう" ], "comment": "start of (construction) work" },
	{ "question": "着席", "answers": [ "ちゃくせき" ], "comment": "sit down; seat" },
	{ "question": "着手", "answers": [ "ちゃくしゅ" ], "comment": "to start work (on); to undertake\nembarkation; launch" },
	{ "question": "着替え", "answers": [ "きがえ" ], "comment": "changing clothes; change of clothes" },
	{ "question": "着替える", "answers": [ "きかえる", "きがえる" ], "comment": "to change one's clothes" },
	{ "question": "着物", "answers": [ "きもの" ], "comment": "clothing; clothes\nkimono (or other trad. Japanese clothing)" },
	{ "question": "着用", "answers": [ "ちゃくよう" ], "comment": "wearing (e.g. uniform, seat belt); having on" },
	{ "question": "着目", "answers": [ "ちゃくもく" ], "comment": "attention; giving one's attention; focusing" },
	{ "question": "着色", "answers": [ "ちゃくしょく" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colorant" },
	{ "question": "着衣", "answers": [ "ちゃくい" ], "comment": "one's clothes; wearing clothes" },
	{ "question": "着陸", "answers": [ "ちゃくりく" ], "comment": "landing; alighting; touch down" },
	{ "question": "着飾る", "answers": [ "きかざる" ], "comment": "to dress up" },
	{ "question": "睡眠", "answers": [ "すいみん" ], "comment": "sleep" },
	{ "question": "督促", "answers": [ "とくそく" ], "comment": "urge; demand; importunity" },
	{ "question": "瞬く", "answers": [ "またたく", "まだたく", "まばたく", "めばたく", "しばたたく", "しばだたく", "しばたく" ], "comment": "to blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat\nto twinkle (e.g. stars); to flicker; to waver /\n to blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat" },
	{ "question": "瞬時", "answers": [ "しゅんじ" ], "comment": "moment; instant" },
	{ "question": "瞬間", "answers": [ "しゅんかん" ], "comment": "moment; second; instant" },
	{ "question": "瞳", "answers": [ "ひとみ" ], "comment": "pupil (of eye)\neye" },
	{ "question": "矛先", "answers": [ "ほこさき" ], "comment": "point of spear; spearhead\nbrunt; aim of attack; force of argument" },
	{ "question": "矛盾", "answers": [ "むじゅん" ], "comment": "contradiction; inconsistency" },
	{ "question": "矢", "answers": [ "や" ], "comment": "arrow\nwedge; chock" },
	{ "question": "矢先", "answers": [ "やさき" ], "comment": "arrowhead; brunt; target\nbeing about to; being on the point of" },
	{ "question": "矢印", "answers": [ "やじるし" ], "comment": "arrow (mark or symbol); directional marker or indicator" },
	{ "question": "知ってのとおり", "answers": [ "しってのとおり" ], "comment": "as we know" },
	{ "question": "知っての通り", "answers": [ "しってのとおり" ], "comment": "as we know" },
	{ "question": "知らず知らず", "answers": [ "しらずしらず" ], "comment": "unconsciously; unwittingly; unawares" },
	{ "question": "知らせ", "answers": [ "しらせ" ], "comment": "news; word; tidings; notice; notification; information\nomen" },
	{ "question": "知らせる", "answers": [ "しらせる" ], "comment": "to notify; to advise; to inform" },
	{ "question": "知らないうちに", "answers": [ "しらないうちに" ], "comment": "before one knew it; before one realized it" },
	{ "question": "知らん顔", "answers": [ "しらんかお" ], "comment": "unconcerned air; indifference; feigned ignorance; pretending not to recognize (somebody)" },
	{ "question": "知り合い", "answers": [ "しりあい" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知り合う", "answers": [ "しりあう" ], "comment": "to get to know (someone); to make acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知る", "answers": [ "しる" ], "comment": "to be aware of; to know; to be conscious of; to cognize; to cognise\nto notice; to feel\nto understand; to comprehend; to grasp\nto remember; to be acquainted with (a procedure)\nto experience; to go through; to learn\nto be acquainted with (a person); to get to know\nto concern" },
	{ "question": "知れる", "answers": [ "しれる" ], "comment": "to become known; to come to light; to be discovered\nto be known; to be understood\nto obviously not amount to much; to seem trivial\nto be evident; to be obvious; to go without saying\nto be very intense (worry, hope, etc.); to be extremely severe" },
	{ "question": "知事", "answers": [ "ちじ" ], "comment": "prefectural governor" },
	{ "question": "知人", "answers": [ "ちじん" ], "comment": "friend; acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知合い", "answers": [ "しりあい" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知合う", "answers": [ "しりあう" ], "comment": "to get to know (someone); to make acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知名", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "well-known" },
	{ "question": "知性", "answers": [ "ちせい" ], "comment": "intelligence" },
	{ "question": "知恵", "answers": [ "ちえ" ], "comment": "wisdom; wit; sagacity; sense; intelligence\nprajna (insight leading to enlightenment)" },
	{ "question": "知的", "answers": [ "ちてき" ], "comment": "intellectual" },
	{ "question": "知能", "answers": [ "ちのう" ], "comment": "intelligence; intellect; brains" },
	{ "question": "知覚", "answers": [ "ちかく" ], "comment": "perception" },
	{ "question": "知識", "answers": [ "ちしき" ], "comment": "knowledge; information" },
	{ "question": "知識人", "answers": [ "ちしきじん" ], "comment": "intellectual" },
	{ "question": "短い", "answers": [ "みじかい" ], "comment": "short" },
	{ "question": "短め", "answers": [ "みじかめ" ], "comment": "rather short; somewhat short" },
	{ "question": "短命", "answers": [ "たんめい" ], "comment": "short life; short lived" },
	{ "question": "短大", "answers": [ "たんだい" ], "comment": "junior college; vocationally oriented two or three year post-secondary education institution" },
	{ "question": "短所", "answers": [ "たんしょ" ], "comment": "defect; demerit; weak point; disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "短時間", "answers": [ "たんじかん" ], "comment": "short time" },
	{ "question": "短期", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "short-term" },
	{ "question": "短期大学", "answers": [ "たんきだいがく" ], "comment": "junior college; vocationally oriented two or three year post-secondary education institution" },
	{ "question": "短期間", "answers": [ "たんきかん" ], "comment": "short term; short time" },
	{ "question": "短歌", "answers": [ "たんか", "みじかうた" ], "comment": "tanka; 31-mora Japanese poem" },
	{ "question": "短気", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "quick temper; short temper" },
	{ "question": "短絡", "answers": [ "たんらく" ], "comment": "electric short-circuit\ndrawing a hasty inference between two events; jumping to a quick conclusion; dealing with matters quickly and carelessly" },
	{ "question": "短編", "answers": [ "たんぺん" ], "comment": "short (e.g. story, film)" },
	{ "question": "短縮", "answers": [ "たんしゅく" ], "comment": "shortening; contraction; reduction; curtailment; abbreviation" },
	{ "question": "短調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "minor key" },
	{ "question": "短距離", "answers": [ "たんきょり" ], "comment": "short distance; short range; short-haul" },
	{ "question": "短銃", "answers": [ "たんじゅう" ], "comment": "pistol; revolver" },
	{ "question": "矯正", "answers": [ "きょうせい" ], "comment": "correction (of fault, defect, flaw, etc.); remedy; rectification; redress; reform" },
	{ "question": "石", "answers": [ "いし", "こく" ], "comment": "stone\ngem; jewel /\n measure of volume (approx. 180.39 liters, 6.37 cub. ft.)\nmeasure of a Japanese-style boat's loading capacity (approx. 278.26 liters)" },
	{ "question": "石器", "answers": [ "せっき" ], "comment": "stone implement (e.g. stone age arrowheads); stone tool" },
	{ "question": "石垣", "answers": [ "いしがけ", "いしがき" ], "comment": "stone wall" },
	{ "question": "石室", "answers": [ "せきしつ", "いしむろ" ], "comment": "stone hut; rock chamber\ntomb; stone burial chamber" },
	{ "question": "石材", "answers": [ "せきざい" ], "comment": "(building) stone" },
	{ "question": "石橋", "answers": [ "いしばし", "せっきょう" ], "comment": "stone bridge" },
	{ "question": "石油", "answers": [ "せきゆ" ], "comment": "oil; petroleum; kerosene" },
	{ "question": "石灰", "answers": [ "いしばい", "せっかい" ], "comment": "lime; quicklime; caustic lime" },
	{ "question": "石炭", "answers": [ "せきたん" ], "comment": "coal" },
	{ "question": "石神", "answers": [ "しゃくじん", "いしがみ" ], "comment": "stone which is worshipped; image of a god in stone" },
	{ "question": "石頭", "answers": [ "いしあたま" ], "comment": "inflexible person" },
	{ "question": "石鹸", "answers": [ "せっけん" ], "comment": "soap" },
	{ "question": "砂", "answers": [ "すな", "いさご", "すなご" ], "comment": "sand; grit\ngold dust; silver dust" },
	{ "question": "砂利", "answers": [ "じゃり", "ざり" ], "comment": "gravel; ballast; pebbles\nchild; rugrat; ankle-biter" },
	{ "question": "砂浜", "answers": [ "すなはま" ], "comment": "sandy beach" },
	{ "question": "砂漠", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "desert" },
	{ "question": "砂糖", "answers": [ "さとう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "砂防", "answers": [ "さぼう" ], "comment": "erosion control" },
	{ "question": "研ぐ", "answers": [ "とぐ" ], "comment": "to sharpen; to hone; to whet; to grind\nto wash (rice)\nto scour; to polish; to burnish" },
	{ "question": "研修", "answers": [ "けんしゅう" ], "comment": "training (esp. in-service); induction course" },
	{ "question": "研究", "answers": [ "けんきゅう" ], "comment": "study; research; investigation" },
	{ "question": "研究員", "answers": [ "けんきゅういん" ], "comment": "researcher; lab worker" },
	{ "question": "研究官", "answers": [ "けんきゅうかん" ], "comment": "research officer" },
	{ "question": "研究室", "answers": [ "けんきゅうしつ" ], "comment": "laboratory\nseminar room\nprofessor's office" },
	{ "question": "研究家", "answers": [ "けんきゅうか" ], "comment": "researcher; student (of)" },
	{ "question": "研究所", "answers": [ "けんきゅうじょ", "けんきゅうしょ" ], "comment": "research establishment; research institute; laboratory" },
	{ "question": "研究結果", "answers": [ "けんきゅうけっか" ], "comment": "results of a scientific investigation; findings" },
	{ "question": "研究者", "answers": [ "けんきゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "researcher" },
	{ "question": "砕く", "answers": [ "くだく" ], "comment": "to break; to smash" },
	{ "question": "砕ける", "answers": [ "くだける" ], "comment": "to break (into pieces); to be broken; to be smashed\nto collapse; to crumble; to decline; to cool (e.g. enthusiasm); to dampen (e.g. one's will to fight)\nto become less formal; to throw off reserve; to become affable\nto become easy to understand (e.g. a story)\nto be worried" },
	{ "question": "砲", "answers": [ "ほう" ], "comment": "gun; cannon; artillery; ordnance" },
	{ "question": "砲弾", "answers": [ "ほうだん" ], "comment": "shell; cannonball" },
	{ "question": "砲撃", "answers": [ "ほうげき" ], "comment": "bombarding; shelling; bombardment" },
	{ "question": "砲火", "answers": [ "ほうか" ], "comment": "gunfire; fire" },
	{ "question": "破り", "answers": [ "やぶり" ], "comment": "getting away from; escaping; defying" },
	{ "question": "破る", "answers": [ "やぶる" ], "comment": "to tear; to break; to destroy\nto break through (opponent's defense etc.); to breach\nto defeat; to beat\nto shatter (dream, peace, etc.); to disturb\nto violate (a rule etc.); to break (a promise etc.)\nto break (a record)" },
	{ "question": "破れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "to get torn; to tear; to rip; to break; to wear out\nto be broken off (of negotiations, etc.); to break down; to collapse; to fall into ruin" },
	{ "question": "破壊", "answers": [ "はかい" ], "comment": "destruction; disruption\n(application) crash" },
	{ "question": "破局", "answers": [ "はきょく" ], "comment": "catastrophe; cataclysm; collapse (of a relationship); breakup; split (friends, lovers, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "破損", "answers": [ "はそん" ], "comment": "damage" },
	{ "question": "破格", "answers": [ "はかく" ], "comment": "extraordinary; special; exceptional; abnormal; unprecedented\nnon-standard grammatical construction; ungrammatical usage; solecism" },
	{ "question": "破棄", "answers": [ "はき" ], "comment": "tearing up and discarding (e.g. documents); disposal (e.g. weaponry); destruction\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; voiding; breaking (e.g. treaty)\nreversal (of an original ruling)" },
	{ "question": "破滅", "answers": [ "はめつ" ], "comment": "ruin; destruction; fall" },
	{ "question": "破片", "answers": [ "はへん" ], "comment": "fragment; broken piece; splinter; chip; shard" },
	{ "question": "破産", "answers": [ "はさん" ], "comment": "bankruptcy; insolvency" },
	{ "question": "破綻", "answers": [ "はたん" ], "comment": "failure; bankruptcy" },
	{ "question": "破裂", "answers": [ "はれつ" ], "comment": "explosion; rupture; break off" },
	{ "question": "硫黄", "answers": [ "いおう", "ゆおう" ], "comment": "sulfur (S); sulphur" },
	{ "question": "硬い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "hard; solid; tough\nstiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing)\nstrong; firm (not viscous or easily moved)\nsafe; steady; honest; steadfast\nobstinate; stubborn\nbookish; formal; stuffy" },
	{ "question": "硬さ", "answers": [ "かたさ" ], "comment": "firmness; hardness; stiffness; honesty" },
	{ "question": "硬化", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "hardening; vulcanization; vulcanisation; sclerosis; curing" },
	{ "question": "硬式", "answers": [ "こうしき" ], "comment": "hard (esp. of hardball, tennis, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "硬派", "answers": [ "こうは" ], "comment": "tough elements; hard-liners; stalwarts; diehards; hawks\nconsidering association with women and interest in fashion as weakness and focusing on strength and manliness; young tough; young rowdy\nhard (news); hard news reporter\nstrait-laced (person); straight-laced; overly serious regarding relations between men and women\nbullish traders" },
	{ "question": "硬直", "answers": [ "こうちょく" ], "comment": "stiffening; rigidity; rigor; stiffness; ossification; petrification" },
	{ "question": "硬貨", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "coin\nhard currency" },
	{ "question": "碁", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "go (board game of capturing territory)" },
	{ "question": "碁会所", "answers": [ "ごかいじょ", "ごかいしょ" ], "comment": "commercial go-playing parlour (parlor)" },
	{ "question": "碑", "answers": [ "ひ", "いしぶみ" ], "comment": "stone monument bearing an inscription (esp. memorial for future generations); stele; stela" },
	{ "question": "碑文", "answers": [ "ひぶん" ], "comment": "inscription; epitaph; epigraph" },
	{ "question": "確か", "answers": [ "たしか" ], "comment": "sure; certain; positive; definite\nreliable; trustworthy; safe; sound; firm; accurate; correct; exact\nIf I'm not mistaken; If I remember correctly; If I remember rightly" },
	{ "question": "確かめる", "answers": [ "たしかめる" ], "comment": "to ascertain; to check; to make sure" },
	{ "question": "確乎", "answers": [ "かっこ" ], "comment": "firm; unshakeable; resolute" },
	{ "question": "確保", "answers": [ "かくほ" ], "comment": "guarantee; maintain; ensure; insure; secure; reservation" },
	{ "question": "確信", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "conviction; belief; confidence" },
	{ "question": "確固", "answers": [ "かっこ" ], "comment": "firm; unshakeable; resolute" },
	{ "question": "確執", "answers": [ "かくしつ" ], "comment": "discord; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "確定", "answers": [ "かくてい" ], "comment": "decision; settlement\ndefinition" },
	{ "question": "確実", "answers": [ "かくじつ" ], "comment": "certainty; reliability; soundness" },
	{ "question": "確率", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "probability; likelihood; chances" },
	{ "question": "確立", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; settlement\nto establish; to settle" },
	{ "question": "確約", "answers": [ "かくやく" ], "comment": "firm promise; definite promise" },
	{ "question": "確認", "answers": [ "かくにん" ], "comment": "confirmation; verification; validation; review; check; affirmation; identification" },
	{ "question": "磁場", "answers": [ "じば", "じじょう" ], "comment": "magnetic field\nambience; atmosphere; focal point" },
	{ "question": "磁気", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "magnetism" },
	{ "question": "磁石", "answers": [ "じしゃく", "じせき" ], "comment": "magnet\ncompass" },
	{ "question": "磨き", "answers": [ "みがき" ], "comment": "polish; improvement; burnishing" },
	{ "question": "磨く", "answers": [ "みがく" ], "comment": "to polish; to shine; to brush (e.g. teeth)\nto refine; to improve" },
	{ "question": "磯", "answers": [ "いそ" ], "comment": "(rocky) beach; seashore" },
	{ "question": "礎", "answers": [ "いしずえ" ], "comment": "foundation stone; cornerstone" },
	{ "question": "示し", "answers": [ "しめし" ], "comment": "discipline; revelation" },
	{ "question": "示す", "answers": [ "しめす" ], "comment": "to (take out and) show; to demonstrate; to tell; to exemplify; to make apparent\nto point out (finger, clock hand, needle, etc.)\nto indicate; to show; to represent; to signify; to display" },
	{ "question": "示唆", "answers": [ "しさ" ], "comment": "suggestion; hint; implication" },
	{ "question": "示談", "answers": [ "じだん" ], "comment": "settlement out of court" },
	{ "question": "礼", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "thanks; gratitude\nmanners; etiquette\nbow\nreward; gift\nceremony; ritual" },
	{ "question": "礼儀", "answers": [ "れいぎ" ], "comment": "manners; courtesy; etiquette" },
	{ "question": "礼拝", "answers": [ "れいはい", "らいはい" ], "comment": "worship (esp. Christian); adoration; divine service\nworship (esp. Buddhist and Shinto)" },
	{ "question": "礼服", "answers": [ "れいふく" ], "comment": "ceremonial dress; evening dress; dress suit; morning suit" },
	{ "question": "礼状", "answers": [ "れいじょう" ], "comment": "acknowledgment; acknowledgement; letter of thanks" },
	{ "question": "礼金", "answers": [ "れいきん" ], "comment": "finder's fee; reward; honorarium\nkey money" },
	{ "question": "社交", "answers": [ "しゃこう" ], "comment": "social life; social intercourse" },
	{ "question": "社交的", "answers": [ "しゃこうてき" ], "comment": "sociable" },
	{ "question": "社会", "answers": [ "しゃかい" ], "comment": "society; public; community; the world\nsocial studies" },
	{ "question": "社会主義", "answers": [ "しゃかいしゅぎ" ], "comment": "socialism" },
	{ "question": "社会事業", "answers": [ "しゃかいじぎょう" ], "comment": "social work" },
	{ "question": "社会人", "answers": [ "しゃかいじん" ], "comment": "working adult; full-fledged member of society" },
	{ "question": "社会保険", "answers": [ "しゃかいほけん" ], "comment": "social insurance" },
	{ "question": "社会保険庁", "answers": [ "しゃかいほけんちょう" ], "comment": "Social Insurance Agency" },
	{ "question": "社会保障", "answers": [ "しゃかいほしょう" ], "comment": "social security" },
	{ "question": "社会党", "answers": [ "しゃかいとう" ], "comment": "Socialist Party" },
	{ "question": "社会問題", "answers": [ "しゃかいもんだい" ], "comment": "social problem" },
	{ "question": "社会学", "answers": [ "しゃかいがく" ], "comment": "sociology" },
	{ "question": "社会復帰", "answers": [ "しゃかいふっき" ], "comment": "rehabilitation (in society)" },
	{ "question": "社会性", "answers": [ "しゃかいせい" ], "comment": "sociality" },
	{ "question": "社会教育", "answers": [ "しゃかいきょういく" ], "comment": "social education" },
	{ "question": "社会的", "answers": [ "しゃかいてき" ], "comment": "social" },
	{ "question": "社会福祉", "answers": [ "しゃかいふくし" ], "comment": "social welfare" },
	{ "question": "社会科", "answers": [ "しゃかいか" ], "comment": "social studies" },
	{ "question": "社会科学", "answers": [ "しゃかいかがく" ], "comment": "social science" },
	{ "question": "社会資本", "answers": [ "しゃかいしほん" ], "comment": "social capital; SOC" },
	{ "question": "社会運動", "answers": [ "しゃかいうんどう" ], "comment": "social movement" },
	{ "question": "社会面", "answers": [ "しゃかいめん" ], "comment": "social page (of newspaper); local news page" },
	{ "question": "社債", "answers": [ "しゃさい" ], "comment": "corporate bond; corporate debenture" },
	{ "question": "社内", "answers": [ "しゃない" ], "comment": "within a company; in-house" },
	{ "question": "社名", "answers": [ "しゃめい" ], "comment": "name of company" },
	{ "question": "社告", "answers": [ "しゃこく" ], "comment": "(company) announcement" },
	{ "question": "社員", "answers": [ "しゃいん" ], "comment": "company employee\ncompany stockholders (esp. in legal contexts); members of a corporation" },
	{ "question": "社団法人", "answers": [ "しゃだんほうじん" ], "comment": "corporate juridical person; incorporated body; corporation" },
	{ "question": "社外", "answers": [ "しゃがい" ], "comment": "outside the company" },
	{ "question": "社宅", "answers": [ "しゃたく" ], "comment": "company owned house" },
	{ "question": "社屋", "answers": [ "しゃおく" ], "comment": "company office building" },
	{ "question": "社民党", "answers": [ "しゃみんとう" ], "comment": "Social Democratic Party" },
	{ "question": "社葬", "answers": [ "しゃそう" ], "comment": "company funeral" },
	{ "question": "社説", "answers": [ "しゃせつ" ], "comment": "editorial; leading article" },
	{ "question": "社長", "answers": [ "しゃちょう" ], "comment": "company president; manager; director" },
	{ "question": "祈り", "answers": [ "いのり" ], "comment": "prayer; supplication" },
	{ "question": "祈る", "answers": [ "いのる" ], "comment": "to pray; to wish" },
	{ "question": "祈念", "answers": [ "きねん" ], "comment": "prayer" },
	{ "question": "祈願", "answers": [ "きがん" ], "comment": "prayer; supplication" },
	{ "question": "祖", "answers": [ "そ" ], "comment": "ancestor; forefather; progenitor" },
	{ "question": "祖先", "answers": [ "そせん" ], "comment": "ancestor" },
	{ "question": "祖国", "answers": [ "そこく" ], "comment": "motherland; fatherland; native country" },
	{ "question": "祖母", "answers": [ "うば", "そぼ", "ばば", "おば", "おおば" ], "comment": "grandmother" },
	{ "question": "祖父", "answers": [ "そふ", "じじ", "おじ", "じい", "おおじ" ], "comment": "grandfather\nold man\nkyogen mask used for the role of an old man" },
	{ "question": "祖父母", "answers": [ "そふぼ" ], "comment": "grandparents" },
	{ "question": "祝い", "answers": [ "いわい" ], "comment": "congratulation; congratulations; celebration; festival; congratulatory gift" },
	{ "question": "祝う", "answers": [ "いわう" ], "comment": "to congratulate; to celebrate; to observe (a festival)" },
	{ "question": "祝儀", "answers": [ "しゅうぎ" ], "comment": "celebration; celebratory event; wedding ceremony\ncongratulatory gift\ntip; gratuity" },
	{ "question": "祝日", "answers": [ "しゅくじつ" ], "comment": "national holiday; public holiday" },
	{ "question": "祝福", "answers": [ "しゅくふく" ], "comment": "blessing" },
	{ "question": "祝賀", "answers": [ "しゅくが" ], "comment": "celebration; congratulations" },
	{ "question": "祝辞", "answers": [ "しゅくじ" ], "comment": "congratulatory address" },
	{ "question": "祝電", "answers": [ "しゅくでん" ], "comment": "congratulatory telegram" },
	{ "question": "神", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "god; deity; divinity; spirit; kami\nincredible; fantastic\nemperor of Japan\nthunder" },
	{ "question": "神主", "answers": [ "かんぬし", "かむぬし" ], "comment": "Shinto priest\nchief Shinto priest (of a shrine)\nWelsh onion; pun in Buddhist monk jargon" },
	{ "question": "神妙", "answers": [ "しんみょう" ], "comment": "meek; quiet; docile; humble; faithful; obedient\nmysterious; marvelous; marvellous" },
	{ "question": "神学", "answers": [ "しんがく" ], "comment": "theology" },
	{ "question": "神宮", "answers": [ "じんぐう" ], "comment": "high-status Shinto shrine with connection to imperial family; imperial Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "神戸", "answers": [ "こうべ" ], "comment": "Kobe (port city near Osaka)" },
	{ "question": "神業", "answers": [ "かみわざ" ], "comment": "divine work; miracle; superhuman feat\nShinto ritual" },
	{ "question": "神楽", "answers": [ "かぐら" ], "comment": "ancient Shinto music and dancing" },
	{ "question": "神様", "answers": [ "かみさん", "かみさま" ], "comment": "God" },
	{ "question": "神殿", "answers": [ "しんでん" ], "comment": "temple; sacred place; shrine; sanctuary; tabernacle" },
	{ "question": "神父", "answers": [ "しんぷ" ], "comment": "Catholic priest; abbe; reverend father; minister; padre" },
	{ "question": "神社", "answers": [ "じんじゃ" ], "comment": "Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "神秘", "answers": [ "しんぴ" ], "comment": "mystery; mysteriousness; secret" },
	{ "question": "神経", "answers": [ "しんけい" ], "comment": "nerve\nnerves; sensitivity" },
	{ "question": "神経質", "answers": [ "しんけいしつ" ], "comment": "nervous; highly strung; sensitive\nfussy; worried about petty things" },
	{ "question": "神聖", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "holiness; sacredness; sanctity; dignity" },
	{ "question": "神話", "answers": [ "しんわ" ], "comment": "myth; legend" },
	{ "question": "神道", "answers": [ "しんどう", "しんとう" ], "comment": "Shinto; Shintoism" },
	{ "question": "神髄", "answers": [ "しんずい" ], "comment": "essence; quintessence; spirit; soul; heart; pith; pith and marrow" },
	{ "question": "票", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "vote; ballot\nlabel; ticket; tag; stub" },
	{ "question": "票田", "answers": [ "ひょうでん" ], "comment": "(favorable voting) constituency (favourable)" },
	{ "question": "祭", "answers": [ "まつり" ], "comment": "festival; feast" },
	{ "question": "祭り", "answers": [ "まつり" ], "comment": "festival; feast" },
	{ "question": "祭る", "answers": [ "まつる" ], "comment": "to deify; to enshrine\nto pray; to worship" },
	{ "question": "祭典", "answers": [ "さいてん" ], "comment": "festival" },
	{ "question": "祭壇", "answers": [ "さいだん" ], "comment": "altar" },
	{ "question": "祭日", "answers": [ "さいじつ" ], "comment": "national holiday; festival day" },
	{ "question": "禁じる", "answers": [ "きんじる" ], "comment": "to prohibit" },
	{ "question": "禁ずる", "answers": [ "きんずる" ], "comment": "to forbid; to suppress" },
	{ "question": "禁句", "answers": [ "きんく" ], "comment": "taboo word" },
	{ "question": "禁固", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "imprisonment; confinement" },
	{ "question": "禁欲的", "answers": [ "きんよくてき" ], "comment": "abstemious; austere" },
	{ "question": "禁止", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "prohibition; inhibition; ban" },
	{ "question": "禁止事項", "answers": [ "きんしじこう" ], "comment": "prohibited item; banned item" },
	{ "question": "禁止法", "answers": [ "きんしほう" ], "comment": "negative statute; law against something" },
	{ "question": "禁煙", "answers": [ "きんえん" ], "comment": "abstaining from smoking; quitting smoking\nNo Smoking!; Smoking Prohibited!" },
	{ "question": "禁物", "answers": [ "きんもつ" ], "comment": "taboo; forbidden thing" },
	{ "question": "禁輸", "answers": [ "きんゆ" ], "comment": "embargo" },
	{ "question": "禁酒", "answers": [ "きんしゅ" ], "comment": "prohibition; temperance; abstinence" },
	{ "question": "禅", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "dhyana (profound meditation)\nZen (Buddhism)" },
	{ "question": "禅寺", "answers": [ "ぜんでら" ], "comment": "Zen temple" },
	{ "question": "福", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "good fortune" },
	{ "question": "福利厚生", "answers": [ "ふくりこうせい" ], "comment": "welfare program; welfare programme" },
	{ "question": "福助", "answers": [ "ふくすけ" ], "comment": "large-headed dwarf statue, bringer of good luck" },
	{ "question": "福祉", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "welfare; well-being; social welfare; social security; social service" },
	{ "question": "秀作", "answers": [ "しゅうさく" ], "comment": "splendid (excellent) work" },
	{ "question": "秀才", "answers": [ "しゅうさい" ], "comment": "bright person; talented student; prodigy" },
	{ "question": "私", "answers": [ "わたくし", "わたし" ], "comment": "I; me\nprivate affairs; personal matter; secrecy\nselfishness" },
	{ "question": "私たち", "answers": [ "わたしたち", "わたくしたち" ], "comment": "we; us" },
	{ "question": "私企業", "answers": [ "しきぎょう" ], "comment": "private enterprise" },
	{ "question": "私大", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "private university or college" },
	{ "question": "私学", "answers": [ "しがく" ], "comment": "private (non-governmental) school (college, university)" },
	{ "question": "私文書", "answers": [ "しぶんしょ" ], "comment": "private document" },
	{ "question": "私書箱", "answers": [ "ししょばこ" ], "comment": "post office box" },
	{ "question": "私有", "answers": [ "しゆう" ], "comment": "private ownership" },
	{ "question": "私服", "answers": [ "しふく" ], "comment": "civilian clothes; plain clothes; mufti\nplainclothes police officer" },
	{ "question": "私案", "answers": [ "しあん" ], "comment": "private plan; one's own plan" },
	{ "question": "私生活", "answers": [ "しせいかつ" ], "comment": "one's private life" },
	{ "question": "私用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "personal use\nprivate business" },
	{ "question": "私的", "answers": [ "してき" ], "comment": "personal; private; proprietary" },
	{ "question": "私立", "answers": [ "わたくしりつ", "しりつ" ], "comment": "private (establishment)" },
	{ "question": "私見", "answers": [ "しけん" ], "comment": "personal opinion" },
	{ "question": "私設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "private" },
	{ "question": "私語", "answers": [ "しご" ], "comment": "whispering; whisper; secret talk; murmur" },
	{ "question": "私費", "answers": [ "しひ" ], "comment": "private expense" },
	{ "question": "私達", "answers": [ "わたしたち", "わたくしたち" ], "comment": "we; us" },
	{ "question": "私邸", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "private residence" },
	{ "question": "私鉄", "answers": [ "してつ" ], "comment": "private railway" },
	{ "question": "秋", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "autumn; fall" },
	{ "question": "秋分", "answers": [ "しゅうぶん" ], "comment": "autumnal equinox; autumn equinox; fall equinox" },
	{ "question": "秋口", "answers": [ "あきぐち" ], "comment": "beginning of autumn; beginning of fall" },
	{ "question": "秋季", "answers": [ "しゅうき" ], "comment": "fall season; autumn season" },
	{ "question": "秋風", "answers": [ "しゅうふう", "あきかぜ" ], "comment": "autumn breeze; fall breeze" },
	{ "question": "科", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "department; section; faculty; school; arm\ncourse (of study); branch of study; specialization\n(taxonomical) family" },
	{ "question": "科する", "answers": [ "かする" ], "comment": "to inflict; to impose (a fine, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "科学", "answers": [ "かがく" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "科学技術", "answers": [ "かがくぎじゅつ" ], "comment": "science and technology\nscientific technique" },
	{ "question": "科学技術庁", "answers": [ "かがくぎじゅつちょう" ], "comment": "Science and Technology Agency" },
	{ "question": "科学者", "answers": [ "かがくしゃ" ], "comment": "scientist" },
	{ "question": "科目", "answers": [ "かもく" ], "comment": "(school) subject; curriculum; course" },
	{ "question": "秒", "answers": [ "びょう" ], "comment": "second (60th min)" },
	{ "question": "秒読み", "answers": [ "びょうよみ" ], "comment": "countdown" },
	{ "question": "秒速", "answers": [ "びょうそく" ], "comment": "per second" },
	{ "question": "秘める", "answers": [ "ひめる" ], "comment": "to hide; to keep to oneself" },
	{ "question": "秘密", "answers": [ "ひみつ" ], "comment": "secret; secrecy; confidentiality; privacy\nsecret; mystery\nesoteric teachings" },
	{ "question": "秘書", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "(private) secretary\ntreasured book; secret book" },
	{ "question": "秘訣", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "secret (method, trick, etc.); mysteries (of an art, trade, etc.); key (e.g. to success); recipe" },
	{ "question": "秘話", "answers": [ "ひわ" ], "comment": "secret story; unknown episode" },
	{ "question": "租税", "answers": [ "そぜい" ], "comment": "taxes; taxation" },
	{ "question": "秤", "answers": [ "はかり" ], "comment": "scales; weighing machine" },
	{ "question": "秩序", "answers": [ "ちつじょ" ], "comment": "order; regularity; system; method" },
	{ "question": "称する", "answers": [ "しょうする" ], "comment": "to take the name of; to call oneself\nto pretend; to feign; to purport" },
	{ "question": "称号", "answers": [ "しょうごう" ], "comment": "title; name; degree" },
	{ "question": "称賛", "answers": [ "しょうさん" ], "comment": "praise; admiration; commendation; approbation" },
	{ "question": "移す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to change; to swap; to substitute; to transfer\nto change the object of one's interest or focus\nto spend or take time\nto infect\nto permeate something with the smell or colour of something\nto move on to the next or different stage of (a plan, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "移り変わり", "answers": [ "うつりかわり" ], "comment": "change (e.g. season)" },
	{ "question": "移住", "answers": [ "いじゅう" ], "comment": "migration; immigration" },
	{ "question": "移動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "movement; transfer; migration; removal; travel\nmobile; moving; traveling; travelling; roving" },
	{ "question": "移動平均", "answers": [ "いどうへいきん" ], "comment": "moving average" },
	{ "question": "移植", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "transplanting (plants, organs, culture, etc.); transplant; grafting\nporting (software)" },
	{ "question": "移民", "answers": [ "いみん" ], "comment": "emigration; immigration\nemigrant; immigrant" },
	{ "question": "移管", "answers": [ "いかん" ], "comment": "transfer of control" },
	{ "question": "移籍", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "changing household registry; transfer (e.g. of one's name in the register)\ntransferring to a different team" },
	{ "question": "移行", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "switching over to; migration; transition" },
	{ "question": "移譲", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "transfer; assignment" },
	{ "question": "移転", "answers": [ "いてん" ], "comment": "moving; relocation; change of address\ntransfer (of deeds, property, etc.); demise" },
	{ "question": "移送", "answers": [ "いそう" ], "comment": "transfer; transport; removal" },
	{ "question": "程度", "answers": [ "ていど" ], "comment": "degree; amount; grade; standard; of the order of (following a number); about; approximately" },
	{ "question": "税制", "answers": [ "ぜいせい" ], "comment": "tax system" },
	{ "question": "税務", "answers": [ "ぜいむ" ], "comment": "taxation business" },
	{ "question": "税務署", "answers": [ "ぜいむしょ" ], "comment": "tax office" },
	{ "question": "税収", "answers": [ "ぜいしゅう" ], "comment": "tax yields; revenue" },
	{ "question": "税引き", "answers": [ "ぜいびき" ], "comment": "tax excluded" },
	{ "question": "税法", "answers": [ "ぜいほう" ], "comment": "taxation law" },
	{ "question": "税率", "answers": [ "ぜいりつ" ], "comment": "tariff\ntax rate" },
	{ "question": "税理士", "answers": [ "ぜいりし" ], "comment": "tax counsellor; tax counselor; licensed tax accountant" },
	{ "question": "税込み", "answers": [ "ぜいこみ" ], "comment": "tax included (e.g. price); before tax (e.g. salary)" },
	{ "question": "税金", "answers": [ "ぜいきん" ], "comment": "tax; duty" },
	{ "question": "税関", "answers": [ "ぜいかん" ], "comment": "customs; customs house" },
	{ "question": "税額", "answers": [ "ぜいがく" ], "comment": "amount of tax" },
	{ "question": "稚魚", "answers": [ "ちぎょ" ], "comment": "fry; juvenile fish; fingerling" },
	{ "question": "種", "answers": [ "たね" ], "comment": "seed (e.g. of a plant); pip; kind; variety; quality; tone\nmaterial (e.g. for an article); matter (e.g. of a story); subject; theme; (news) copy\ningredient; leaven (bread); main ingredient of a sushi\ncause; source\ntrick; secret; magician's trick; inside story\npaternal blood; lineage\nbreed (of a stock); sperm; semen" },
	{ "question": "種々", "answers": [ "しゅじゅ", "くさぐさ" ], "comment": "variety" },
	{ "question": "種別", "answers": [ "しゅべつ" ], "comment": "classification; assortment" },
	{ "question": "種子", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "seed; pit" },
	{ "question": "種目", "answers": [ "しゅもく" ], "comment": "event; item of business" },
	{ "question": "種類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "variety; kind; type; category\ncounter for different sorts of things" },
	{ "question": "種類豊富", "answers": [ "しゅるいほうふ" ], "comment": "rich in variety; diverse; wide-ranging; multifarious" },
	{ "question": "稲", "answers": [ "いね" ], "comment": "rice plant" },
	{ "question": "稲作", "answers": [ "いなさく" ], "comment": "rice cultivation; rice crop" },
	{ "question": "稲妻", "answers": [ "いなずま", "いなづま" ], "comment": "lightning; flash of lightning; lightning bolt" },
	{ "question": "稲田", "answers": [ "いなだ" ], "comment": "paddy field; rice field" },
	{ "question": "稼ぎ", "answers": [ "かせぎ" ], "comment": "earnings" },
	{ "question": "稼ぐ", "answers": [ "かせぐ" ], "comment": "to earn (income); to make (money)\nto score (points, victory); to gain (time); to play (for time)\nto work hard (at one's job); to labor; to labour; to toil" },
	{ "question": "稼働", "answers": [ "かどう" ], "comment": "operation (of machine); operating; running; working" },
	{ "question": "稼働率", "answers": [ "かどうりつ" ], "comment": "operating ratio; rate of operation; availability factor" },
	{ "question": "稽古", "answers": [ "けいこ" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training; study" },
	{ "question": "稿", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "manuscript; version; draft" },
	{ "question": "穀物", "answers": [ "こくもつ" ], "comment": "grain; cereal; corn" },
	{ "question": "穂", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "ear (of plant); head (of plant)\npoint; tip\nscion (in grafting); cion" },
	{ "question": "積", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "product\nvolume; area" },
	{ "question": "積み立て", "answers": [ "つみたて" ], "comment": "saving; savings; accumulation; putting aside; reserving" },
	{ "question": "積み込む", "answers": [ "つみこむ" ], "comment": "to load (with goods, cargo); to put on board; to stow aboard" },
	{ "question": "積み重ね", "answers": [ "つみかさね" ], "comment": "pile; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "積む", "answers": [ "つむ" ], "comment": "to pile up; to stack\nto load (car, ship, etc.); to pack\nto acquire; to accumulate" },
	{ "question": "積もる", "answers": [ "つもる" ], "comment": "to pile up; to accumulate\nto estimate" },
	{ "question": "積ん読", "answers": [ "つんどく" ], "comment": "buying books and not reading them; stockpiling books\nbooks bought but not read" },
	{ "question": "積極", "answers": [ "せっきょく" ], "comment": "positive; progressive" },
	{ "question": "積極的", "answers": [ "せっきょくてき" ], "comment": "positive; assertive; active; proactive; aggressive" },
	{ "question": "積立", "answers": [ "つみたて" ], "comment": "saving; savings; accumulation; putting aside; reserving" },
	{ "question": "積立金", "answers": [ "つみたてきん" ], "comment": "reserve (fund); deposit" },
	{ "question": "積算", "answers": [ "せきさん" ], "comment": "addition; adding up\nintegration\nestimate; quantity survey" },
	{ "question": "積載", "answers": [ "せきさい" ], "comment": "lading; loading; carrying" },
	{ "question": "積雪", "answers": [ "せきせつ" ], "comment": "fallen snow; snow cover" },
	{ "question": "穏やか", "answers": [ "おだやか" ], "comment": "calm; gentle; quiet" },
	{ "question": "穏健", "answers": [ "おんけん" ], "comment": "quiet; dependable; uniform; (politically) moderate" },
	{ "question": "穏和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; moderate" },
	{ "question": "穴", "answers": [ "あな" ], "comment": "hole\ndeficit; shortage; missing person (in a team, meeting, etc.)\nvacancy; opening\nflaw\nprofitable place (or item, etc.) not well known by others\nupset victory (with a large payoff)\npit (of a theater)\nhiding place\nunderbelly (of society, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "穴埋め", "answers": [ "あなうめ" ], "comment": "filling in gaps; filling in blanks (in a form, etc.); stopgap; temporary measure\ncovering up a deficit; making up for something (e.g. one's mistake)" },
	{ "question": "究明", "answers": [ "きゅうめい" ], "comment": "investigation (esp. in academic and scientific contexts)" },
	{ "question": "究極", "answers": [ "きゅうきょく" ], "comment": "ultimate; extreme; final; eventual" },
	{ "question": "空", "answers": [ "から", "そら" ], "comment": "emptiness; vacuum; blank /\n sky; the air; the heavens\nweather\nfar-off place; distant place\nstate of mind; feeling\n(from) memory; (by) heart\nfalsehood; lie\nsomehow; vaguely\nfake" },
	{ "question": "空き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "space; room; gap; emptiness\nvacancy; opening; empty seat\nfree time; time to spare\ndisuse; unused thing" },
	{ "question": "空き地", "answers": [ "くうち", "あきち" ], "comment": "vacant land" },
	{ "question": "空き家", "answers": [ "あきや" ], "comment": "vacant house; unoccupied house" },
	{ "question": "空き缶", "answers": [ "あきかん" ], "comment": "empty can" },
	{ "question": "空く", "answers": [ "あく", "すく" ], "comment": "to become less crowded; to thin out; to get empty\nto be hungry /\n to open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "空ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "to open (a door, etc.); to unwrap (e.g. parcel, package); to unlock\nto open (for business, etc.)\nto empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole)" },
	{ "question": "空しい", "answers": [ "むなしい" ], "comment": "empty; void; vacant\nvain; fruitless; futile; ineffective\nlifeless" },
	{ "question": "空っぽ", "answers": [ "からっぽ" ], "comment": "empty; vacant; hollow" },
	{ "question": "空中", "answers": [ "くうちゅう" ], "comment": "sky; air" },
	{ "question": "空前", "answers": [ "くうぜん" ], "comment": "unprecedented; record-breaking" },
	{ "question": "空地", "answers": [ "くうち", "あきち" ], "comment": "vacant land" },
	{ "question": "空域", "answers": [ "くういき" ], "comment": "airspace" },
	{ "question": "空席", "answers": [ "くうせき" ], "comment": "empty seat; unoccupied seat\nvacancy; vacant post" },
	{ "question": "空想", "answers": [ "くうそう" ], "comment": "daydream; fantasy; fancy; vision" },
	{ "question": "空手", "answers": [ "からて" ], "comment": "karate\nempty handed" },
	{ "question": "空振り", "answers": [ "からぶり" ], "comment": "striking (at something) and missing; in vain" },
	{ "question": "空母", "answers": [ "くうぼ" ], "comment": "aircraft carrier" },
	{ "question": "空気", "answers": [ "くうき" ], "comment": "air; atmosphere\nmood; situation\nsomeone with no presence; someone who doesn't stand out at all" },
	{ "question": "空洞", "answers": [ "くうどう" ], "comment": "cave; hollow; cavity\nhollow" },
	{ "question": "空港", "answers": [ "くうこう" ], "comment": "airport" },
	{ "question": "空爆", "answers": [ "くうばく" ], "comment": "aerial bombing" },
	{ "question": "空白", "answers": [ "くうはく" ], "comment": "blank space; vacuum; space; null (NUL)" },
	{ "question": "空砲", "answers": [ "くうほう" ], "comment": "empty gun; gun loaded with blanks; firing a blank" },
	{ "question": "空腹", "answers": [ "くうふく" ], "comment": "hunger" },
	{ "question": "空虚", "answers": [ "くうきょ" ], "comment": "emptiness; hollowness; vacancy; void\ninanity; pointlessness; meaninglessness" },
	{ "question": "空襲", "answers": [ "くうしゅう" ], "comment": "air-raid" },
	{ "question": "空調", "answers": [ "くうちょう" ], "comment": "air conditioning" },
	{ "question": "空路", "answers": [ "くうろ" ], "comment": "air lane" },
	{ "question": "空車", "answers": [ "からぐるま", "あきぐるま", "くうしゃ" ], "comment": "empty conveyance; free taxi\nparking lot with spaces available" },
	{ "question": "空軍", "answers": [ "くうぐん" ], "comment": "Air Force" },
	{ "question": "空転", "answers": [ "くうてん" ], "comment": "racing (an engine); idling (an engine)\ngoing in circles (esp. argument, discussion, etc.); spinning one's wheels" },
	{ "question": "空輸", "answers": [ "くうゆ" ], "comment": "air transport" },
	{ "question": "空間", "answers": [ "くうかん" ], "comment": "space; room; airspace" },
	{ "question": "突き", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "thrust; stab; lunge; pass (in fencing)\ntsuki; thrust to the throat (in kendo)\ntsuki; thrust to the chest" },
	{ "question": "突き上げる", "answers": [ "つきあげる" ], "comment": "to push up; to force up; to toss\nto pressure one's superiors\nto burst out (of emotions, etc.); to fill one's heart" },
	{ "question": "突き刺す", "answers": [ "つきさす" ], "comment": "to stab; to pierce; to thrust" },
	{ "question": "突き当たり", "answers": [ "つきあたり" ], "comment": "end (e.g. of street, hallway, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "突き当たる", "answers": [ "つきあたる" ], "comment": "to run into; to collide with; to crash into; to bump against\nto come to the end of (a street)\nto run into (difficulties, problems, etc.); to run up against" },
	{ "question": "突き抜ける", "answers": [ "つきぬける" ], "comment": "to pierce through; to break through" },
	{ "question": "突く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to prick; to stab\nto poke; to prod; to push; to thrust; to nudge; to hit; to strike\nto use (a cane); to prop oneself up with; to press against (the floor, etc.)\nto attack\nto brave (the rain, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "突っ張り", "answers": [ "つっぱり" ], "comment": "prop; strut; support; bar\nbecoming taut; bracing\nthrust; slapping attacks\n(juvenile) delinquent; punk" },
	{ "question": "突っ張る", "answers": [ "つっぱる" ], "comment": "to support; to become stiff; to become taut; to thrust (one's opponent); to stick to (one's opinion); to insist on" },
	{ "question": "突っ掛ける", "answers": [ "つっかける" ], "comment": "to slip on (slippers, sandals, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "突っ込む", "answers": [ "つっこむ" ], "comment": "to thrust (something) into (something); to cram\nto plunge into; to go into deeply\nto get involved with; to meddle; to poke one's nose into\nto riposte; to retort; to quip" },
	{ "question": "突入", "answers": [ "とつにゅう" ], "comment": "rushing into; breaking into; storming\nplunging into (war, etc.); embarking on (a new venture)" },
	{ "question": "突出", "answers": [ "とっしゅつ" ], "comment": "projection; protrusion" },
	{ "question": "突如", "answers": [ "とつじょ" ], "comment": "suddenly; all of a sudden" },
	{ "question": "突然", "answers": [ "とつぜん" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden; unexpected; all at once" },
	{ "question": "突破", "answers": [ "とっぱ" ], "comment": "breaking through; breakthrough; penetration" },
	{ "question": "突起", "answers": [ "とっき" ], "comment": "protuberance; projection; prominence; bump; boss; process; apophysis" },
	{ "question": "突進", "answers": [ "とっしん" ], "comment": "rush; charge" },
	{ "question": "突風", "answers": [ "とっぷう" ], "comment": "squall; sudden gust" },
	{ "question": "窃盗", "answers": [ "せっとう" ], "comment": "theft; stealing; larceny" },
	{ "question": "窒息", "answers": [ "ちっそく" ], "comment": "suffocation; choking; asphyxia" },
	{ "question": "窒素", "answers": [ "ちっそ" ], "comment": "nitrogen (N)" },
	{ "question": "窓", "answers": [ "まど" ], "comment": "window" },
	{ "question": "窓口", "answers": [ "まどぐち" ], "comment": "ticket window; teller window; counter\ncontact person; point of contact" },
	{ "question": "窓際", "answers": [ "まどぎわ" ], "comment": "(at the) window" },
	{ "question": "窪み", "answers": [ "へこみ", "くぼみ" ], "comment": "hollow; cavity; dent; depression" },
	{ "question": "窮地", "answers": [ "きゅうち" ], "comment": "dilemma; predicament" },
	{ "question": "窮屈", "answers": [ "きゅうくつ" ], "comment": "narrow; tight; cramped\nformal; stiff; strict; ceremonious; rigid\nconstrained; uncomfortable\ntight (e.g. finances)" },
	{ "question": "窮状", "answers": [ "きゅうじょう" ], "comment": "distress; wretched condition" },
	{ "question": "窯", "answers": [ "かま" ], "comment": "stove; furnace; kiln" },
	{ "question": "立ち", "answers": [ "たち" ], "comment": "departure; setting off; start\nbeing used up; being consumed; being burnt out\npassage of time; lapse\nrehearsal\nleading male role in kabuki\nrising from a crouch to charge; initial charge; faceoff\nverb prefix conveying emphasis and sometimes formality" },
	{ "question": "立ちなおる", "answers": [ "たちなおる" ], "comment": "to regain one's footing; to get back on one's feet\nto recover; (of the market) to improve" },
	{ "question": "立ち上がり", "answers": [ "たちあがり" ], "comment": "start; beginning; build up\nhow well a pitcher pitches at the start of the game" },
	{ "question": "立ち上がる", "answers": [ "たちあがる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to get up\nto rise\nto recover\nto take action; to start\nto make the initial charge\nto start up; to boot up" },
	{ "question": "立ち上げる", "answers": [ "たちあげる" ], "comment": "to start (something); to start up; to boot (a computer); to launch (a business)" },
	{ "question": "立ち会い", "answers": [ "たちあい" ], "comment": "presence (e.g. of an observer); observation; observer; witness\ntrading session (at an exchange)" },
	{ "question": "立ち入り", "answers": [ "たちいり" ], "comment": "entering; going into" },
	{ "question": "立ち入り禁止", "answers": [ "たちいりきんし" ], "comment": "No Entry; No Trespassing; No Admittance; Off Limits; Keep Out; Keep Off\noff-limits; restricted; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "立ち入禁止", "answers": [ "たちいりきんし" ], "comment": "No Entry; No Trespassing; No Admittance; Off Limits; Keep Out; Keep Off\noff-limits; restricted; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "立ち去る", "answers": [ "たちさる" ], "comment": "to leave; to depart; to take one's leave" },
	{ "question": "立ち合い", "answers": [ "たちあい" ], "comment": "rising from a crouch to charge; initial charge; face-off" },
	{ "question": "立ち寄る", "answers": [ "たちよる" ], "comment": "to stop by; to drop in for a short visit" },
	{ "question": "立ち往生", "answers": [ "たちおうじょう" ], "comment": "being brought to a standstill; being stranded; getting stuck; stalling; deadlock\nbeing stumped; being in a dilemma; stopping in one's tracks; standing speechless\ndying on one's feet" },
	{ "question": "立ち止まる", "answers": [ "たちどまる" ], "comment": "to stop; to halt; to stand still" },
	{ "question": "立ち消え", "answers": [ "たちぎえ" ], "comment": "going out (e.g. of a fire); dying out\nfizzling out; falling through; coming to nothing" },
	{ "question": "立ち直り", "answers": [ "たちなおり" ], "comment": "recovery; restoration" },
	{ "question": "立ち直る", "answers": [ "たちなおる" ], "comment": "to regain one's footing; to get back on one's feet\nto recover; (of the market) to improve" },
	{ "question": "立ち話", "answers": [ "たちばなし" ], "comment": "talking while standing; standing around talking" },
	{ "question": "立ち読み", "answers": [ "たちよみ" ], "comment": "reading while standing (in a bookstore, etc.); browsing (i.e. reading an item but not buying it)" },
	{ "question": "立ち退き", "answers": [ "たちのき" ], "comment": "eviction" },
	{ "question": "立ち退く", "answers": [ "たちのく" ], "comment": "to evacuate; to clear out; to vacate; to withdraw; to take refuge" },
	{ "question": "立つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to stand; to rise; to stand up\nto find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)\nto depart (on a plane, train, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "立てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "to stand up; to put up; to set up; to erect; to raise\nto thrust into; to bury into; to dig into\nto make (a noise); to start (a rumour); to raise (a cloud of dust, etc.); to cause\nto make; to establish; to set up; to develop; to formulate\nto put up (a political candidate); to make (one's leader)\nto treat with respect; to give (someone) their due; to make (someone) look good; to avoid embarrassing (someone)\nto sharpen; to make clear\nto shut; to close\nto make tea (matcha); to perform the tea ceremony\nto divide by\nto do ... vigorously" },
	{ "question": "立て替える", "answers": [ "たてかえる" ], "comment": "to pay an advance; to put down money on something\nto pay for another; to pay someone else's debt as a loan to him" },
	{ "question": "立て札", "answers": [ "たてふだ" ], "comment": "bulletin board; notice board; billboard; roadside sign; sign on a post, usu. wooden, esp. containing information about a sight, warning, congratulations, etc." },
	{ "question": "立て直す", "answers": [ "たてなおす" ], "comment": "to rally; to make over; to rearrange; to reorganize; to reorganise" },
	{ "question": "立て続け", "answers": [ "たてつづけ" ], "comment": "succession; continuation; series; sequence" },
	{ "question": "立て込む", "answers": [ "たてこむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded\nto be busy" },
	{ "question": "立会い", "answers": [ "たちあい" ], "comment": "presence (e.g. of an observer); observation; observer; witness\ntrading session (at an exchange)" },
	{ "question": "立体", "answers": [ "りったい" ], "comment": "solid body; three-dimensional object\nmulti-storey car park" },
	{ "question": "立体的", "answers": [ "りったいてき" ], "comment": "three-dimensional" },
	{ "question": "立候補", "answers": [ "りっこうほ" ], "comment": "announcing candidacy; becoming a candidate; bidding (to host an event e.g. Olympics, World Cup)" },
	{ "question": "立入り禁止", "answers": [ "たちいりきんし" ], "comment": "No Entry; No Trespassing; No Admittance; Off Limits; Keep Out; Keep Off\noff-limits; restricted; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "立入禁止", "answers": [ "たちいりきんし" ], "comment": "No Entry; No Trespassing; No Admittance; Off Limits; Keep Out; Keep Off\noff-limits; restricted; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "立国", "answers": [ "りっこく" ], "comment": "founding of a nation" },
	{ "question": "立地", "answers": [ "りっち" ], "comment": "site; location (e.g. of industry)" },
	{ "question": "立場", "answers": [ "たちば" ], "comment": "standpoint; position; situation" },
	{ "question": "立憲", "answers": [ "りっけん" ], "comment": "constitutionalism" },
	{ "question": "立方メートル", "answers": [ "りっぽうメートル" ], "comment": "cubic meter" },
	{ "question": "立札", "answers": [ "たてふだ" ], "comment": "bulletin board; notice board; billboard; roadside sign; sign on a post, usu. wooden, esp. containing information about a sight, warning, congratulations, etc." },
	{ "question": "立案", "answers": [ "りつあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught; (rough) design" },
	{ "question": "立法", "answers": [ "りっぽう" ], "comment": "legislation; lawmaking" },
	{ "question": "立法府", "answers": [ "りっぽうふ" ], "comment": "assize; court\nlegislature" },
	{ "question": "立派", "answers": [ "りっぱ" ], "comment": "splendid; fine; handsome; elegant; imposing; prominent\npraiseworthy; creditable; worthy\nlegal; legitimate; lawful\nundeniable (e.g. crime); indisputable; solid" },
	{ "question": "立脚", "answers": [ "りっきゃく" ], "comment": "being based on" },
	{ "question": "立証", "answers": [ "りっしょう" ], "comment": "establishing proof; demonstration; substantiation" },
	{ "question": "竜", "answers": [ "たつ", "りゅう", "りょう" ], "comment": "dragon (esp. a Chinese dragon)\nnaga; semi-divine human-cobra chimera in Hindu and Buddhist mythology\npromoted rook" },
	{ "question": "竜王", "answers": [ "りゅうおう" ], "comment": "Dragon King\npromoted rook" },
	{ "question": "章", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "chapter; section\nmedal" },
	{ "question": "童話", "answers": [ "どうわ" ], "comment": "fairy-tale" },
	{ "question": "童謡", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "children's song; nursery rhyme" },
	{ "question": "端", "answers": [ "はし", "はな", "はじ" ], "comment": "end (e.g. of street); tip; point; edge; margin\nbeginning; start; first\nodds and ends; scrap; odd bit; least" },
	{ "question": "端末", "answers": [ "たんまつ" ], "comment": "terminal; computer terminal\ninformation access device (smartphone, tablet, book-reader, etc.)\nend (e.g. of a roll of film)" },
	{ "question": "端末機", "answers": [ "たんまつき" ], "comment": "terminal (unit)" },
	{ "question": "端的", "answers": [ "たんてき" ], "comment": "frank; direct; plain; straightforward; point-blank; concise" },
	{ "question": "端緒", "answers": [ "たんちょ", "たんしょ" ], "comment": "a clue; start; beginning" },
	{ "question": "競う", "answers": [ "きそう" ], "comment": "to compete with\nto emulate" },
	{ "question": "競り合い", "answers": [ "せりあい" ], "comment": "competition" },
	{ "question": "競り合う", "answers": [ "せりあう" ], "comment": "to struggle for; to compete with; to vie with" },
	{ "question": "競る", "answers": [ "せる" ], "comment": "to compete\nto bid\nto sell at auction" },
	{ "question": "競争", "answers": [ "きょうそう" ], "comment": "competition; contest\nto compete" },
	{ "question": "競争入札", "answers": [ "きょうそうにゅうさつ" ], "comment": "competitive bidding (esp. for government contracts)" },
	{ "question": "競合", "answers": [ "きょうごう" ], "comment": "contention; competition; rivalry; quarrel" },
	{ "question": "競合他社", "answers": [ "きょうごうたしゃ" ], "comment": "competing companies; rival companies" },
	{ "question": "競売", "answers": [ "けいばい", "きょうばい" ], "comment": "auction" },
	{ "question": "競技", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "game; match; contest" },
	{ "question": "競歩", "answers": [ "きょうほ" ], "comment": "racewalking; race walking; walking race" },
	{ "question": "競泳", "answers": [ "きょうえい" ], "comment": "competitive swimming; swimming race" },
	{ "question": "競演", "answers": [ "きょうえん" ], "comment": "recital contest" },
	{ "question": "競艇", "answers": [ "きょうてい" ], "comment": "boat race" },
	{ "question": "競走", "answers": [ "きょうそう" ], "comment": "race" },
	{ "question": "競走馬", "answers": [ "きょうそうば" ], "comment": "racehorse" },
	{ "question": "競輪", "answers": [ "けいりん" ], "comment": "keirin; cycle racing event, usu. 2km with a paced start and sprint finish" },
	{ "question": "競馬", "answers": [ "けいば" ], "comment": "horse racing" },
	{ "question": "競馬場", "answers": [ "けいばじょう" ], "comment": "racecourse; race track" },
	{ "question": "竹", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "bamboo\nmiddle (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "竿", "answers": [ "さお" ], "comment": "rod; pole\nneck (of a shamisen, etc.); shamisen\nbeam (i.e. the crossbar of a balance)\nsingle line (esp. as a flying formation for geese)\npenis\ncounter for flags (on poles); counter for long, thin Japanese sweets (e.g. youkan)" },
	{ "question": "笑い", "answers": [ "わらい" ], "comment": "laugh; laughter\nsmile\nsneer\nsex aids (e.g. dildos, pornographic books, erotic woodblock prints, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "笑い声", "answers": [ "わらいごえ" ], "comment": "laughter" },
	{ "question": "笑う", "answers": [ "わらう" ], "comment": "to laugh\nto smile\nto sneer; to ridicule\nto be dumbfounded; to be flabbergasted" },
	{ "question": "笑み", "answers": [ "えみ" ], "comment": "smile" },
	{ "question": "笑顔", "answers": [ "えがお" ], "comment": "smiling face; smile" },
	{ "question": "笛", "answers": [ "ふえ" ], "comment": "flute; fife; pipe; recorder; flageolet; shakuhachi; clarinet\nwhistle" },
	{ "question": "笠", "answers": [ "かさ" ], "comment": "conical hat (East-Asian style); coolie hat\nsomething shaped like a conical hat or an umbrella; shade (of a lamp); mushroom cap; pileus" },
	{ "question": "符号", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "sign; mark; symbol; code\nsign (e.g. positive, negative)" },
	{ "question": "第", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "prefix for forming ordinal numbers" },
	{ "question": "第一", "answers": [ "だいいち" ], "comment": "first; foremost; number one" },
	{ "question": "第一人者", "answers": [ "だいいちにんしゃ" ], "comment": "leading person" },
	{ "question": "第一声", "answers": [ "だいいっせい" ], "comment": "first tone; first speech" },
	{ "question": "第一歩", "answers": [ "だいいっぽ" ], "comment": "first step" },
	{ "question": "第一線", "answers": [ "だいいっせん" ], "comment": "the front (of a battlefield); forefront" },
	{ "question": "第一義", "answers": [ "だいいちぎ" ], "comment": "first principle; original or greatest import" },
	{ "question": "第三国", "answers": [ "だいさんごく" ], "comment": "a third country" },
	{ "question": "第三者", "answers": [ "だいさんしゃ" ], "comment": "third party; third person; outsider; disinterested person" },
	{ "question": "第二次世界大戦", "answers": [ "だいにじせかいたいせん" ], "comment": "Second World War; World War II; WWII; WW2" },
	{ "question": "笹", "answers": [ "ささ" ], "comment": "bamboo grass; generally smaller species of running bamboo that do not shed their sheaths (e.g. Sasa spp.)" },
	{ "question": "筆", "answers": [ "ふで" ], "comment": "writing brush" },
	{ "question": "筆者", "answers": [ "ひっしゃ" ], "comment": "writer (often in self-reference); author" },
	{ "question": "筆記", "answers": [ "ひっき" ], "comment": "(taking) notes; copying" },
	{ "question": "筆記用具", "answers": [ "ひっきようぐ" ], "comment": "writing implement" },
	{ "question": "筆記試験", "answers": [ "ひっきしけん" ], "comment": "written examination" },
	{ "question": "筆跡", "answers": [ "ふであと", "ひっせき" ], "comment": "handwriting\ncalligraphy specimen; example of penmanship; holograph" },
	{ "question": "筆順", "answers": [ "ひつじゅん" ], "comment": "stroke order" },
	{ "question": "筆頭", "answers": [ "ふでがしら", "ひっとう" ], "comment": "brush tip\nfirst on a list\nhead; chief" },
	{ "question": "等々", "answers": [ "などなど", "とうとう" ], "comment": "etc.; et cetera; and so on" },
	{ "question": "等しい", "answers": [ "ひとしい" ], "comment": "equal; similar; like; equivalent" },
	{ "question": "等価", "answers": [ "とうか" ], "comment": "equivalence" },
	{ "question": "等分", "answers": [ "とうぶん" ], "comment": "division into equal parts" },
	{ "question": "等身", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "body proportions" },
	{ "question": "筋", "answers": [ "すじ" ], "comment": "muscle; tendon; sinew\nvein; artery\nfiber; fibre; string\nline; stripe; streak\nreason; logic\nplot; storyline\nlineage; descent\nschool (e.g. of scholarship or arts)\naptitude; talent\nsource (of information, etc.); circle; channel\nwell-informed person (in a transaction)\nlogical move (in go, shogi, etc.)\nninth vertical line\nseam on a helmet\ngristly fish paste (made of muscle, tendons, skin, etc.)\nsocial position; status\non (a river, road, etc.); along\ncounter for long thin things; counter for roads or blocks when giving directions\n(Edo period) counter for hundreds of mon (obsolete unit of currency)" },
	{ "question": "筋力", "answers": [ "きんりょく" ], "comment": "physical strength; muscle strength" },
	{ "question": "筋書き", "answers": [ "すじがき" ], "comment": "synopsis; outline; plot" },
	{ "question": "筋肉", "answers": [ "きんにく" ], "comment": "muscle; sinew" },
	{ "question": "筋道", "answers": [ "すじみち" ], "comment": "reason; logic\nmethod; system; order; thread (e.g. of an argument)" },
	{ "question": "筐体", "answers": [ "きょうたい" ], "comment": "case (of a machine, computer, etc.); casing; housing; enclosure; cabinet; chassis; frame" },
	{ "question": "筒", "answers": [ "つつ" ], "comment": "pipe; tube; cylinder\ngun barrel\ngun" },
	{ "question": "筒井", "answers": [ "つつい" ], "comment": "round well" },
	{ "question": "答", "answers": [ "こたえ", "いらえ" ], "comment": "answer; reply; response; solution" },
	{ "question": "答え", "answers": [ "こたえ", "いらえ" ], "comment": "answer; reply; response; solution" },
	{ "question": "答える", "answers": [ "こたえる" ], "comment": "to answer; to reply" },
	{ "question": "答弁", "answers": [ "とうべん" ], "comment": "response; reply; answer; defence; defense" },
	{ "question": "答案", "answers": [ "とうあん" ], "comment": "examination paper; examination script" },
	{ "question": "答申", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "report; reply; findings" },
	{ "question": "策", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "策定", "answers": [ "さくてい" ], "comment": "formulation (of a plan, policy, etc.); decision; settling on" },
	{ "question": "策略", "answers": [ "さくりゃく" ], "comment": "scheme; tactic; stratagem; trick" },
	{ "question": "箇所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "passage; place; point; part" },
	{ "question": "算出", "answers": [ "さんしゅつ" ], "comment": "calculation; computation" },
	{ "question": "算定", "answers": [ "さんてい" ], "comment": "calculation; estimation; computation" },
	{ "question": "算数", "answers": [ "さんすう" ], "comment": "arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "管", "answers": [ "かん", "くだ" ], "comment": "pipe; tube" },
	{ "question": "管内", "answers": [ "かんない" ], "comment": "within the jurisdiction of" },
	{ "question": "管制", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "control" },
	{ "question": "管制官", "answers": [ "かんせいかん" ], "comment": "controller (usually air-traffic)" },
	{ "question": "管区", "answers": [ "かんく" ], "comment": "jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "管区気象台", "answers": [ "かんくきしょうだい" ], "comment": "district meteorological observatory" },
	{ "question": "管弦楽", "answers": [ "かんげんがく" ], "comment": "orchestral music" },
	{ "question": "管弦楽団", "answers": [ "かんげんがくだん" ], "comment": "orchestra" },
	{ "question": "管理", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "control; management (e.g. of a business)" },
	{ "question": "管理者", "answers": [ "かんりしゃ" ], "comment": "manager; landlord; warden; superintendent; supervisor; custodian\nroot (user)" },
	{ "question": "管理職", "answers": [ "かんりしょく" ], "comment": "management" },
	{ "question": "管財", "answers": [ "かんざい" ], "comment": "administration of property; custodianship; receivership" },
	{ "question": "管轄", "answers": [ "かんかつ" ], "comment": "jurisdiction; control" },
	{ "question": "管長", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "superintendent priest; chief abbot" },
	{ "question": "箱", "answers": [ "はこ" ], "comment": "box; case; chest; package; pack; crate\ncar (of a train, etc.)\nshamisen case; shamisen\npublic building; community building\nman who carries a geisha's shamisen\nreceptacle for human waste; feces (faeces)\ncounter for boxes (or boxed objects)" },
	{ "question": "箸", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "節", "answers": [ "ふし", "せつ" ], "comment": "occasion; time\nsection (of a literary work); paragraph; verse; stanza; passage\nprinciple; integrity\nnode (of a plant stem)\nclause\n(taxonomical) section /\n joint; knuckle\ntune; melody\nknot (in wood); node in a bamboo stem\npart; notable characteristic" },
	{ "question": "節句", "answers": [ "せっく" ], "comment": "seasonal festival" },
	{ "question": "節度", "answers": [ "せつど" ], "comment": "moderation; standard" },
	{ "question": "節減", "answers": [ "せつげん" ], "comment": "retrenchment; curtailment; economy" },
	{ "question": "節目", "answers": [ "ふしめ", "フシめ" ], "comment": "turning point; critical juncture\nknot (in a tree, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "節約", "answers": [ "せつやく" ], "comment": "economising; saving" },
	{ "question": "範", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "example; model" },
	{ "question": "範囲", "answers": [ "はんい" ], "comment": "extent; scope; sphere; range; span" },
	{ "question": "築き上げる", "answers": [ "きずきあげる" ], "comment": "to build up; to establish (one's reputation)" },
	{ "question": "築く", "answers": [ "きずく" ], "comment": "to build; to construct; to erect\nto amass (e.g. fortune); to pile up" },
	{ "question": "築地", "answers": [ "ついじ" ], "comment": "mud wall with a roof; roofed mud wall" },
	{ "question": "簡単", "answers": [ "かんたん" ], "comment": "simple; easy; uncomplicated\nbrief; quick; light" },
	{ "question": "簡易", "answers": [ "かんい" ], "comment": "simplicity; convenience; easiness; quasi-" },
	{ "question": "簡易保険", "answers": [ "かんいほけん" ], "comment": "postal life insurance" },
	{ "question": "簡潔", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "brevity; conciseness; simplicity" },
	{ "question": "簡略", "answers": [ "かんりゃく" ], "comment": "simple; simplicity; brief; brevity" },
	{ "question": "簡素", "answers": [ "かんそ" ], "comment": "simplicity; plain" },
	{ "question": "簡裁", "answers": [ "かんさい" ], "comment": "summary court; court of summary offences" },
	{ "question": "籍", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "one's family register; one's domicile\nnationality\nmembership (club, party, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "籤引", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "籤引き", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "米", "answers": [ "こめ" ], "comment": "(husked grains of) rice\n88 years old" },
	{ "question": "米人", "answers": [ "べいじん" ], "comment": "an American" },
	{ "question": "米価", "answers": [ "べいか" ], "comment": "rice price" },
	{ "question": "米倉", "answers": [ "こめぐら" ], "comment": "rice granary" },
	{ "question": "米国", "answers": [ "べいこく" ], "comment": "America; USA" },
	{ "question": "米穀", "answers": [ "べいこく" ], "comment": "rice" },
	{ "question": "米飯", "answers": [ "べいはん" ], "comment": "cooked rice" },
	{ "question": "粉", "answers": [ "こな", "こ" ], "comment": "flour; meal; powder" },
	{ "question": "粉ミルク", "answers": [ "こなミルク" ], "comment": "milk powder\nbaby formula" },
	{ "question": "粉末", "answers": [ "ふんまつ" ], "comment": "fine powder" },
	{ "question": "粋", "answers": [ "いき", "すい" ], "comment": "chic; smart; stylish; tasteful; refined; sophisticated; worldly\nconsiderate; understanding; sympathetic\nessence; the best; the cream" },
	{ "question": "粒", "answers": [ "つぶ" ], "comment": "grain; bead; drop\ncounter for small round objects including grains, seeds, pills, drops" },
	{ "question": "粒子", "answers": [ "りゅうし" ], "comment": "particle; grain" },
	{ "question": "粗い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "coarse; rough" },
	{ "question": "粗大", "answers": [ "そだい" ], "comment": "coarse; rough; bulky" },
	{ "question": "粗末", "answers": [ "そまつ" ], "comment": "crude; rough; plain; humble; shabby" },
	{ "question": "粗鋼", "answers": [ "そこう" ], "comment": "crude steel" },
	{ "question": "粘り", "answers": [ "ねばり" ], "comment": "stickiness; viscosity\ntenacity; persistence" },
	{ "question": "粘り強い", "answers": [ "ねばりづよい" ], "comment": "tenacious; persevering; persistent; stubborn; steadfast\nsticky" },
	{ "question": "粘る", "answers": [ "ねばる" ], "comment": "to be sticky; to be adhesive\nto persevere; to persist; to stick to; to hold out; to linger" },
	{ "question": "粘土", "answers": [ "ねばつち", "ねんど" ], "comment": "clay" },
	{ "question": "粘着", "answers": [ "ねんちゃく" ], "comment": "cohesion; adhesion" },
	{ "question": "粘膜", "answers": [ "ねんまく" ], "comment": "mucous membrane" },
	{ "question": "粥", "answers": [ "かゆ" ], "comment": "thin rice porridge; watery cooked rice; rice gruel; congee" },
	{ "question": "精", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "spirit; sprite; nymph\nenergy; vigor (vigour); strength\nfine details\nsemen" },
	{ "question": "精一杯", "answers": [ "せいいっぱい" ], "comment": "the best one can do; one's best effort\nwith all one's might; to the best of one's ability" },
	{ "question": "精力", "answers": [ "せいりょく" ], "comment": "energy; vigor; vigour; vitality" },
	{ "question": "精子", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "sperm" },
	{ "question": "精密", "answers": [ "せいみつ" ], "comment": "precise; exact; detailed; minute; close" },
	{ "question": "精巧", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "elaborate; delicate; exquisite" },
	{ "question": "精度", "answers": [ "せいど" ], "comment": "precision; accuracy" },
	{ "question": "精彩", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "brilliance; luster; lustre; colorfulness; colourfulness\nvividness; life" },
	{ "question": "精神", "answers": [ "せいしん" ], "comment": "mind; soul; heart; spirit; intention" },
	{ "question": "精神的", "answers": [ "せいしんてき" ], "comment": "mental; emotional" },
	{ "question": "精神科", "answers": [ "せいしんか" ], "comment": "psychiatry" },
	{ "question": "精神薄弱", "answers": [ "せいしんはくじゃく" ], "comment": "mental retardation; mentally retarded" },
	{ "question": "精神障害", "answers": [ "せいしんしょうがい" ], "comment": "mental disorder" },
	{ "question": "精算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "exact calculation; squaring of accounts; adjustment" },
	{ "question": "精米", "answers": [ "せいまい" ], "comment": "rice polishing; polished rice" },
	{ "question": "精製", "answers": [ "せいせい" ], "comment": "refining; purification" },
	{ "question": "精通", "answers": [ "せいつう" ], "comment": "acquaintance; having knowledge; being expert; being versed in; conversant\nfirst ejaculation" },
	{ "question": "精鋭", "answers": [ "せいえい" ], "comment": "elite; best; pick; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "糊", "answers": [ "のり" ], "comment": "paste; glue\nclothing starch" },
	{ "question": "糖", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "糖尿病", "answers": [ "とうにょうびょう" ], "comment": "diabetes mellitus; sugar diabetes" },
	{ "question": "糞", "answers": [ "くそ", "ふん" ], "comment": "bullshit; shit; damn\nfeces; excrement; dung\ndamn; damned; blasted; stupid\nvery; extremely\na lot" },
	{ "question": "糸", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "thread; yarn; string" },
	{ "question": "糸口", "answers": [ "いとぐち" ], "comment": "thread end\nbeginning\nclue" },
	{ "question": "系", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "system; lineage; group\ncorollary\nsystem (range of strata that correspond to a particular time period)\n(taxonomical) series" },
	{ "question": "系列", "answers": [ "けいれつ" ], "comment": "series; sequence; system; order of succession\nkeiretsu (conglomeration of businesses linked by cross-shareholdings)" },
	{ "question": "系統", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "system\nlineage; ancestry; family line\ngroup (e.g. of colors) (colours); family (e.g. of languages); party; school (of thought)\nclose (evolutionary) relationship\na population sharing a common ancestor (in genetics); strain (e.g. bacterial)" },
	{ "question": "系譜", "answers": [ "けいふ" ], "comment": "genealogy; pedigree" },
	{ "question": "紀元", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "era\nCE (Common Era); AD (Anno Domini)" },
	{ "question": "紀元前", "answers": [ "きげんぜん" ], "comment": "pre-era; BC; BCE" },
	{ "question": "紀行", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "traveller's journal; traveler's journal; travelogue" },
	{ "question": "約", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "approximately; about\npromise\nshortening; reduction; simplification\ncontraction (in phonetics)" },
	{ "question": "約束", "answers": [ "やくそく" ], "comment": "promise; agreement; arrangement; one's word; contract; pact; appointment; engagement; date\nconvention; rule\ndestiny; fate" },
	{ "question": "約束通り", "answers": [ "やくそくどおり" ], "comment": "as one promised" },
	{ "question": "紅", "answers": [ "べに", "くれない", "こう" ], "comment": "deep red; crimson\nrouge; lipstick" },
	{ "question": "紅い", "answers": [ "あかい" ], "comment": "red\nRed (i.e. communist)" },
	{ "question": "紅潮", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "flush; blush" },
	{ "question": "紅白", "answers": [ "こうはく" ], "comment": "red and white; colours for festive or auspicious occasions (colors)\nRed and White singing contest; annual contest between male and female popular singers on New Year's Eve (sponsored and broadcast by NHK)" },
	{ "question": "紅茶", "answers": [ "こうちゃ" ], "comment": "black tea" },
	{ "question": "紅葉", "answers": [ "もみじ", "こうよう" ], "comment": "autumn colours; fall colors; leaves changing color (colour)\nleaves turning red; red leaves\nleaves turning yellow; yellow leaves\n(Japanese) maple (Acer japonicum)\nvenison" },
	{ "question": "紋", "answers": [ "もん" ], "comment": "(family) crest; coat of arms" },
	{ "question": "納まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "納める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "納付", "answers": [ "のうふ" ], "comment": "payment; supply" },
	{ "question": "納入", "answers": [ "のうにゅう" ], "comment": "payment (taxes, fees, etc.)\nsupply (of goods); delivery" },
	{ "question": "納得", "answers": [ "なっとく" ], "comment": "consent; assent; agreement\nunderstanding; comprehension; grasp" },
	{ "question": "納税", "answers": [ "のうぜい" ], "comment": "payment of taxes" },
	{ "question": "納豆", "answers": [ "なっとう" ], "comment": "natto (fermented soybeans)" },
	{ "question": "納金", "answers": [ "のうきん" ], "comment": "payment" },
	{ "question": "紐", "answers": [ "ひも" ], "comment": "string; cord\nman who is financially dependent on a woman (such as a gigolo or, in the case of a prostitute, a pimp); pimp" },
	{ "question": "純", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "innocent; chaste; naive\npure; genuine" },
	{ "question": "純度", "answers": [ "じゅんど" ], "comment": "purity (of a substance)" },
	{ "question": "純情", "answers": [ "じゅんじょう" ], "comment": "pure heart; naivete; innocence" },
	{ "question": "純益", "answers": [ "じゅんえき" ], "comment": "clear profit; net income; net profit" },
	{ "question": "純粋", "answers": [ "じゅんすい" ], "comment": "pure; true; genuine; unmixed" },
	{ "question": "純金", "answers": [ "じゅんきん" ], "comment": "pure gold; solid gold; fine gold" },
	{ "question": "紙", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "paper" },
	{ "question": "紙上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "on paper; in the newspapers; in a letter" },
	{ "question": "紙屑", "answers": [ "かみくず" ], "comment": "wastepaper; paper scraps; paper waste" },
	{ "question": "紙幣", "answers": [ "しへい" ], "comment": "paper money; note; bill" },
	{ "question": "紙芝居", "answers": [ "かみしばい" ], "comment": "picture story show" },
	{ "question": "紙袋", "answers": [ "かみぶくろ", "かんぶくろ" ], "comment": "paper bag" },
	{ "question": "紙面", "answers": [ "しめん" ], "comment": "space on a page (e.g. in a newspaper)\nsurface of paper\nletter; writings; document" },
	{ "question": "級", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "class (e.g. school); grade; rank" },
	{ "question": "紛らす", "answers": [ "まぎらす" ], "comment": "to divert (e.g. one's mind); to distract; to relieve (e.g. boredom)\nto conceal (e.g. one's sorrow with a smile); to shift (the conversation)" },
	{ "question": "紛らわしい", "answers": [ "まぎらわしい" ], "comment": "confusing; misleading; equivocal; ambiguous; easily mixed up (e.g. similar words)" },
	{ "question": "紛れ", "answers": [ "まぐれ" ], "comment": "fluke; chance" },
	{ "question": "紛れもない", "answers": [ "まぎれもない" ], "comment": "certain; unmistaken; evident; obvious; beyond doubt" },
	{ "question": "紛れも無い", "answers": [ "まぎれもない" ], "comment": "certain; unmistaken; evident; obvious; beyond doubt" },
	{ "question": "紛れる", "answers": [ "まぎれる" ], "comment": "to disappear into; to be lost in; to slip into; to get mixed in among\nto do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)\nto be almost indistinguishable; to be confusingly similar\nto be diverted from (negative emotions, etc.); to forget about\nto be distracted by; to be too absorbed in" },
	{ "question": "紛争", "answers": [ "ふんそう" ], "comment": "dispute; trouble; strife" },
	{ "question": "紛失", "answers": [ "ふんしつ" ], "comment": "losing something" },
	{ "question": "紛糾", "answers": [ "ふんきゅう" ], "comment": "complication; confusion; disorder" },
	{ "question": "素", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "plain; unadorned; undecorated; unadulterated; au naturel\nmere; poor\nexceedingly" },
	{ "question": "素人", "answers": [ "しらびと", "しろと", "しろうと" ], "comment": "amateur; layman; ordinary person; novice\nrespectable woman (not a prostitute, hostess, geisha, etc.)\nunlicensed prostitute" },
	{ "question": "素子", "answers": [ "そし" ], "comment": "element (esp. component in electronics); elemental device; device\ndata; datum" },
	{ "question": "素敵", "answers": [ "すてき" ], "comment": "lovely; dreamy; beautiful; great; fantastic; superb; cool; capital" },
	{ "question": "素早い", "answers": [ "すばやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; prompt; nimble; agile\nquick (to understand); sharp (judgement)" },
	{ "question": "素晴しい", "answers": [ "すばらしい", "すんばらしい" ], "comment": "wonderful; splendid; magnificent" },
	{ "question": "素晴らしい", "answers": [ "すばらしい", "すんばらしい" ], "comment": "wonderful; splendid; magnificent" },
	{ "question": "素朴", "answers": [ "そぼく" ], "comment": "simplicity; artlessness; naivete; pristineness; idyll" },
	{ "question": "素材", "answers": [ "そざい" ], "comment": "raw materials; subject matter" },
	{ "question": "素案", "answers": [ "そあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "素直", "answers": [ "すなお" ], "comment": "obedient; meek; docile; unaffected\nhonest; frank; upfront (about one's feelings)" },
	{ "question": "素質", "answers": [ "そしつ" ], "comment": "character; qualities; genius; the makings of" },
	{ "question": "素顔", "answers": [ "すがお" ], "comment": "face with no make-up; unpainted face\nhonesty; frankness" },
	{ "question": "紡績", "answers": [ "ぼうせき" ], "comment": "spinning" },
	{ "question": "索引", "answers": [ "さくいん" ], "comment": "index; indices; indexes" },
	{ "question": "紫外線", "answers": [ "しがいせん" ], "comment": "ultra-violet rays" },
	{ "question": "紫色", "answers": [ "むらさきいろ", "ししょく" ], "comment": "purple; violet" },
	{ "question": "累積", "answers": [ "るいせき" ], "comment": "accumulation" },
	{ "question": "累計", "answers": [ "るいけい" ], "comment": "cumulative total; accumulated total; total up to now" },
	{ "question": "累進", "answers": [ "るいしん" ], "comment": "successive promotion; gradual promotion; graduated" },
	{ "question": "細々", "answers": [ "こまごま", "ほそぼそ" ], "comment": "minutely; in detail; with particular attention /\n poor (living)\nbarely continuing; just scraping along\nvery narrow" },
	{ "question": "細い", "answers": [ "ほそい" ], "comment": "thin; slender; fine\nunlucky (billiards slang)" },
	{ "question": "細か", "answers": [ "こまか" ], "comment": "small; fine; detailed; stingy" },
	{ "question": "細かい", "answers": [ "こまかい" ], "comment": "small\nfine; minute\nminor; trivial\nsensitive; attentive" },
	{ "question": "細かいこと", "answers": [ "こまかいこと" ], "comment": "trifles; minor details" },
	{ "question": "細かく", "answers": [ "こまかく" ], "comment": "minutely; finely" },
	{ "question": "細分", "answers": [ "さいぶん" ], "comment": "divide into small portions" },
	{ "question": "細工", "answers": [ "さいく" ], "comment": "work; craftsmanship; tactics; trick" },
	{ "question": "細心", "answers": [ "さいしん" ], "comment": "meticulous; careful; discreet; scrupulous; prudent" },
	{ "question": "細目", "answers": [ "さいもく" ], "comment": "particulars; details; specified items" },
	{ "question": "細胞", "answers": [ "さいほう", "さいぼう" ], "comment": "cell" },
	{ "question": "細胞内", "answers": [ "さいぼうない" ], "comment": "inside the cell; intracellular" },
	{ "question": "細菌", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "bacillus; bacterium; germ" },
	{ "question": "細部", "answers": [ "さいぶ" ], "comment": "details" },
	{ "question": "細長い", "answers": [ "ほそながい" ], "comment": "long and narrow" },
	{ "question": "紳士", "answers": [ "しんし" ], "comment": "gentleman" },
	{ "question": "紹介", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "introduction; presentation; referral; listing" },
	{ "question": "紹介文", "answers": [ "しょうかいぶん" ], "comment": "introductory essay" },
	{ "question": "紹介者", "answers": [ "しょうかいしゃ" ], "comment": "person who introduces someone; introducer" },
	{ "question": "紺", "answers": [ "こん" ], "comment": "navy blue; deep blue" },
	{ "question": "紺屋", "answers": [ "こんや", "こうや" ], "comment": "dyer" },
	{ "question": "終える", "answers": [ "おえる" ], "comment": "to finish\nto graduate" },
	{ "question": "終わり", "answers": [ "おわり" ], "comment": "the end" },
	{ "question": "終わる", "answers": [ "おわる" ], "comment": "to finish; to end; to close" },
	{ "question": "終了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "end; close; termination" },
	{ "question": "終了後", "answers": [ "しゅうりょうご" ], "comment": "after the end (of something); post-" },
	{ "question": "終値", "answers": [ "おわりね" ], "comment": "closing price (e.g. stock exchange)" },
	{ "question": "終始", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "beginning and end\ndoing something from beginning to end; being unchanged from beginning to end\nfrom beginning to end; the whole time; throughout; consistently" },
	{ "question": "終局", "answers": [ "しゅうきょく" ], "comment": "end; close; conclusion; denouement; finale; end of a game of go" },
	{ "question": "終息", "answers": [ "しゅうそく" ], "comment": "having ended; being resolved" },
	{ "question": "終戦", "answers": [ "しゅうせん" ], "comment": "end of war; cessation of hostilities" },
	{ "question": "終日", "answers": [ "ひめもす", "ひねもす", "ひもすがら", "しゅうじつ" ], "comment": "all day; for a whole day" },
	{ "question": "終末", "answers": [ "しゅうまつ" ], "comment": "an end; a close" },
	{ "question": "終止符", "answers": [ "しゅうしふ" ], "comment": "full stop; period\nend" },
	{ "question": "終点", "answers": [ "しゅうてん" ], "comment": "terminus; last stop (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "終焉", "answers": [ "しゅうえん" ], "comment": "demise" },
	{ "question": "終盤", "answers": [ "しゅうばん" ], "comment": "endgame; final stage" },
	{ "question": "終着駅", "answers": [ "しゅうちゃくえき" ], "comment": "terminal station" },
	{ "question": "終結", "answers": [ "しゅうけつ" ], "comment": "end; close" },
	{ "question": "終身", "answers": [ "しゅうしん" ], "comment": "the whole life" },
	{ "question": "終電", "answers": [ "しゅうでん" ], "comment": "last train" },
	{ "question": "組", "answers": [ "くみ" ], "comment": "set (of items)\ngroup (of people); class (of students); company (esp. construction); family (i.e. mafia); team\ntypesetting; composition" },
	{ "question": "組み", "answers": [ "くみ" ], "comment": "set (of items)\ngroup (of people); class (of students); company (esp. construction); family (i.e. mafia); team\ntypesetting; composition" },
	{ "question": "組み合わせ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "combination" },
	{ "question": "組み合わせる", "answers": [ "くみあわせる" ], "comment": "to join together; to combine; to join up" },
	{ "question": "組み替え", "answers": [ "くみかえ" ], "comment": "rearrangement (of classes); recomposition; recombination; reclassification" },
	{ "question": "組み立て", "answers": [ "くみたて" ], "comment": "construction; framework; erection; assembly; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "組み立てる", "answers": [ "くみたてる" ], "comment": "to assemble; to set up; to construct" },
	{ "question": "組み込む", "answers": [ "くみこむ" ], "comment": "to insert; to include; to incorporate; to cut in (printing)" },
	{ "question": "組む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "to cross (legs or arms); to link (arms)\nto put together; to construct; to assemble; to produce (e.g. TV program)\nto braid; to plait\nto grapple; to wrestle\nto unite; to join; to link up; to form an alliance\nto set (e.g. type)\nto issue (e.g. money order)" },
	{ "question": "組合", "answers": [ "くみあい" ], "comment": "association; union; guild" },
	{ "question": "組合せ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "combination" },
	{ "question": "組合わせ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "combination" },
	{ "question": "組曲", "answers": [ "くみきょく" ], "comment": "musical suite; musical selection" },
	{ "question": "組織", "answers": [ "そしき" ], "comment": "organization; organisation\nstructure; construction\ntissue\nsystem" },
	{ "question": "組織的", "answers": [ "そしきてき" ], "comment": "systematic; organized; organizational" },
	{ "question": "組長", "answers": [ "くみちょう" ], "comment": "boss (esp. yakuza); foreman" },
	{ "question": "組閣", "answers": [ "そかく" ], "comment": "formation of a cabinet" },
	{ "question": "絆", "answers": [ "きずな", "きづな" ], "comment": "bonds (between people); (emotional) ties; relationship; connection; link\ntether; fetters" },
	{ "question": "経", "answers": [ "きょう" ], "comment": "sutra; Buddhist scriptures" },
	{ "question": "経つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to pass (of time); to elapse" },
	{ "question": "経る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "to pass; to elapse; to go by\nto pass through; to go through\nto experience; to go through; to undergo" },
	{ "question": "経企庁", "answers": [ "けいきちょう" ], "comment": "Economic Planning Agency (defunct as of 2001)" },
	{ "question": "経営", "answers": [ "けいえい" ], "comment": "management; administration; operation; running (business); conducting" },
	{ "question": "経営者", "answers": [ "けいえいしゃ" ], "comment": "manager; proprietor" },
	{ "question": "経常", "answers": [ "けいつね", "けいじょう" ], "comment": "ordinary" },
	{ "question": "経常利益", "answers": [ "けいじょうりえき" ], "comment": "current profits; ordinary profit; income before income taxes; ordinary income; operating income" },
	{ "question": "経度", "answers": [ "けいど" ], "comment": "longitude" },
	{ "question": "経歴", "answers": [ "けいれき" ], "comment": "personal history; career" },
	{ "question": "経済", "answers": [ "けいざい" ], "comment": "economics; business; finance; economy" },
	{ "question": "経済企画庁", "answers": [ "けいざいきかくちょう" ], "comment": "Economic Planning Agency (defunct as of 2001)" },
	{ "question": "経済封鎖", "answers": [ "けいざいふうさ" ], "comment": "economic blockade; embargo" },
	{ "question": "経済成長率", "answers": [ "けいざいせいちょうりつ" ], "comment": "rate of economic growth" },
	{ "question": "経済界", "answers": [ "けいざいかい" ], "comment": "economic world; financial circles; business community" },
	{ "question": "経済的", "answers": [ "けいざいてき" ], "comment": "economic; economical; financial" },
	{ "question": "経済研究所", "answers": [ "けいざいけんきゅうしょ" ], "comment": "economics research centre; economics research center" },
	{ "question": "経理", "answers": [ "けいり" ], "comment": "management; accounting" },
	{ "question": "経由", "answers": [ "けいゆ", "けいゆう" ], "comment": "through; by way of; via\nto go via; to go by way of" },
	{ "question": "経緯", "answers": [ "いきさつ", "けいい", "たてぬき" ], "comment": "details; particulars; whole story; sequence of events; chronology; circumstances; how it started; how things got this way\nlongitude and latitude\nwarp and weft; warp and woof" },
	{ "question": "経費", "answers": [ "けいひ" ], "comment": "expenses; cost; outlay" },
	{ "question": "経路", "answers": [ "けいろ" ], "comment": "course; route; path; channel\nprocess; means" },
	{ "question": "経過", "answers": [ "けいか" ], "comment": "passage; expiration; progress; transition" },
	{ "question": "経験", "answers": [ "けいけん" ], "comment": "experience" },
	{ "question": "経験値", "answers": [ "けいけんち" ], "comment": "amount of experience\nexperience point (in video games, etc.); exp; XP" },
	{ "question": "経験者", "answers": [ "けいけんしゃ" ], "comment": "experienced person; person who has had a particular experience" },
	{ "question": "経験豊富", "answers": [ "けいけんほうふ" ], "comment": "experienced; well-versed" },
	{ "question": "結う", "answers": [ "いう", "ゆう" ], "comment": "to do up (hair); to braid; to fasten; to fix" },
	{ "question": "結び", "answers": [ "むすび" ], "comment": "ending; conclusion\njoin; union; connecting\nknot; knotting\nrice ball" },
	{ "question": "結びつき", "answers": [ "むすびつき" ], "comment": "connection; relation" },
	{ "question": "結びつく", "answers": [ "むすびつく" ], "comment": "to be related; to be connected; to be joined together\nto result in; to lead to; to bring about" },
	{ "question": "結び付き", "answers": [ "むすびつき" ], "comment": "connection; relation" },
	{ "question": "結ぶ", "answers": [ "むすぶ" ], "comment": "to tie; to bind; to link\nto bear (fruit)\nto close (e.g. deal); to confirm; to conclude\nto connect (two distant places)\nto close tightly; to purse (e.g. lips)\nto unite (with); to ally; to join hands" },
	{ "question": "結党", "answers": [ "けっとう" ], "comment": "formation of a party" },
	{ "question": "結合", "answers": [ "けつごう" ], "comment": "combination; union; binding; catenation; coupling; joining\nbond" },
	{ "question": "結婚", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "marriage" },
	{ "question": "結婚式", "answers": [ "けっこんしき" ], "comment": "marriage ceremony; wedding; nuptials" },
	{ "question": "結婚相手", "answers": [ "けっこんあいて" ], "comment": "marriage partner; spouse\nwife-to-be; husband-to-be; future spouse" },
	{ "question": "結局", "answers": [ "けっきょく" ], "comment": "after all; eventually; in the end\nconclusion; end\nending of a game of Go" },
	{ "question": "結成", "answers": [ "けっせい" ], "comment": "formation; combination" },
	{ "question": "結晶", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "crystal; crystallization; crystallisation\nfruits (of labor, union, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "結末", "answers": [ "けつまつ" ], "comment": "end; conclusion" },
	{ "question": "結束", "answers": [ "けっそく" ], "comment": "union; unity; solidarity\nbundling; binding; tying\nputting on (clothes, armour, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "結果", "answers": [ "けっか" ], "comment": "result; consequence; outcome; effect\ncoming to fruition; bearing fruit" },
	{ "question": "結核", "answers": [ "けっかく" ], "comment": "tuberculosis; tubercule" },
	{ "question": "結構", "answers": [ "けっこう" ], "comment": "splendid; nice; wonderful; delicious; sweet\nsufficient; fine (in the sense of \"I'm fine\"); (by implication) no thank you\nwell enough; OK; tolerable\nquite; reasonably; fairly; tolerably\nconstruction; architecture" },
	{ "question": "結社", "answers": [ "けっしゃ" ], "comment": "association; society" },
	{ "question": "結論", "answers": [ "けつろん" ], "comment": "conclusion" },
	{ "question": "結集", "answers": [ "けっしゅう" ], "comment": "concentration; regimentation" },
	{ "question": "絞り", "answers": [ "しぼり" ], "comment": "tye-dye; tye-dyeing\naperture (e.g. camera, iris of the eye); aperture stop; stop\ncontraction; squeezing; choke" },
	{ "question": "絞り込む", "answers": [ "しぼりこむ" ], "comment": "to squeeze; to wring out\nto narrow down; to refine" },
	{ "question": "絞る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "to wring (towel, rag); to squeeze\nto squeeze (fruit to extract juice); to press; to extract; to milk; to express milk\nto rack (one's brains); to strain (one's voice)\nto extort; to exploit\nto chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke\nto drill into; to train\nto narrow down (one's focus); to whittle down\nto gather up (curtain, etc.); to tighten (drawstring)\nto stop down (lens)\nto turn down (e.g. radio)\nto bend (bow); to draw\nto hold down; to constrict; to immobilize" },
	{ "question": "絡み", "answers": [ "からみ" ], "comment": "linkage; entanglement; involvement; relationship" },
	{ "question": "絡む", "answers": [ "からむ" ], "comment": "to entangle; to entwine\nto pick a quarrel; to find fault\nto be involved with; to be influenced by; to develop a connection with" },
	{ "question": "給与", "answers": [ "きゅうよ" ], "comment": "pay; salary; wages; allowance; grant; supply" },
	{ "question": "給付", "answers": [ "きゅうふ" ], "comment": "payment; provision; benefit; present; delivery\nperformance" },
	{ "question": "給料", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "salary; wages" },
	{ "question": "給水", "answers": [ "きゅうすい" ], "comment": "water supply" },
	{ "question": "給油", "answers": [ "きゅうゆ" ], "comment": "refueling (car, plane, etc.)\nlubricating (a machine); oiling" },
	{ "question": "給油所", "answers": [ "きゅうゆしょ", "きゅうゆじょ" ], "comment": "petrol filling station; gasoline filling station" },
	{ "question": "給食", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "provision of lunch (e.g. at office, school, etc.); providing a meal; lunch service" },
	{ "question": "統一", "answers": [ "とういつ" ], "comment": "unity; consolidation; uniformity; unification; compatible" },
	{ "question": "統一感", "answers": [ "とういつかん" ], "comment": "sense of unity; sense of oneness" },
	{ "question": "統制", "answers": [ "とうせい" ], "comment": "regulation; control" },
	{ "question": "統合", "answers": [ "とうごう" ], "comment": "integration; unification; synthesis\nintegrated; built-in" },
	{ "question": "統括", "answers": [ "とうかつ" ], "comment": "unification; bringing together; generalization\ncontrol; supervision" },
	{ "question": "統治", "answers": [ "とうち", "とうじ" ], "comment": "rule; reign; government; governing" },
	{ "question": "統計", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "statistics" },
	{ "question": "絵", "answers": [ "え" ], "comment": "picture; drawing; painting; sketch" },
	{ "question": "絵の具", "answers": [ "えのぐ" ], "comment": "paint; coloring materials; colors; colours" },
	{ "question": "絵を描く", "answers": [ "えをえがく", "えをかく" ], "comment": "to paint (draw) a picture" },
	{ "question": "絵巻", "answers": [ "えまき" ], "comment": "picture scroll" },
	{ "question": "絵文字", "answers": [ "えもじ" ], "comment": "emoji; pictorial symbol; pictograph" },
	{ "question": "絵本", "answers": [ "えほん" ], "comment": "picture book" },
	{ "question": "絵画", "answers": [ "かいが" ], "comment": "picture; painting" },
	{ "question": "絵葉書", "answers": [ "えはがき" ], "comment": "picture postcard" },
	{ "question": "絶えず", "answers": [ "たえず" ], "comment": "constantly; always; continually; steadily" },
	{ "question": "絶える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to die out; to peter out; to become extinct\nto cease; to be stopped; to be discontinued; to be cut off" },
	{ "question": "絶え間なく", "answers": [ "たえまなく" ], "comment": "incessantly; without a pause" },
	{ "question": "絶つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to sever; to cut off\nto suppress; to eradicate; to exterminate\nto abstain (from); to give up" },
	{ "question": "絶交", "answers": [ "ぜっこう" ], "comment": "breaking off a relationship; permanent breach of friendship; rupture" },
	{ "question": "絶句", "answers": [ "ぜっく" ], "comment": "being lost for words; becoming speechless\njueju (Chinese quatrain with lines of either five or seven syllables)" },
	{ "question": "絶大", "answers": [ "ぜつだい" ], "comment": "tremendous; immense" },
	{ "question": "絶好", "answers": [ "ぜっこう" ], "comment": "best; ideal; perfect" },
	{ "question": "絶好調", "answers": [ "ぜっこうちょう" ], "comment": "in perfect form; going swimmingly" },
	{ "question": "絶妙", "answers": [ "ぜつみょう" ], "comment": "exquisite; superb; perfect; miraculous" },
	{ "question": "絶対", "answers": [ "ぜったい" ], "comment": "absolutely; unconditionally\nabsolute; unconditional; unmistakable\nabsoluteness" },
	{ "question": "絶対に", "answers": [ "ぜったいに" ], "comment": "absolutely; unconditionally; never (with neg. verb)" },
	{ "question": "絶対的", "answers": [ "ぜったいてき" ], "comment": "absolute" },
	{ "question": "絶望", "answers": [ "ぜつぼう" ], "comment": "despair; hopelessness" },
	{ "question": "絶滅", "answers": [ "ぜつめつ" ], "comment": "destruction; extinction" },
	{ "question": "絶縁", "answers": [ "ぜつえん" ], "comment": "breaking off relations; disconnection\ninsulation (esp. electrical); isolation" },
	{ "question": "絶頂", "answers": [ "ぜっちょう" ], "comment": "top (of a mountain); summit\npeak; height; zenith; climax" },
	{ "question": "絹", "answers": [ "きぬ" ], "comment": "silk" },
	{ "question": "絹糸", "answers": [ "きぬいと", "けんし" ], "comment": "silk thread" },
	{ "question": "継ぎはぎ", "answers": [ "つぎはぎ" ], "comment": "patching (clothing); darning\ncobbling together; gathering" },
	{ "question": "継ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "to succeed (someone in a business or inheritance)" },
	{ "question": "継承", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "inheritance; succession; accession" },
	{ "question": "継投", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "relieving the (starting) pitcher" },
	{ "question": "継続", "answers": [ "けいぞく" ], "comment": "continuation" },
	{ "question": "継続的", "answers": [ "けいぞくてき" ], "comment": "continuous" },
	{ "question": "続々", "answers": [ "ぞくぞく" ], "comment": "successively; one after another" },
	{ "question": "続き", "answers": [ "つづき" ], "comment": "sequel; continuation; (also suffix) continuation (in time and space); second series; succession; spell" },
	{ "question": "続く", "answers": [ "つづく" ], "comment": "to continue; to last; to go on\nto continue (without a break); to be unbroken\nto occur again and again\nto lead to; to connect to; to adjoin\nto come after; to follow; to succeed; to rank next to\nto hold out; to keep; to last" },
	{ "question": "続ける", "answers": [ "つづける" ], "comment": "to continue; to keep up; to keep on" },
	{ "question": "続伸", "answers": [ "ぞくしん" ], "comment": "continuous rise" },
	{ "question": "続出", "answers": [ "ぞくしゅつ" ], "comment": "appearance one after another" },
	{ "question": "続編", "answers": [ "ぞくへん" ], "comment": "continuation; sequel" },
	{ "question": "続行", "answers": [ "ぞっこう" ], "comment": "continuation; continuance; going on; resuming" },
	{ "question": "維持", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "maintenance; preservation; improvement" },
	{ "question": "維新", "answers": [ "いしん" ], "comment": "reformation; revolution; renewal\nMeiji Restoration" },
	{ "question": "綱", "answers": [ "つな" ], "comment": "rope\ngrand champion's braided belt" },
	{ "question": "綱引き", "answers": [ "つなひき" ], "comment": "tug of war (orig. a form of divination to predict whether the year will be favourable or unfavourable)\nforward puller (of a rickshaw)" },
	{ "question": "綱渡り", "answers": [ "つなわたり" ], "comment": "tightrope walking; funambulism" },
	{ "question": "綱領", "answers": [ "こうりょう" ], "comment": "general plan; main points; summary; platform (e.g. for a campaign); mission statement" },
	{ "question": "網", "answers": [ "あみ" ], "comment": "net; netting\nweb" },
	{ "question": "網戸", "answers": [ "あみど" ], "comment": "window screen; insect screen; mosquito screen; screen; screen door" },
	{ "question": "網羅", "answers": [ "もうら" ], "comment": "comprising; including; covering; encompassing; comprehending" },
	{ "question": "網膜", "answers": [ "もうまく" ], "comment": "retina" },
	{ "question": "綴", "answers": [ "つづり" ], "comment": "spelling\northography\npatching; binding" },
	{ "question": "綴じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "to bind; to file\nto top with egg (e.g. donburi)" },
	{ "question": "綴り", "answers": [ "つづり" ], "comment": "spelling\northography\npatching; binding" },
	{ "question": "綿", "answers": [ "めん", "わた" ], "comment": "cotton\ncotton plant (Gossypium spp.)​\nbatting; wadding; padding" },
	{ "question": "綿密", "answers": [ "めんみつ" ], "comment": "minute; detailed; careful; scrupulous; thorough" },
	{ "question": "緊密", "answers": [ "きんみつ" ], "comment": "rigour; rigor; closeness; compactness; tightly knit" },
	{ "question": "緊張", "answers": [ "きんちょう" ], "comment": "tension; mental strain; nervousness" },
	{ "question": "緊急", "answers": [ "きんきゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing; emergency" },
	{ "question": "緊縮", "answers": [ "きんしゅく" ], "comment": "shrinkage; contraction; economy; retrenchment" },
	{ "question": "緊迫", "answers": [ "きんぱく" ], "comment": "tension; strain" },
	{ "question": "総", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "whole; all; general; gross; entire; overall" },
	{ "question": "総会", "answers": [ "そうかい" ], "comment": "general meeting" },
	{ "question": "総会屋", "answers": [ "そうかいや" ], "comment": "extortionist that threatens to disrupt stock-holder meetings" },
	{ "question": "総体", "answers": [ "そうたい" ], "comment": "the whole; originally" },
	{ "question": "総力", "answers": [ "そうりょく" ], "comment": "total energy; all efforts" },
	{ "question": "総動員", "answers": [ "そうどういん" ], "comment": "general mobilization; general mobilisation" },
	{ "question": "総務", "answers": [ "そうむ" ], "comment": "general affairs; general business; manager; director; adjutant general" },
	{ "question": "総務局", "answers": [ "そうむきょく" ], "comment": "General Affairs Bureau" },
	{ "question": "総務部", "answers": [ "そうむぶ" ], "comment": "general affairs department (bureau); executive section" },
	{ "question": "総勢", "answers": [ "そうぜい" ], "comment": "all members; whole army" },
	{ "question": "総合", "answers": [ "そうごう" ], "comment": "synthesis; coordination; putting together; integration; composite\ncomprehensive" },
	{ "question": "総合的", "answers": [ "そうごうてき" ], "comment": "synthetic; comprehensive" },
	{ "question": "総帥", "answers": [ "そうすい" ], "comment": "commander-in-chief; leader; head of a group of companies" },
	{ "question": "総当たり", "answers": [ "そうあたり" ], "comment": "round-robin; using all combinations; brute force (e.g. in code-breaking)" },
	{ "question": "総意", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "consensus of opinion" },
	{ "question": "総括", "answers": [ "そうかつ" ], "comment": "synthesis; recap; generalize; generalise" },
	{ "question": "総数", "answers": [ "そうすう" ], "comment": "total (number); count" },
	{ "question": "総本山", "answers": [ "そうほんざん" ], "comment": "head temple of a sect\n(organizational) headquarters; (organisational) headquarters" },
	{ "question": "総決算", "answers": [ "そうけっさん" ], "comment": "complete financial statement\nsumming up; concluding" },
	{ "question": "総理", "answers": [ "そうり" ], "comment": "prime minister (as the head of a cabinet government); premier\nleading; overseeing; leader; overseer; president" },
	{ "question": "総理大臣", "answers": [ "そうりだいじん" ], "comment": "prime minister (as the head of a cabinet government); premier" },
	{ "question": "総理府", "answers": [ "そうりふ" ], "comment": "Prime Minister's office; PMO" },
	{ "question": "総監", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "inspector general; commissioner" },
	{ "question": "総督", "answers": [ "そうとく" ], "comment": "governor-general; governor; viceroy" },
	{ "question": "総統", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "supreme ruler; generalissimo\npresident (of Taiwan)\nfuhrer; fuehrer" },
	{ "question": "総裁", "answers": [ "そうさい" ], "comment": "president (of an organization); director general; governor (of a central bank); party leader (esp. LDP)" },
	{ "question": "総評", "answers": [ "そうひょう" ], "comment": "general comment\nSohyo (General Council of Trade Unions of Japan)" },
	{ "question": "総論", "answers": [ "そうろん" ], "comment": "general remarks" },
	{ "question": "総辞職", "answers": [ "そうじしょく" ], "comment": "mass resignation" },
	{ "question": "総選挙", "answers": [ "そうせんきょ" ], "comment": "general election (of the lower house)" },
	{ "question": "総量", "answers": [ "そうりょう" ], "comment": "aggregate amount" },
	{ "question": "総長", "answers": [ "そうちょう" ], "comment": "(college) president; secretary-general" },
	{ "question": "総領事", "answers": [ "そうりょうじ" ], "comment": "consul general" },
	{ "question": "総額", "answers": [ "そうがく" ], "comment": "sum total; total amount" },
	{ "question": "緑", "answers": [ "みどり" ], "comment": "green\ngreenery (esp. fresh verdure)" },
	{ "question": "緑化", "answers": [ "りょくか", "りょっか" ], "comment": "greening (i.e. planting to increase greenery); tree planting; afforestation" },
	{ "question": "緑地", "answers": [ "りょくち" ], "comment": "green tract of land" },
	{ "question": "緑色", "answers": [ "すいしょく", "みどりいろ", "りょくしょく" ], "comment": "green; emerald green; green color of new foliage; verdure" },
	{ "question": "緑茶", "answers": [ "りょくちゃ" ], "comment": "green tea; Japanese tea" },
	{ "question": "緒", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "cord; strap; thong\nstring (of a musical instrument, bow, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "線", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "line; stripe; stria\nline (e.g. telephone line); wire\nray (e.g. X-ray); beam\nline (e.g. of a railroad); track; route; lane\noutline; contours; form\nlevel\ndivision\nline (of action); position; approach; policy; principle\nimpression one leaves; air one gives off" },
	{ "question": "線路", "answers": [ "せんろ" ], "comment": "railway track; railway line; railroad; railway; track; line" },
	{ "question": "線量", "answers": [ "せんりょう" ], "comment": "dose (of radioactivity)" },
	{ "question": "締まる", "answers": [ "しまる" ], "comment": "to be shut; to close; to be closed\nto be firm (of a body, face, etc.); to be well-knit\nto be locked\nto tighten; to be tightened\nto become sober; to become tense" },
	{ "question": "締め", "answers": [ "しめ" ], "comment": "tie up; bind; fastening; tightening\nsum; total amount; total\njudo choking (strangling) techniques\nlast meal eaten when going restaurant hopping\ncompletion; conclusion; rounding off\ncounter for bundles; counter for faggots; counter for bundles of 2000 sheets of paper\nend mark; closure mark" },
	{ "question": "締める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to tie; to fasten; to tighten\nto wear (necktie, belt); to put on\nto total; to sum\nto be strict with\nto economize; to economise; to cut down on\nto salt; to marinate; to pickle; to make sushi adding a mixture of vinegar and salt" },
	{ "question": "締め付け", "answers": [ "しめつけ" ], "comment": "pressure; clamping; tightening; fastening" },
	{ "question": "締め出す", "answers": [ "しめだす" ], "comment": "to shut out; to bar; to lock out; to exclude" },
	{ "question": "締め切り", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "deadline; closing; cut-off; end\ncofferdam\nclosed (door, window, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "締め切る", "answers": [ "しめきる" ], "comment": "to close up; to shut up (e.g. behind doors)\nto cut off (e.g. because a deadline has expired); to close off (e.g. subscription list)" },
	{ "question": "締切", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "deadline; closing; cut-off; end\ncofferdam\nclosed (door, window, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "締切り", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "deadline; closing; cut-off; end\ncofferdam\nclosed (door, window, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "締約", "answers": [ "ていやく" ], "comment": "conclusion of a treaty" },
	{ "question": "締結", "answers": [ "ていけつ" ], "comment": "conclusion; execution (of a contract); entering (into treaty)\nfastening (as in a joint)" },
	{ "question": "編", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "compilation (of a text); editing\nvolume (of a text)\ncompleted literary work" },
	{ "question": "編み物", "answers": [ "あみもの" ], "comment": "knitting; knitted material; crochet" },
	{ "question": "編む", "answers": [ "あむ" ], "comment": "to knit; to plait; to braid\nto compile (anthology, dictionary, etc.); to edit" },
	{ "question": "編入", "answers": [ "へんにゅう" ], "comment": "admission; incorporation" },
	{ "question": "編成", "answers": [ "へんせい" ], "comment": "composition; formation; organization; organisation; compilation" },
	{ "question": "編物", "answers": [ "あみもの" ], "comment": "knitting; knitted material; crochet" },
	{ "question": "編者", "answers": [ "へんじゃ", "へんしゃ" ], "comment": "editor; compiler" },
	{ "question": "編著", "answers": [ "へんちょ" ], "comment": "compilation" },
	{ "question": "編集", "answers": [ "へんしゅう" ], "comment": "editing; compilation; editorial (e.g. committee)" },
	{ "question": "編集者", "answers": [ "へんしゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "editor (in publishing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "緩い", "answers": [ "ゆるい" ], "comment": "loose\nlenient; lax\ngentle (curve, slope, etc.)\nslow; weak\nsoft; not firm\ndifficult; hard" },
	{ "question": "緩む", "answers": [ "ゆるむ" ], "comment": "to become loose; to slacken (e.g. rope)\nto become less tense; to relax; to let one's guard down\nto slacken (e.g. coldness, supervision); to become lax\nto become softer (e.g. ground, facial expression); (of ice) to partially melt\nto decrease (e.g. speed)\n(of a market price) to go down slightly" },
	{ "question": "緩める", "answers": [ "ゆるめる" ], "comment": "to loosen; to slow down" },
	{ "question": "緩やか", "answers": [ "ゆるやか" ], "comment": "loose; slack\ngentle; easy; slow\nlenient; liberal; lax" },
	{ "question": "緩和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "relief; mitigation; alleviation; relaxation; softening" },
	{ "question": "緩急", "answers": [ "かんきゅう" ], "comment": "pace; tempo; slow and fast\nin case of emergency" },
	{ "question": "緯度", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "latitude (nav.)" },
	{ "question": "練り", "answers": [ "ねり" ], "comment": "kneading; gloss; tempering\npaste (e.g. bean paste, mustard paste)\nparading of portable shrines and floats at festivals" },
	{ "question": "練る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "to knead; to thicken into a paste (stirring over a flame)\nto polish (a plan, etc.); to refine; to elaborate; to work out\nto train; to drill; to exercise\nto gloss (silk); to soften; to degum\nto tan (leather)\nto temper (steel)\nto walk in procession; to parade; to march" },
	{ "question": "練習", "answers": [ "れんしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising" },
	{ "question": "縁", "answers": [ "ふち" ], "comment": "rim; brim; edge; brink" },
	{ "question": "縁側", "answers": [ "えんがわ" ], "comment": "veranda; porch; balcony; open corridor\nbone at the base of a fin; meat at the base of a fin (esp. of a flatfish)" },
	{ "question": "縁談", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "marriage proposal; marriage talks" },
	{ "question": "縁起", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "omen; sign of luck\norigin; causation" },
	{ "question": "縄", "answers": [ "なわ" ], "comment": "rope; cord\npoliceman's rope" },
	{ "question": "縄張り", "answers": [ "なわばり" ], "comment": "stretching a rope around; roping off; cordoning off; demarcation\none's turf; domain; territory; jurisdiction; sphere of influence" },
	{ "question": "縄文", "answers": [ "じょうもん" ], "comment": "Jōmon period\nstraw-rope pattern" },
	{ "question": "縛り首", "answers": [ "しばりくび" ], "comment": "(death by) hanging" },
	{ "question": "縛る", "answers": [ "しばる" ], "comment": "to tie; to bind" },
	{ "question": "縞", "answers": [ "しま" ], "comment": "stripe; bar; streak" },
	{ "question": "縦", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "the vertical; height\nfront-to-back; length\nnorth-to-south\nvertical (relationship); hierarchy\n(weaving) warp" },
	{ "question": "縦断", "answers": [ "じゅうだん" ], "comment": "running through (north-south); cutting across; travelling across\ncutting vertically; sectioning longitudinally" },
	{ "question": "縦書", "answers": [ "たてがき" ], "comment": "vertical writing" },
	{ "question": "縦書き", "answers": [ "たてがき" ], "comment": "vertical writing" },
	{ "question": "縦横", "answers": [ "じゅうおう", "たてよこ" ], "comment": "length and width; length and breadth; lengthwise and crosswise; longitude and latitude; vertical and horizontal\nfour cardinal points; every direction\nas one wishes; as one pleases; at will\nwarp and weft; warp and woof" },
	{ "question": "縫う", "answers": [ "ぬう" ], "comment": "to sew; to stitch\nto weave one's way (e.g. through a crowd)" },
	{ "question": "縫目", "answers": [ "ぬいめ" ], "comment": "seam; stitch; suture" },
	{ "question": "縫製", "answers": [ "ほうせい" ], "comment": "sewing" },
	{ "question": "縮まる", "answers": [ "ちぢまる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to narrow; to close" },
	{ "question": "縮み", "answers": [ "ちぢみ" ], "comment": "shrinkage\ncotton crepe" },
	{ "question": "縮む", "answers": [ "ちぢむ", "ちじむ" ], "comment": "to shrink; to contract; to diminish (in size)" },
	{ "question": "縮める", "answers": [ "ちぢめる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to reduce; to condense; to shrink\nto crumple (fabric); to wrinkle\nto make (one's body) smaller; to draw in (one's legs); to duck (one's head)" },
	{ "question": "縮れる", "answers": [ "ちぢれる" ], "comment": "to be wavy; to be curled; to be frizzled" },
	{ "question": "縮小", "answers": [ "しゅくしょう" ], "comment": "reduction; curtailment" },
	{ "question": "繁栄", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "prospering; prosperity; thriving; flourishing" },
	{ "question": "繁殖", "answers": [ "はんしょく" ], "comment": "breeding; multiplication; increase; propagation; reproduction" },
	{ "question": "繁盛", "answers": [ "はんじょう", "はんせい" ], "comment": "prosperity; flourishing; thriving" },
	{ "question": "繁華街", "answers": [ "はんかがい" ], "comment": "business district; shopping district; bustling street; shopping centre; shopping center; downtown" },
	{ "question": "繊細", "answers": [ "せんさい" ], "comment": "dainty; delicate (e.g. fingers); fine; slim\nsensitive; delicate (feelings, sense, etc.); subtle" },
	{ "question": "繊維", "answers": [ "せんい" ], "comment": "fibre; fiber; textile" },
	{ "question": "織り", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "weave; weaving; woven item" },
	{ "question": "織る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "to weave" },
	{ "question": "織物", "answers": [ "おりもの" ], "comment": "textile; fabric" },
	{ "question": "繕う", "answers": [ "つくろう" ], "comment": "to mend; to patch up; to repair; to fix; to darn; to trim\nto fix (hair, clothes, appearance etc.); to adjust; to tidy up; to groom\nto keep up appearances; to cover up (mistakes etc.); to gloss over\nto treat (illness, injury, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "繭糸", "answers": [ "きぬいと", "けんし" ], "comment": "silk thread" },
	{ "question": "繰り上げ", "answers": [ "くりあげ" ], "comment": "upward move; advance" },
	{ "question": "繰り上げる", "answers": [ "くりあげる" ], "comment": "to move up; to advance" },
	{ "question": "繰り入れ", "answers": [ "くりいれ" ], "comment": "inward transfer (of money); carry over (money from previous period)" },
	{ "question": "繰り出し梯子", "answers": [ "くりだしはしご", "くりだしばしご" ], "comment": "extension ladder; aerial ladder" },
	{ "question": "繰り出す", "answers": [ "くりだす" ], "comment": "to draw (a thread); to let out (e.g. a rope)\nto sally forth\nto send out; to dispatch\nto lunge; to unleash" },
	{ "question": "繰り広げる", "answers": [ "くりひろげる" ], "comment": "to unfold; to unroll; to open" },
	{ "question": "繰り延べ", "answers": [ "くりのべ" ], "comment": "postponement" },
	{ "question": "繰り返し", "answers": [ "くりかえし" ], "comment": "repetition; repeat; reiteration; iteration; refrain; cycle\nrepeatedly" },
	{ "question": "繰り返す", "answers": [ "くりかえす" ], "comment": "to repeat; to do something over again" },
	{ "question": "繰入", "answers": [ "くりいれ" ], "comment": "inward transfer (of money); carry over (money from previous period)" },
	{ "question": "缶", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "can; tin\ncanned food" },
	{ "question": "缶コーヒー", "answers": [ "かんコーヒー" ], "comment": "canned coffee" },
	{ "question": "缶詰", "answers": [ "かんづめ" ], "comment": "canned food; tinned food\nconfining someone (e.g. so they can concentrate on work)\nbeing stuck in a confined space" },
	{ "question": "缶詰め", "answers": [ "かんづめ" ], "comment": "canned food; tinned food\nconfining someone (e.g. so they can concentrate on work)\nbeing stuck in a confined space" },
	{ "question": "罠", "answers": [ "わな" ], "comment": "snare; trap (for catching wild game, etc.)\ntrap (i.e. ruse, subterfuge, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "罪", "answers": [ "つみ" ], "comment": "crime; sin; wrongdoing; indiscretion\npenalty; sentence; punishment\nfault; responsibility; culpability\nthoughtlessness; lack of consideration" },
	{ "question": "置き去り", "answers": [ "おきざり" ], "comment": "desertion; leaving behind; leaving in the lurch" },
	{ "question": "置き場", "answers": [ "おきば" ], "comment": "place for something; storehouse" },
	{ "question": "置き換える", "answers": [ "おきかえる" ], "comment": "to replace; to move; to change the position of" },
	{ "question": "置物", "answers": [ "おきもの" ], "comment": "ornament; figurehead; object placed in tokonoma" },
	{ "question": "罰", "answers": [ "ばち", "ばつ" ], "comment": "(divine) punishment; curse; retribution /\n punishment; penalty" },
	{ "question": "罰する", "answers": [ "ばっする" ], "comment": "to punish; to penalize; to penalise" },
	{ "question": "罰則", "answers": [ "ばっそく" ], "comment": "punishment; penalty\npenal regulations; penal code" },
	{ "question": "罰金", "answers": [ "ばっきん" ], "comment": "fine; penalty" },
	{ "question": "署名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "signature" },
	{ "question": "署員", "answers": [ "しょいん" ], "comment": "staff member; station employee; official" },
	{ "question": "署長", "answers": [ "しょちょう" ], "comment": "chief (of police); head (of office)" },
	{ "question": "罵る", "answers": [ "ののしる" ], "comment": "to abuse (verbally); to curse at; to shout abuse at; to speak ill of" },
	{ "question": "罷免", "answers": [ "ひめん" ], "comment": "dismissal; discharge" },
	{ "question": "羊", "answers": [ "ひつじ" ], "comment": "sheep (Ovis aries)" },
	{ "question": "羊毛", "answers": [ "ようもう" ], "comment": "wool" },
	{ "question": "美", "answers": [ "び" ], "comment": "beauty" },
	{ "question": "美しい", "answers": [ "うつくしい" ], "comment": "beautiful; lovely" },
	{ "question": "美人", "answers": [ "びじん" ], "comment": "beautiful woman" },
	{ "question": "美化", "answers": [ "びか" ], "comment": "beautification; glorification" },
	{ "question": "美女", "answers": [ "びじょ" ], "comment": "beautiful woman" },
	{ "question": "美学", "answers": [ "びがく" ], "comment": "esthetics; aesthetics" },
	{ "question": "美容", "answers": [ "びよう" ], "comment": "beauty of figure or form" },
	{ "question": "美容師", "answers": [ "びようし" ], "comment": "beautician; hairdresser" },
	{ "question": "美容院", "answers": [ "びよういん" ], "comment": "beauty parlour; beauty parlor; beauty salon; hairdressing salon" },
	{ "question": "美意識", "answers": [ "びいしき" ], "comment": "sense of beauty; aesthetic sense" },
	{ "question": "美術", "answers": [ "びじゅつ" ], "comment": "art; fine arts" },
	{ "question": "美術展", "answers": [ "びじゅつてん" ], "comment": "art exhibition" },
	{ "question": "美術館", "answers": [ "びじゅつかん" ], "comment": "art gallery; art museum" },
	{ "question": "群", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "group; bunch; crowd; throng; swarm; band\ngroup" },
	{ "question": "群がる", "answers": [ "むらがる" ], "comment": "to swarm; to gather" },
	{ "question": "群れ", "answers": [ "むれ" ], "comment": "group; crowd; flock; herd; bevy; school; swarm; cluster (e.g. of stars); clump; pack (e.g. of dogs)" },
	{ "question": "群れる", "answers": [ "むれる" ], "comment": "to crowd; to flock; to swarm" },
	{ "question": "群像", "answers": [ "ぐんぞう" ], "comment": "lively group (usu. young people); dynamic bunch\nsculptured group (art)" },
	{ "question": "群島", "answers": [ "ぐんとう" ], "comment": "island group; archipelago" },
	{ "question": "群衆", "answers": [ "ぐんじゅ", "ぐんしゅ", "ぐんしゅう" ], "comment": "group (of people); crowd; horde; throng; mob; multitude" },
	{ "question": "群集", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; community; group; herd; gathering; assembly" },
	{ "question": "義勇", "answers": [ "ぎゆう" ], "comment": "heroism; loyalty and courage" },
	{ "question": "義務", "answers": [ "ぎむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "義務付け", "answers": [ "ぎむづけ" ], "comment": "obligation" },
	{ "question": "義務教育", "answers": [ "ぎむきょういく" ], "comment": "compulsory education" },
	{ "question": "義塾", "answers": [ "ぎじゅく" ], "comment": "private school" },
	{ "question": "義太夫", "answers": [ "ぎだゆう" ], "comment": "gidayuu (type of reciting used in the puppet theater)" },
	{ "question": "義援金", "answers": [ "ぎえんきん" ], "comment": "donation money (esp. disaster relief or charity); contribution" },
	{ "question": "義母", "answers": [ "ぎぼ" ], "comment": "mother-in-law\nfoster mother\nstep mother" },
	{ "question": "義父", "answers": [ "ぎふ" ], "comment": "father-in-law\nfoster father\nstepfather" },
	{ "question": "義理", "answers": [ "ぎり" ], "comment": "duty; sense of duty; honor; honour; decency; courtesy; debt of gratitude; social obligation\nin-law; relation by marriage" },
	{ "question": "羽", "answers": [ "ぱ", "ば", "はね", "わ" ], "comment": "feather; plume; down\nwing\nblade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)\nshuttlecock\narrow feathers /\n counter for birds and rabbits" },
	{ "question": "羽根", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "feather; plume; down\nwing\nblade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)\nshuttlecock\narrow feathers" },
	{ "question": "羽毛", "answers": [ "うもう" ], "comment": "feathers; plumage; down" },
	{ "question": "羽目", "answers": [ "はめ" ], "comment": "panel; wainscoting; wainscotting\nplight; fix; bind; awkward situation; difficult situation; mess" },
	{ "question": "羽織", "answers": [ "はおり" ], "comment": "haori (Japanese formal coat)" },
	{ "question": "翁", "answers": [ "おきな", "おう" ], "comment": "old man; venerable gentleman\nvenerable; old; father" },
	{ "question": "翌年", "answers": [ "よくとし", "よくねん" ], "comment": "following year" },
	{ "question": "翌日", "answers": [ "よくじつ" ], "comment": "next day" },
	{ "question": "翌月", "answers": [ "よくげつ" ], "comment": "following month" },
	{ "question": "翌朝", "answers": [ "よくちょう", "よくあさ" ], "comment": "next morning" },
	{ "question": "習う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "to take lessons in; to be taught; to learn (from a teacher); to study (under a teacher); to get training in" },
	{ "question": "習得", "answers": [ "しゅうとく" ], "comment": "learning; acquisition" },
	{ "question": "習性", "answers": [ "しゅうせい" ], "comment": "habit\nbehavior; behaviour; trait; nature" },
	{ "question": "習慣", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "habit\ncustom; cultural practice" },
	{ "question": "翔る", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to soar; to fly\nto run; to dash" },
	{ "question": "翻す", "answers": [ "ひるがえす" ], "comment": "to turn over; to turn around\nto change (one's mind); to reverse (one's decision); to take back (one's words)\nto fly (flag, etc.); to wave (skirt, cape, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "翻訳", "answers": [ "ほんやく" ], "comment": "translation\nde-encryption; deciphering\nrendering" },
	{ "question": "翼", "answers": [ "つばさ", "よく" ], "comment": "wing\nChinese \"Wings\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\ncounter for birds or bird wings" },
	{ "question": "老い", "answers": [ "おい" ], "comment": "old age; old person; the old; the aged" },
	{ "question": "老いる", "answers": [ "おいる" ], "comment": "to age; to grow old" },
	{ "question": "老ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to age; to grow old (esp. in appearance); to show marks of age" },
	{ "question": "老人", "answers": [ "ろうじん" ], "comment": "the aged; old person" },
	{ "question": "老人ホーム", "answers": [ "ろうじんホーム" ], "comment": "retirement home; old people's home; senior citizens' home" },
	{ "question": "老人性", "answers": [ "ろうじんせい" ], "comment": "senile" },
	{ "question": "老人福祉", "answers": [ "ろうじんふくし" ], "comment": "welfare for the aged" },
	{ "question": "老化", "answers": [ "ろうか" ], "comment": "ageing; aging; senile deterioration" },
	{ "question": "老夫婦", "answers": [ "ろうふうふ" ], "comment": "old couple; elderly couple" },
	{ "question": "老女", "answers": [ "ろうじょ" ], "comment": "elderly woman; senior lady-in-waiting" },
	{ "question": "老婦", "answers": [ "ろうふ" ], "comment": "old woman" },
	{ "question": "老年", "answers": [ "ろうねん" ], "comment": "old age" },
	{ "question": "老後", "answers": [ "ろうご" ], "comment": "old age" },
	{ "question": "老朽", "answers": [ "ろうきゅう" ], "comment": "superannuated; decrepitude" },
	{ "question": "老眼", "answers": [ "ろうがん" ], "comment": "presbyopia; age-related longsightedness; farsightedness" },
	{ "question": "老舗", "answers": [ "しにせ", "ろうほ" ], "comment": "old shop; shop of long standing\nwell-established; first of the kind; veteran" },
	{ "question": "老若", "answers": [ "ろうにゃく", "ろうじゃく" ], "comment": "young and old; all ages" },
	{ "question": "老衰", "answers": [ "ろうすい" ], "comment": "senility; senile decay; infirmity (through age)" },
	{ "question": "老齢", "answers": [ "ろうれい" ], "comment": "advanced age; senility" },
	{ "question": "考え", "answers": [ "かんがえ" ], "comment": "thinking; thought; view; opinion; concept\nidea; notion; imagination\nintention; plan; design\nconsideration; judgement; deliberation; reflection\nwish; hope; expectation" },
	{ "question": "考える", "answers": [ "かんがえる" ], "comment": "to think about; to take into consideration\nto ponder; to reflect; to try to come at a conclusion; to think over (something)\nto intend; to decide (to do); to plan\nto come up with; to devise; to scheme\nto predict; to anticipate; to expect\nto suspect; to doubt\nto consider (somebody to be something); to look on" },
	{ "question": "考え方", "answers": [ "かんがえかた" ], "comment": "way of thinking" },
	{ "question": "考え直す", "answers": [ "かんがえなおす" ], "comment": "to reconsider; to rethink; to reassess" },
	{ "question": "考古学", "answers": [ "こうこがく" ], "comment": "archaeology; archeology" },
	{ "question": "考察", "answers": [ "こうさつ" ], "comment": "consideration; inquiry; enquiry; investigation; study" },
	{ "question": "考慮", "answers": [ "こうりょ" ], "comment": "consideration; taking into account" },
	{ "question": "者", "answers": [ "もの", "もん" ], "comment": "person" },
	{ "question": "耐える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to bear; to stand; to endure; to put up with\nto support; to withstand; to resist; to brave\nto be fit for; to be equal to" },
	{ "question": "耐久", "answers": [ "たいきゅう" ], "comment": "endurance; persistence" },
	{ "question": "耐久性", "answers": [ "たいきゅうせい" ], "comment": "durability" },
	{ "question": "耐性", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "resistance (e.g. to antibiotics); tolerance (e.g. drug tolerance)" },
	{ "question": "耕す", "answers": [ "たがやす" ], "comment": "to till; to plow; to plough; to cultivate" },
	{ "question": "耕作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "cultivation; farming" },
	{ "question": "耳", "answers": [ "みみ" ], "comment": "ear\nhearing\nedge; crust\nselvedge (non-fray machined edge of fabrics); selvage" },
	{ "question": "耳より", "answers": [ "みみより" ], "comment": "welcome (news); inviting; encouraging; tempting; hopeful" },
	{ "question": "耳元", "answers": [ "みみもと" ], "comment": "close to the ear" },
	{ "question": "耳寄り", "answers": [ "みみより" ], "comment": "welcome (news); inviting; encouraging; tempting; hopeful" },
	{ "question": "耳障り", "answers": [ "みみざわり" ], "comment": "hard (on the ears); offensive (to the ear); rasping; rough; harsh; grating; jarring; cacophonous" },
	{ "question": "耳鼻科", "answers": [ "じびか" ], "comment": "otolaryngology; concerning the ear, nose, and throat" },
	{ "question": "聖地", "answers": [ "せいち" ], "comment": "sacred place; holy ground; the Holy Land" },
	{ "question": "聖域", "answers": [ "せいいき" ], "comment": "sacred precincts; sanctuary; consecrated ground; holy ground\nissue that is regarded as being off-limits; matter that is not up for discussion" },
	{ "question": "聖堂", "answers": [ "せいどう" ], "comment": "(Confucian) temple; church; sanctuary" },
	{ "question": "聖戦", "answers": [ "せいせん" ], "comment": "holy war; crusade" },
	{ "question": "聖書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "Bible; scriptures" },
	{ "question": "聖火", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "sacred fire (torch)\nOlympic flame" },
	{ "question": "聖職者", "answers": [ "せいしょくしゃ" ], "comment": "clergyman; churchman; clergy" },
	{ "question": "聞かす", "answers": [ "きかす" ], "comment": "to inform about; to read to; to sing for" },
	{ "question": "聞き取り", "answers": [ "ききとり" ], "comment": "listening comprehension; aural comprehension\nhearing what others say; gathering information, opinions, etc.; public hearing" },
	{ "question": "聞き手", "answers": [ "ききて" ], "comment": "hearer; listener; audience\ninterviewer; questioner" },
	{ "question": "聞き書き", "answers": [ "ききがき" ], "comment": "writing down what one hears; account of what one hears" },
	{ "question": "聞く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "to hear\nto listen (e.g. to music)\nto ask; to enquire; to query\nto learn of; to hear about\nto follow (advice); to comply with\nto smell (esp. incense); to sample fragrance" },
	{ "question": "聞こえる", "answers": [ "きこえる" ], "comment": "to be heard; to be audible\nto be said to be; to be reputed" },
	{ "question": "聴取", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅ" ], "comment": "listening; hearing; audition\nradio reception" },
	{ "question": "聴聞", "answers": [ "ちょうもん" ], "comment": "listening; hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴衆", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "audience; attendance; hearers" },
	{ "question": "聴覚", "answers": [ "ちょうかく" ], "comment": "the sense of hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴講", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "lecture attendance; auditing" },
	{ "question": "職", "answers": [ "しょく" ], "comment": "job; work; employment; occupation; position\nduties\ntrade; skill" },
	{ "question": "職人", "answers": [ "しょくにん" ], "comment": "worker; mechanic; artisan; craftsman" },
	{ "question": "職務", "answers": [ "しょくむ" ], "comment": "professional duties" },
	{ "question": "職員", "answers": [ "しょくいん" ], "comment": "staff member; personnel" },
	{ "question": "職場", "answers": [ "しょくば" ], "comment": "one's post; place of work; workplace" },
	{ "question": "職業", "answers": [ "しょくぎょう" ], "comment": "occupation; business" },
	{ "question": "職権", "answers": [ "しょっけん" ], "comment": "authority; commission" },
	{ "question": "職歴", "answers": [ "しょくれき" ], "comment": "work experience; work history" },
	{ "question": "職種", "answers": [ "しょくしゅ" ], "comment": "type of occupation; occupational category" },
	{ "question": "職能", "answers": [ "しょくのう" ], "comment": "occupational ability\nfunction; role" },
	{ "question": "肉", "answers": [ "しし", "にく" ], "comment": "flesh\nmeat\nthe physical body (as opposed to the spirit)\nthickness\nink pad" },
	{ "question": "肉体", "answers": [ "にくたい" ], "comment": "the body; the flesh" },
	{ "question": "肉体的", "answers": [ "にくたいてき" ], "comment": "corporeal; material" },
	{ "question": "肉声", "answers": [ "にくせい" ], "comment": "natural voice (without a microphone)" },
	{ "question": "肉眼", "answers": [ "にくがん", "にくげん" ], "comment": "naked eye\nthe physical eye" },
	{ "question": "肉薄", "answers": [ "にくはく" ], "comment": "closing in on (the enemy, first place, etc.); coming close to; pressing hard\npressing hard (e.g. with a question); taking to task; grilling" },
	{ "question": "肉親", "answers": [ "にくしん" ], "comment": "blood relationship; blood relative" },
	{ "question": "肉食", "answers": [ "にくしょく" ], "comment": "meat eating; eating of meat; meat diet\ncarnivorous" },
	{ "question": "肌", "answers": [ "はだえ", "はだ" ], "comment": "skin\nbody (in the context of intimate bodily contact)\nsurface; grain (e.g. of wood); texture\ndisposition; temperament; character; type" },
	{ "question": "肌着", "answers": [ "はだぎ", "はだぎぬ" ], "comment": "underwear; underclothes; lingerie; chemise; singlet" },
	{ "question": "肌色", "answers": [ "はだいろ" ], "comment": "flesh-coloured; flesh-colored; skin-coloured; skin-colored" },
	{ "question": "肖像", "answers": [ "しょうぞう" ], "comment": "portrait; likeness; picture" },
	{ "question": "肘", "answers": [ "ひじ" ], "comment": "elbow" },
	{ "question": "肝", "answers": [ "たん", "きも" ], "comment": "liver; innards\ncourage; spirit; pluck; guts\ncrux; essential point" },
	{ "question": "肝心", "answers": [ "かんじん" ], "comment": "essential; fundamental; crucial; vital; main" },
	{ "question": "肝炎", "answers": [ "かんえん" ], "comment": "hepatitis" },
	{ "question": "肝硬変", "answers": [ "かんこうへん" ], "comment": "cirrhosis of the liver" },
	{ "question": "肝臓", "answers": [ "かんぞう" ], "comment": "liver" },
	{ "question": "肝要", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "extremely important; essential; vital; crucial" },
	{ "question": "股", "answers": [ "もも", "また" ], "comment": "crotch; crutch; groin; thigh\nfork (in a tree, road, river, etc.); tines (of a fork) /\n thigh\nfemoral" },
	{ "question": "肥", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "manure; night soil; dung; fertiliser; fertilizer" },
	{ "question": "肥える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to grow fat; to gain weight; to put on weight\nto grow fertile\nto be refined (palate); to be discerning (eye, ear)\nto become rich; to become successful" },
	{ "question": "肥大", "answers": [ "ひだい" ], "comment": "swelling; enlargement; becoming fat\nhypertrophy" },
	{ "question": "肥料", "answers": [ "ひりょう" ], "comment": "manure; fertilizer; fertiliser" },
	{ "question": "肥満", "answers": [ "ひまん" ], "comment": "corpulence; fatness; obesity" },
	{ "question": "肩", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "shoulder" },
	{ "question": "肩代わり", "answers": [ "かたがわり" ], "comment": "taking over another's debt; shouldering someone else's burden; subrogation" },
	{ "question": "肩書", "answers": [ "かたがき" ], "comment": "title; degree; address (on letter); criminal record" },
	{ "question": "肩書き", "answers": [ "かたがき" ], "comment": "title; degree; address (on letter); criminal record" },
	{ "question": "肯定", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "positive; affirmation" },
	{ "question": "育ち", "answers": [ "そだち" ], "comment": "breeding; growth" },
	{ "question": "育つ", "answers": [ "そだつ" ], "comment": "to be raised (e.g. child); to be brought up; to grow (up)" },
	{ "question": "育てる", "answers": [ "そだてる" ], "comment": "to raise; to rear; to bring up\nto train; to teach; to educate\nto promote the growth of; to nurture; to foster; to develop" },
	{ "question": "育む", "answers": [ "はぐくむ" ], "comment": "to raise; to bring up; to rear\nto cultivate; to foster; to nurture" },
	{ "question": "育児", "answers": [ "いくじ" ], "comment": "childcare; child-rearing; nursing; upbringing" },
	{ "question": "育成", "answers": [ "いくせい" ], "comment": "rearing; training; nurture; cultivation; promotion" },
	{ "question": "育英", "answers": [ "いくえい" ], "comment": "education" },
	{ "question": "肺", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "lung" },
	{ "question": "肺炎", "answers": [ "はいえん" ], "comment": "pneumonia" },
	{ "question": "胃", "answers": [ "い" ], "comment": "stomach\nChinese \"stomach\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "胃腸", "answers": [ "いちょう" ], "comment": "stomach and intestines; gastrointestinal tract; digestive organs" },
	{ "question": "胆", "answers": [ "たん", "きも" ], "comment": "liver; innards\ncourage; spirit; pluck; guts\ncrux; essential point" },
	{ "question": "胆石", "answers": [ "たんせき" ], "comment": "gallstones" },
	{ "question": "背", "answers": [ "せ", "せい" ], "comment": "height; stature /\n back; spine\nreverse; rear side\nheight; stature\nridge (of a mountain)" },
	{ "question": "背く", "answers": [ "そむく" ], "comment": "to run counter to; to go against; to disobey; to infringe" },
	{ "question": "背中", "answers": [ "せなか" ], "comment": "back (of body)" },
	{ "question": "背任", "answers": [ "はいにん" ], "comment": "breach of trust; malfeasance; malpractice; misappropriation" },
	{ "question": "背信", "answers": [ "はいしん" ], "comment": "betrayal; infidelity" },
	{ "question": "背広", "answers": [ "せびろ" ], "comment": "business suit" },
	{ "question": "背後", "answers": [ "はいご" ], "comment": "back; rear\nbackground; behind the scenes" },
	{ "question": "背景", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "background; scenery; backdrop; setting; circumstance; context\nbacking; support (from behind the scenes)" },
	{ "question": "背泳ぎ", "answers": [ "せおよぎ" ], "comment": "backstroke (swim.)" },
	{ "question": "背番号", "answers": [ "せばんごう" ], "comment": "number on player's back" },
	{ "question": "背筋", "answers": [ "せすじ", "はいきん" ], "comment": "the muscles along the spine; dorsal muscles\nspinal column\nseam in the back; back seam" },
	{ "question": "背負う", "answers": [ "しょう", "せおう" ], "comment": "to carry on one's back\nto be burdened with; to take responsibility for\nto have (something) in the background; to be in front (of something)\nto be conceited; to think highly of oneself" },
	{ "question": "背骨", "answers": [ "せぼね" ], "comment": "spine; backbone; spinal column" },
	{ "question": "胎児", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "fetus; foetus; embryo; unborn child" },
	{ "question": "胴", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "trunk; torso; body; abdomen; waist\nplastron (in kendo); touching the plastron (kimari-te in kendo)\nframe (of a drum, etc.); sound box (of a shamisen, etc.); hull (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "胴上げ", "answers": [ "どうあげ" ], "comment": "lifting a person high (in celebration); tossing someone into the air; carrying someone on shoulders" },
	{ "question": "胴体", "answers": [ "どうたい" ], "comment": "body; trunk; torso; hull (boat); fuselage (aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "胸", "answers": [ "むな", "むね" ], "comment": "chest; breast\nbreasts; bosom; bust\nheart\nlungs\nstomach\nheart; mind; feelings" },
	{ "question": "胸中", "answers": [ "きょうちゅう" ], "comment": "one's heart; one's mind; one's intentions" },
	{ "question": "胸部", "answers": [ "きょうぶ" ], "comment": "chest; breast" },
	{ "question": "能", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "talent; gift; function\nnoh (theatre)" },
	{ "question": "能力", "answers": [ "のうりょく" ], "comment": "ability; faculty" },
	{ "question": "能動", "answers": [ "のうどう" ], "comment": "active" },
	{ "question": "能動的", "answers": [ "のうどうてき" ], "comment": "active" },
	{ "question": "能楽", "answers": [ "のうがく" ], "comment": "noh play" },
	{ "question": "能率", "answers": [ "のうりつ" ], "comment": "efficiency\nmoment (i.e. magnetic moment)" },
	{ "question": "脂", "answers": [ "あぶら" ], "comment": "fat; tallow; lard; grease" },
	{ "question": "脂肪", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "fat; grease; blubber" },
	{ "question": "脅かす", "answers": [ "おびやかす", "おどかす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace\nto startle; to surprise /\n to intimidate; to scare\nto jeopardize; to endanger; to imperil" },
	{ "question": "脅し", "answers": [ "おどし" ], "comment": "threat" },
	{ "question": "脅す", "answers": [ "おどす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace; to bully" },
	{ "question": "脅威", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "threat; menace" },
	{ "question": "脅迫", "answers": [ "きょうはく" ], "comment": "threat; menace; coercion; terrorism" },
	{ "question": "脇", "answers": [ "わき" ], "comment": "armpit; under one's arm; side; flank\nbeside; close to; near; by\naside; to the side; away; out of the way\noff-track; off-topic\ndeuteragonist; supporting role\nsecond verse (in a linked series of poems)" },
	{ "question": "脇役", "answers": [ "わきやく" ], "comment": "supporting role (actor); minor role" },
	{ "question": "脇見", "answers": [ "ぼうし", "わきみ" ], "comment": "looking from the side\nlooking aside" },
	{ "question": "脈", "answers": [ "みゃく" ], "comment": "pulse\nvein\nchain (of mountains, etc.)\nhope\nthread (of an argument)" },
	{ "question": "脈拍", "answers": [ "みゃくはく" ], "comment": "pulse; pulse rate; pulsation; stroke of pulse" },
	{ "question": "脈絡", "answers": [ "みゃくらく" ], "comment": "chain of reasoning; logical connection; coherence; context" },
	{ "question": "脚", "answers": [ "あし" ], "comment": "foot\nleg\ngait\npace\nbottom structural component (i.e. radical) of a kanji\nmeans of transportation\nmoney; coin" },
	{ "question": "脚光", "answers": [ "きゃっこう" ], "comment": "footlight; limelight" },
	{ "question": "脚本", "answers": [ "きゃくほん" ], "comment": "script; screenplay; scenario" },
	{ "question": "脚色", "answers": [ "きゃくしょく" ], "comment": "dramatization (e.g. of a novel); dramatisation; adaptation\ndramatization; embellishment; exaggeration; embroidery" },
	{ "question": "脱ぐ", "answers": [ "ぬぐ" ], "comment": "to take off (clothes, shoes, etc.); to undress" },
	{ "question": "脱する", "answers": [ "だっする" ], "comment": "to escape from; to get out" },
	{ "question": "脱出", "answers": [ "だっしゅつ" ], "comment": "escape; break-out\nprolapse; proptosis" },
	{ "question": "脱却", "answers": [ "だっきゃく" ], "comment": "ridding oneself; freeing oneself of; growing out of; overcoming; outgrowing" },
	{ "question": "脱水", "answers": [ "だっすい" ], "comment": "evaporation; dehydration; dessication" },
	{ "question": "脱皮", "answers": [ "だっぴ" ], "comment": "ecdysis; shedding (of skin); sloughing; molting; moulting; casting off\nfreeing oneself; breaking with (convention, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "脱硫", "answers": [ "だつりゅう" ], "comment": "desulfurization; desulphurisation; desulphurization" },
	{ "question": "脱税", "answers": [ "だつぜい" ], "comment": "tax evasion" },
	{ "question": "脱線", "answers": [ "だっせん" ], "comment": "derailment\ndigression; deviation" },
	{ "question": "脱落", "answers": [ "だつらく" ], "comment": "loss; dropping out; falling by the wayside\nomission; lacuna; gap; hiatus\ndesertion; defection\napostasy" },
	{ "question": "脱衣", "answers": [ "だつい" ], "comment": "undressing; taking off one's clothes" },
	{ "question": "脱衣所", "answers": [ "だついじょ", "だついしょ" ], "comment": "dressing room; bath house" },
	{ "question": "脱走", "answers": [ "だっそう" ], "comment": "desertion; escape" },
	{ "question": "脱退", "answers": [ "だったい" ], "comment": "secession; retirement; withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)" },
	{ "question": "脳", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "brain\nbrains; mind" },
	{ "question": "脳出血", "answers": [ "のうしゅっけつ" ], "comment": "cerebral hemorrhage; cerebral haemorrhage" },
	{ "question": "脳卒中", "answers": [ "のうそっちゅう" ], "comment": "stroke; cerebral haemorrhage; cerebral hemorrhage" },
	{ "question": "脳死", "answers": [ "のうし" ], "comment": "brain death" },
	{ "question": "脳波", "answers": [ "のうは" ], "comment": "brain waves\nelectroencephalogram; EEG" },
	{ "question": "脳裏", "answers": [ "のうり" ], "comment": "one's mind" },
	{ "question": "腎臓", "answers": [ "じんぞう" ], "comment": "kidney" },
	{ "question": "腐心", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "taking pains to; racking one's brains; doing everything one can" },
	{ "question": "腐敗", "answers": [ "ふはい" ], "comment": "decomposition; putrefaction; putrescence; spoilage\ncorruption; degeneracy; decay; depravity" },
	{ "question": "腕", "answers": [ "うで" ], "comment": "arm\nskill; efforts; ability" },
	{ "question": "腕前", "answers": [ "うでまえ" ], "comment": "ability; skill; facility" },
	{ "question": "腕力", "answers": [ "わんりょく" ], "comment": "physical strength; brute strength; arm strength" },
	{ "question": "腕時計", "answers": [ "うでどけい" ], "comment": "wristwatch" },
	{ "question": "腫れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "to swell (from inflammation); to become swollen" },
	{ "question": "腰", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "back; lower back; waist; hips; lumbar region\nbody (of hair, noodle, paper, etc.); resilience; spring" },
	{ "question": "腰掛", "answers": [ "こしかけ" ], "comment": "seat; bench" },
	{ "question": "腰掛け", "answers": [ "こしかけ" ], "comment": "seat; bench" },
	{ "question": "腰掛ける", "answers": [ "こしかける" ], "comment": "to sit (down)" },
	{ "question": "腰痛", "answers": [ "ようつう" ], "comment": "lower back (or hip) pain; lumbago" },
	{ "question": "腸", "answers": [ "わた", "ちょう", "はらわた" ], "comment": "guts; bowels; intestines" },
	{ "question": "腹", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "abdomen; belly; stomach\nwomb\none's mind; one's real intentions; one's true motive\ncourage; nerve; willpower\ngenerosity; magnanimity\nfeelings; emotions\nwide middle part; bulging part\ninside; interior; inner part\nanti-node\ncounter for hard roe\ncounter for containers with bulging middles (pots, vases, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "腹一杯", "answers": [ "はらいっぱい" ], "comment": "full stomach; bellyful; (eat) heartily\nto one's heart's content" },
	{ "question": "腹心", "answers": [ "ふくしん" ], "comment": "one's confidant; trusted friend; trusted retainer" },
	{ "question": "腹痛", "answers": [ "はらいた", "ふくつう" ], "comment": "stomach ache; abdominal pain" },
	{ "question": "腹部", "answers": [ "ふくぶ" ], "comment": "abdomen" },
	{ "question": "膜", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "membrane; film" },
	{ "question": "膝", "answers": [ "ひざ" ], "comment": "knee\nlap; knee and thigh (while sitting)" },
	{ "question": "膨らます", "answers": [ "ふくらます" ], "comment": "to swell; to expand; to inflate; to bulge" },
	{ "question": "膨らむ", "answers": [ "ふくらむ" ], "comment": "to expand; to swell (out); to get big; to become inflated" },
	{ "question": "膨れる", "answers": [ "ふくれる" ], "comment": "to swell (out); to expand; to be inflated; to distend; to bulge\nto get cross; to get sulky; to pout" },
	{ "question": "膨大", "answers": [ "ぼうだい" ], "comment": "huge; vast; enormous; colossal; extensive; multitudinous\nswelling; expansion" },
	{ "question": "膨張", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; swelling; increase; growth" },
	{ "question": "膨脹", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; swelling; increase; growth" },
	{ "question": "膳", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "small dining table (usu. for a single person); serving tray (with legs)\nmeal; food; serving\ncounter for bowlfuls of rice; counter for pairs of chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "臆病", "answers": [ "おくびょう" ], "comment": "cowardice; timidity" },
	{ "question": "臆病者", "answers": [ "おくびょうもの" ], "comment": "coward" },
	{ "question": "臓器", "answers": [ "ぞうき" ], "comment": "internal organs; viscera; intestines" },
	{ "question": "臨む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "to look out on\nto face\nto deal with\nto attend (e.g. function); to appear (e.g. in court)" },
	{ "question": "臨場感", "answers": [ "りんじょうかん" ], "comment": "(sense of) presence; realism; ambiance" },
	{ "question": "臨床", "answers": [ "りんしょう" ], "comment": "clinical (e.g. pathology, physiology)" },
	{ "question": "臨時", "answers": [ "りんじ" ], "comment": "temporary; special; extraordinary" },
	{ "question": "臨海", "answers": [ "りんかい" ], "comment": "coastal; seaside; oceanfront; maritime" },
	{ "question": "臨界", "answers": [ "りんかい" ], "comment": "critical (pressure, temperature, state, point)" },
	{ "question": "臨終", "answers": [ "りんじゅう" ], "comment": "deathbed; dying hour; one's death" },
	{ "question": "自ら", "answers": [ "みずから" ], "comment": "oneself\nfor one's self; personally" },
	{ "question": "自主", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "independence; autonomy" },
	{ "question": "自主的", "answers": [ "じしゅてき" ], "comment": "independent; autonomous; voluntary; of one's own initiative; unilateral" },
	{ "question": "自他", "answers": [ "じた" ], "comment": "oneself and others\ntransitive and intransitive" },
	{ "question": "自任", "answers": [ "じにん" ], "comment": "self-appointment; pretension" },
	{ "question": "自伝", "answers": [ "じでん" ], "comment": "autobiography" },
	{ "question": "自作", "answers": [ "じさく" ], "comment": "one's own work" },
	{ "question": "自信", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "self-confidence; confidence (in oneself)" },
	{ "question": "自分", "answers": [ "じぶん" ], "comment": "myself; yourself; oneself; himself; herself\nI; me\nyou" },
	{ "question": "自分で", "answers": [ "じぶんで" ], "comment": "by myself; in person; by oneself" },
	{ "question": "自分自身", "answers": [ "じぶんじしん" ], "comment": "oneself; myself" },
	{ "question": "自制", "answers": [ "じせい" ], "comment": "self control; self restraint" },
	{ "question": "自前", "answers": [ "じまえ" ], "comment": "taking care of one's responsibilities by oneself; one's own efforts; one's own expense\ngoing into business for oneself (selling one's own products); entrepreneur of such a business" },
	{ "question": "自力", "answers": [ "じりき", "じりょく" ], "comment": "one's own strength; one's own efforts\nself-salvation" },
	{ "question": "自助", "answers": [ "じじょ" ], "comment": "self-help" },
	{ "question": "自動", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "automatic; self-motion\nintransitive verb" },
	{ "question": "自動化", "answers": [ "じどうか" ], "comment": "automation" },
	{ "question": "自動的", "answers": [ "じどうてき" ], "comment": "automatic" },
	{ "question": "自動販売機", "answers": [ "じどうはんばいき" ], "comment": "vending machine" },
	{ "question": "自動車", "answers": [ "じどうしゃ" ], "comment": "automobile" },
	{ "question": "自問", "answers": [ "じもん" ], "comment": "asking oneself" },
	{ "question": "自営", "answers": [ "じえい" ], "comment": "independent; self-employed; self-supporting; operating own business" },
	{ "question": "自営業", "answers": [ "じえいぎょう" ], "comment": "independent business" },
	{ "question": "自国", "answers": [ "じこく" ], "comment": "one's own country" },
	{ "question": "自在", "answers": [ "じざい" ], "comment": "freely; at will" },
	{ "question": "自宅", "answers": [ "じたく" ], "comment": "one's home; one's house" },
	{ "question": "自室", "answers": [ "じしつ" ], "comment": "one's own room" },
	{ "question": "自家", "answers": [ "じか" ], "comment": "own; personal; autologous" },
	{ "question": "自家用", "answers": [ "じかよう" ], "comment": "for private or home use" },
	{ "question": "自己", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "self; oneself" },
	{ "question": "自己管理", "answers": [ "じこかんり" ], "comment": "taking care of something by oneself; self-management" },
	{ "question": "自己資本", "answers": [ "じこしほん" ], "comment": "net worth; owned capital" },
	{ "question": "自律", "answers": [ "じりつ" ], "comment": "autonomy (philosophy)\nself-control" },
	{ "question": "自慢", "answers": [ "じまん" ], "comment": "pride; boast" },
	{ "question": "自我", "answers": [ "じが" ], "comment": "self; the ego" },
	{ "question": "自明", "answers": [ "じめい" ], "comment": "obvious; self-evident; trivial; axiomatic; self-explanatory" },
	{ "question": "自棄", "answers": [ "じき", "やけ" ], "comment": "desperation; despair; self-abandonment" },
	{ "question": "自殺", "answers": [ "じさつ" ], "comment": "suicide" },
	{ "question": "自民", "answers": [ "じみん" ], "comment": "Liberal Democratic Party; LDP" },
	{ "question": "自民党", "answers": [ "じみんとう" ], "comment": "Liberal Democratic Party; LDP" },
	{ "question": "自決", "answers": [ "じけつ" ], "comment": "self-determination\nsuicide" },
	{ "question": "自治", "answers": [ "じち" ], "comment": "self-government; autonomy\nlocal (governmental) autonomy" },
	{ "question": "自治体", "answers": [ "じちたい" ], "comment": "municipality; local government; self-governing body; autonomous entity" },
	{ "question": "自治権", "answers": [ "じちけん" ], "comment": "autonomy; right of self-government" },
	{ "question": "自治省", "answers": [ "じちしょう" ], "comment": "(former) Ministry of Home Affairs" },
	{ "question": "自活", "answers": [ "じかつ" ], "comment": "self-support" },
	{ "question": "自浄", "answers": [ "じじょう" ], "comment": "self-purification; self-cleansing" },
	{ "question": "自滅", "answers": [ "じめつ" ], "comment": "ruining oneself; destroying oneself; self-destruction" },
	{ "question": "自炊", "answers": [ "じすい" ], "comment": "cooking for oneself; cooking one's own food; doing one's own cooking; making food oneself; self-catering\nscanning a book or magazine to create an ebook by oneself" },
	{ "question": "自然", "answers": [ "しぜん" ], "comment": "nature\nnatural; spontaneous\nnaturally; spontaneously" },
	{ "question": "自然に", "answers": [ "しぜんに" ], "comment": "naturally; smoothly; spontaneously" },
	{ "question": "自然公園", "answers": [ "しぜんこうえん" ], "comment": "nature park; natural park" },
	{ "question": "自然界", "answers": [ "しぜんかい" ], "comment": "nature; the natural world; realm of nature" },
	{ "question": "自然科学", "answers": [ "しぜんかがく" ], "comment": "natural science" },
	{ "question": "自由", "answers": [ "じゆう" ], "comment": "freedom; liberty; as it pleases you" },
	{ "question": "自由主義", "answers": [ "じゆうしゅぎ" ], "comment": "liberalism" },
	{ "question": "自由化", "answers": [ "じゆうか" ], "comment": "liberalization; liberalisation; freeing" },
	{ "question": "自由形", "answers": [ "じゆうがた" ], "comment": "freestyle (e.g. swimming event)" },
	{ "question": "自由経済", "answers": [ "じゆうけいざい" ], "comment": "free economy" },
	{ "question": "自発", "answers": [ "じはつ" ], "comment": "spontaneous" },
	{ "question": "自発的", "answers": [ "じはつてき" ], "comment": "spontaneous; voluntary" },
	{ "question": "自白", "answers": [ "じはく" ], "comment": "confession; acknowledgement; acknowledgment" },
	{ "question": "自社", "answers": [ "じしゃ" ], "comment": "one's company; company one works for\nin-house; belonging to the company" },
	{ "question": "自称", "answers": [ "じしょう" ], "comment": "self-alleged; self-proclaimed; calling oneself; self-styled; would-be\nfirst person" },
	{ "question": "自立", "answers": [ "じりつ" ], "comment": "independence; self-reliance" },
	{ "question": "自筆", "answers": [ "じひつ" ], "comment": "one's own handwriting; autograph; holograph" },
	{ "question": "自粛", "answers": [ "じしゅく" ], "comment": "self-restraint; self-control; self-discipline" },
	{ "question": "自給", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "self-support" },
	{ "question": "自習", "answers": [ "じしゅう" ], "comment": "self-study; teaching oneself" },
	{ "question": "自衛", "answers": [ "じえい" ], "comment": "self-defense; self-defence" },
	{ "question": "自衛官", "answers": [ "じえいかん" ], "comment": "Japanese Self-Defense Force official; Self-Defense Force official" },
	{ "question": "自衛隊", "answers": [ "じえいたい" ], "comment": "self-defence force; self-defense force\nJapan Self-Defence Force; JSDF" },
	{ "question": "自覚", "answers": [ "じかく" ], "comment": "self-consciousness; self-awareness" },
	{ "question": "自負", "answers": [ "じふ" ], "comment": "conceit; bragging about one's own ability" },
	{ "question": "自販", "answers": [ "じはん" ], "comment": "automobile sales" },
	{ "question": "自販機", "answers": [ "じはんき" ], "comment": "vending machine" },
	{ "question": "自費", "answers": [ "じひ" ], "comment": "one's own expense; out-of-pocket expense" },
	{ "question": "自身", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "by oneself; personally" },
	{ "question": "自転車", "answers": [ "じてんしゃ" ], "comment": "bicycle" },
	{ "question": "自閉症", "answers": [ "じへいしょう" ], "comment": "autism" },
	{ "question": "自首", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "surrender; give oneself up" },
	{ "question": "臭い", "answers": [ "くさい" ], "comment": "stinking; smelly\nsuspicious; fishy\nclumsy; unskilled\nsmelling of\nlooking like; appearing like; smacking of; -ish" },
	{ "question": "臭う", "answers": [ "におう" ], "comment": "to be fragrant; to smell (good)\nto stink; to smell (bad)\nto glow; to be bright\nto smack of; to show hints of" },
	{ "question": "至って", "answers": [ "いたって" ], "comment": "very much; exceedingly; extremely" },
	{ "question": "至る", "answers": [ "いたる" ], "comment": "to arrive at (e.g. a decision); to reach (a stage); to attain\nto lead to (a place); to get to\nto come; to arrive; to result in" },
	{ "question": "至上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "supremacy" },
	{ "question": "至急", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "至難", "answers": [ "しなん" ], "comment": "most difficult; next to impossible" },
	{ "question": "致命傷", "answers": [ "ちめいしょう" ], "comment": "fatal wound" },
	{ "question": "致命的", "answers": [ "ちめいてき" ], "comment": "fatal; lethal" },
	{ "question": "致死", "answers": [ "ちし" ], "comment": "lethal; fatal" },
	{ "question": "舅", "answers": [ "しうと", "しゅうと" ], "comment": "father-in-law" },
	{ "question": "興", "answers": [ "きょう" ], "comment": "interest; entertainment; pleasure\nimplicit comparison (style of the Shi Jing)" },
	{ "question": "興す", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "to establish (e.g. company); to build up; to set up; to promote; to vitalize; to revive" },
	{ "question": "興味", "answers": [ "きょうみ" ], "comment": "interest (in something); curiosity (about something); zest (for)" },
	{ "question": "興味深い", "answers": [ "きょうみぶかい" ], "comment": "very interesting; of great interest" },
	{ "question": "興奮", "answers": [ "こうふん" ], "comment": "excitement; stimulation; agitation; arousal" },
	{ "question": "興業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "industrial enterprise" },
	{ "question": "興行", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "show; performance; act\nentertainment industry; show business" },
	{ "question": "舌", "answers": [ "した" ], "comment": "tongue\ntongue-like object; clapper (of a bell); talon (of a lock)" },
	{ "question": "舎", "answers": [ "しゃ" ], "comment": "hut; house\n(in the ancient Chinese army) one day's march (approx. 12.2 km)" },
	{ "question": "舐める", "answers": [ "なめる" ], "comment": "to lick\nto taste\nto experience (esp. a hardship)\nto make fun of; to make light of; to put down; to treat with contempt; to underestimate" },
	{ "question": "舗装", "answers": [ "ほそう" ], "comment": "pavement; road surface" },
	{ "question": "舞", "answers": [ "まい" ], "comment": "dancing; dance" },
	{ "question": "舞う", "answers": [ "まう" ], "comment": "to dance (orig. a whirling dance)\nto flutter about; to revolve" },
	{ "question": "舞台", "answers": [ "ぶたい" ], "comment": "stage (theatre, theater)\nscene or setting (e.g. of novel, play, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "舞台裏", "answers": [ "ぶたいうら" ], "comment": "offstage; backstage; behind the scenes" },
	{ "question": "舞踊", "answers": [ "ぶよう" ], "comment": "dancing; dance" },
	{ "question": "舞踏", "answers": [ "ぶとう" ], "comment": "dancing\ncontemporary performance dance" },
	{ "question": "航法", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "sailing; navigation" },
	{ "question": "航海", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "sail; voyage" },
	{ "question": "航空", "answers": [ "こうくう" ], "comment": "aviation; flying" },
	{ "question": "航空便", "answers": [ "こうくうびん" ], "comment": "air mail" },
	{ "question": "航空券", "answers": [ "こうくうけん" ], "comment": "airline ticket; plane ticket; air ticket" },
	{ "question": "航空機", "answers": [ "こうくうき" ], "comment": "aircraft" },
	{ "question": "航空自衛隊", "answers": [ "こうくうじえいたい" ], "comment": "Air Self-Defense Force; ASDF" },
	{ "question": "航行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "cruise; navigation; sailing" },
	{ "question": "航路", "answers": [ "こうろ" ], "comment": "(air or sea) route; course; line; run" },
	{ "question": "舵", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "rudder; helm" },
	{ "question": "船", "answers": [ "ふね" ], "comment": "ship; boat; watercraft; vessel; steamship\ntank; tub; vat; trough\ncounter for boat-shaped containers (e.g. of sashimi)" },
	{ "question": "船主", "answers": [ "せんしゅ", "ふなぬし" ], "comment": "shipowner" },
	{ "question": "船体", "answers": [ "せんたい" ], "comment": "hull" },
	{ "question": "船便", "answers": [ "ふなびん" ], "comment": "surface mail (ship); sea mail\nferry service; steamer service" },
	{ "question": "船出", "answers": [ "ふなで" ], "comment": "setting sail; putting out to sea" },
	{ "question": "船員", "answers": [ "せんいん" ], "comment": "sailor" },
	{ "question": "船橋", "answers": [ "せんきょう", "ふなばし" ], "comment": "pontoon bridge; temporary bridge made using ships\nbridge (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "船籍", "answers": [ "せんせき" ], "comment": "ship's nationality; ship's country of registration" },
	{ "question": "船舶", "answers": [ "せんぱく" ], "comment": "ship" },
	{ "question": "船長", "answers": [ "せんちょう", "ふなおさ" ], "comment": "ship's captain; skipper\nlength of a ship\nboatman" },
	{ "question": "艦", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "warship" },
	{ "question": "艦船", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "(ocean) vessels; warship" },
	{ "question": "艦艇", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "military vessel; war fleet" },
	{ "question": "艦隊", "answers": [ "かんたい" ], "comment": "(naval) fleet; armada" },
	{ "question": "良", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "good\nB grade (in an A, B, C ... system)" },
	{ "question": "良き", "answers": [ "よき" ], "comment": "goodness\ngood" },
	{ "question": "良さ", "answers": [ "よさ" ], "comment": "merit; virtue; good quality" },
	{ "question": "良好", "answers": [ "りょうこう" ], "comment": "favorable; favourable; satisfactory" },
	{ "question": "良心", "answers": [ "りょうしん" ], "comment": "conscience" },
	{ "question": "良識", "answers": [ "りょうしき" ], "comment": "good sense" },
	{ "question": "良質", "answers": [ "りょうしつ" ], "comment": "good quality; fine quality; superior quality; high quality" },
	{ "question": "色", "answers": [ "いろ" ], "comment": "colour; color\ncomplexion\nappearance; look\nlove; lust; sensuality; love affair; lover\nkind; type; variety" },
	{ "question": "色合い", "answers": [ "いろあい" ], "comment": "hue; tinge; tint" },
	{ "question": "色彩", "answers": [ "しきさい" ], "comment": "colour; color; hue; tints" },
	{ "question": "色気", "answers": [ "いろけ" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; shade of colour; shade of color\nsex appeal (esp. women); interest in the opposite sex; sensuality; seductiveness; glamor; glamour; sexual passion\nromance; poetry; charm\ndesire; interest; inclination; ambition" },
	{ "question": "色紙", "answers": [ "しきし" ], "comment": "square fancy cardboard, used for autographs, poetry, etc." },
	{ "question": "色素", "answers": [ "しきそ" ], "comment": "pigment; coloring; colouring; colorant; colourant" },
	{ "question": "色調", "answers": [ "しきちょう" ], "comment": "color tone; colour tone" },
	{ "question": "艶", "answers": [ "つや" ], "comment": "gloss; glaze\ncharm; romance; love; youthfulness\ncolor; colour; feeling" },
	{ "question": "芋", "answers": [ "いも" ], "comment": "tuber; taro; potato\nyokel; bumpkin" },
	{ "question": "芝", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "lawn; sod; turf" },
	{ "question": "芝居", "answers": [ "しばい" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "芝生", "answers": [ "しばふ" ], "comment": "lawn" },
	{ "question": "芯", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "wick; marrow; staple (for stapler); (pencil) lead; stuffing; pith\ncore; heart; centre; center" },
	{ "question": "花", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "flower; blossom; bloom; petal\ncherry blossom\nbeauty\nblooming (esp. of cherry blossoms)\nikebana\nJapanese playing cards\n(the) best" },
	{ "question": "花びら", "answers": [ "かべん", "はなびら" ], "comment": "(flower) petal" },
	{ "question": "花園", "answers": [ "はなぞの", "かえん" ], "comment": "flower garden" },
	{ "question": "花壇", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "flower bed" },
	{ "question": "花婿", "answers": [ "はなむこ" ], "comment": "bridegroom" },
	{ "question": "花嫁", "answers": [ "はなよめ" ], "comment": "bride" },
	{ "question": "花弁", "answers": [ "かべん", "はなびら" ], "comment": "(flower) petal" },
	{ "question": "花形", "answers": [ "はながた", "かけい" ], "comment": "floral pattern; flourish; ornament\nstar (actor, player, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "花束", "answers": [ "はなたば" ], "comment": "bunch of flowers; bouquet" },
	{ "question": "花柳", "answers": [ "かりゅう" ], "comment": "red-light district" },
	{ "question": "花火", "answers": [ "はなび" ], "comment": "fireworks" },
	{ "question": "花王", "answers": [ "かおう" ], "comment": "peony; king of flowers" },
	{ "question": "花瓶", "answers": [ "かへい", "はながめ", "かびん" ], "comment": "(flower) vase" },
	{ "question": "花盛り", "answers": [ "はなざかり" ], "comment": "flowers in full bloom; time of year in which flowers are in full bloom\nthe age at which someone (esp. a woman) is at the peak of their beauty\nbooming or peaking (in popularity)" },
	{ "question": "花粉", "answers": [ "かふん" ], "comment": "pollen" },
	{ "question": "花粉症", "answers": [ "かふんしょう" ], "comment": "hay fever; pollinosis (allergy to pollen)" },
	{ "question": "花見", "answers": [ "はなみ" ], "comment": "cherry blossom viewing; flower viewing" },
	{ "question": "花輪", "answers": [ "はなわ" ], "comment": "wreath; garland" },
	{ "question": "花道", "answers": [ "はなみち" ], "comment": "passage through audience to stage" },
	{ "question": "芸", "answers": [ "げい" ], "comment": "art; craft; accomplishment; artistic skill; technique; performance" },
	{ "question": "芸人", "answers": [ "げいにん" ], "comment": "player; performer; actor" },
	{ "question": "芸名", "answers": [ "げいめい" ], "comment": "stage name" },
	{ "question": "芸者", "answers": [ "げいしゃ" ], "comment": "geisha; Japanese singing and dancing girl" },
	{ "question": "芸能", "answers": [ "げいのう" ], "comment": "public entertainment; performing arts\naccomplishments; attainments" },
	{ "question": "芸能人", "answers": [ "げいのうじん" ], "comment": "performer; entertainer; celebrity" },
	{ "question": "芸術", "answers": [ "げいじゅつ" ], "comment": "(fine) art; the arts" },
	{ "question": "芸術家", "answers": [ "げいじゅつか" ], "comment": "artist" },
	{ "question": "芸術祭", "answers": [ "げいじゅつさい" ], "comment": "art festival" },
	{ "question": "芸術院", "answers": [ "げいじゅついん" ], "comment": "academy of arts; arts academy" },
	{ "question": "芽", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "sprout" },
	{ "question": "苗", "answers": [ "なえ" ], "comment": "seedling" },
	{ "question": "苗字", "answers": [ "みょうじ" ], "comment": "surname; family name" },
	{ "question": "苗木", "answers": [ "なえぎ" ], "comment": "seedling; sapling; young tree" },
	{ "question": "若々しい", "answers": [ "わかわかしい" ], "comment": "youthful; young" },
	{ "question": "若い", "answers": [ "わかい" ], "comment": "young; youthful\nimmature; green\nlow (number); small" },
	{ "question": "若いころ", "answers": [ "わかいころ" ], "comment": "one's youth; early life; one's early days; one's early years" },
	{ "question": "若い頃", "answers": [ "わかいころ" ], "comment": "one's youth; early life; one's early days; one's early years" },
	{ "question": "若さ", "answers": [ "わかさ" ], "comment": "youth" },
	{ "question": "若干", "answers": [ "じゃっかん", "そくばく", "そこばく" ], "comment": "some; few; a number of; a little (bit)\nsomewhat; to a certain extent\nmany; a lot" },
	{ "question": "若年", "answers": [ "じゃくねん" ], "comment": "youth" },
	{ "question": "若手", "answers": [ "わかて" ], "comment": "young person" },
	{ "question": "若松", "answers": [ "わかまつ" ], "comment": "young pine; New Year's symbolic pine decoration" },
	{ "question": "若者", "answers": [ "わかもの" ], "comment": "young man; young woman; young people; youth; youngsters" },
	{ "question": "若葉", "answers": [ "わかば", "どんよう" ], "comment": "new leaves; fresh verdure" },
	{ "question": "若返り", "answers": [ "わかがえり" ], "comment": "rejuvenation; restoration of youth" },
	{ "question": "苦い", "answers": [ "にがい" ], "comment": "bitter" },
	{ "question": "苦しい", "answers": [ "くるしい" ], "comment": "painful; difficult; agonizing\nneedy; tight (budget); straitened (circumstances)\nforced (smile, joke); lame (excuse); strained (interpretation)\nawkward (situation); painful (position)\n(after masu stem) hard to do; unpleasant" },
	{ "question": "苦しみ", "answers": [ "くるしみ" ], "comment": "pain; anguish; distress; suffering; hardship" },
	{ "question": "苦しむ", "answers": [ "くるしむ" ], "comment": "to suffer; to groan; to be worried" },
	{ "question": "苦しめる", "answers": [ "くるしめる" ], "comment": "to torment; to pain; to inflict (physical) pain; to hurt\nto harass; to cause (emotional) pain; to afflict; to distress; to bother; to trouble; to stump; to baffle" },
	{ "question": "苦労", "answers": [ "くろう" ], "comment": "troubles; hardships" },
	{ "question": "苦味", "answers": [ "くみ", "にがみ" ], "comment": "bitterness; bitter taste" },
	{ "question": "苦境", "answers": [ "くきょう" ], "comment": "trouble; crisis; predicament; squeeze; pinch" },
	{ "question": "苦心", "answers": [ "くしん" ], "comment": "pain; trouble; anxiety; diligence; hard work" },
	{ "question": "苦悩", "answers": [ "くのう" ], "comment": "suffering; distress; affliction; anguish; agony; trouble" },
	{ "question": "苦情", "answers": [ "くじょう" ], "comment": "complaint; troubles; objection; grievance" },
	{ "question": "苦慮", "answers": [ "くりょ" ], "comment": "racking one's brains; worrying oneself; being anxious" },
	{ "question": "苦戦", "answers": [ "くせん" ], "comment": "hard fight; close game; struggle; tight contest" },
	{ "question": "苦手", "answers": [ "にがて" ], "comment": "poor (at); weak (in); not very good (at)\ndislike (of); difficult to deal with" },
	{ "question": "苦渋", "answers": [ "くじゅう" ], "comment": "bitterness; mortification; difficulty in understanding; distress; affliction" },
	{ "question": "苦痛", "answers": [ "くつう" ], "comment": "pain; agony; bitterness" },
	{ "question": "苦笑い", "answers": [ "にがわらい" ], "comment": "bitter smile; wry smile; forced smile; strained laugh" },
	{ "question": "苦肉の策", "answers": [ "くにくのさく" ], "comment": "last resort; desperate measure taken under pressure of necessity" },
	{ "question": "苦言", "answers": [ "くげん" ], "comment": "candid advice; frank advice; honest opinion; exhortation" },
	{ "question": "苦難", "answers": [ "くなん" ], "comment": "suffering; distress; hardship; trial" },
	{ "question": "英和", "answers": [ "えいわ" ], "comment": "English-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)" },
	{ "question": "英国", "answers": [ "えいこく" ], "comment": "Great Britain; the United Kingdom" },
	{ "question": "英字", "answers": [ "えいじ" ], "comment": "English letter; alphabetic character" },
	{ "question": "英文", "answers": [ "えいぶん" ], "comment": "sentence in English; article in English; English text\nEnglish literature (study of)" },
	{ "question": "英文学", "answers": [ "えいぶんがく" ], "comment": "study of English literature" },
	{ "question": "英明", "answers": [ "えいめい" ], "comment": "intelligent; wise; bright; brilliant; clear-sighted" },
	{ "question": "英気", "answers": [ "えいき" ], "comment": "great wisdom; excellent disposition\nstrength (to face something); willpower; vigor; vigour; energy" },
	{ "question": "英知", "answers": [ "えいち" ], "comment": "wisdom; intelligence; intellect" },
	{ "question": "英訳", "answers": [ "えいやく" ], "comment": "English translation" },
	{ "question": "英語", "answers": [ "えいご" ], "comment": "English (language)" },
	{ "question": "英雄", "answers": [ "えいゆう" ], "comment": "hero; heroine; great person\nEroica Symphony (Beethoven, 1804)\nHeroic Polonaise (Chopin)" },
	{ "question": "茂る", "answers": [ "しげる" ], "comment": "to grow thickly; to be in full leaf; to be rampant; to luxuriate; to be luxurious" },
	{ "question": "茎", "answers": [ "くき" ], "comment": "stalk; stem" },
	{ "question": "茶", "answers": [ "ちゃ" ], "comment": "tea\ntea plant (Camellia sinensis)\ntea preparation; making tea\nbrown\nmockery" },
	{ "question": "茶の間", "answers": [ "ちゃのま" ], "comment": "living room (Japanese-style)" },
	{ "question": "茶わん", "answers": [ "ちゃわん" ], "comment": "rice bowl; tea cup; teacup" },
	{ "question": "茶屋", "answers": [ "ちゃや" ], "comment": "tea house; tea dealer" },
	{ "question": "茶碗", "answers": [ "ちゃわん" ], "comment": "rice bowl; tea cup; teacup" },
	{ "question": "茶色", "answers": [ "ちゃいろ" ], "comment": "light brown; tawny" },
	{ "question": "茶道", "answers": [ "さどう" ], "comment": "tea ceremony; Way of Tea" },
	{ "question": "茹でる", "answers": [ "うでる", "ゆでる" ], "comment": "to boil (something in hot water)\nto treat with medicinal steam (a swelling, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "草", "answers": [ "くさ" ], "comment": "grass; weed; herb; thatch\nninja\nnot genuine; substandard\nlaughter; LOL" },
	{ "question": "草の根", "answers": [ "くさのね" ], "comment": "grassroots; rank and file; the roots of grass" },
	{ "question": "草分け", "answers": [ "くさわけ" ], "comment": "pathfinder; trailblazer; early settler\npioneer; founder; originator; groundbreaker" },
	{ "question": "草刈り", "answers": [ "くさかり" ], "comment": "mowing; mower" },
	{ "question": "草原", "answers": [ "くさはら", "くさわら", "そうげん" ], "comment": "grass-covered plain; grasslands; meadows; savannah; prairie; steppe" },
	{ "question": "草履", "answers": [ "ぞうり" ], "comment": "zori; Japanese sandals" },
	{ "question": "草木", "answers": [ "そうもく", "くさき" ], "comment": "plants; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "草案", "answers": [ "そうあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "草花", "answers": [ "そうか", "くさばな" ], "comment": "flower; flowering plant" },
	{ "question": "草食", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "herbivorous; plant-eating; graminivorous" },
	{ "question": "荒々しい", "answers": [ "あらあらしい" ], "comment": "rough; wild; rude; harsh; gruff; violent" },
	{ "question": "荒い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "rough; rude; wild" },
	{ "question": "荒す", "answers": [ "あらす" ], "comment": "to lay waste; to devastate; to damage\nto invade; to break into\nto troll (e.g. web forums); to spam" },
	{ "question": "荒っぽい", "answers": [ "あらっぽい" ], "comment": "rough; rude" },
	{ "question": "荒らげる", "answers": [ "あららげる" ], "comment": "to roughen (e.g. one's attitude); to raise (one's voice)" },
	{ "question": "荒らす", "answers": [ "あらす" ], "comment": "to lay waste; to devastate; to damage\nto invade; to break into\nto troll (e.g. web forums); to spam" },
	{ "question": "荒れ", "answers": [ "あれ" ], "comment": "stormy weather; tempest; chaps (of skin)" },
	{ "question": "荒れる", "answers": [ "あれる" ], "comment": "to be stormy; to be rough\nto be ruined; to fall into ruin\nto be in a bad temper; to lose one's temper" },
	{ "question": "荒廃", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "ruin; destruction; devastation; waste; decay" },
	{ "question": "荒木", "answers": [ "あらき" ], "comment": "logs in bark; rough wood; unseasoned timber; new lumber" },
	{ "question": "荒波", "answers": [ "あらなみ" ], "comment": "raging waves; stormy seas\nhardships; troubles; adversities" },
	{ "question": "荒野", "answers": [ "あらの", "こうや", "あれの" ], "comment": "wasteland; wilderness; deserted land; prairie; vast plain; wilds; desert; wild land" },
	{ "question": "荷", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "load; baggage; cargo; freight; goods\nburden; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "荷作り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "packing; baling; crating" },
	{ "question": "荷台", "answers": [ "にだい" ], "comment": "(truck) load-carrying tray; (bicycle) luggage carrier; roof rack" },
	{ "question": "荷札", "answers": [ "にふだ" ], "comment": "label; tag" },
	{ "question": "荷物", "answers": [ "にもつ" ], "comment": "luggage; baggage; package\nburden\npayload (of a packet, cell, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "荷造り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "packing; baling; crating" },
	{ "question": "荻", "answers": [ "おぎ" ], "comment": "Amur silvergrass (Miscanthus sacchariflorus)" },
	{ "question": "莫大", "answers": [ "ばくだい" ], "comment": "enormous; vast\nmalva nut (Sterculia lychnophora)" },
	{ "question": "菊", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "chrysanthemum (Chrysanthemum morifolium)" },
	{ "question": "菌", "answers": [ "きん" ], "comment": "fungus\ngerm; bacterium; bacillus" },
	{ "question": "菓子", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "pastry; confectionery" },
	{ "question": "菜園", "answers": [ "さいえん" ], "comment": "vegetable garden" },
	{ "question": "菜食", "answers": [ "さいしょく" ], "comment": "vegetable diet" },
	{ "question": "菠薐草", "answers": [ "ほうれんそう" ], "comment": "spinach" },
	{ "question": "菩薩", "answers": [ "ぼさつ" ], "comment": "bodhisattva; one who has reached enlightenment but vows to save all beings before becoming a buddha\nHigh Monk (title bestowed by the imperial court)\ntitle bestowed to Shinto kami in manifestation theory" },
	{ "question": "華々しい", "answers": [ "はなばなしい" ], "comment": "brilliant; magnificent; spectacular" },
	{ "question": "華やか", "answers": [ "はなやか" ], "comment": "showy; brilliant; gorgeous; florid; gay" },
	{ "question": "華僑", "answers": [ "かきょう" ], "comment": "overseas Chinese" },
	{ "question": "華麗", "answers": [ "かれい" ], "comment": "splendid; magnificent; gorgeous" },
	{ "question": "萌芽", "answers": [ "ほうが" ], "comment": "germination; germ; sprout; bud; sign" },
	{ "question": "萎縮", "answers": [ "いしゅく" ], "comment": "withering; atrophy; contraction; dwarf" },
	{ "question": "萩原", "answers": [ "はぎわら", "はぎはら" ], "comment": "reedy field" },
	{ "question": "落ちこぼれ", "answers": [ "おちこぼれ" ], "comment": "leftovers; odds and ends; pickings\nstudent who can't keep up in school; dunce" },
	{ "question": "落ちる", "answers": [ "おちる" ], "comment": "to fall down; to drop; to fall (e.g. rain); to sink (e.g. sun or moon); to fall onto (e.g. light or one's gaze); to be used in a certain place (e.g. money)\nto be omitted; to be missing\nto decrease; to sink\nto fail (e.g. exam or class); to lose (contest, election, etc.)\nto crash; to degenerate; to degrade; to fall behind\nto become indecent (of a conversation)\nto be ruined; to go under\nto fade; to come out (e.g. a stain); to come off (e.g. makeup); to be removed (e.g. illness, possessing spirit, name on a list)\nto fall (into someone's hands); to become someone's possession\nto fall (into a trap); to fall (for a trick)\nto give in; to give up; to confess; to flee\nto fall; to be defeated; to surrender\nto come to (in the end); to end in\nto fall (in love, asleep, etc.)\nto swoon (judo)\nto consent; to understand\nto crash; to freeze\nto die\nto move to the depths" },
	{ "question": "落ち合う", "answers": [ "おちあう" ], "comment": "to meet; to gather; to rendezvous\nto join (of roads, rivers, etc.); to flow together" },
	{ "question": "落ち度", "answers": [ "おちど" ], "comment": "mistake; error; fault; slip; blunder; omission; oversight; lapse" },
	{ "question": "落ち着いた", "answers": [ "おちついた" ], "comment": "calm; composed; cool\nsettled; fixed; established\nunobtrusive; quiet; subdued; low-key (color)" },
	{ "question": "落ち着き", "answers": [ "おちつき" ], "comment": "calmness; composure; presence of mind\nstability; steadiness" },
	{ "question": "落ち着く", "answers": [ "おちつく" ], "comment": "to calm down; to compose oneself; to regain presence of mind\nto calm down; to settle down; to die down; to become stable; to abate\nto settle down (in a location, job, etc.); to settle in\nto be settled; to be fixed; to have been reached\nto harmonize with; to harmonise with; to match; to suit; to fit\nto be unobtrusive; to be quiet; to be subdued" },
	{ "question": "落ち葉", "answers": [ "おちば" ], "comment": "fallen leaves; leaf litter\ndeciduous" },
	{ "question": "落ち込む", "answers": [ "おちこむ" ], "comment": "to feel down; to feel sad; to be depressed; to be in low spirits\nto be in a slump (business, economy, etc.); to be in an unfavourable condition\nto fall into (e.g. a hole)" },
	{ "question": "落とし物", "answers": [ "おとしもの" ], "comment": "lost property; something dropped and left behind" },
	{ "question": "落とし穴", "answers": [ "おとしあな" ], "comment": "pitfall; trap; pit" },
	{ "question": "落とす", "answers": [ "おとす" ], "comment": "to drop; to lose; to let fall; to shed (light); to cast (one's gaze); to pour in (liquid); to leave behind\nto clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.); to remove (e.g. stains or facial hair); to lose; to spend money at a certain place; to omit; to leave out; to secretly let escape\nto lose (a match); to reject (an applicant); to fail (a course); to defeat (in an election)\nto lower (e.g. shoulders or voice); to lessen (e.g. production or body weight); to worsen (quality); to reduce (e.g. rank or popularity); to speak badly of; to make light of; to fall into straitened circumstances\nto fall into (e.g. a dilemma or sin); to make one's own; to have one's bid accepted; to force surrender; to take (e.g. an enemy camp or castle); to forcefully convince; to press for a confession; to deal with\nto download; to copy from a computer to another medium\nto make someone swoon (judo)\nto finish a story (e.g. with the punch line)\nto finish (a period, e.g. of fasting)" },
	{ "question": "落下", "answers": [ "らっか" ], "comment": "fall; drop; coming down" },
	{ "question": "落差", "answers": [ "らくさ" ], "comment": "a head (of water); a difference" },
	{ "question": "落書き", "answers": [ "らくがき" ], "comment": "scrawl; scribble; graffiti" },
	{ "question": "落札", "answers": [ "らくさつ" ], "comment": "successful bid; winning a tender" },
	{ "question": "落第", "answers": [ "らくだい" ], "comment": "failure; dropping out of a class" },
	{ "question": "落胆", "answers": [ "らくたん" ], "comment": "discouragement; despondency; dejection; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "落語", "answers": [ "らくご" ], "comment": "rakugo; traditional Japanese comic storytelling; comic story (told by a professional storyteller)" },
	{ "question": "落語家", "answers": [ "らくごか" ], "comment": "rakugo story teller; comic story teller" },
	{ "question": "落選", "answers": [ "らくせん" ], "comment": "election loss; rejection" },
	{ "question": "葉", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "leaf" },
	{ "question": "著", "answers": [ "ちょ" ], "comment": "work; book\n(a book) by\nobvious; striking" },
	{ "question": "著しい", "answers": [ "いちじるしい" ], "comment": "striking; remarkable; considerable (used for good, bad, and neutral observations)" },
	{ "question": "著す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to write; to publish" },
	{ "question": "著作", "answers": [ "ちょさく" ], "comment": "writing; book" },
	{ "question": "著作権", "answers": [ "ちょさくけん" ], "comment": "copyright" },
	{ "question": "著名", "answers": [ "ちょめい" ], "comment": "well-known; noted; celebrated" },
	{ "question": "著書", "answers": [ "ちょしょ" ], "comment": "literary work; book" },
	{ "question": "著者", "answers": [ "ちょしゃ" ], "comment": "author (usu. of a particular book); writer" },
	{ "question": "葛", "answers": [ "つづら", "くず" ], "comment": "kudzu (Pueraria montana); Japanese arrowroot\nChinese moonseed (Sinomenium acutum)" },
	{ "question": "葛藤", "answers": [ "かっとう" ], "comment": "conflict; complication; troubles; discord" },
	{ "question": "葬る", "answers": [ "ほうむる", "ほうぶる" ], "comment": "to bury; to inter; to entomb\nto cover up; to hush up; to shelve" },
	{ "question": "葬儀", "answers": [ "そうぎ" ], "comment": "funeral service" },
	{ "question": "葬式", "answers": [ "そうしき" ], "comment": "funeral" },
	{ "question": "葬祭", "answers": [ "そうさい" ], "comment": "funerals and ceremonial occasions" },
	{ "question": "葬送", "answers": [ "そうそう" ], "comment": "funeral; burial rites\nattendance at a funeral" },
	{ "question": "蒔く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to sow; to plant; to seed\nto sprinkle (gold or silver powder on lacquerware)" },
	{ "question": "蒸かす", "answers": [ "ふかす" ], "comment": "to steam (food)" },
	{ "question": "蒸し", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "steaming" },
	{ "question": "蒸しパン", "answers": [ "むしパン" ], "comment": "steamed bun; steamed bread" },
	{ "question": "蒸し暑い", "answers": [ "むしあつい" ], "comment": "humid; sultry" },
	{ "question": "蒸す", "answers": [ "むす" ], "comment": "to steam (food, towel, etc.)\nto be hot and humid; to be sultry" },
	{ "question": "蒸気", "answers": [ "じょうき" ], "comment": "steam; vapour; vapor\nsteamboat; steam locomotive" },
	{ "question": "蒸発", "answers": [ "じょうはつ" ], "comment": "evaporation\ndisappearance (of people intentionally concealing their whereabouts); unexplained disappearance" },
	{ "question": "蓄える", "answers": [ "たくわえる" ], "comment": "to store; to save up; to stock up on; to lay in stock; to set aside\nto accumulate (e.g. knowledge); to build up (e.g. experience); to develop (e.g. one's skills)\nto grow (a beard, moustache, etc.); to wear" },
	{ "question": "蓄積", "answers": [ "ちくせき" ], "comment": "accumulation; accumulate; store" },
	{ "question": "蓄財", "answers": [ "ちくざい" ], "comment": "amassing of wealth" },
	{ "question": "蔑む", "answers": [ "さげすむ" ], "comment": "to scorn; to despise; to hold in contempt; to look down on; to disdain" },
	{ "question": "蔵", "answers": [ "くら" ], "comment": "warehouse; storehouse; cellar; magazine; granary; godown; depository; treasury; elevator" },
	{ "question": "蔵書", "answers": [ "ぞうしょ" ], "comment": "book collection; library" },
	{ "question": "蔵相", "answers": [ "ぞうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Finance" },
	{ "question": "蕎麦屋", "answers": [ "そばや" ], "comment": "buckwheat-noodle restaurant" },
	{ "question": "蕾", "answers": [ "つぼみ" ], "comment": "(flower) bud\npromising young person; budding beauty" },
	{ "question": "薄い", "answers": [ "うすい" ], "comment": "thin\npale; light\nwatery; dilute; sparse\nweak (taste, etc.)\nslim (probability, etc.); small" },
	{ "question": "薄まる", "answers": [ "うすまる" ], "comment": "to become weak" },
	{ "question": "薄める", "answers": [ "うすめる" ], "comment": "to dilute; to water down" },
	{ "question": "薄れる", "answers": [ "うすれる" ], "comment": "to fade; to become dim" },
	{ "question": "薄弱", "answers": [ "はくじゃく" ], "comment": "feebleness; weakness; weak" },
	{ "question": "薄暗い", "answers": [ "うすぐらい" ], "comment": "dim; gloomy" },
	{ "question": "薄着", "answers": [ "うすぎ" ], "comment": "being lightly dressed" },
	{ "question": "薔薇色", "answers": [ "バラいろ" ], "comment": "rose-colour; rose-color" },
	{ "question": "薦める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to recommend; to advise; to encourage; to offer (wine)" },
	{ "question": "薪", "answers": [ "まき", "たきぎ" ], "comment": "firewood; kindling; fuel\npiece(s) of firewood" },
	{ "question": "薬", "answers": [ "くすり" ], "comment": "medicine; pharmaceuticals; (legal) drugs; pill; ointment; salve\nefficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)\n(pottery) glaze\nsmall bribe" },
	{ "question": "薬価", "answers": [ "やくか", "やっか" ], "comment": "National Health Insurance drug price; NHI drug price" },
	{ "question": "薬剤", "answers": [ "やくざい" ], "comment": "medicine; drug" },
	{ "question": "薬剤師", "answers": [ "やくざいし" ], "comment": "chemist; pharmacist; apothecary" },
	{ "question": "薬品", "answers": [ "やくひん" ], "comment": "medicine; chemicals" },
	{ "question": "薬学", "answers": [ "やくがく" ], "comment": "(study of) pharmacy; pharmaceutics" },
	{ "question": "薬害", "answers": [ "やくがい" ], "comment": "harmful side effects of a medicine or drug" },
	{ "question": "薬局", "answers": [ "やっきょく" ], "comment": "pharmacy; chemist (shop); drugstore" },
	{ "question": "薬指", "answers": [ "くすりゆび" ], "comment": "ring finger; fourth finger" },
	{ "question": "薬物", "answers": [ "やくぶつ" ], "comment": "medicines; drugs" },
	{ "question": "藤", "answers": [ "ふじ" ], "comment": "wisteria (esp. Japanese wisteria, Wisteria floribunda); wistaria" },
	{ "question": "藩", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "feudal domain (Edo and early Meiji periods, precursor to current prefectures); fiefdom; province; clan" },
	{ "question": "藩主", "answers": [ "はんしゅ" ], "comment": "feudal lord; daimyo" },
	{ "question": "藻", "answers": [ "も" ], "comment": "algae; waterweed; seaweed; duckweed" },
	{ "question": "蘇る", "answers": [ "よみがえる" ], "comment": "to be resurrected; to be resuscitated; to be rehabilitated; to be revived; to be refreshed; to be restored\nto be recalled (e.g. memories); to be brought back" },
	{ "question": "蘭", "answers": [ "らん" ], "comment": "orchid\nHolland; The Netherlands" },
	{ "question": "虎", "answers": [ "とら" ], "comment": "tiger (Panthera tigris)\ndrunkard; drunk; sot" },
	{ "question": "虐待", "answers": [ "ぎゃくたい" ], "comment": "abuse; ill-treatment; maltreatment; mistreatment; cruelty" },
	{ "question": "虐殺", "answers": [ "ぎゃくさつ" ], "comment": "atrocity; massive killing" },
	{ "question": "虚しい", "answers": [ "むなしい" ], "comment": "empty; void; vacant\nvain; fruitless; futile; ineffective\nlifeless" },
	{ "question": "虚偽", "answers": [ "きょぎ", "こぎ" ], "comment": "falsehood; untruth; lie; misinformation\nfallacy (logic)" },
	{ "question": "虚栄心", "answers": [ "きょえいしん" ], "comment": "vanity" },
	{ "question": "虚構", "answers": [ "きょこう" ], "comment": "fiction; fabrication; concoction\nfictitious; fictional; imaginary" },
	{ "question": "虚無", "answers": [ "きょむ" ], "comment": "nihility; nothingness" },
	{ "question": "虫", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "insect; bug; cricket; moth; worm" },
	{ "question": "虫歯", "answers": [ "むしば"], "comment": "cavity; tooth decay; decayed tooth; dental caries" },
	{ "question": "虫除け", "answers": [ "むしよけ" ], "comment": "insecticide; insect repellent" },
	{ "question": "虹", "answers": [ "にじ" ], "comment": "rainbow" },
	{ "question": "蚊", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "mosquito" },
	{ "question": "蚊帳", "answers": [ "かや", "（かちょう）" ], "comment": "mosquito net" },
	{ "question": "蛇", "answers": [ "へび", "くちなわ", "じゃ" ], "comment": "snake\nserpent; large snake" },
	{ "question": "蛇の目", "answers": [ "じゃのめ" ], "comment": "bull's-eye (pattern); double ring (pattern)\numbrella with bull's-eye pattern" },
	{ "question": "蛇口", "answers": [ "じゃぐち" ], "comment": "faucet; tap" },
	{ "question": "蛋白質", "answers": [ "たんぱくしつ" ], "comment": "protein" },
	{ "question": "蛍光灯", "answers": [ "けいこうとう" ], "comment": "fluorescent lamp; fluorescent light\nperson who is slow to react; someone slow on the uptake" },
	{ "question": "蜂", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "bee; wasp; hornet" },
	{ "question": "蜜", "answers": [ "みつ" ], "comment": "nectar\nhoney\nhoneydew\ntreacle; molasses\nsorbitol (when visible as dark patches inside an apple)" },
	{ "question": "蝉", "answers": [ "せみ" ], "comment": "cicada; locust\nsmall-sized pulley" },
	{ "question": "蝕む", "answers": [ "むしばむ" ], "comment": "to be worm-eaten; to be eaten by worms\nto affect adversely; to spoil; to ruin; to undermine; to gnaw at (one's heart, body, etc.); to eat into; to destroy" },
	{ "question": "蝶", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "butterfly" },
	{ "question": "蝶々", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう", "ちょうちょ" ], "comment": "butterfly" },
	{ "question": "融合", "answers": [ "ゆうごう" ], "comment": "agglutination; adhesion; fusion; combination; blending; uniting" },
	{ "question": "融和", "answers": [ "ゆうわ" ], "comment": "harmony; reconciliation" },
	{ "question": "融資", "answers": [ "ゆうし" ], "comment": "financing; loan" },
	{ "question": "融通", "answers": [ "ゆうずう", "ゆうづう" ], "comment": "lending (money); finance\nadaptability; versatility; flexibility; accommodation" },
	{ "question": "螺旋", "answers": [ "らせん" ], "comment": "spiral; helix\nscrew" },
	{ "question": "血", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "blood; consanguinity" },
	{ "question": "血友病", "answers": [ "けつゆうびょう" ], "comment": "haemophilia" },
	{ "question": "血圧", "answers": [ "けつあつ" ], "comment": "blood pressure" },
	{ "question": "血液", "answers": [ "けつえき" ], "comment": "blood" },
	{ "question": "血液型", "answers": [ "けつえきがた" ], "comment": "blood type; blood group" },
	{ "question": "血痕", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "bloodstain" },
	{ "question": "血管", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "blood vessel; vein" },
	{ "question": "血縁", "answers": [ "けつえん" ], "comment": "blood relative or relationship; consanguinity" },
	{ "question": "衆", "answers": [ "しゅ", "しゅう" ], "comment": "great numbers (of people); numerical superiority; masses\npeople; folk; clique; bunch" },
	{ "question": "衆議院", "answers": [ "しゅうぎいん" ], "comment": "lower house; House of Representatives" },
	{ "question": "衆院", "answers": [ "しゅういん" ], "comment": "lower house of the Diet; House of Representatives" },
	{ "question": "行", "answers": [ "ぎょう" ], "comment": "line (i.e. of text); row; verse\ncarya (austerities)\nsamskara (formations)\nrunning script (a semi-cursive style of kanji)" },
	{ "question": "行い", "answers": [ "おこない" ], "comment": "deed; act; action; conduct; behavior; behaviour; asceticism" },
	{ "question": "行う", "answers": [ "おこなう" ], "comment": "to perform; to do; to conduct oneself; to carry out" },
	{ "question": "行き", "answers": [ "いき", "ゆき" ], "comment": "bound for ...\ngoing (to)" },
	{ "question": "行き先", "answers": [ "ゆきさき", "いきさき" ], "comment": "destination\nwhereabouts; address" },
	{ "question": "行き届く", "answers": [ "ゆきとどく", "いきとどく" ], "comment": "to be scrupulous; to be attentive; to be prudent; to be complete; to be thorough" },
	{ "question": "行き来", "answers": [ "ゆきき", "いきき" ], "comment": "coming and going; keeping in touch; visiting each other\nstreet traffic; highway" },
	{ "question": "行き止まり", "answers": [ "ゆきどまり", "いきどまり" ], "comment": "dead end; no passage" },
	{ "question": "行き渡る", "answers": [ "ゆきわたる", "いきわたる" ], "comment": "to diffuse; to spread throughout; to prevail; to become widespread; to reach everyone" },
	{ "question": "行き詰まり", "answers": [ "いきづまり", "ゆきづまり" ], "comment": "deadlock; stalemate; impasse; dead end" },
	{ "question": "行き過ぎ", "answers": [ "いきすぎ", "ゆきすぎ" ], "comment": "going too far; going to extremes" },
	{ "question": "行き過ぎる", "answers": [ "ゆきすぎる", "いきすぎる" ], "comment": "to go too far; to go past\nto go to extremes; to overdo it" },
	{ "question": "行き違い", "answers": [ "ゆきちがい", "いきちがい" ], "comment": "crossing without meeting (e.g. letters in the post, people on the road); going astray\ndifference of opinion; misunderstanding; estrangement; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "行ったり来たり", "answers": [ "いったりきたり" ], "comment": "going to and fro; back and forth" },
	{ "question": "行ってきます", "answers": [ "いってきます" ], "comment": "I'm off; see you later" },
	{ "question": "行って来ます", "answers": [ "いってきます" ], "comment": "I'm off; see you later" },
	{ "question": "行事", "answers": [ "ぎょうじ" ], "comment": "event; function" },
	{ "question": "行使", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "use; exercise (of one's right, authority, power, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "行儀", "answers": [ "ぎょうぎ" ], "comment": "manners; behavior; behaviour" },
	{ "question": "行列", "answers": [ "ぎょうれつ" ], "comment": "line; queue; procession; parade\nmatrix" },
	{ "question": "行動", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "action; conduct; behaviour; behavior; mobilization; mobilisation" },
	{ "question": "行司", "answers": [ "ぎょうじ" ], "comment": "referee (in sumo)" },
	{ "question": "行員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "bank clerk" },
	{ "question": "行政", "answers": [ "ぎょうせい" ], "comment": "administration" },
	{ "question": "行政処分", "answers": [ "ぎょうせいしょぶん" ], "comment": "administrative measures (disposition)" },
	{ "question": "行政機関", "answers": [ "ぎょうせいきかん" ], "comment": "administrative organ; administrative body" },
	{ "question": "行政訴訟", "answers": [ "ぎょうせいそしょう" ], "comment": "administrative litigation (action)" },
	{ "question": "行方", "answers": [ "ゆくえ" ], "comment": "(one's) whereabouts\noutcome" },
	{ "question": "行楽", "answers": [ "こうらく" ], "comment": "outing; excursion; pleasure trip; going on a picnic" },
	{ "question": "行楽地", "answers": [ "こうらくち" ], "comment": "tourist resort; holiday resort" },
	{ "question": "行渡る", "answers": [ "ゆきわたる", "いきわたる" ], "comment": "to diffuse; to spread throughout; to prevail; to become widespread; to reach everyone" },
	{ "question": "行為", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "act; deed; conduct" },
	{ "question": "行程", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "journey; course; distance; march; flight (airplane); drive (automobile); leg (of a journey or a relay race); itinerary; stroke (of a piston); throw (of a switch)" },
	{ "question": "行脚", "answers": [ "あんぎゃ" ], "comment": "pilgrimage; traveling on foot" },
	{ "question": "行進", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "march; parade" },
	{ "question": "行革", "answers": [ "ぎょうかく" ], "comment": "administrative reform" },
	{ "question": "術", "answers": [ "じゅつ" ], "comment": "art; technique\nmeans; way\ntrick; trap; plot; stratagem\nmagic" },
	{ "question": "術後", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "postoperative" },
	{ "question": "術語", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "technical term; terminology; nomenclature" },
	{ "question": "街", "answers": [ "がい" ], "comment": ".. street; .. quarter; .. district" },
	{ "question": "街宣車", "answers": [ "がいせんしゃ" ], "comment": "(right-wing) propaganda truck" },
	{ "question": "街角", "answers": [ "まちかど" ], "comment": "street corner" },
	{ "question": "街路", "answers": [ "がいろ" ], "comment": "road; street; avenue" },
	{ "question": "街路樹", "answers": [ "がいろじゅ" ], "comment": "roadside trees" },
	{ "question": "街道", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "highway (esp. one existing from the Edo period); main road\nhighway (e.g. to success); path (to becoming ...)" },
	{ "question": "街頭", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "in the street" },
	{ "question": "衛星", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "satellite" },
	{ "question": "衛生", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "health; hygiene; sanitation; medical" },
	{ "question": "衛生的", "answers": [ "えいせいてき" ], "comment": "hygienic; sanitary" },
	{ "question": "衝動", "answers": [ "しょうどう" ], "comment": "impulse; impetus; urge" },
	{ "question": "衝撃", "answers": [ "しょうげき" ], "comment": "shock; impact; crash" },
	{ "question": "衝突", "answers": [ "しょうとつ" ], "comment": "collision; crash; running into\nconflict; quarrel; clashing" },
	{ "question": "衣", "answers": [ "ころも" ], "comment": "clothes; garment\ngown; robe\ncoating (e.g. glaze, batter, icing)" },
	{ "question": "衣料", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "clothing" },
	{ "question": "衣料品", "answers": [ "いりょうひん" ], "comment": "clothing; articles of clothing; apparel" },
	{ "question": "衣替え", "answers": [ "ころもがえ" ], "comment": "seasonal change of clothing; changing (one's) dress for the season\nrenovation; facelift; changing appearance" },
	{ "question": "衣服", "answers": [ "いふく" ], "comment": "clothes" },
	{ "question": "衣装", "answers": [ "いしょう" ], "comment": "clothing; costume; outfit; garment; dress" },
	{ "question": "衣類", "answers": [ "いるい" ], "comment": "clothes; clothing; garments" },
	{ "question": "衣食住", "answers": [ "いしょくじゅう" ], "comment": "necessities of life (food, clothing & shelter)" },
	{ "question": "表", "answers": [ "おもて", "ひょう" ], "comment": "surface\nface (i.e. the visible side of an object)\nfront (of a building, etc.); obverse side (i.e. \"head\") of a coin\noutside; exterior\nappearance\npublic\nfirst half (of an inning); top (of an inning)\ncover (for tatami mats, etc.)\nforeground /\n table (e.g. Table 1); chart; list" },
	{ "question": "表す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known" },
	{ "question": "表する", "answers": [ "ひょうする" ], "comment": "to express; to show" },
	{ "question": "表れ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "embodiment; manifestation; materialization; materialisation; expression; indication" },
	{ "question": "表れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "表わす", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to represent; to signify; to stand for\nto reveal; to show; to display\nto express\nto make widely known" },
	{ "question": "表向き", "answers": [ "おもてむき" ], "comment": "outward appearance; ostensible; public; official" },
	{ "question": "表彰", "answers": [ "ひょうしょう" ], "comment": "public acknowledgment; public acknowledgement; public recognition; commendation; awarding" },
	{ "question": "表彰状", "answers": [ "ひょうしょうじょう" ], "comment": "testimonial; certificate of commendation" },
	{ "question": "表情", "answers": [ "ひょうじょう" ], "comment": "facial expression; countenance\nlook; appearance; expression (vocal, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "表明", "answers": [ "ひょうめい" ], "comment": "declaration; indication; representation; manifestation; demonstration; expression; announcement; assertion" },
	{ "question": "表札", "answers": [ "ひょうさつ" ], "comment": "nameplate; doorplate" },
	{ "question": "表決", "answers": [ "ひょうけつ" ], "comment": "vote; voting" },
	{ "question": "表現", "answers": [ "ひょうげん" ], "comment": "expression; presentation\nrepresentation; notation" },
	{ "question": "表示", "answers": [ "ひょうじ" ], "comment": "indication; expression; showing; manifestation; demonstration\ndisplay; displaying\nrepresentation" },
	{ "question": "表立って", "answers": [ "おもてだって" ], "comment": "publicly; openly; ostensibly; formally" },
	{ "question": "表立つ", "answers": [ "おもてだつ" ], "comment": "to become public; to be known" },
	{ "question": "表紙", "answers": [ "ひょうし" ], "comment": "front cover; binding; (book) cover\nappearing on the cover of a magazine" },
	{ "question": "表裏", "answers": [ "ひょうり" ], "comment": "front and back; inside and outside; two sides; both sides\nduplicity; double-dealing; being two-faced" },
	{ "question": "表計算", "answers": [ "ひょうけいさん" ], "comment": "spread sheet" },
	{ "question": "表記", "answers": [ "ひょうき" ], "comment": "writing on the surface (e.g. an address on an envelope); inscribing on the face\nexpression in writing; notation; surface form; transcription" },
	{ "question": "表通り", "answers": [ "おもてどおり" ], "comment": "main street" },
	{ "question": "表面", "answers": [ "ひょうめん" ], "comment": "surface; face\noutside; exterior\nappearances; superficiality" },
	{ "question": "表題", "answers": [ "ひょうだい" ], "comment": "title; index; heading; headline; caption" },
	{ "question": "衰え", "answers": [ "おとろえ" ], "comment": "weakening; emaciation; decline" },
	{ "question": "衰える", "answers": [ "おとろえる" ], "comment": "to become weak; to decline; to wear; to abate; to decay; to wither; to waste away" },
	{ "question": "衰弱", "answers": [ "すいじゃく" ], "comment": "weakness; debility; breakdown; prostration" },
	{ "question": "衰退", "answers": [ "すいたい" ], "comment": "decline; degeneration; decay; waning; ebbing" },
	{ "question": "袋", "answers": [ "ふくろ" ], "comment": "bag; sack; pouch\nskin of an orange (and other like fruits)\ndead end\nplot of land surrounded by water" },
	{ "question": "袖", "answers": [ "そで" ], "comment": "sleeve\nwing (of a stage, desk, gate, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "被保険者", "answers": [ "ひほけんしゃ" ], "comment": "insured person" },
	{ "question": "被告", "answers": [ "ひこく" ], "comment": "defendant; the accused" },
	{ "question": "被告人", "answers": [ "ひこくにん" ], "comment": "accused; defendant; prisoner at the bar" },
	{ "question": "被害", "answers": [ "ひがい" ], "comment": "(suffering) damage; injury; harm" },
	{ "question": "被害者", "answers": [ "ひがいしゃ" ], "comment": "victim; injured party; sufferer" },
	{ "question": "被災", "answers": [ "ひさい" ], "comment": "being a victim of (some disaster); suffering from" },
	{ "question": "被爆", "answers": [ "ひばく" ], "comment": "being bombed\nbeing A-bombed; being nuked; being exposed to radiation (from an atomic blast)" },
	{ "question": "被疑者", "answers": [ "ひぎしゃ" ], "comment": "suspect (person)" },
	{ "question": "袴", "answers": [ "はかま" ], "comment": "hakama; man's formal divided skirt" },
	{ "question": "裁く", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "to judge" },
	{ "question": "裁つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to cut (cloth)" },
	{ "question": "裁判", "answers": [ "さいばん" ], "comment": "trial; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "裁判官", "answers": [ "さいばんかん" ], "comment": "judge" },
	{ "question": "裁判所", "answers": [ "さいばんしょ" ], "comment": "court; courthouse" },
	{ "question": "裁定", "answers": [ "せいてい", "さいてい" ], "comment": "decision; ruling; award; arbitration" },
	{ "question": "裁決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "decision; ruling; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "裁縫", "answers": [ "さいほう" ], "comment": "sewing" },
	{ "question": "裁量", "answers": [ "さいりょう" ], "comment": "admeasure; discretion" },
	{ "question": "裂く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to tear; to rip up\nto cut up; to cleave; to cut open (esp. the abdomen)\nto forcibly separate (e.g. two lovers)\nto spare (time, money, etc.); to use part of something\nto have a tattoo in the corner of one's eye" },
	{ "question": "裂ける", "answers": [ "さける" ], "comment": "to split; to tear; to burst" },
	{ "question": "装い", "answers": [ "よそおい" ], "comment": "dress; outfit; equipment; makeup; adornment; guise; get-up" },
	{ "question": "装う", "answers": [ "よそおう" ], "comment": "to dress\nto pretend; to feign" },
	{ "question": "装丁", "answers": [ "そうてい" ], "comment": "binding (book); format" },
	{ "question": "装備", "answers": [ "そうび" ], "comment": "equipment" },
	{ "question": "装甲", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "armoring; armouring; armor; armour" },
	{ "question": "装着", "answers": [ "そうちゃく" ], "comment": "equipping; installing; mounting; laying down" },
	{ "question": "装置", "answers": [ "そうち" ], "comment": "equipment; installation; apparatus; device" },
	{ "question": "装飾", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "ornament; decoration" },
	{ "question": "裏", "answers": [ "うら" ], "comment": "bottom (or another side that is hidden from view); undersurface; opposite side; reverse side\nrear; back; behind (the house)\nlining; inside\nout of sight; behind the scenes; in the shadows\nproof\nopposite (of a prediction, common sense, etc.)\ninverse (of a hypothesis, etc.)\nbottom (of an inning); last half (of an inning)" },
	{ "question": "裏づける", "answers": [ "うらづける" ], "comment": "to support; to endorse; to substantiate" },
	{ "question": "裏付け", "answers": [ "うらづけ" ], "comment": "backing; support; endorsement; collateral; security; guarantee; proof; substantiation; foundation; lining (something); something lined" },
	{ "question": "裏側", "answers": [ "うらがわ" ], "comment": "the reverse; other side; lining" },
	{ "question": "裏切り", "answers": [ "うらぎり" ], "comment": "treachery; betrayal; perfidy" },
	{ "question": "裏切り者", "answers": [ "うらぎりもの" ], "comment": "betrayer; traitor; turncoat; informer" },
	{ "question": "裏切る", "answers": [ "うらぎる" ], "comment": "to betray; to turn traitor to; to double-cross" },
	{ "question": "裏口", "answers": [ "うらぐち" ], "comment": "backdoor; rear entrance" },
	{ "question": "裏方", "answers": [ "うらかた" ], "comment": "someone working behind-the-scenes; scene shifter\nlady consort (to a high personage)" },
	{ "question": "裏目", "answers": [ "うらめ" ], "comment": "reverse side\nopposite (of the expected)\npurl stitch (knitting)" },
	{ "question": "裏腹", "answers": [ "うらはら" ], "comment": "opposite; reverse; contrary" },
	{ "question": "裏表", "answers": [ "うらおもて" ], "comment": "back and front; inside and outside; both sides\ninside out (e.g. clothing)\ndouble-dealing; two faces (c.f. two-faced)\noutward appearance and actual condition; inner workings" },
	{ "question": "裏返し", "answers": [ "うらがえし" ], "comment": "inside out; upside down\nflip side; opposite; contrary; reverse" },
	{ "question": "裏返す", "answers": [ "うらがえす" ], "comment": "to turn inside out; to turn the other way; to turn (something) over" },
	{ "question": "裏通り", "answers": [ "うらどおり" ], "comment": "side street (often parallel to a main street); back street; alley" },
	{ "question": "裏金", "answers": [ "うらがね" ], "comment": "bribe\nsecret fund; slush fund; money for bribery" },
	{ "question": "裏門", "answers": [ "うらもん" ], "comment": "back gate" },
	{ "question": "裏面", "answers": [ "りめん" ], "comment": "back; reverse; other side; inside; tails (of coins); background" },
	{ "question": "裕福", "answers": [ "ゆうふく" ], "comment": "wealthy; rich; affluent; well-off" },
	{ "question": "補う", "answers": [ "おぎなう" ], "comment": "to compensate for; to supplement" },
	{ "question": "補佐", "answers": [ "ほさ" ], "comment": "aid; help; assistance; assistant; counselor; counsellor; adviser; advisor" },
	{ "question": "補修", "answers": [ "ほしゅう" ], "comment": "maintenance; mending; repair" },
	{ "question": "補償", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reparation" },
	{ "question": "補充", "answers": [ "ほじゅう" ], "comment": "replenishment; supplementation; supplement; replacement; refilling" },
	{ "question": "補助", "answers": [ "ほじょ" ], "comment": "assistance; support; aid; help\nsubsidy; supplement; subvention; grant-in-aid\nauxiliary; subsidiary\nspot (in bodybuilding)" },
	{ "question": "補完", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "complementation; supplementation; completion" },
	{ "question": "補強", "answers": [ "ほきょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "補欠", "answers": [ "ほけつ" ], "comment": "filling a vacancy; supplementation\nsubstitute; deputy; alternate; spare" },
	{ "question": "補正", "answers": [ "ほせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; compensation (e.g. to a pendulum)" },
	{ "question": "補正予算", "answers": [ "ほせいよさん" ], "comment": "revised or supplementary budget" },
	{ "question": "補給", "answers": [ "ほきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; supplying; replenishment" },
	{ "question": "補聴器", "answers": [ "ほちょうき" ], "comment": "hearing aid" },
	{ "question": "補足", "answers": [ "ほそく" ], "comment": "supplement; complement" },
	{ "question": "裸", "answers": [ "はだか" ], "comment": "naked; nude; bare" },
	{ "question": "裸足", "answers": [ "せんそく", "はだし" ], "comment": "barefoot\nsuperior to (a professional, etc. in ability or achievement)" },
	{ "question": "製", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "-made; make" },
	{ "question": "製作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "manufacture; production" },
	{ "question": "製作費", "answers": [ "せいさくひ" ], "comment": "manufacturing cost; production cost" },
	{ "question": "製品", "answers": [ "せいひん" ], "comment": "manufactured goods; finished goods; product" },
	{ "question": "製図", "answers": [ "せいず" ], "comment": "draughtsmanship; draftsmanship; drawing; sketching; mapmaking; cartography" },
	{ "question": "製油所", "answers": [ "せいゆじょ" ], "comment": "oil refinery" },
	{ "question": "製法", "answers": [ "せいほう" ], "comment": "manufacturing method; recipe; formula" },
	{ "question": "製紙", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "papermaking; paper-making; paper making; paper manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製薬", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "medicine manufacture; drug manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製造", "answers": [ "せいぞう" ], "comment": "manufacture; production" },
	{ "question": "製鉄", "answers": [ "せいてつ" ], "comment": "iron manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製鉄所", "answers": [ "せいてつじょ", "せいてつしょ" ], "comment": "ironworks; steelworks" },
	{ "question": "製鋼", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "steel manufacture" },
	{ "question": "裾", "answers": [ "すそ" ], "comment": "hem; (trouser) cuff; shirttail\nbottom edge\nfoot (of a mountain)\ntips (of hair)\ndownstream" },
	{ "question": "複写", "answers": [ "ふくしゃ" ], "comment": "copy; duplicate" },
	{ "question": "複利", "answers": [ "ふくり" ], "comment": "compound interest" },
	{ "question": "複合", "answers": [ "ふくごう" ], "comment": "composite; combined; complex" },
	{ "question": "複数", "answers": [ "ふくすう" ], "comment": "several; plural; plurality; multiple" },
	{ "question": "複製", "answers": [ "ふくせい" ], "comment": "reproduction; duplication; reprinting" },
	{ "question": "複雑", "answers": [ "ふくざつ" ], "comment": "complex; complicated; mixed (feelings)" },
	{ "question": "複雑さ", "answers": [ "ふくざつさ" ], "comment": "complexity" },
	{ "question": "褐色", "answers": [ "かっしょく" ], "comment": "dark brown; colour of tanned skin" },
	{ "question": "褒める", "answers": [ "ほめる" ], "comment": "to praise; to admire; to speak well of someone" },
	{ "question": "褒美", "answers": [ "ほうび" ], "comment": "reward; prize" },
	{ "question": "襖", "answers": [ "ふすま" ], "comment": "fusuma; Japanese sliding screen" },
	{ "question": "襟", "answers": [ "えり" ], "comment": "collar; lapel; neckband; neck\nnape of the neck; scruff of the neck" },
	{ "question": "襟巻き", "answers": [ "えりまき" ], "comment": "muffler (often fur); scarf; comforter" },
	{ "question": "襲う", "answers": [ "おそう" ], "comment": "to attack; to assail; to make an assault; to strike; to hunt down\nto succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)\nto make a sudden visit" },
	{ "question": "襲名", "answers": [ "しゅうめい" ], "comment": "succession to another's professional name" },
	{ "question": "襲撃", "answers": [ "しゅうげき" ], "comment": "attack; charge; raid" },
	{ "question": "西", "answers": [ "にし" ], "comment": "west" },
	{ "question": "西ドイツ", "answers": [ "にしドイツ" ], "comment": "West Germany (1949-1990); Federal Republic of Germany" },
	{ "question": "西側", "answers": [ "にしがわ" ], "comment": "west side; west bank" },
	{ "question": "西南", "answers": [ "せいなん", "にしみなみ" ], "comment": "south-west" },
	{ "question": "西口", "answers": [ "にしぐち" ], "comment": "west entrance" },
	{ "question": "西方", "answers": [ "にしがた", "さいほう", "せいほう" ], "comment": "western direction\nWestern Pure Land (Amitabha's Buddhist paradise)\nwestern fighter in a match (e.g. sumo)" },
	{ "question": "西日本", "answers": [ "にしにっぽん", "にしにほん" ], "comment": "western Japan; Japan west of the Itoigawa-Shizuoka Tectonic Line, i.e. the Chubu region and westward" },
	{ "question": "西暦", "answers": [ "せいれき" ], "comment": "Christian Era; CE; anno domini; AD\nWestern (Gregorian) calendar" },
	{ "question": "西欧", "answers": [ "せいおう" ], "comment": "Western Europe" },
	{ "question": "西洋", "answers": [ "せいよう" ], "comment": "the west; Western countries" },
	{ "question": "西洋人", "answers": [ "せいようじん" ], "comment": "Western people" },
	{ "question": "西独", "answers": [ "せいどく" ], "comment": "West Germany (1949-1990)" },
	{ "question": "西部", "answers": [ "せいぶ" ], "comment": "western part; the west (of a region); the West (i.e. of the US)" },
	{ "question": "要", "answers": [ "かなめ" ], "comment": "pivot\nvital point; cornerstone; keystone\nJapanese photinia" },
	{ "question": "要する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "to need; to demand; to take; to require" },
	{ "question": "要するに", "answers": [ "ようするに" ], "comment": "in a word; after all; the point is ...; in short ...; to put simply; the long and short of it is that ...." },
	{ "question": "要は", "answers": [ "ようは" ], "comment": "in short; the point is" },
	{ "question": "要人", "answers": [ "ようじん" ], "comment": "important person" },
	{ "question": "要件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "important matter\nrequirement; requisite; necessary condition; sine qua non" },
	{ "question": "要員", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "essential member; necessary person; personnel" },
	{ "question": "要因", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "main cause; primary factor" },
	{ "question": "要所", "answers": [ "ようしょ" ], "comment": "important point; important position" },
	{ "question": "要旨", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "point; essentials; gist; summary; fundamentals" },
	{ "question": "要望", "answers": [ "ようぼう" ], "comment": "demand for; request" },
	{ "question": "要求", "answers": [ "ようきゅう" ], "comment": "demand; firm request; requisition; requirement; desire" },
	{ "question": "要注意", "answers": [ "ようちゅうい" ], "comment": "attention (care) required; needs special attention" },
	{ "question": "要点", "answers": [ "ようてん" ], "comment": "gist; main point" },
	{ "question": "要約", "answers": [ "ようやく" ], "comment": "summary; digest" },
	{ "question": "要素", "answers": [ "ようそ" ], "comment": "component; factor; item (e.g. in list)\nelement (e.g. in array); member (e.g. data structure)" },
	{ "question": "要綱", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "main principle; gist; general plan; guidelines; outline" },
	{ "question": "要職", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "important office" },
	{ "question": "要衝", "answers": [ "ようしょう" ], "comment": "important point; strategic position; key point" },
	{ "question": "要請", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "appeal; call for something; request; claim; demand\naxiom" },
	{ "question": "要項", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "important points; main points" },
	{ "question": "要領", "answers": [ "ようりょう" ], "comment": "point; gist; essentials; tenets; outline\nknack; trick; the ropes" },
	{ "question": "覆う", "answers": [ "おおう" ], "comment": "to cover; to hide; to conceal; to wrap; to disguise" },
	{ "question": "覆す", "answers": [ "くつがえす" ], "comment": "to overturn; to capsize; to upset\nto overthrow (government etc.)\nto reverse (decision etc.); to disprove (an established theory etc.); to overrule" },
	{ "question": "覆面", "answers": [ "ふくめん" ], "comment": "mask; veil; disguise\nanonymous; unmarked; incognito" },
	{ "question": "覇権", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "hegemony" },
	{ "question": "覇者", "answers": [ "はしゃ" ], "comment": "supreme ruler; champion; titleholder" },
	{ "question": "見える", "answers": [ "みえる" ], "comment": "to be seen; to be in sight\nto look; to seem; to appear\nto come" },
	{ "question": "見え隠れ", "answers": [ "みえがくれ" ], "comment": "appearing and disappearing" },
	{ "question": "見かけ", "answers": [ "みかけ" ], "comment": "outward appearance\napparent" },
	{ "question": "見かける", "answers": [ "みかける" ], "comment": "to (happen to) see; to notice; to catch sight of" },
	{ "question": "見ず知らず", "answers": [ "みずしらず" ], "comment": "strange; unfamiliar; unknown; new\nunfamiliarity; strangeness; stranger" },
	{ "question": "見せびらかす", "answers": [ "みせびらかす" ], "comment": "to show off; to flaunt" },
	{ "question": "見せる", "answers": [ "みせる" ], "comment": "to show; to display" },
	{ "question": "見せ場", "answers": [ "みせば" ], "comment": "highlight scene (of play)" },
	{ "question": "見せ掛け", "answers": [ "みせかけ" ], "comment": "seeming; pose; show; pretense; sham; mock" },
	{ "question": "見た目", "answers": [ "みため" ], "comment": "appearance" },
	{ "question": "見つかる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "to be found; to be discovered" },
	{ "question": "見つける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "to discover; to find (e.g. an error in a book); to come across; to detect; to spot\nto locate; to find (e.g. something missing); to find fault\nto be used to seeing; to be familiar with" },
	{ "question": "見つめる", "answers": [ "みつめる" ], "comment": "to stare at; to gaze at; to look hard at; to watch intently; to fix one's eyes on" },
	{ "question": "見どころ", "answers": [ "みどころ" ], "comment": "point worthy of note; highlight (e.g. in a film); thing to note\ngood prospects for the future; promise" },
	{ "question": "見上げる", "answers": [ "みあげる" ], "comment": "to look up at; to raise one's eyes\nto look up to; to admire; to respect" },
	{ "question": "見下す", "answers": [ "みくだす" ], "comment": "to despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見下ろす", "answers": [ "みおろす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to command a view of; to look down on\nto despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見事", "answers": [ "みごと" ], "comment": "splendid; magnificent; beautiful; admirable\npraiseworthy act; feat; commendable deed\nutter (esp. defeat); total; complete" },
	{ "question": "見付かる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "to be found; to be discovered" },
	{ "question": "見付ける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "to discover; to find (e.g. an error in a book); to come across; to detect; to spot\nto locate; to find (e.g. something missing); to find fault\nto be used to seeing; to be familiar with" },
	{ "question": "見入る", "answers": [ "みいる" ], "comment": "to gaze at; to fix one's eyes upon" },
	{ "question": "見出し", "answers": [ "みだし" ], "comment": "heading; headline; title; caption\nindex\nheadword" },
	{ "question": "見出す", "answers": [ "みいだす", "みだす" ], "comment": "to find out; to discover; to notice; to detect\nto select; to pick out\nto look out (from the inside)\nto be wide-eyed (in surprise, anger, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見分け", "answers": [ "みわけ" ], "comment": "distinction" },
	{ "question": "見切り", "answers": [ "みきり" ], "comment": "abandonment; giving up; forsaking\nbargain (e.g. in a sale)" },
	{ "question": "見切り発車", "answers": [ "みきりはっしゃ" ], "comment": "starting a train (or bus, etc.) before all the passengers are on board\nmaking a snap decision; starting an action without considering objections to it any longer" },
	{ "question": "見受ける", "answers": [ "みうける" ], "comment": "to catch sight of; to see; to suppose; to assume from appearances" },
	{ "question": "見合い", "answers": [ "みあい" ], "comment": "formal marriage interview; marriage meeting" },
	{ "question": "見合わせる", "answers": [ "みあわせる" ], "comment": "to exchange glances; to look at each other\nto postpone; to put off; to withhold; to abandon\nto contrast; to compare" },
	{ "question": "見地", "answers": [ "けんち" ], "comment": "point of view" },
	{ "question": "見失う", "answers": [ "みうしなう" ], "comment": "to lose sight of; to miss" },
	{ "question": "見学", "answers": [ "けんがく" ], "comment": "inspection; study by observation; field trip" },
	{ "question": "見守る", "answers": [ "みまもる" ], "comment": "to watch over; to watch attentively" },
	{ "question": "見届ける", "answers": [ "みとどける" ], "comment": "to make sure of; to assure oneself of; to see with one's own eyes; to ascertain" },
	{ "question": "見張り", "answers": [ "みはり" ], "comment": "watch-keeping; guard; lookout" },
	{ "question": "見張る", "answers": [ "みはる" ], "comment": "to stand watch; to stand guard; to look out\nto open one's eyes wide" },
	{ "question": "見当", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "aim; mark; estimate; guess; approximation; direction" },
	{ "question": "見当たらない", "answers": [ "みあたらない" ], "comment": "not be found" },
	{ "question": "見当たる", "answers": [ "みあたる" ], "comment": "to be found" },
	{ "question": "見惚れる", "answers": [ "みほれる", "みとれる" ], "comment": "to be fascinated (by); to be captivated by; to be enchanted by; to gaze admiringly at; to watch in fascination" },
	{ "question": "見所", "answers": [ "みどころ" ], "comment": "point worthy of note; highlight (e.g. in a film); thing to note\ngood prospects for the future; promise" },
	{ "question": "見捨てる", "answers": [ "みすてる" ], "comment": "to abandon; to fail; to desert; to forsake" },
	{ "question": "見損なう", "answers": [ "みそこなう" ], "comment": "to misjudge; to mistake; to misread\nto misjudge (someone); to overestimate\nto miss seeing; to overlook; to fail to notice" },
	{ "question": "見放す", "answers": [ "みはなす" ], "comment": "to abandon; to give up on; to desert" },
	{ "question": "見方", "answers": [ "みかた" ], "comment": "viewpoint; point of view\nway of understanding; way of appreciating; how to look at something (e.g. noh, train schedule)" },
	{ "question": "見晴らし", "answers": [ "みはらし" ], "comment": "view; prospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "見晴らす", "answers": [ "みはらす" ], "comment": "to command a view" },
	{ "question": "見本", "answers": [ "みほん" ], "comment": "sample; specimen; pattern\nmodel; example" },
	{ "question": "見本市", "answers": [ "みほんいち" ], "comment": "trade fair" },
	{ "question": "見栄", "answers": [ "みえ" ], "comment": "airs; pretensions; show; ostentation; display; appearance; vanity; charm" },
	{ "question": "見栄え", "answers": [ "みばえ" ], "comment": "airs; pretensions; show; ostentation; display; appearance; vanity; charm" },
	{ "question": "見極める", "answers": [ "みきわめる" ], "comment": "to ascertain; to make sure of; to determine; to probe; to get to the bottom (of something)" },
	{ "question": "見比べる", "answers": [ "みくらべる" ], "comment": "to compare with the eye" },
	{ "question": "見渡す", "answers": [ "みわたす" ], "comment": "to look out over; to survey (scene); to take an extensive view of" },
	{ "question": "見物", "answers": [ "けんぶつ", "みもの" ], "comment": "sightseeing; watching; viewing\nsightseer; watcher; spectator" },
	{ "question": "見物人", "answers": [ "けんぶつにん" ], "comment": "spectator; sightseer; onlookers" },
	{ "question": "見直し", "answers": [ "みなおし" ], "comment": "review; reconsideration; revision" },
	{ "question": "見直す", "answers": [ "みなおす" ], "comment": "to look again\nto re-examine (policy, estimate, plan, etc.); to review\nto get a better opinion of; to see something in a more positive light\nto improve; to recover (market, illness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見知らぬ", "answers": [ "みしらぬ" ], "comment": "strange; unfamiliar; unknown" },
	{ "question": "見積もり", "answers": [ "みつもり" ], "comment": "estimate; estimation; valuation; quotation" },
	{ "question": "見積り", "answers": [ "みつもり" ], "comment": "estimate; estimation; valuation; quotation" },
	{ "question": "見縊る", "answers": [ "みくびる" ], "comment": "to underrate; to belittle; to look down on; to despise" },
	{ "question": "見習い", "answers": [ "みならい" ], "comment": "apprenticeship; probation; learning by observation\napprentice; trainee; probationer" },
	{ "question": "見習う", "answers": [ "みならう" ], "comment": "to follow another's example" },
	{ "question": "見聞", "answers": [ "けんもん", "けんぶん" ], "comment": "information; observation" },
	{ "question": "見舞い", "answers": [ "みまい" ], "comment": "visiting ill or distressed people; writing get-well letters\nget-well gifts; get-well letters\nexpression of sympathy; expression of concern; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "見舞う", "answers": [ "みまう" ], "comment": "to ask after (someone's health); to visit\nto attack; to strike; to meet with misfortune; to suffer an attack" },
	{ "question": "見苦しい", "answers": [ "みぐるしい" ], "comment": "unsightly; ugly" },
	{ "question": "見落とす", "answers": [ "みおとす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to fail to notice; to miss (seeing)" },
	{ "question": "見覚え", "answers": [ "みおぼえ" ], "comment": "remembrance; recollection; recognition" },
	{ "question": "見解", "answers": [ "けんかい" ], "comment": "opinion; point of view" },
	{ "question": "見詰める", "answers": [ "みつめる" ], "comment": "to stare at; to gaze at; to look hard at; to watch intently; to fix one's eyes on" },
	{ "question": "見識", "answers": [ "けんしき" ], "comment": "views; opinion; discernment\npride; self-respect" },
	{ "question": "見込み", "answers": [ "みこみ" ], "comment": "hope; promise; possibility; chance; probability; likelihood\nexpectation; anticipation; forecast; estimate\nside of a structural member" },
	{ "question": "見込む", "answers": [ "みこむ" ], "comment": "to anticipate; to estimate; to expect\nto count on" },
	{ "question": "見返り", "answers": [ "みかえり" ], "comment": "collateral; reward; compensation; security; quid pro quo" },
	{ "question": "見送り", "answers": [ "みおくり" ], "comment": "seeing one off; farewell; escort" },
	{ "question": "見送る", "answers": [ "みおくる" ], "comment": "to see someone off (at a station, an airport, etc.); to escort (e.g. home)\nto follow something with one's eyes until it is out of sight\nto let pass; to pass up (an opportunity etc.); to let a pitch go by (baseball); to watch a batted ball go into the stands\nto shelve (a plan, deliberation on a bill, etc.); to postpone\nto have someone related or close to you die; to bury someone\nto take care of somebody until he dies\nto wait and see; to continue (e.g. in legal contexts)" },
	{ "question": "見逃す", "answers": [ "みのがす" ], "comment": "to miss; to overlook; to fail to notice\nto turn a blind eye (to a wrongdoing etc.); to ignore\nto pass up (an opportunity etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見通し", "answers": [ "みとおし" ], "comment": "unobstructed view; perspective; visibility; vista\nforecast; outlook; prospect; prediction\ninsight; foresight" },
	{ "question": "見過ごす", "answers": [ "みすごす" ], "comment": "to let go by; to let pass; to overlook; to miss" },
	{ "question": "見違える", "answers": [ "みちがえる" ], "comment": "to hardly recognise; to mistake for something or somebody else" },
	{ "question": "見限る", "answers": [ "みかぎる" ], "comment": "to give up; to turn one's back; to abandon" },
	{ "question": "規制", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "regulation; (traffic) policing; control; restriction" },
	{ "question": "規則", "answers": [ "きそく" ], "comment": "rules; regulations; conventions" },
	{ "question": "規定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "stipulation; prescription; provision; regulation; rule" },
	{ "question": "規律", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "order; observance; discipline\nrules; law; regulations" },
	{ "question": "規格", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "standard; norm" },
	{ "question": "規模", "answers": [ "きぼ" ], "comment": "scale; scope; plan; structure" },
	{ "question": "規準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; basis; criterion; norm; reference; datum" },
	{ "question": "規程", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "official regulations; inner rules" },
	{ "question": "規範", "answers": [ "きはん" ], "comment": "model; standard; pattern; norm; criterion; example" },
	{ "question": "規約", "answers": [ "きやく" ], "comment": "agreement; rules; code; protocol; convention; bylaw" },
	{ "question": "視力", "answers": [ "しりょく" ], "comment": "eyesight" },
	{ "question": "視察", "answers": [ "しさつ" ], "comment": "inspection; observation" },
	{ "question": "視点", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "opinion; point of view; visual point" },
	{ "question": "視界", "answers": [ "しかい" ], "comment": "field of vision; visibility; view; visual field; (one's) ken" },
	{ "question": "視線", "answers": [ "しせん" ], "comment": "one's line of sight; one's gaze; one's eyes (looking); glance; gaze; look" },
	{ "question": "視聴", "answers": [ "しちょう" ], "comment": "looking and listening; (television) viewing\nattention; interest" },
	{ "question": "視聴率", "answers": [ "しちょうりつ" ], "comment": "ratings (of a television program) (programme)" },
	{ "question": "視聴者", "answers": [ "しちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "viewer; (television) audience" },
	{ "question": "視覚", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "sense of sight; vision" },
	{ "question": "視野", "answers": [ "しや" ], "comment": "field of vision; outlook" },
	{ "question": "覗く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to peek (though a keyhole, gap, etc.)\nto look down into (a ravine, etc.)\nto peek into (a shop, bookstore, etc.)\nto sneak a look at; to take a quick look at\nto peep (through a telescope, microscope, etc.)\nto stick out (a scarf from a collar, etc.); to peek through (sky through a forest canopy, etc.)\nto examine (an expression); to study (a face)\nto face" },
	{ "question": "覚え", "answers": [ "おぼえ" ], "comment": "memory; sense; experience" },
	{ "question": "覚える", "answers": [ "おぼえる" ], "comment": "to memorize; to memorise; to commit to memory; to learn by heart; to bear in mind; to remember\nto learn; to pick up; to acquire\nto feel\nto think; to regard" },
	{ "question": "覚せい剤", "answers": [ "かくせいざい" ], "comment": "stimulant (e.g. psychoactive drugs like methamphetamine, ritalin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "覚ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "to awaken\nto disabuse\nto sober up\nto dampen; to throw a damper on; to spoil" },
	{ "question": "覚める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "to wake; to wake up\nto become sober; to sober up; to regain consciousness (e.g. after anaesthesia)\nto come to one's senses; to be disillusioned" },
	{ "question": "覚悟", "answers": [ "かくご" ], "comment": "resolution; resignation; readiness; preparedness" },
	{ "question": "覚書", "answers": [ "おぼえがき" ], "comment": "memo; memorandum; note; memorial; protocol" },
	{ "question": "覚醒剤", "answers": [ "かくせいざい" ], "comment": "stimulant (e.g. psychoactive drugs like methamphetamine, ritalin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "親", "answers": [ "おや" ], "comment": "parent; parents\ndealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)\nfounder\n(pet) owner" },
	{ "question": "親しい", "answers": [ "したしい" ], "comment": "intimate; close (e.g. friend)" },
	{ "question": "親しみ", "answers": [ "したしみ" ], "comment": "intimacy; affection; familiarity" },
	{ "question": "親しむ", "answers": [ "したしむ" ], "comment": "to be intimate with; to befriend" },
	{ "question": "親不孝", "answers": [ "おやふこう" ], "comment": "lack of filial piety" },
	{ "question": "親交", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "intimacy; friendship; friendly relations" },
	{ "question": "親会社", "answers": [ "おやがいしゃ" ], "comment": "parent company" },
	{ "question": "親分", "answers": [ "おやぶん" ], "comment": "boss; kingpin; chief; head (e.g. of a crime syndicate)" },
	{ "question": "親切", "answers": [ "しんせつ" ], "comment": "kindness; gentleness" },
	{ "question": "親友", "answers": [ "しんゆう" ], "comment": "close friend; bosom (old, intimate) friend; buddy; crony; chum" },
	{ "question": "親善", "answers": [ "しんぜん" ], "comment": "friendship; goodwill; friendly relations; amity" },
	{ "question": "親子", "answers": [ "しんし", "おやこ" ], "comment": "parent and child" },
	{ "question": "親孝行", "answers": [ "おやこうこう" ], "comment": "filial piety" },
	{ "question": "親密", "answers": [ "しんみつ" ], "comment": "intimacy; friendship" },
	{ "question": "親愛", "answers": [ "しんあい" ], "comment": "deep affection\ndear; beloved" },
	{ "question": "親戚", "answers": [ "しんせき" ], "comment": "relative; relation; kin" },
	{ "question": "親指", "answers": [ "おやゆび" ], "comment": "thumb" },
	{ "question": "親方", "answers": [ "おやかた", "おやがた" ], "comment": "master; boss; chief; foreman; supervisor\nstable master\ncraftsman; artisan\nfoster parent" },
	{ "question": "親族", "answers": [ "しんぞく" ], "comment": "relatives" },
	{ "question": "親日", "answers": [ "しんにち" ], "comment": "pro-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "親書", "answers": [ "しんしょ" ], "comment": "handwritten or autograph letter" },
	{ "question": "親睦", "answers": [ "しんぼく" ], "comment": "friendship; amity" },
	{ "question": "親衛", "answers": [ "しんえい" ], "comment": "monarch's guards" },
	{ "question": "親近感", "answers": [ "しんきんかん" ], "comment": "affinity" },
	{ "question": "親類", "answers": [ "しんるい" ], "comment": "relation; kin" },
	{ "question": "観", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "look; appearance\nspectacle; sight\nobservation meditation\noutlook on ...; view of ..." },
	{ "question": "観光", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "sightseeing" },
	{ "question": "観光客", "answers": [ "かんこうきゃく" ], "comment": "tourist" },
	{ "question": "観劇", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "theatre-going; theater-going" },
	{ "question": "観客", "answers": [ "かんきゃく" ], "comment": "audience; spectator; spectators" },
	{ "question": "観察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "observation; survey; watching" },
	{ "question": "観念", "answers": [ "かんねん" ], "comment": "idea; notion; conception\nsense (e.g. of duty)\nresignation; preparedness; acceptance\nobservation and contemplation" },
	{ "question": "観戦", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "watching a (sports) game; spectating; observing (military operations)" },
	{ "question": "観測", "answers": [ "かんそく" ], "comment": "observation; survey; measurement" },
	{ "question": "観点", "answers": [ "かんてん" ], "comment": "point of view" },
	{ "question": "観衆", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "spectators; onlookers; members of the audience" },
	{ "question": "観賞", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "admiration; enjoyment" },
	{ "question": "観音", "answers": [ "かんのん" ], "comment": "Avalokiteshvara (Bodhisattva); Avalokitesvara; Kannon; Kwannon; Guanyin; Buddhist deity of compassion" },
	{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "つの", "かど", "かく" ], "comment": "angle\nsquare (or cube)\nbishop\nthird degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nChinese \"horn\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\njiao (monetary unit of China; one-tenth of a yuan) /\n corner (e.g. desk, pavement)\nedge /\n horn" },
	{ "question": "角度", "answers": [ "かくど" ], "comment": "angle" },
	{ "question": "角界", "answers": [ "かくかい", "かっかい" ], "comment": "the world of sumo" },
	{ "question": "角膜", "answers": [ "かくまく" ], "comment": "cornea" },
	{ "question": "解きほぐす", "answers": [ "ときほぐす" ], "comment": "to disentangle; to untangle; to unravel\nto relax; to soften; to relieve (e.g. stress, tension); to remove (e.g. doubt)" },
	{ "question": "解く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "to untie; to unfasten; to unwrap; to undo; to unbind; to unpack\nto unsew; to unstitch\nto solve; to work out; to answer\nto dispel (misunderstanding, etc.); to clear up; to remove (suspicion); to appease\nto dissolve (a contract); to cancel; to remove (a prohibition); to lift (a ban); to raise (a siege)\nto release (from duty); to relieve; to dismiss\nto comb (out); to card; to untangle (hair)" },
	{ "question": "解ける", "answers": [ "とける" ], "comment": "to be solved\nto loosen; to come untied\nto be removed (e.g. restrictions); to be cleared (e.g. misunderstandings); to be broken (e.g. spells, curses)\nto melt" },
	{ "question": "解任", "answers": [ "かいにん" ], "comment": "dismissal" },
	{ "question": "解体", "answers": [ "かいたい" ], "comment": "demolition; disassembly; dismantling; deconstruction; dissolution\ndissection (i.e. postmortem)" },
	{ "question": "解剖", "answers": [ "かいぼう" ], "comment": "dissection; autopsy\nanalysis" },
	{ "question": "解放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "release; unleashing; liberation; emancipation; setting free\ndeallocation (of computer memory)" },
	{ "question": "解散", "answers": [ "かいさん" ], "comment": "breakup; dissolution" },
	{ "question": "解明", "answers": [ "かいめい" ], "comment": "clarification; elucidation; explication" },
	{ "question": "解析", "answers": [ "かいせき" ], "comment": "analysis; analytical study\nparsing; parse" },
	{ "question": "解決", "answers": [ "かいけつ" ], "comment": "settlement; solution; resolution" },
	{ "question": "解決方法", "answers": [ "かいけつほうほう" ], "comment": "way of solving (a problem); solution" },
	{ "question": "解消", "answers": [ "かいしょう" ], "comment": "cancellation; liquidation; resolution; reduction (e.g. of stress)" },
	{ "question": "解熱", "answers": [ "げねつ" ], "comment": "lowering a fever; alleviation of fever" },
	{ "question": "解禁", "answers": [ "かいきん" ], "comment": "lifting a ban" },
	{ "question": "解答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "answer; solution" },
	{ "question": "解約", "answers": [ "かいやく" ], "comment": "cancellation of contract" },
	{ "question": "解説", "answers": [ "かいせつ" ], "comment": "explanation; commentary; exposition; elucidation" },
	{ "question": "解読", "answers": [ "かいどく" ], "comment": "deciphering; decoding" },
	{ "question": "解釈", "answers": [ "かいしゃく" ], "comment": "explanation; interpretation" },
	{ "question": "解除", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "cancellation; rescinding; release; calling off; lifting (sanctions); delisting" },
	{ "question": "解雇", "answers": [ "かいこ" ], "comment": "discharge; dismissal" },
	{ "question": "触る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "to touch; to feel" },
	{ "question": "触れる", "answers": [ "ふれる" ], "comment": "to touch; to feel\nto experience; to come in contact with; to be emotionally moved (by); to perceive\nto touch on a subject; to allude to\nto be in conflict (with); to violate (law, copyright, etc.)\nto proclaim" },
	{ "question": "触れ合う", "answers": [ "ふれあう" ], "comment": "to come into contact with; to touch (each other); to have a brush with" },
	{ "question": "触媒", "answers": [ "しょくばい" ], "comment": "catalyst" },
	{ "question": "触発", "answers": [ "しょくはつ" ], "comment": "detonation by contact; contact detonation\ntouching off something; triggering; provocation; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "言", "answers": [ "こと", "げん" ], "comment": "word; remark; statement" },
	{ "question": "言いなり", "answers": [ "いいなり" ], "comment": "doing as one is told; yes-man" },
	{ "question": "言いようがない", "answers": [ "いいようがない" ], "comment": "indescribable; having no way to express" },
	{ "question": "言い出す", "answers": [ "いいだす" ], "comment": "to start talking; to speak; to tell; to propose; to suggest; to break the ice" },
	{ "question": "言い分", "answers": [ "いいぶん" ], "comment": "one's say; one's point\ncomplaint; grievance; objection; excuse" },
	{ "question": "言い切る", "answers": [ "いいきる" ], "comment": "to declare; to assert; to state definitively\nto finish saying; to say it all; to finish one's sentence" },
	{ "question": "言い回し", "answers": [ "いいまわし" ], "comment": "expression; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "言い換える", "answers": [ "いいかえる" ], "comment": "to say in other words; to put another way; to express in different words; to reword; to rephrase" },
	{ "question": "言い方", "answers": [ "いいかた" ], "comment": "way of talking; speaking style" },
	{ "question": "言い渡し", "answers": [ "いいわたし" ], "comment": "sentence; judgment; judgement; pronouncement; order; command" },
	{ "question": "言い渡す", "answers": [ "いいわたす" ], "comment": "to announce; to tell; to sentence; to order" },
	{ "question": "言い表す", "answers": [ "いいあらわす" ], "comment": "to express (in words)\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "言い表わす", "answers": [ "いいあらわす" ], "comment": "to express (in words)\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "言い訳", "answers": [ "いいわけ" ], "comment": "excuse\nexplanation" },
	{ "question": "言い返す", "answers": [ "いいかえす" ], "comment": "to talk back; to answer back; to retort\nto say over; to repeat words; to say repeatedly" },
	{ "question": "言う", "answers": [ "いう", "ゆう" ], "comment": "to say; to utter; to declare\nto name; to call\nto go (e.g. \"the alarm went ping\"); to make a noise" },
	{ "question": "言うまでもない", "answers": [ "ゆうまでもない", "いうまでもない" ], "comment": "it goes without saying; there is no need to say so, but of course; it is needless to say; it need scarcely be said" },
	{ "question": "言付ける", "answers": [ "ことづける" ], "comment": "to send word; to send a message\nto make an excuse; to make a pretext of" },
	{ "question": "言動", "answers": [ "げんどう" ], "comment": "speech and conduct; words and deeds" },
	{ "question": "言及", "answers": [ "げんきゅう" ], "comment": "reference; allusion" },
	{ "question": "言葉", "answers": [ "ことば" ], "comment": "language; dialect\nword; words; phrase; term; expression; remark\nspeech; (manner of) speaking" },
	{ "question": "言葉遣い", "answers": [ "ことばづかい" ], "comment": "speech; expression; wording; language" },
	{ "question": "言語", "answers": [ "げんご", "ごんご" ], "comment": "language" },
	{ "question": "言論", "answers": [ "げんろん" ], "comment": "(one's) speech; expression of views; discussion" },
	{ "question": "言質", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "commitment; pledge; promise" },
	{ "question": "訂正", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; amendment" },
	{ "question": "計", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "plan\nmeter; measuring device\n(in) total; total (of)" },
	{ "question": "計り知れない", "answers": [ "はかりしれない" ], "comment": "unfathomable; inestimable; immeasurable" },
	{ "question": "計る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "計上", "answers": [ "けいじょう" ], "comment": "including a sum of money in one's calculations\nappropriation (a sum of money)" },
	{ "question": "計器", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "meter; gauge" },
	{ "question": "計測", "answers": [ "けいそく" ], "comment": "measurement; measure; instrumentation" },
	{ "question": "計画", "answers": [ "けいかく" ], "comment": "plan; project; schedule; scheme; program; programme" },
	{ "question": "計画的", "answers": [ "けいかくてき" ], "comment": "planned; scheduled; systematic" },
	{ "question": "計算", "answers": [ "けいさん" ], "comment": "calculation; reckoning; count\nforecast" },
	{ "question": "計量", "answers": [ "けいりょう" ], "comment": "measurement; computation\nmetric; measure" },
	{ "question": "討つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "to shoot (at)\nto attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge" },
	{ "question": "討論", "answers": [ "とうろん" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "討議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "訓", "answers": [ "くん" ], "comment": "native Japanese reading (rendering) of a Chinese character" },
	{ "question": "訓示", "answers": [ "くんじ" ], "comment": "instruction; direction" },
	{ "question": "訓練", "answers": [ "くんれん" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training" },
	{ "question": "訓読み", "answers": [ "くんよみ" ], "comment": "kun-yomi (Japanese reading of character)" },
	{ "question": "託す", "answers": [ "たくす" ], "comment": "to entrust\nto use something as a pretext; to express (something) through" },
	{ "question": "記す", "answers": [ "しるす", "きす" ], "comment": "to write down; to note; to jot down\nto remember" },
	{ "question": "記事", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "article; news story; report; account" },
	{ "question": "記入", "answers": [ "きにゅう" ], "comment": "entry; filling in of forms" },
	{ "question": "記号", "answers": [ "きごう" ], "comment": "symbol; code; sign; notation" },
	{ "question": "記帳", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "registry; entry; book-keeping; signature" },
	{ "question": "記念", "answers": [ "きねん" ], "comment": "commemoration; celebration; honoring the memory of something; turning something into a memento; memory" },
	{ "question": "記念日", "answers": [ "きねんび" ], "comment": "holiday; anniversary; memorial day" },
	{ "question": "記念碑", "answers": [ "きねんひ" ], "comment": "commemorative plaque (usu. on a stone); stone monument (bearing an inscription)" },
	{ "question": "記憶", "answers": [ "きおく" ], "comment": "memory; recollection; remembrance\nstorage" },
	{ "question": "記者", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "reporter" },
	{ "question": "記載", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "record; statement; description; mention; listing; registration; booking; entry" },
	{ "question": "記述", "answers": [ "きじゅつ" ], "comment": "description; descriptor" },
	{ "question": "記録", "answers": [ "きろく" ], "comment": "record; minutes; document\nrecord (e.g. in sports); results; score\nto record; to document\nto set a record (e.g. in sports); to show a result; to reach a value" },
	{ "question": "記録的", "answers": [ "きろくてき" ], "comment": "record(-setting)" },
	{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on; to pay a visit to" },
	{ "question": "訪れ", "answers": [ "おとずれ" ], "comment": "visit; call\narrival (e.g. of spring); advent; coming; appearance\nnews; tidings; word" },
	{ "question": "訪れる", "answers": [ "おとずれる", "おとづれる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on\nto arrive; to come; to appear" },
	{ "question": "訪中", "answers": [ "ほうちゅう" ], "comment": "visit to China" },
	{ "question": "訪問", "answers": [ "ほうもん" ], "comment": "call; visit" },
	{ "question": "訪日", "answers": [ "ほうにち" ], "comment": "visit to Japan" },
	{ "question": "訪欧", "answers": [ "ほうおう" ], "comment": "visit to Europe" },
	{ "question": "訪米", "answers": [ "ほうべい" ], "comment": "visit to America" },
	{ "question": "設ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "to prepare ahead of time\nto create; to establish" },
	{ "question": "設備", "answers": [ "せつび" ], "comment": "equipment; device; facilities; installation" },
	{ "question": "設問", "answers": [ "せつもん" ], "comment": "posing a question\nquestion" },
	{ "question": "設定", "answers": [ "せってい" ], "comment": "establishment; creation; posing (a problem); setting (movie, novel, etc.); scene\noptions setting; preference settings; configuration; setup" },
	{ "question": "設定可能", "answers": [ "せっていかのう" ], "comment": "configurable" },
	{ "question": "設立", "answers": [ "せつりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; incorporation (of a business)" },
	{ "question": "設置", "answers": [ "せっち" ], "comment": "establishment; institution\ninstallation (of a machine or equipment)" },
	{ "question": "設計", "answers": [ "せっけい" ], "comment": "plan; design; layout" },
	{ "question": "許し", "answers": [ "ゆるし" ], "comment": "pardon; forgiveness; exemption; permission" },
	{ "question": "許す", "answers": [ "ゆるす" ], "comment": "to permit; to allow; to approve; to tolerate\nto exempt (from fine); to excuse (from); to pardon; to forgive; to release; to let off\nto confide in\nto give up; to yield" },
	{ "question": "許可", "answers": [ "きょか" ], "comment": "permission; approval; authorization; license\nto permit; to authorize" },
	{ "question": "許容", "answers": [ "きょよう" ], "comment": "permission; pardon" },
	{ "question": "許諾", "answers": [ "きょだく" ], "comment": "consent" },
	{ "question": "訳す", "answers": [ "やくす" ], "comment": "to translate; to interpret" },
	{ "question": "訳者", "answers": [ "やくしゃ" ], "comment": "translator" },
	{ "question": "訴え", "answers": [ "うったえ" ], "comment": "lawsuit; complaint" },
	{ "question": "訴える", "answers": [ "うったえる" ], "comment": "to raise; to bring to (someone's attention)\nto appeal to (reason, emotions, etc.); to work on (one's emotions); to play on (one's sympathies)\nto complain\nto sue (a person); to take someone to court\nto resort to (e.g. arms, violence)" },
	{ "question": "訴状", "answers": [ "そじょう" ], "comment": "petition; complaint; (legal) brief" },
	{ "question": "訴訟", "answers": [ "そしょう" ], "comment": "litigation; lawsuit" },
	{ "question": "訴追", "answers": [ "そつい" ], "comment": "prosecution; indictment\nimpeachment" },
	{ "question": "診る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "to examine (medically)" },
	{ "question": "診察", "answers": [ "しんさつ" ], "comment": "medical examination" },
	{ "question": "診断", "answers": [ "しんだん" ], "comment": "diagnosis; medical examination" },
	{ "question": "診療", "answers": [ "しんりょう" ], "comment": "diagnosis and treatment; medical care" },
	{ "question": "診療所", "answers": [ "しんりょうしょ", "しんりょうじょ" ], "comment": "clinic; medical office; infirmary" },
	{ "question": "証", "answers": [ "あかし", "しょう" ], "comment": "proof (e.g. of love, of innocence); evidence; testimony; vindication (of innocence)\nlicense; membership card; permit\nto testify (usu. Christian religious context)" },
	{ "question": "証人", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "witness" },
	{ "question": "証券", "answers": [ "しょうけん" ], "comment": "securities; bonds; certificates" },
	{ "question": "証拠", "answers": [ "しょうこ" ], "comment": "evidence; proof" },
	{ "question": "証明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "proof; verification; certification" },
	{ "question": "証明書", "answers": [ "しょうめいしょ" ], "comment": "certificate (usually of proof of something); credentials" },
	{ "question": "証書", "answers": [ "しょうしょ" ], "comment": "bond; deed; certificate" },
	{ "question": "証言", "answers": [ "しょうげん" ], "comment": "testimony; (verbal) evidence" },
	{ "question": "詐欺", "answers": [ "さぎ" ], "comment": "fraud; swindle; graft; cheating; trick; scam" },
	{ "question": "評", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "criticism; commentary; a council" },
	{ "question": "評伝", "answers": [ "ひょうでん" ], "comment": "a critical biography" },
	{ "question": "評価", "answers": [ "ひょうか" ], "comment": "valuation; estimation; assessment; evaluation; rating\nto value; to assess; to rate; to estimate value\nto appreciate; to value highly; to acknowledge the value (of something)" },
	{ "question": "評判", "answers": [ "ひょうばん" ], "comment": "fame; reputation; popularity\nrumour (rumor); talk" },
	{ "question": "評決", "answers": [ "ひょうけつ" ], "comment": "decision; verdict" },
	{ "question": "評論", "answers": [ "ひょうろん" ], "comment": "criticism; critique" },
	{ "question": "評論家", "answers": [ "ひょうろんか" ], "comment": "critic; reviewer; commentator" },
	{ "question": "評議", "answers": [ "ひょうぎ" ], "comment": "conference; discussion" },
	{ "question": "評議員", "answers": [ "ひょうぎいん" ], "comment": "trustee; councillor (councilor)" },
	{ "question": "詠む", "answers": [ "よむ" ], "comment": "to compose (e.g. a Japanese poem); to write\nto recite (e.g. a poem); to chant" },
	{ "question": "試し", "answers": [ "ためし" ], "comment": "trial; test" },
	{ "question": "試す", "answers": [ "ためす" ], "comment": "to attempt; to test; to try out" },
	{ "question": "試み", "answers": [ "こころみ" ], "comment": "attempt; trial; experiment\nendeavour (endeavor); effort; venture; initiative" },
	{ "question": "試みる", "answers": [ "こころみる" ], "comment": "to try; to attempt; to have a go (at something)" },
	{ "question": "試作", "answers": [ "しさく" ], "comment": "trial manufacture; experiment; test piece; prototype" },
	{ "question": "試写", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "preview; private showing" },
	{ "question": "試合", "answers": [ "しあい" ], "comment": "match; game; bout; contest" },
	{ "question": "試料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "sample; specimen; test piece" },
	{ "question": "試案", "answers": [ "しあん" ], "comment": "tentative plan; draft plan" },
	{ "question": "試算", "answers": [ "しさん" ], "comment": "trial calculation; preliminary calculation" },
	{ "question": "試練", "answers": [ "しれん" ], "comment": "test; trial; probation; ordeal; tribulation" },
	{ "question": "試薬", "answers": [ "しやく" ], "comment": "reagent" },
	{ "question": "試行", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "making an attempt; trial run" },
	{ "question": "試行錯誤", "answers": [ "しこうさくご" ], "comment": "trial and error" },
	{ "question": "試金石", "answers": [ "しきんせき" ], "comment": "touchstone; test case" },
	{ "question": "試食", "answers": [ "ししょく" ], "comment": "sampling food" },
	{ "question": "試験", "answers": [ "しけん" ], "comment": "examination; exam; test\ntrial; experiment; test" },
	{ "question": "試験場", "answers": [ "しけんじょう" ], "comment": "examination hall; examination room\nlaboratory; experimental station; testing ground" },
	{ "question": "試験的", "answers": [ "しけんてき" ], "comment": "experimental; provisional" },
	{ "question": "詩", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "poem; verse of poetry" },
	{ "question": "詩人", "answers": [ "しじん" ], "comment": "poet" },
	{ "question": "詩歌", "answers": [ "しいか", "しか" ], "comment": "Japanese (and Chinese) poetry" },
	{ "question": "詩集", "answers": [ "ししゅう" ], "comment": "poetry anthology; collection of poems; collected poems" },
	{ "question": "詫び", "answers": [ "わび" ], "comment": "apology; excuse" },
	{ "question": "詫びる", "answers": [ "わびる" ], "comment": "to apologize; to apologise" },
	{ "question": "詰まらせる", "answers": [ "つまらせる" ], "comment": "to clog; to block; to choke up; to jam; to obstruct" },
	{ "question": "詰まる", "answers": [ "つまる" ], "comment": "to be packed (with); to be full (space, schedule, etc.)\nto be blocked (road, pipe, etc.); to be clogged; to be plugged up\nto shorten (width, interval, etc.); to shrink (shirt, word form, etc.); to narrow\nto be at a loss; to be hard pressed\nto end up; to be settled\nto become a geminate consonant\nto hit the ball near the handle of the bat" },
	{ "question": "詰める", "answers": [ "つめる" ], "comment": "to stuff into; to jam; to cram; to pack; to fill; to plug; to stop up\nto shorten; to move closer together\nto reduce (spending); to conserve\nto focus intently on; to strain oneself to do\nto work out (details)\nto be on duty; to be stationed\nto corner (esp. an opponent's king in shogi); to trap; to checkmate\nto cut off (one's finger as an act of apology); to catch (one's finger in a door, etc.)\nto continue ...; to keep doing ... without a break\nto do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly\nto force someone into a difficult situation by ..." },
	{ "question": "話", "answers": [ "はなし" ], "comment": "talk; speech; chat; story; conversation\ndiscussions; negotiation; argument" },
	{ "question": "話しかける", "answers": [ "はなしかける" ], "comment": "to address (someone); to accost a person; to talk (to someone)\nto begin to talk; to start a conversation" },
	{ "question": "話し合い", "answers": [ "はなしあい" ], "comment": "discussion; conference" },
	{ "question": "話し合う", "answers": [ "はなしあう" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk together" },
	{ "question": "話し声", "answers": [ "はなしごえ" ], "comment": "speaking voice; talking voice" },
	{ "question": "話し掛ける", "answers": [ "はなしかける" ], "comment": "to address (someone); to accost a person; to talk (to someone)\nto begin to talk; to start a conversation" },
	{ "question": "話し方", "answers": [ "はなしかた" ], "comment": "way of talking; speaking style" },
	{ "question": "話し言葉", "answers": [ "はなしことば" ], "comment": "spoken language; colloquial expression" },
	{ "question": "話し込む", "answers": [ "はなしこむ" ], "comment": "to be deep in talk" },
	{ "question": "話す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to talk; to speak; to converse; to chat\nto tell; to explain; to narrate; to mention; to describe; to discuss\nto speak (a language)" },
	{ "question": "話合い", "answers": [ "はなしあい" ], "comment": "discussion; conference" },
	{ "question": "話込む", "answers": [ "はなしこむ" ], "comment": "to be deep in talk" },
	{ "question": "話題", "answers": [ "わだい" ], "comment": "topic; subject" },
	{ "question": "該当", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "corresponding to; being applicable to; relevant to; coming under; falling under; applying to; fulfilling; qualifying as" },
	{ "question": "詳しい", "answers": [ "くわしい" ], "comment": "detailed; full; accurate\nknowing very well; well-acquainted; well-informed" },
	{ "question": "詳報", "answers": [ "しょうほう" ], "comment": "full report; particulars" },
	{ "question": "詳細", "answers": [ "しょうさい" ], "comment": "detail; particulars" },
	{ "question": "誇り", "answers": [ "ほこり" ], "comment": "pride; boast" },
	{ "question": "誇る", "answers": [ "ほこる" ], "comment": "to boast of; to be proud of" },
	{ "question": "誇張", "answers": [ "こちょう" ], "comment": "exaggeration" },
	{ "question": "誌", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "magazine" },
	{ "question": "認め", "answers": [ "みとめ" ], "comment": "approval; final seal (of approval); acceptance" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる" ], "comment": "to recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "認め印", "answers": [ "みとめいん" ], "comment": "private seal; personal seal; unregistered seal; informal seal; signet" },
	{ "question": "認可", "answers": [ "にんか" ], "comment": "approval; license; licence; permission" },
	{ "question": "認定", "answers": [ "にんてい" ], "comment": "authorization; authorisation; acknowledgment; acknowledgement; certification; recognition" },
	{ "question": "認知", "answers": [ "にんち" ], "comment": "acknowledgement; acknowledgment; recognition; cognition" },
	{ "question": "認証", "answers": [ "にんしょう" ], "comment": "certification; attestation; authentication; confirmation\nImperial attestation" },
	{ "question": "認識", "answers": [ "にんしき" ], "comment": "recognition; awareness; perception; understanding; knowledge; cognition; cognizance; cognisance" },
	{ "question": "誓い", "answers": [ "ちかい" ], "comment": "oath; vow" },
	{ "question": "誓う", "answers": [ "ちかう" ], "comment": "to swear; to vow; to take an oath; to pledge" },
	{ "question": "誓って", "answers": [ "ちかって" ], "comment": "surely; upon my word; by Jove\n(with neg) by no means; never" },
	{ "question": "誓約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "written vow; pledge; covenant" },
	{ "question": "誕生", "answers": [ "たんじょう" ], "comment": "birth; creation; formation" },
	{ "question": "誕生日", "answers": [ "たんじょうび" ], "comment": "birthday" },
	{ "question": "誘い", "answers": [ "さそい", "いざない" ], "comment": "invitation; introduction\ntemptation" },
	{ "question": "誘う", "answers": [ "さそう", "いざなう" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask; to call (for)\nto tempt; to lure; to induce" },
	{ "question": "誘導", "answers": [ "ゆうどう" ], "comment": "guidance; leading; induction; introduction; incitement; inducement" },
	{ "question": "誘惑", "answers": [ "ゆうわく" ], "comment": "temptation; allurement; lure; enticement; seduction" },
	{ "question": "誘拐", "answers": [ "ゆうかい" ], "comment": "abduction; kidnapping; kidnaping" },
	{ "question": "誘致", "answers": [ "ゆうち" ], "comment": "attraction; lure; invitation" },
	{ "question": "語", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "language\nword" },
	{ "question": "語らう", "answers": [ "かたらう" ], "comment": "to talk; to tell; to recite; to pledge; to conspire with" },
	{ "question": "語り", "answers": [ "かたり" ], "comment": "talk; recital\nnarration\ntopic" },
	{ "question": "語り口", "answers": [ "かたりくち" ], "comment": "way of reciting; way of telling a story" },
	{ "question": "語る", "answers": [ "かたる" ], "comment": "to talk about; to speak of; to tell; to narrate\nto recite; to chant\nto indicate; to show" },
	{ "question": "語学", "answers": [ "ごがく" ], "comment": "language study" },
	{ "question": "語彙", "answers": [ "ごい" ], "comment": "vocabulary; lexicon; lexis; terminology" },
	{ "question": "語気", "answers": [ "ごき" ], "comment": "tone; manner of speaking" },
	{ "question": "語源", "answers": [ "ごげん" ], "comment": "word root; word derivation; etymology" },
	{ "question": "誠", "answers": [ "まこと" ], "comment": "truth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; integrity; fidelity\nthat's right (used when recalling forgotten information, suddenly changing the subject, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "誠に", "answers": [ "しんに", "まことに" ], "comment": "indeed; really; absolutely; truly; actually; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "誠実", "answers": [ "せいじつ" ], "comment": "sincere; honest; faithful" },
	{ "question": "誠意", "answers": [ "せいい" ], "comment": "sincerity; good faith" },
	{ "question": "誤って", "answers": [ "あやまって" ], "comment": "in error; by mistake; by accident" },
	{ "question": "誤り", "answers": [ "あやまり" ], "comment": "error; mistake; slip; bug" },
	{ "question": "誤る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to err\nto mislead; to misguide" },
	{ "question": "誤字", "answers": [ "ごじ" ], "comment": "misprint; misspelling; typo; typographical error; erratum" },
	{ "question": "誤差", "answers": [ "ごさ" ], "comment": "measurement error; calculation error" },
	{ "question": "誤算", "answers": [ "ごさん" ], "comment": "miscalculation" },
	{ "question": "誤解", "answers": [ "ごかい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding" },
	{ "question": "誤認", "answers": [ "ごにん" ], "comment": "misrecognition; mistaking (x for y)" },
	{ "question": "説", "answers": [ "せつ" ], "comment": "theory; doctrine\nopinion; view\nrumour; rumor; gossip; hearsay" },
	{ "question": "説く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "to explain; to advocate; to preach; to persuade" },
	{ "question": "説得", "answers": [ "せっとく" ], "comment": "persuasion" },
	{ "question": "説教", "answers": [ "せっきょう" ], "comment": "propounding; preaching; sermonizing\nremonstration; scolding; lecturing" },
	{ "question": "説明", "answers": [ "せつめい" ], "comment": "explanation; exposition" },
	{ "question": "説明書", "answers": [ "せつめいしょ" ], "comment": "(printed) instructions" },
	{ "question": "読み", "answers": [ "よみ" ], "comment": "reading" },
	{ "question": "読みにくい", "answers": [ "よみにくい" ], "comment": "hard to read; illegible" },
	{ "question": "読み上げる", "answers": [ "よみあげる" ], "comment": "to read out loud (and clearly); to call a roll" },
	{ "question": "読み取り", "answers": [ "よみとり" ], "comment": "reading (e.g. by a scanner)" },
	{ "question": "読み悪い", "answers": [ "よみにくい" ], "comment": "hard to read; illegible" },
	{ "question": "読み方", "answers": [ "よみかた" ], "comment": "pronunciation; reading (e.g. of a kanji)\nway of reading (out loud)\ninterpretation (e.g. of a text); reading" },
	{ "question": "読み書き", "answers": [ "よみかき" ], "comment": "reading and writing" },
	{ "question": "読み物", "answers": [ "よみもの" ], "comment": "reading matter; reading material" },
	{ "question": "読む", "answers": [ "よむ" ], "comment": "to read\nto count\nto guess; to predict; to read (someone's thoughts); to see (e.g. into someone's heart); to divine" },
	{ "question": "読書", "answers": [ "どくしょ", "とくしょ" ], "comment": "reading" },
	{ "question": "読者", "answers": [ "どくしゃ" ], "comment": "reader" },
	{ "question": "誰", "answers": [ "だれ" ], "comment": "who" },
	{ "question": "誰か", "answers": [ "だれか" ], "comment": "someone; somebody" },
	{ "question": "誰でも", "answers": [ "だれでも" ], "comment": "anyone; anybody; everyone; everybody; whoever" },
	{ "question": "誰にでも", "answers": [ "だれにでも" ], "comment": "anyone (used with positive verbs); anybody; everyone; whoever" },
	{ "question": "誰にも", "answers": [ "だれにも" ], "comment": "anybody and everybody; with the best of them; as the next fellow" },
	{ "question": "誰も", "answers": [ "だれも" ], "comment": "everyone; anyone\nno-one (with neg. verb)" },
	{ "question": "課", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "lesson\nsection (in an organization); division; department\ncounter for lessons and chapters (of a book)" },
	{ "question": "課する", "answers": [ "かする" ], "comment": "to levy; to charge; to assess; to impose; to assign" },
	{ "question": "課員", "answers": [ "かいん" ], "comment": "section staff" },
	{ "question": "課徴金", "answers": [ "かちょうきん" ], "comment": "charges (i.e. fees)" },
	{ "question": "課目", "answers": [ "かもく" ], "comment": "(school) subject; curriculum; course" },
	{ "question": "課程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "course; curriculum" },
	{ "question": "課税", "answers": [ "かぜい" ], "comment": "taxation" },
	{ "question": "課長", "answers": [ "かちょう" ], "comment": "section manager; section chief" },
	{ "question": "課題", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "subject; theme; issue; matter\nhomework; assignment\ntask; challenge; problem; question" },
	{ "question": "調べ", "answers": [ "しらべ" ], "comment": "investigation; inspection; examination\ntune; note; melody" },
	{ "question": "調べる", "answers": [ "しらべる" ], "comment": "to examine; to investigate; to check up; to sense; to study; to inquire; to search" },
	{ "question": "調停", "answers": [ "ちょうてい" ], "comment": "arbitration; conciliation; mediation" },
	{ "question": "調印", "answers": [ "ちょういん" ], "comment": "signature; signing; sealing" },
	{ "question": "調味料", "answers": [ "ちょうみりょう" ], "comment": "flavoring (e.g. salt, sugar, soy sauce, vinegar, etc.); seasoning" },
	{ "question": "調和", "answers": [ "ちょうわ" ], "comment": "harmony; accord; reconciliation; agreement" },
	{ "question": "調子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "tune; tone; key; pitch; time; rhythm\nvein; mood; way; manner; style; knack\ncondition; state of health\nimpetus; spur of the moment; strain\ntrend" },
	{ "question": "調教", "answers": [ "ちょうきょう" ], "comment": "training (animals); breaking (animals)" },
	{ "question": "調整", "answers": [ "ちょうせい" ], "comment": "adjustment; regulation; coordination; reconciliation; tuning; fixing; tailoring" },
	{ "question": "調書", "answers": [ "ちょうしょ" ], "comment": "protocol; written evidence; record (investigation, interrogation, etc.); preliminary memo; charge sheet" },
	{ "question": "調査", "answers": [ "ちょうさ" ], "comment": "investigation; examination; inquiry; enquiry; survey" },
	{ "question": "調理", "answers": [ "ちょうり" ], "comment": "cooking; food preparation" },
	{ "question": "調節", "answers": [ "ちょうせつ" ], "comment": "regulation; adjustment; control" },
	{ "question": "調達", "answers": [ "ちょうたつ" ], "comment": "supply; provision; raising; procurement" },
	{ "question": "談合", "answers": [ "だんごう" ], "comment": "consultation; discussion; conference\ncollusion; bid-rigging" },
	{ "question": "談話", "answers": [ "だんわ" ], "comment": "a talk; conversation" },
	{ "question": "請け負う", "answers": [ "うけおう" ], "comment": "to contract; to undertake\nto take over; to take responsibility for" },
	{ "question": "請求", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "claim; demand; charge; application; request; billing (for a service)" },
	{ "question": "請求権", "answers": [ "せいきゅうけん" ], "comment": "claim rights" },
	{ "question": "請託", "answers": [ "せいたく" ], "comment": "solicitation" },
	{ "question": "請負", "answers": [ "うけおい" ], "comment": "contract (for work); contracting; undertaking" },
	{ "question": "請願", "answers": [ "せいがん" ], "comment": "petition" },
	{ "question": "論じる", "answers": [ "ろんじる" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk about; to deal with (a topic)\nto argue; to dispute\nto take into consideration; to make an issue of" },
	{ "question": "論ずる", "answers": [ "ろんずる" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk about; to deal with (a topic)\nto argue; to dispute\nto take into consideration; to make an issue of" },
	{ "question": "論争", "answers": [ "ろんそう" ], "comment": "dispute; controversy" },
	{ "question": "論告", "answers": [ "ろんこく" ], "comment": "prosecutor's closing argument" },
	{ "question": "論外", "answers": [ "ろんがい" ], "comment": "out of the question" },
	{ "question": "論客", "answers": [ "ろんきゃく", "ろんかく" ], "comment": "controversialist" },
	{ "question": "論戦", "answers": [ "ろんせん" ], "comment": "verbal dispute" },
	{ "question": "論拠", "answers": [ "ろんきょ" ], "comment": "grounds of an argument" },
	{ "question": "論文", "answers": [ "ろんぶん" ], "comment": "thesis; essay; treatise; paper; article" },
	{ "question": "論点", "answers": [ "ろんてん" ], "comment": "point in question (at issue)" },
	{ "question": "論理", "answers": [ "ろんり" ], "comment": "logic\nlogical" },
	{ "question": "論理的", "answers": [ "ろんりてき" ], "comment": "logical" },
	{ "question": "論者", "answers": [ "ろんしゃ" ], "comment": "advocate" },
	{ "question": "論評", "answers": [ "ろんぴょう" ], "comment": "comment; criticism" },
	{ "question": "論説", "answers": [ "ろんせつ" ], "comment": "editorial; dissertation" },
	{ "question": "論調", "answers": [ "ろんちょう" ], "comment": "tenor or drift of an argument" },
	{ "question": "論議", "answers": [ "ろんぎ" ], "comment": "discussion; argument; debate" },
	{ "question": "諦める", "answers": [ "あきらめる" ], "comment": "to give up; to abandon (hope, plans); to resign oneself (to)" },
	{ "question": "諮問", "answers": [ "しもん" ], "comment": "consultation; question; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "諸", "answers": [ "しょ" ], "comment": "various; many; several" },
	{ "question": "諸君", "answers": [ "しょくん" ], "comment": "you (people)\ngentlemen; ladies and gentlemen; my friends; everyone" },
	{ "question": "諸国", "answers": [ "しょこく" ], "comment": "various countries; various regions; various provinces" },
	{ "question": "謀る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to plan; to attempt; to devise\nto plot; to conspire; to scheme\nto aim for; to strive for; to work towards; to seek\nto deceive; to trick; to take in" },
	{ "question": "謎", "answers": [ "なぞ" ], "comment": "riddle; puzzle; enigma; mystery\nenigmatic; mysterious" },
	{ "question": "謙虚", "answers": [ "けんきょ" ], "comment": "modesty; humility" },
	{ "question": "謙遜", "answers": [ "けんそん" ], "comment": "modesty; humility; being humble" },
	{ "question": "講ずる", "answers": [ "こうずる" ], "comment": "to take measures; to work out a plan\nto lecture; to read aloud\nto confer" },
	{ "question": "講和", "answers": [ "こうわ" ], "comment": "reconciliation (between warring nations); (making of) peace" },
	{ "question": "講堂", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "auditorium; lecture hall" },
	{ "question": "講師", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "lecturer" },
	{ "question": "講座", "answers": [ "こうざ" ], "comment": "academic teaching unit; lectureship; professorial chair\ncourse (e.g. of lectures)" },
	{ "question": "講演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "lecture; address; speech" },
	{ "question": "講義", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "lecture" },
	{ "question": "講習", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "short course; training" },
	{ "question": "講談", "answers": [ "こうだん" ], "comment": "story-telling" },
	{ "question": "謝る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to apologize; to apologise" },
	{ "question": "謝意", "answers": [ "しゃい" ], "comment": "gratitude; thanks" },
	{ "question": "謝礼", "answers": [ "しゃれい" ], "comment": "reward; honorarium; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "謝罪", "answers": [ "しゃざい" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "謹慎", "answers": [ "きんしん" ], "comment": "self restraint; moderating one's behaviour; penitence; discipline\nconfinement to one's home; house arrest" },
	{ "question": "謹賀新年", "answers": [ "きんがしんねん" ], "comment": "Happy New Year" },
	{ "question": "識別", "answers": [ "しきべつ" ], "comment": "discrimination; discernment; identification" },
	{ "question": "識者", "answers": [ "しきしゃ" ], "comment": "well-informed person; thinking person; intelligent person" },
	{ "question": "警備", "answers": [ "けいび" ], "comment": "defense; defence; guard; policing; security" },
	{ "question": "警告", "answers": [ "けいこく" ], "comment": "warning; advice" },
	{ "question": "警報", "answers": [ "けいほう" ], "comment": "alarm; warning" },
	{ "question": "警官", "answers": [ "けいかん" ], "comment": "police officer; policeman; constable" },
	{ "question": "警察", "answers": [ "けいさつ" ], "comment": "police\npolice officer\npolice station" },
	{ "question": "警察官", "answers": [ "けいさつかん" ], "comment": "policeman; policewoman; police officer" },
	{ "question": "警察庁", "answers": [ "けいさつちょう" ], "comment": "National Police Agency" },
	{ "question": "警察署", "answers": [ "けいさつしょ" ], "comment": "police station" },
	{ "question": "警戒", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "vigilance; caution; alertness; precaution; being on guard" },
	{ "question": "警視", "answers": [ "けいし" ], "comment": "police superintendent; metropolitan police" },
	{ "question": "警視庁", "answers": [ "けいしちょう" ], "comment": "Metropolitan Police Department (esp. Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "警護", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "bodyguard; escort" },
	{ "question": "警部", "answers": [ "けいぶ" ], "comment": "police inspector" },
	{ "question": "警鐘", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "alarm bell; fire bell\nwarning; wake-up call" },
	{ "question": "議事", "answers": [ "ぎじ" ], "comment": "proceedings (e.g. parliament, congress); business (of the day)" },
	{ "question": "議事堂", "answers": [ "ぎじどう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; parliament house; diet building; capitol; houses of parliament; congress hall" },
	{ "question": "議事録", "answers": [ "ぎじろく" ], "comment": "record of proceedings; minutes" },
	{ "question": "議会", "answers": [ "ぎかい" ], "comment": "congress; parliament; diet; legislative assembly" },
	{ "question": "議員", "answers": [ "ぎいん" ], "comment": "member of the Diet, congress or parliament" },
	{ "question": "議場", "answers": [ "ぎじょう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; the House" },
	{ "question": "議定書", "answers": [ "ぎていしょ" ], "comment": "protocol" },
	{ "question": "議席", "answers": [ "ぎせき" ], "comment": "parliamentary seat" },
	{ "question": "議案", "answers": [ "ぎあん" ], "comment": "legislative bill; measure\nagenda item" },
	{ "question": "議決", "answers": [ "ぎけつ" ], "comment": "resolution; decision; vote" },
	{ "question": "議論", "answers": [ "ぎろん" ], "comment": "argument; discussion; dispute; controversy" },
	{ "question": "議長", "answers": [ "ぎちょう" ], "comment": "chairman; speaker (e.g. of assembly); president (e.g. of council, senate, etc.); moderator (e.g. of a newsgroup)" },
	{ "question": "議院", "answers": [ "ぎいん" ], "comment": "parliament; congress; diet\nhouse (of parliament, etc.); chamber" },
	{ "question": "議院運営委員会", "answers": [ "ぎいんうんえいいいんかい" ], "comment": "Committee on Rules and Administration (Diet); House Steering Committee; Standing Committee for House Management" },
	{ "question": "議題", "answers": [ "ぎだい" ], "comment": "topic of discussion; agenda" },
	{ "question": "譲り渡す", "answers": [ "ゆずりわたす" ], "comment": "to hand over; to turn over; to cede" },
	{ "question": "譲る", "answers": [ "ゆずる" ], "comment": "to turn over; to assign; to hand over; to transmit; to convey; to sell; to dispose of\nto yield; to surrender; to concede" },
	{ "question": "譲歩", "answers": [ "じょうほ" ], "comment": "concession; conciliation; compromise" },
	{ "question": "譲渡", "answers": [ "じょうと" ], "comment": "transfer; assignment; conveyance" },
	{ "question": "護国", "answers": [ "ごこく" ], "comment": "defense of one's country; defence of one's country" },
	{ "question": "護岸", "answers": [ "ごがん" ], "comment": "river dike" },
	{ "question": "護憲", "answers": [ "ごけん" ], "comment": "protecting the constitution" },
	{ "question": "護衛", "answers": [ "ごえい" ], "comment": "guard; convoy; escort" },
	{ "question": "護送", "answers": [ "ごそう" ], "comment": "escort (e.g. under guard); convoy" },
	{ "question": "谷", "answers": [ "たに" ], "comment": "valley" },
	{ "question": "谷川", "answers": [ "たにがわ" ], "comment": "mountain stream" },
	{ "question": "谷間", "answers": [ "たにあい", "たにま" ], "comment": "valley; ravine; chasm; dell\ncleavage" },
	{ "question": "豆", "answers": [ "まめ" ], "comment": "legume (esp. edible legumes or their seeds, such as beans, peas, pulses, etc.); beans; peas\nsoya bean (Glycine max); soybean; soy\nfemale genitalia (esp. the clitoris)\nkidney\nminiature; tiny\nchild" },
	{ "question": "豆腐", "answers": [ "とうふ" ], "comment": "tofu; bean-curd" },
	{ "question": "豊か", "answers": [ "ゆたか" ], "comment": "abundant; wealthy; plentiful; rich; affluent\nvery; extremely; full of; great" },
	{ "question": "豊作", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "abundant harvest; bumper crop" },
	{ "question": "豊富", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "abundance; wealth; plenty; bounty" },
	{ "question": "豊胸", "answers": [ "ほうきょう" ], "comment": "full breasts; ample breasts\nbreast enlargement" },
	{ "question": "豚", "answers": [ "ぶた" ], "comment": "pig (Sus scrofa domesticus)\nfat person" },
	{ "question": "豚肉", "answers": [ "とんにく", "ぶたにく" ], "comment": "pork" },
	{ "question": "象", "answers": [ "しょう", "ぞう" ], "comment": "phenomenon /\n elephant (Elephantidae spp.)" },
	{ "question": "象徴", "answers": [ "しょうちょう" ], "comment": "symbol" },
	{ "question": "象徴的", "answers": [ "しょうちょうてき" ], "comment": "symbolic" },
	{ "question": "象牙", "answers": [ "ぞうげ" ], "comment": "ivory" },
	{ "question": "豪快", "answers": [ "ごうかい" ], "comment": "hearty; exciting; stirring; lively; heroic; largehearted; splendid" },
	{ "question": "豪華", "answers": [ "ごうか" ], "comment": "wonderful; gorgeous; splendor; splendour; pomp; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "豪雨", "answers": [ "ごうう" ], "comment": "torrential rain; heavy rain; cloudburst; downpour" },
	{ "question": "貝", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "shellfish\nseashell; shell" },
	{ "question": "貝殻", "answers": [ "かいがら" ], "comment": "seashell; shell" },
	{ "question": "負", "answers": [ "ふ" ], "comment": "negative; minus" },
	{ "question": "負い目", "answers": [ "おいめ" ], "comment": "(feeling of) indebtedness; feeling obliged" },
	{ "question": "負う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "to bear; to carry on one's back\nto take responsibility for; to accept a duty\nto be injured\nto owe" },
	{ "question": "負かす", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "to defeat" },
	{ "question": "負け", "answers": [ "まけ" ], "comment": "defeat; loss; losing (a game)" },
	{ "question": "負ける", "answers": [ "まける" ], "comment": "to lose; to be defeated\nto succumb; to give in; to surrender; to yield\nto be inferior to\nto break out in a rash due to (e.g. lacquer, shaving, etc.)\nto reduce the price; to give a discount; to throw in (something extra) for free" },
	{ "question": "負け越し", "answers": [ "まけこし" ], "comment": "more losses than wins (sport)" },
	{ "question": "負債", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "debt; liabilities" },
	{ "question": "負傷", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "injury; wound" },
	{ "question": "負担", "answers": [ "ふたん" ], "comment": "burden; charge; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "負荷", "answers": [ "ふか" ], "comment": "burden; load (e.g. cpu time, electricity, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "財", "answers": [ "ざい" ], "comment": "fortune; riches\ngoods\nincorporated foundation" },
	{ "question": "財務", "answers": [ "ざいむ" ], "comment": "financial affairs" },
	{ "question": "財務官", "answers": [ "ざいむかん" ], "comment": "finance official" },
	{ "question": "財団", "answers": [ "ざいだん" ], "comment": "foundation" },
	{ "question": "財団法人", "answers": [ "ざいだんほうじん" ], "comment": "incorporated foundation; juridical foundation" },
	{ "question": "財布", "answers": [ "さいふ" ], "comment": "purse; handbag; wallet" },
	{ "question": "財政", "answers": [ "ざいせい" ], "comment": "public finance\nfinancial affairs; financial situation" },
	{ "question": "財政投融資", "answers": [ "ざいせいとうゆうし" ], "comment": "Fiscal Investment and Loan Program; FILP" },
	{ "question": "財政難", "answers": [ "ざいせいなん" ], "comment": "economic difficulties; financial difficulties; fiscal difficulties" },
	{ "question": "財源", "answers": [ "ざいげん" ], "comment": "source of funds; resources; finances" },
	{ "question": "財産", "answers": [ "ざいさん" ], "comment": "property; fortune; assets" },
	{ "question": "財界", "answers": [ "ざいかい" ], "comment": "financial world" },
	{ "question": "財閥", "answers": [ "ざいばつ" ], "comment": "zaibatsu; financial conglomerate; industrial group" },
	{ "question": "貢献", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "contribution (furthering a goal or cause); services (to a cause)" },
	{ "question": "貧しい", "answers": [ "まずしい" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking (quantity and quality-wise); poor; scanty; skimpy; slight; inadequate" },
	{ "question": "貧乏", "answers": [ "びんぼう" ], "comment": "poverty; destitute; poor" },
	{ "question": "貧乏人", "answers": [ "びんぼうにん" ], "comment": "poor person; pauper; the poor; the indigent" },
	{ "question": "貧困", "answers": [ "ひんこん" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking; meagre; meager" },
	{ "question": "貧富", "answers": [ "ひんぷ" ], "comment": "wealth and poverty; rich and poor" },
	{ "question": "貧弱", "answers": [ "ひんじゃく" ], "comment": "poor; meagre; meager; insubstantial" },
	{ "question": "貧血", "answers": [ "ひんけつ" ], "comment": "anemia; anaemia" },
	{ "question": "貨幣", "answers": [ "かへい" ], "comment": "money; currency; coinage" },
	{ "question": "貨物", "answers": [ "かぶつ", "かもつ" ], "comment": "cargo; freight\nmoney or assets" },
	{ "question": "貨車", "answers": [ "かしゃ" ], "comment": "freight car; van" },
	{ "question": "販売", "answers": [ "はんばい" ], "comment": "sales; selling; marketing" },
	{ "question": "販売員", "answers": [ "はんばいいん" ], "comment": "sales staff; salesperson" },
	{ "question": "貪欲", "answers": [ "とんよく", "どんよく", "たんよく" ], "comment": "avarice; greed; covetousness\nraga (desire)" },
	{ "question": "貫", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "kan (obs. unit of weight, approx. 3.75 kg, 8.3 lb)\nkan (obs. unit of currency)\npieces of sushi" },
	{ "question": "貫く", "answers": [ "つらぬく" ], "comment": "to go through; to pierce; to penetrate\nto carry out; to persist; to keep (faith); to stick to (principles); to maintain (independence)" },
	{ "question": "責める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "to condemn; to blame; to criticize; to criticise; to reproach; to accuse\nto urge; to press; to pester\nto torture; to torment; to persecute\nto break in (a horse)" },
	{ "question": "責任", "answers": [ "せきにん" ], "comment": "duty; responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)\nliability; onus" },
	{ "question": "責任を持つ", "answers": [ "せきにんをもつ" ], "comment": "to be responsible for; to bear the responsibility of" },
	{ "question": "責任感", "answers": [ "せきにんかん" ], "comment": "sense of responsibility" },
	{ "question": "責任者", "answers": [ "せきにんしゃ" ], "comment": "person in charge (including a supervisory role for other staff); person responsible for ...; responsible party; supervisor; manager" },
	{ "question": "責務", "answers": [ "せきむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation" },
	{ "question": "貯水", "answers": [ "ちょすい" ], "comment": "storage of water" },
	{ "question": "貯蓄", "answers": [ "ちょちく" ], "comment": "savings" },
	{ "question": "貯蔵", "answers": [ "ちょぞう" ], "comment": "storage; preservation" },
	{ "question": "貯金", "answers": [ "ちょきん" ], "comment": "putting money aside; savings; deposit (e.g. in a bank)\naccumulated surplus of wins; wins in the bank" },
	{ "question": "貴い", "answers": [ "たっとい", "とうとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "貴ぶ", "answers": [ "たっとぶ", "とうとぶ" ], "comment": "to value; to prize; to esteem; to respect" },
	{ "question": "貴族", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "noble; aristocrat" },
	{ "question": "貴重", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "precious; valuable" },
	{ "question": "貴重品", "answers": [ "きちょうひん" ], "comment": "valuables; treasures" },
	{ "question": "貴金属", "answers": [ "ききんぞく" ], "comment": "precious metal" },
	{ "question": "買い", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "buying; shopping\nbuyer\npurchase" },
	{ "question": "買い上げ", "answers": [ "かいあげ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing; procurement" },
	{ "question": "買い付け", "answers": [ "かいつけ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing" },
	{ "question": "買い入れ", "answers": [ "かいいれ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing; laying in" },
	{ "question": "買い出し", "answers": [ "かいだし" ], "comment": "going out to shop; going shopping\nbuying in quantity; buying wholesale; bulk purchasing" },
	{ "question": "買い占め", "answers": [ "かいしめ" ], "comment": "buying up of goods; cornering (market)" },
	{ "question": "買い占める", "answers": [ "かいしめる" ], "comment": "to buy up" },
	{ "question": "買い取り", "answers": [ "かいとり" ], "comment": "purchase; buying; buying out\nbuying used articles as a company; trade-in; buy back\npurchase on a no-return policy\nlump-sum payment; flat fee" },
	{ "question": "買い得", "answers": [ "かいどく" ], "comment": "bargain; good buy" },
	{ "question": "買い戻し", "answers": [ "かいもどし" ], "comment": "repurchase; redemption" },
	{ "question": "買い手", "answers": [ "かいて" ], "comment": "buyer" },
	{ "question": "買い控え", "answers": [ "かいびかえ" ], "comment": "restrained buying" },
	{ "question": "買い物", "answers": [ "かいもの" ], "comment": "shopping; purchased goods" },
	{ "question": "買う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "to buy; to purchase\nto value; to have a high opinion\nto stir; to provoke" },
	{ "question": "買収", "answers": [ "ばいしゅう" ], "comment": "acquisition (esp. corporate); buy-out; takeover; purchase\ncorruption; bribery" },
	{ "question": "買取", "answers": [ "かいとり" ], "comment": "purchase; buying; buying out\nbuying used articles as a company; trade-in; buy back\npurchase on a no-return policy\nlump-sum payment; flat fee" },
	{ "question": "買手", "answers": [ "かいて" ], "comment": "buyer" },
	{ "question": "買物", "answers": [ "かいもの" ], "comment": "shopping; purchased goods" },
	{ "question": "貸し", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "loan; lending\nfavor; favour; debt; obligation\ncreditor; method of lending; credit side" },
	{ "question": "貸し出し", "answers": [ "かしだし" ], "comment": "lending; loaning" },
	{ "question": "貸し出す", "answers": [ "かしだす" ], "comment": "to lend; to loan; to let out on hire" },
	{ "question": "貸し切り", "answers": [ "かしきり" ], "comment": "reserving; chartering; engaging; reservation" },
	{ "question": "貸す", "answers": [ "かす" ], "comment": "to lend; to loan\nto rent out; to hire out" },
	{ "question": "貸与", "answers": [ "たいよ" ], "comment": "loan; lending" },
	{ "question": "貸付", "answers": [ "かしつけ" ], "comment": "loan" },
	{ "question": "貸借", "answers": [ "たいしゃく" ], "comment": "loan; debit and credit; lending and borrowing" },
	{ "question": "貸出用", "answers": [ "かしだしよう" ], "comment": "circulation or lending (e.g. library books)" },
	{ "question": "貸切り", "answers": [ "かしきり" ], "comment": "reserving; chartering; engaging; reservation" },
	{ "question": "貸家", "answers": [ "かしや", "かしいえ" ], "comment": "house for rent" },
	{ "question": "貸金", "answers": [ "かしきん" ], "comment": "loan; advance" },
	{ "question": "貸間", "answers": [ "かしま" ], "comment": "room to let; room for rent" },
	{ "question": "費", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "cost; expense" },
	{ "question": "費やす", "answers": [ "ついやす" ], "comment": "to spend; to expend; to consume\nto waste; to squander; to throw away\nto devote" },
	{ "question": "費用", "answers": [ "ひよう" ], "comment": "cost; expense" },
	{ "question": "貼り付ける", "answers": [ "はりつける" ], "comment": "to paste; to stick; to affix\nto station; to post" },
	{ "question": "貼る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "to stick; to paste; to affix\nto stretch; to spread; to strain; to tighten; to put up (tent)\nto form (e.g. ice on a pond)\nto fill; to swell\nto stick out; to put; to slap\nto be expensive\nto keep a watch on; to be on the lookout\nto become one tile away from completion\nto span; to generate" },
	{ "question": "貿易", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "trade (foreign)" },
	{ "question": "賃上げ", "answers": [ "ちんあげ" ], "comment": "wage increase" },
	{ "question": "賃貸", "answers": [ "ちんたい" ], "comment": "lease; rent; hire" },
	{ "question": "賃金", "answers": [ "ちんきん", "ちんぎん" ], "comment": "wages\ncash payment of rent" },
	{ "question": "賄う", "answers": [ "まかなう" ], "comment": "to give board to; to provide meals; to pay; to cover (the cost)" },
	{ "question": "賄賂", "answers": [ "わいろ" ], "comment": "bribe; sweetener; douceur" },
	{ "question": "資する", "answers": [ "しする" ], "comment": "to contribute; to play a part in; to have a hand in; to be conducive to; to be instrumental in\nto finance" },
	{ "question": "資料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "materials; data; document" },
	{ "question": "資本", "answers": [ "しほん" ], "comment": "funds; capital" },
	{ "question": "資本主義", "answers": [ "しほんしゅぎ" ], "comment": "capitalism" },
	{ "question": "資本家", "answers": [ "しほんか" ], "comment": "capitalist; financier" },
	{ "question": "資本金", "answers": [ "しほんきん" ], "comment": "capital stock" },
	{ "question": "資材", "answers": [ "しざい" ], "comment": "(raw) material" },
	{ "question": "資格", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "qualifications; requirements; capabilities" },
	{ "question": "資源", "answers": [ "しげん" ], "comment": "resources" },
	{ "question": "資源エネルギー庁", "answers": [ "しげんエネルギーちょう" ], "comment": "Agency of Natural Resources and Energy" },
	{ "question": "資産", "answers": [ "しさん" ], "comment": "property; fortune; means; assets" },
	{ "question": "資質", "answers": [ "ししつ" ], "comment": "nature; disposition; temperament; qualities; attributes; talents" },
	{ "question": "資金", "answers": [ "しきん" ], "comment": "funds; capital" },
	{ "question": "資金繰り", "answers": [ "しきんぐり" ], "comment": "fundraising; financing; cash flow" },
	{ "question": "資金調達", "answers": [ "しきんちょうたつ" ], "comment": "fundraising" },
	{ "question": "賑やか", "answers": [ "にぎやか" ], "comment": "bustling; busy; lively" },
	{ "question": "賑わう", "answers": [ "にぎわう" ], "comment": "to be crowded with people; to be bustling with\nto prosper; to flourish; to do thriving business" },
	{ "question": "賓客", "answers": [ "ひんきゃく", "ひんかく" ], "comment": "guest of honour; guest of honor; privileged guest; visitor" },
	{ "question": "賛", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "praise; tribute\ninscription (on a painting)" },
	{ "question": "賛同", "answers": [ "さんどう" ], "comment": "approval; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "賛否", "answers": [ "さんぴ" ], "comment": "yes and no; for and against" },
	{ "question": "賛意", "answers": [ "さんい" ], "comment": "approval; assent" },
	{ "question": "賛成", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "approval; agreement; support; favour; favor" },
	{ "question": "賛歌", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "song of praise; eulogy; paean; hymn" },
	{ "question": "賛美", "answers": [ "さんび" ], "comment": "praise; adoration; glorification" },
	{ "question": "賛辞", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "eulogy; compliment" },
	{ "question": "賜杯", "answers": [ "しはい" ], "comment": "Emperor's cup; trophy given by the Emperor" },
	{ "question": "賞", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "prize; award" },
	{ "question": "賞与", "answers": [ "しょうよ" ], "comment": "bonus\nreward; prize" },
	{ "question": "賞品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "prize; trophy" },
	{ "question": "賞牌", "answers": [ "しょうはい" ], "comment": "medal" },
	{ "question": "賞状", "answers": [ "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "honorable certificate; honourable certificate" },
	{ "question": "賞罰", "answers": [ "しょうばつ" ], "comment": "rewards and punishments" },
	{ "question": "賞賛", "answers": [ "しょうさん" ], "comment": "praise; admiration; commendation; approbation" },
	{ "question": "賞金", "answers": [ "しょうきん" ], "comment": "prize; monetary award" },
	{ "question": "賠償", "answers": [ "ばいしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reparations; indemnity; damages" },
	{ "question": "賠償金", "answers": [ "ばいしょうきん" ], "comment": "indemnities; reparations" },
	{ "question": "賢い", "answers": [ "かしこい" ], "comment": "wise; clever; smart" },
	{ "question": "賢人", "answers": [ "けんじん" ], "comment": "wise man" },
	{ "question": "賢明", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "wisdom; intelligence; prudence" },
	{ "question": "質", "answers": [ "しつ" ], "comment": "quality; value\nnature; inherent quality; character\nlogical quality" },
	{ "question": "質問", "answers": [ "しつもん" ], "comment": "question; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "質問をする", "answers": [ "しつもんをする" ], "comment": "to ask a question; to ask questions" },
	{ "question": "質屋", "answers": [ "しちや" ], "comment": "pawnshop" },
	{ "question": "質疑", "answers": [ "しつぎ" ], "comment": "question\ninterpellation" },
	{ "question": "質的", "answers": [ "しつてき" ], "comment": "qualitative" },
	{ "question": "質素", "answers": [ "しっそ" ], "comment": "simple; plain\nmodest; frugal; reserved" },
	{ "question": "質量", "answers": [ "しつりょう" ], "comment": "mass" },
	{ "question": "賭け", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "betting; gambling; a gamble" },
	{ "question": "賭ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to wager; to bet; to risk; to stake; to gamble" },
	{ "question": "購入", "answers": [ "こうにゅう" ], "comment": "purchase; buy" },
	{ "question": "購読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "paid subscription (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "購買", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "procurement; purchase; buying\nschool store; co-op; school canteen; tuck shop" },
	{ "question": "購買力", "answers": [ "こうばいりょく" ], "comment": "buying power; purchasing power" },
	{ "question": "贅沢", "answers": [ "ぜいたく" ], "comment": "luxury; extravagance\nto live in luxury; to indulge oneself\nlavish (use of something); abundant; copious; wasteful" },
	{ "question": "贈り物", "answers": [ "おくりもの" ], "comment": "present; gift" },
	{ "question": "贈る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "to give (as a gift); to present\nto confer; to bestow; to award" },
	{ "question": "贈与", "answers": [ "ぞうよ" ], "comment": "donation; presentation" },
	{ "question": "贈呈", "answers": [ "ぞうてい" ], "comment": "presentation (e.g. of a gift, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "贈物", "answers": [ "おくりもの" ], "comment": "present; gift" },
	{ "question": "贈答", "answers": [ "ぞうとう" ], "comment": "exchange of presents" },
	{ "question": "贈賄", "answers": [ "ぞうわい" ], "comment": "bribery; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "贔屓", "answers": [ "ひいき" ], "comment": "favour; favor; patronage; partiality; patron\nfavourite; favorite" },
	{ "question": "赤", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "red; crimson; scarlet\nred-containing colour (e.g. brown, pink, orange)\nRed (i.e. communist)\nred light\nred ink (i.e. in finance or proof-reading); (in) the red\ncomplete; total; perfect; obvious\ncopper" },
	{ "question": "赤い", "answers": [ "あかい" ], "comment": "red\nRed (i.e. communist)" },
	{ "question": "赤ちゃん", "answers": [ "あかちゃん" ], "comment": "baby; infant" },
	{ "question": "赤ん坊", "answers": [ "あかんぼう", "あかんぼ" ], "comment": "baby; infant" },
	{ "question": "赤信号", "answers": [ "あかしんごう" ], "comment": "red light (traffic)" },
	{ "question": "赤外線", "answers": [ "せきがいせん" ], "comment": "infrared rays" },
	{ "question": "赤字", "answers": [ "あかじ" ], "comment": "deficit; (being in or going into) the red\nred text; red letters\ncorrections (by a teacher or proofreader) written in red" },
	{ "question": "赤旗", "answers": [ "あかはた" ], "comment": "red flag\nRed Flag (Communist Party newspaper)" },
	{ "question": "赤松", "answers": [ "あかまつ" ], "comment": "Japanese red pine (Pinus densiflora); Japanese umbrella pine; tanyosho pine" },
	{ "question": "赤色", "answers": [ "あかいろ", "せきしょく" ], "comment": "red; red color (colour)\nred-colored; red\ncommunism; the left" },
	{ "question": "赤軍", "answers": [ "せきぐん" ], "comment": "Red Army (Soviet Union, 1918-1946); Workers' and Peasants' Red Army" },
	{ "question": "赤道", "answers": [ "せきどう" ], "comment": "equator" },
	{ "question": "赤面", "answers": [ "せきめん" ], "comment": "blushing; getting red in the face\nembarrassment" },
	{ "question": "赤飯", "answers": [ "せきはん" ], "comment": "red rice (beans and mochi) for auspicious occasions" },
	{ "question": "走り", "answers": [ "はしり" ], "comment": "running\ngliding\nfirst (harvest) of the season\nbeginning; start\nkitchen sink" },
	{ "question": "走り出す", "answers": [ "はしりだす" ], "comment": "to begin to run; to start running; to break into a run" },
	{ "question": "走り幅跳び", "answers": [ "はしりはばとび" ], "comment": "running long jump" },
	{ "question": "走り高跳び", "answers": [ "はしりたかとび" ], "comment": "running high jump" },
	{ "question": "走る", "answers": [ "はしる" ], "comment": "to run\nto travel (movement of vehicles); to drive\nto hurry to\nto retreat (from battle); to take flight\nto run away from home\nto elope\nto tend heavily toward\nto flash; to streak; to shoot through (e.g. pain)" },
	{ "question": "走塁", "answers": [ "そうるい" ], "comment": "base running" },
	{ "question": "走者", "answers": [ "そうしゃ" ], "comment": "runner\nbase runner" },
	{ "question": "走行", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "running a wheeled vehicle (e.g. car); running to program, job, etc.; traveling; travelling" },
	{ "question": "赴任", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "moving to a different location to start a new job; (proceeding to) new appointment" },
	{ "question": "起きる", "answers": [ "おきる" ], "comment": "to get up; to rise; to blaze up (fire)\nto wake up; to be awake; to stay awake\nto occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents); to happen; to take place" },
	{ "question": "起き上がる", "answers": [ "おきあがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to erect; to get up" },
	{ "question": "起こす", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "to raise; to raise up; to set up; to pick up\nto wake; to wake up; to waken; to awaken\nto cause; to bring about; to lead to; to trigger; to give rise to; to create; to generate (e.g. heat, electricity); to produce\nto start; to begin; to launch; to establish; to found; to set up; to open\nto plough; to plow; to till\nto fall ill with\nto transcribe; to write down (what is spoken)\nto turn over (a card)" },
	{ "question": "起こる", "answers": [ "おこる" ], "comment": "to occur; to happen" },
	{ "question": "起伏", "answers": [ "きふく" ], "comment": "undulation\nups and downs; highs and lows" },
	{ "question": "起債", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "issuing of bonds" },
	{ "question": "起因", "answers": [ "きいん" ], "comment": "cause; origin" },
	{ "question": "起工", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "setting to work" },
	{ "question": "起床", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "rising; getting out of bed" },
	{ "question": "起死回生", "answers": [ "きしかいせい" ], "comment": "revival from the brink of death; recovering from a hopeless situation; resuscitation; revitalization" },
	{ "question": "起源", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "origin; beginning; rise" },
	{ "question": "起点", "answers": [ "きてん" ], "comment": "starting point; origin" },
	{ "question": "起爆", "answers": [ "きばく" ], "comment": "exploding" },
	{ "question": "起用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "appointment (to a position, job, etc.); being used for a role; promotion" },
	{ "question": "起立", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "standing up" },
	{ "question": "起草", "answers": [ "きそう" ], "comment": "drafting; draughting; drawing up a bill" },
	{ "question": "起訴", "answers": [ "きそ" ], "comment": "prosecution; indictment" },
	{ "question": "起訴猶予", "answers": [ "きそゆうよ" ], "comment": "suspension of indictment; leaving charge on the file" },
	{ "question": "超", "answers": [ "ちょう", "チョー" ], "comment": "super-; ultra-; hyper-; very; really\nover (after a number or counter); more than" },
	{ "question": "超える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to cross; to pass through; to pass over (out of)\nto exceed" },
	{ "question": "超す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "to cross over (e.g. mountain); to go across\nto go over (e.g. with audience)\nto pass time (e.g. a winter)\nto surpass; to be better than; to exceed\nto move house\nto go; to come" },
	{ "question": "超伝導", "answers": [ "ちょうでんどう" ], "comment": "superconductivity; super-conductivity" },
	{ "question": "超党派", "answers": [ "ちょうとうは" ], "comment": "suprapartisan; multiparty; bipartisan; nonpartisan" },
	{ "question": "超特急", "answers": [ "ちょうとっきゅう" ], "comment": "super express" },
	{ "question": "超越", "answers": [ "ちょうえつ" ], "comment": "transcendence; transcendency\ntranscendental\nto transcend; to rise above" },
	{ "question": "超過", "answers": [ "ちょうか" ], "comment": "excess; being more than" },
	{ "question": "超電導", "answers": [ "ちょうでんどう" ], "comment": "superconductivity; super-conductivity" },
	{ "question": "超音波", "answers": [ "ちょうおんぱ" ], "comment": "ultrasonic waves; ultrasound" },
	{ "question": "越える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to cross; to pass through; to pass over (out of)\nto exceed" },
	{ "question": "越し", "answers": [ "ごし" ], "comment": "across; over; beyond; through; crossing\nthroughout (a period of time); for" },
	{ "question": "越す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "to cross over (e.g. mountain); to go across\nto go over (e.g. with audience)\nto pass time (e.g. a winter)\nto surpass; to be better than; to exceed\nto move house\nto go; to come" },
	{ "question": "越冬", "answers": [ "えっとう" ], "comment": "passing the winter; hibernation" },
	{ "question": "越境", "answers": [ "えっきょう" ], "comment": "border transgression" },
	{ "question": "越年", "answers": [ "えつねん" ], "comment": "ring out the old year; hibernation" },
	{ "question": "越後", "answers": [ "えちご" ], "comment": "Echigo; old name for Niigata Prefecture" },
	{ "question": "趣", "answers": [ "おもむき" ], "comment": "meaning; tenor; gist\neffect; influence\nappearance; aspect\ntaste\ngrace; charm; refinement" },
	{ "question": "趣き", "answers": [ "おもむき" ], "comment": "meaning; tenor; gist\neffect; influence\nappearance; aspect\ntaste\ngrace; charm; refinement" },
	{ "question": "趣向", "answers": [ "しゅこう" ], "comment": "plan; idea; design; plot" },
	{ "question": "趣味", "answers": [ "しゅみ" ], "comment": "hobby; pastime\ntastes; preference; liking" },
	{ "question": "趣旨", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "meaning; point (e.g. of a statement); gist; effect\ngoal; intent; object; aim; point" },
	{ "question": "足", "answers": [ "あし" ], "comment": "foot\nleg\ngait\npace\nbottom structural component (i.e. radical) of a kanji\nmeans of transportation\nmoney; coin" },
	{ "question": "足あと", "answers": [ "そくせき", "あしあと" ], "comment": "footprints\nrecord of page visitors (e.g. in social networking sites)" },
	{ "question": "足し算", "answers": [ "たしざん" ], "comment": "addition" },
	{ "question": "足す", "answers": [ "たす" ], "comment": "to add (numbers)\nto add (something); to top up (with something)\nto take care of (e.g. one's business)" },
	{ "question": "足りる", "answers": [ "たりる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough\nto be worth doing; to be worthy\nto be sufficient; to answer; to do" },
	{ "question": "足る", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough; to be worthy of" },
	{ "question": "足下", "answers": [ "そっか", "あしもと" ], "comment": "at one's feet; underfoot; one's step (as in \"watch your step\")\ngait; pace; step\nmost recent; current\nyou; thou" },
	{ "question": "足並み", "answers": [ "あしなみ" ], "comment": "pace; step" },
	{ "question": "足元", "answers": [ "そっか", "あしもと" ], "comment": "at one's feet; underfoot; one's step (as in \"watch your step\")\ngait; pace; step\nmost recent; current\nyou; thou" },
	{ "question": "足取り", "answers": [ "あしどり" ], "comment": "gait; walk; stride; pace; step; manner of walking\ntrace (e.g. of route taken by hunted criminal); track; trail; movements" },
	{ "question": "足場", "answers": [ "あしば" ], "comment": "scaffold; scaffolding\nfoothold; footing\nfoothold (e.g. in business); foundation; base\nconvenience for transportation; convenience of access (by road or rail)" },
	{ "question": "足掛かり", "answers": [ "あしがかり" ], "comment": "foothold" },
	{ "question": "足早", "answers": [ "あしばや" ], "comment": "quick-footed; light-footed; quick pace" },
	{ "question": "足腰", "answers": [ "あしこし" ], "comment": "legs and loins" },
	{ "question": "足跡", "answers": [ "そくせき", "あしあと" ], "comment": "footprints\nrecord of page visitors (e.g. in social networking sites)" },
	{ "question": "足踏み", "answers": [ "あしぶみ" ], "comment": "stepping; stamping; marking time (for a soldier)\nstandstill; stalemate" },
	{ "question": "足音", "answers": [ "きょうおん", "あしおと" ], "comment": "(sound of) footsteps\nsense or sign that something is approaching" },
	{ "question": "足首", "answers": [ "あしくび" ], "comment": "ankle" },
	{ "question": "距離", "answers": [ "きょり" ], "comment": "distance; range" },
	{ "question": "跡", "answers": [ "あと" ], "comment": "trace; tracks; mark; sign\nsite; remains; ruins\nscar" },
	{ "question": "跣", "answers": [ "せんそく", "はだし" ], "comment": "barefoot\nsuperior to (a professional, etc. in ability or achievement)" },
	{ "question": "路上", "answers": [ "ろじょう" ], "comment": "(on the) road; (on the) way; (in the) street" },
	{ "question": "路地", "answers": [ "ろじ" ], "comment": "alley; alleyway; lane\nbare earth (i.e. ground not covered by a roof); open field; outdoors (non-greenhouse cultivation of crops)\nteahouse garden\npath through a gate (or through a garden, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "路線", "answers": [ "ろせん" ], "comment": "route; line; alignment" },
	{ "question": "路面", "answers": [ "ろめん" ], "comment": "road surface" },
	{ "question": "跳ねる", "answers": [ "はねる" ], "comment": "to jump; to leap; to prance; to spring up; to bound; to hop\nto break up; to close; to come to an end\nto hit (e.g. to have a car hit something or someone)" },
	{ "question": "跳び上がる", "answers": [ "とびあがる" ], "comment": "to spring; to jump up; to fly up; to skip" },
	{ "question": "跳ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "to fly; to soar\nto jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop" },
	{ "question": "跳躍", "answers": [ "ちょうやく" ], "comment": "jump; leap; skip; bound" },
	{ "question": "踊り", "answers": [ "おどり" ], "comment": "dance" },
	{ "question": "踊り子", "answers": [ "おどりこ" ], "comment": "dancer (usu. female)" },
	{ "question": "踊る", "answers": [ "おどる" ], "comment": "to dance (orig. a hopping dance)" },
	{ "question": "踏まえる", "answers": [ "ふまえる" ], "comment": "to be based on; to have origin in\nto have one's feet firmly planted on; to plant oneself on" },
	{ "question": "踏み切る", "answers": [ "ふみきる" ], "comment": "to take off; to jump; to leap\nto take the plunge; to decide; to embark on; to venture into; to launch out into\nto step out of the ring" },
	{ "question": "踏み絵", "answers": [ "ふみえ" ], "comment": "tablet bearing Christian images, on which Edo-period authorities forced suspected Christians to trample" },
	{ "question": "踏む", "answers": [ "ふむ" ], "comment": "to step on; to tread on\nto experience; to undergo\nto estimate; to value; to appraise\nto rhyme\nto inherit (the throne, etc.)\nto follow (rules, morals, principles, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "踏ん張る", "answers": [ "ふんばる" ], "comment": "to brace one's legs; to straddle; to stand firm; to plant oneself (somewhere); to hold out; to persist" },
	{ "question": "踏切", "answers": [ "ふみきり" ], "comment": "railway crossing; railroad crossing; train crossing; level crossing\nstarting line; scratch\ndetermination\nstepping over the edge of the ring" },
	{ "question": "踏切り", "answers": [ "ふみきり" ], "comment": "railway crossing; railroad crossing; train crossing; level crossing\nstarting line; scratch\ndetermination\nstepping over the edge of the ring" },
	{ "question": "蹴る", "answers": [ "ける" ], "comment": "to kick\nto refuse; to reject" },
	{ "question": "躍り", "answers": [ "おどり" ], "comment": "leaping; jumping; spring; exciting" },
	{ "question": "躍動", "answers": [ "やくどう" ], "comment": "lively motion; throb" },
	{ "question": "躍起", "answers": [ "やっき" ], "comment": "desperation; eagerness" },
	{ "question": "躍進", "answers": [ "やくしん" ], "comment": "making rapid progress; making great advances; rush; dash; onslaught" },
	{ "question": "身", "answers": [ "み" ], "comment": "body\noneself\none's place; one's position\nmain part; meat (as opposed to bone, skin, etc.); wood (as opposed to bark); blade (as opposed to its handle); container (as opposed to its lid)" },
	{ "question": "身なり", "answers": [ "みなり" ], "comment": "dress; attire; clothing; getup; outfit; personal appearance" },
	{ "question": "身につける", "answers": [ "みにつける" ], "comment": "to learn; to acquire knowledge\nto carry; to wear (clothes, etc.); to put on" },
	{ "question": "身の上", "answers": [ "みのうえ" ], "comment": "one's future; one's welfare; one's personal history" },
	{ "question": "身の回り", "answers": [ "みのまわり" ], "comment": "one's personal belongings; one's vicinity; one's daily life; everyday necessities" },
	{ "question": "身上", "answers": [ "しんじょう", "しんしょう" ], "comment": "merit; body; social position" },
	{ "question": "身代わり", "answers": [ "みがわり" ], "comment": "substitute (for); sacrifice (of, to); scapegoat (for)" },
	{ "question": "身代金要求", "answers": [ "みのしろきんようきゅう" ], "comment": "ransom demand" },
	{ "question": "身体", "answers": [ "しんてい", "しんたい" ], "comment": "body; physical system; person" },
	{ "question": "身体障害者", "answers": [ "しんたいしょうがいしゃ" ], "comment": "disabled person; physically handicapped person" },
	{ "question": "身元", "answers": [ "みもと" ], "comment": "person's identity; ID; past; background" },
	{ "question": "身内", "answers": [ "みうち" ], "comment": "relatives; one's family\nfriends; members of the same organization\nfollowers; henchmen\none's whole body" },
	{ "question": "身分", "answers": [ "みぶん" ], "comment": "social position; social status" },
	{ "question": "身分証明書", "answers": [ "みぶんしょうめいしょ" ], "comment": "identification papers; ID; piece of identification; identity document" },
	{ "question": "身動き", "answers": [ "みうごき" ], "comment": "moving about; stirring about" },
	{ "question": "身寄り", "answers": [ "みより" ], "comment": "relative" },
	{ "question": "身投げ", "answers": [ "みなげ" ], "comment": "throwing oneself (e.g. into the water to commit suicide)" },
	{ "question": "身振り", "answers": [ "みぶり" ], "comment": "gesture; gesticulation; motion" },
	{ "question": "身柄", "answers": [ "みがら" ], "comment": "one's person" },
	{ "question": "身軽", "answers": [ "みがる" ], "comment": "agile; nimble; light (of foot)\ncasual (clothing); light (e.g. luggage)\ncarefree; with limited responsibility" },
	{ "question": "身辺", "answers": [ "しんぺん" ], "comment": "one's person; around one's person" },
	{ "question": "身近", "answers": [ "みぢか" ], "comment": "near oneself; close to one; familiar" },
	{ "question": "身長", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "height (of body); stature" },
	{ "question": "身障者", "answers": [ "しんしょうしゃ" ], "comment": "disabled person; physically handicapped person" },
	{ "question": "車", "answers": [ "くるま" ], "comment": "car; automobile; vehicle\nwheel" },
	{ "question": "車両", "answers": [ "しゃりょう" ], "comment": "rolling stock; railroad cars; wheeled vehicles" },
	{ "question": "車中", "answers": [ "しゃちゅう" ], "comment": "in a train or vehicle" },
	{ "question": "車体", "answers": [ "しゃたい" ], "comment": "body (of car); frame" },
	{ "question": "車内", "answers": [ "しゃない" ], "comment": "inside a train, car, etc." },
	{ "question": "車庫", "answers": [ "しゃこ" ], "comment": "garage; carport; depot (trains, buses, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "車掌", "answers": [ "しゃしょう" ], "comment": "(train) conductor" },
	{ "question": "車椅子", "answers": [ "くるまいす" ], "comment": "wheelchair; folding push-chair" },
	{ "question": "車検", "answers": [ "しゃけん" ], "comment": "vehicle inspection" },
	{ "question": "車種", "answers": [ "しゃしゅ" ], "comment": "car make; car model" },
	{ "question": "車線", "answers": [ "しゃせん" ], "comment": "traffic lane; road lane" },
	{ "question": "車輪", "answers": [ "しゃりん" ], "comment": "(car) wheel" },
	{ "question": "車道", "answers": [ "しゃどう" ], "comment": "roadway" },
	{ "question": "軌範", "answers": [ "きはん" ], "comment": "model; standard; pattern; norm; criterion; example" },
	{ "question": "軌跡", "answers": [ "きせき" ], "comment": "tire track\ntraces of a person or thing; path one has taken\nlocus" },
	{ "question": "軌道", "answers": [ "きどう" ], "comment": "orbit; trajectory\nrailroad track\n(on the right) track; going smoothly" },
	{ "question": "軍", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "army; force; troops" },
	{ "question": "軍事", "answers": [ "ぐんじ" ], "comment": "military affairs" },
	{ "question": "軍人", "answers": [ "ぐんじん" ], "comment": "military personnel; soldier" },
	{ "question": "軍備", "answers": [ "ぐんび" ], "comment": "armaments; military preparations" },
	{ "question": "軍兵", "answers": [ "ぐんびょう", "ぐんぺい", "ぐんぴょう" ], "comment": "armed forces; battle troops" },
	{ "question": "軍医", "answers": [ "ぐんい" ], "comment": "military physician or surgeon" },
	{ "question": "軍団", "answers": [ "ぐんだん" ], "comment": "army corps" },
	{ "question": "軍国主義", "answers": [ "ぐんこくしゅぎ" ], "comment": "militarism" },
	{ "question": "軍属", "answers": [ "ぐんぞく" ], "comment": "civilian in military employ" },
	{ "question": "軍拡", "answers": [ "ぐんかく" ], "comment": "military expansion; expansion of armaments" },
	{ "question": "軍政", "answers": [ "ぐんせい" ], "comment": "military government" },
	{ "question": "軍服", "answers": [ "ぐんぷく" ], "comment": "military or naval uniform" },
	{ "question": "軍機", "answers": [ "ぐんき" ], "comment": "military secret; classified military material" },
	{ "question": "軍用", "answers": [ "ぐんよう" ], "comment": "for military use" },
	{ "question": "軍縮", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅく" ], "comment": "disarmament; limitation of arms" },
	{ "question": "軍艦", "answers": [ "ぐんかん" ], "comment": "warship; battleship" },
	{ "question": "軍部", "answers": [ "ぐんぶ" ], "comment": "military authorities; army circles" },
	{ "question": "軍配", "answers": [ "ぐんばい" ], "comment": "gourd-shaped war fan\nreferee's fan\nstratagem; tactics" },
	{ "question": "軍隊", "answers": [ "ぐんたい" ], "comment": "armed forces; military; troops" },
	{ "question": "軍需", "answers": [ "ぐんじゅ" ], "comment": "munitions; military stores" },
	{ "question": "軒", "answers": [ "のき" ], "comment": "eaves\nnarrow aisle surrounding the core of a temple building" },
	{ "question": "軒並", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "軒並み", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "軟らか", "answers": [ "やわらか" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; subdued (colour or light) (color); gentle; meek" },
	{ "question": "軟らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; limber\ngentle; mild\ninformal; lighter" },
	{ "question": "軟化", "answers": [ "なんか" ], "comment": "softening; mollification\nweakening (of the market)" },
	{ "question": "軟式", "answers": [ "なんしき" ], "comment": "soft (esp. of softball, tennis, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "軟禁", "answers": [ "なんきん" ], "comment": "house arrest" },
	{ "question": "転々", "answers": [ "てんてん" ], "comment": "moving from place to place; being passed around repeatedly\nrolling about" },
	{ "question": "転がす", "answers": [ "ころがす" ], "comment": "to roll\nto turn over; to tip over; to throw down\nto leave\nto buy and sell (quickly for a profit)" },
	{ "question": "転がる", "answers": [ "ころがる" ], "comment": "to roll; to tumble\nto fall over; to roll over\nto lie down\nto be scattered about; to be common\n(of a situation or outcome) to change; to turn out" },
	{ "question": "転じる", "answers": [ "てんじる" ], "comment": "to turn; to shift; to alter; to distract" },
	{ "question": "転ぶ", "answers": [ "まろぶ", "ころぶ" ], "comment": "to fall down; to fall over" },
	{ "question": "転倒", "answers": [ "てんとう" ], "comment": "falling down; tumbling; overturning; turning over\nreversing; inverting; inversion\ngetting upset" },
	{ "question": "転出", "answers": [ "てんしゅつ" ], "comment": "moving out; transfer" },
	{ "question": "転勤", "answers": [ "てんきん" ], "comment": "job transfer; job relocation; intra-company transfer" },
	{ "question": "転向", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "conversion; shift; about-face; switch" },
	{ "question": "転売", "answers": [ "てんばい" ], "comment": "resale" },
	{ "question": "転嫁", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "imputation; shifting (e.g. blame, costs); passing the buck\nsecond marriage; remarriage" },
	{ "question": "転居", "answers": [ "てんきょ" ], "comment": "moving; changing residence" },
	{ "question": "転戦", "answers": [ "てんせん" ], "comment": "fighting in numerous battles" },
	{ "question": "転換", "answers": [ "てんかん" ], "comment": "conversion; diversion; changeover; commutation; switchover" },
	{ "question": "転機", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "turning point" },
	{ "question": "転用", "answers": [ "てんよう" ], "comment": "diversion; putting something to another use" },
	{ "question": "転移", "answers": [ "てんい" ], "comment": "moving (location, with the times, etc.); change; transition\nmetastasis; spread\ntransition (e.g phase transition)\ntransfer (of learning)\ntransference (in psychoanalysis)" },
	{ "question": "転職", "answers": [ "てんしょく" ], "comment": "change of occupation" },
	{ "question": "転落", "answers": [ "てんらく" ], "comment": "fall; tumble; spill; plunge; dive\ndegradation; comedown; demotion; slump" },
	{ "question": "転覆", "answers": [ "てんぷく" ], "comment": "capsizing; overturn; turning over; upset\noverthrow (e.g. a government)" },
	{ "question": "転身", "answers": [ "てんしん" ], "comment": "(job) turnover" },
	{ "question": "軸", "answers": [ "じく" ], "comment": "axis; shaft; axle\ncenter; centre; focal point; key point\nstalk; stem\nhanging scroll" },
	{ "question": "軽", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "light (e.g. vehicle, aircraft, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "軽々", "answers": [ "かるがる" ], "comment": "lightly; easily; carelessly" },
	{ "question": "軽い", "answers": [ "かるい", "かろい" ], "comment": "light (i.e. not heavy); feeling light (i.e. offering little resistance, moving easily)\nlight (i.e. of foot); nimble; agile\nnon-serious; minor; unimportant; trivial\nslight; small; gentle; soft\neasy; simple\nindiscriminate" },
	{ "question": "軽はずみ", "answers": [ "かるはずみ", "かろはずみ" ], "comment": "thoughtless; rash; hasty; imprudent" },
	{ "question": "軽やか", "answers": [ "かるやか", "かろやか" ], "comment": "light; easy; non-serious; minor" },
	{ "question": "軽傷", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "minor injury" },
	{ "question": "軽妙", "answers": [ "けいみょう" ], "comment": "light and easy; lambent; facile; clever; witty; smart" },
	{ "question": "軽快", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "light (of movements); nimble; sprightly; springy\nlight-hearted; cheerful; buoyant; jaunty; casual (e.g. clothing); rhythmical (e.g. melody)\ntaking a turn for the better (of an illness); receding of symptoms; recovery; convalescence" },
	{ "question": "軽油", "answers": [ "けいゆ" ], "comment": "diesel oil; gas oil\nlight oil" },
	{ "question": "軽減", "answers": [ "けいげん" ], "comment": "abatement; reduction" },
	{ "question": "軽率", "answers": [ "けいそつ" ], "comment": "rash; thoughtless; careless; hasty; imprudent" },
	{ "question": "軽自動車", "answers": [ "けいじどうしゃ" ], "comment": "light motor vehicle (up to 660cc and 64bhp); k-car; kei car" },
	{ "question": "軽蔑", "answers": [ "けいべつ" ], "comment": "scorn; disdain; contempt" },
	{ "question": "軽薄", "answers": [ "けいはく" ], "comment": "frivolous; flippant; superficial; trifling" },
	{ "question": "軽視", "answers": [ "けいし" ], "comment": "making light of; slight; ignore; neglect; contempt; disdain" },
	{ "question": "軽量", "answers": [ "けいりょう" ], "comment": "light weight" },
	{ "question": "軽震", "answers": [ "けいしん" ], "comment": "weak earthquake" },
	{ "question": "載る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "to be placed on; to be set on; to be piled on; to be loaded on\nto appear (in print); to be mentioned; to be recorded; to be reported; to be given" },
	{ "question": "輝かしい", "answers": [ "かがやかしい" ], "comment": "brilliant; glorious; glittering; bright; splendid (e.g. achievement, success); promising (e.g. future)" },
	{ "question": "輝き", "answers": [ "かがやき" ], "comment": "brightness; brilliance; brilliancy; radiance; glitter" },
	{ "question": "輝く", "answers": [ "かがやく" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to sparkle" },
	{ "question": "輩出", "answers": [ "はいしゅつ" ], "comment": "turning out in great numbers; appearing one after the other" },
	{ "question": "輪", "answers": [ "わ" ], "comment": "ring; circle; loop\nhoop\nwheel\ncircle (e.g. of friends)" },
	{ "question": "輪ゴム", "answers": [ "わゴム" ], "comment": "rubber band" },
	{ "question": "輪切り", "answers": [ "わぎり" ], "comment": "round slices" },
	{ "question": "輪郭", "answers": [ "りんかく" ], "comment": "contour; outline; border; silhouette\nsummary; outline; sketch\nlooks; features; appearance" },
	{ "question": "輸入", "answers": [ "ゆにゅう", "しゅにゅう" ], "comment": "importation; import; introduction\nafferent" },
	{ "question": "輸出", "answers": [ "しゅしゅつ", "ゆしゅつ" ], "comment": "export\nefferent" },
	{ "question": "輸出入", "answers": [ "ゆしゅつにゅう" ], "comment": "export and import" },
	{ "question": "輸血", "answers": [ "ゆけつ" ], "comment": "blood transfusion" },
	{ "question": "輸送", "answers": [ "ゆそう" ], "comment": "transport; transportation" },
	{ "question": "輸銀", "answers": [ "ゆぎん" ], "comment": "import-export bank" },
	{ "question": "辛い", "answers": [ "からい", "つらい" ], "comment": "spicy; hot\nsalty\nharsh (criticism); severe (punishment); strict\npainful; bitter; difficult; tough" },
	{ "question": "辛口", "answers": [ "からくち" ], "comment": "dry taste (e.g. sake, wine)\na liking for sake; one who likes sake\nsalty (taste)\nharsh; scathing" },
	{ "question": "辛抱", "answers": [ "しんぼう" ], "comment": "patience; endurance" },
	{ "question": "辞す", "answers": [ "じす" ], "comment": "to excuse oneself; to take one's leave\nto quit; to resign; to retire; to leave post\nto decline; to turn down\nunhesitatingly" },
	{ "question": "辞める", "answers": [ "やめる" ], "comment": "to resign; to retire; to quit; to leave (one's job, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "辞令", "answers": [ "じれい" ], "comment": "notice of personnel change (appointment, dismissal, etc.)\nwording; choice of language; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "辞任", "answers": [ "じにん" ], "comment": "resignation (from a position)" },
	{ "question": "辞典", "answers": [ "じてん", "ことばてん" ], "comment": "dictionary" },
	{ "question": "辞意", "answers": [ "じい" ], "comment": "intention to resign" },
	{ "question": "辞書", "answers": [ "じしょ" ], "comment": "dictionary; lexicon\nletter of resignation" },
	{ "question": "辞職", "answers": [ "じしょく" ], "comment": "resignation" },
	{ "question": "辞表", "answers": [ "じひょう" ], "comment": "letter of resignation" },
	{ "question": "辞退", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "declining; refusal; nonacceptance; turning down; withdrawal (e.g. candidacy); pulling out (e.g. race); excusing oneself" },
	{ "question": "辰", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "fifth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Dragon, 7am-9am, east-southeast, March)" },
	{ "question": "農", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "farming; agriculture" },
	{ "question": "農作業", "answers": [ "のうさぎょう" ], "comment": "farmwork" },
	{ "question": "農作物", "answers": [ "のうさくもつ", "のうさくぶつ" ], "comment": "crops; agricultural produce" },
	{ "question": "農協", "answers": [ "のうきょう" ], "comment": "agricultural cooperative" },
	{ "question": "農園", "answers": [ "のうえん" ], "comment": "plantation" },
	{ "question": "農地", "answers": [ "のうち" ], "comment": "agricultural land; farmland" },
	{ "question": "農地改革", "answers": [ "のうちかいかく" ], "comment": "agrarian reform" },
	{ "question": "農場", "answers": [ "のうじょう" ], "comment": "farm (agriculture)" },
	{ "question": "農学部", "answers": [ "のうがくぶ" ], "comment": "department of agriculture" },
	{ "question": "農家", "answers": [ "のうか" ], "comment": "farmer; farming family\nfarmhouse" },
	{ "question": "農政", "answers": [ "のうせい" ], "comment": "agricultural administration" },
	{ "question": "農村", "answers": [ "のうそん" ], "comment": "agricultural community; farm village\nrural" },
	{ "question": "農林", "answers": [ "のうりん" ], "comment": "agriculture and forestry" },
	{ "question": "農業", "answers": [ "のうぎょう" ], "comment": "agriculture" },
	{ "question": "農業協同組合", "answers": [ "のうぎょうきょうどうくみあい" ], "comment": "agricultural cooperative" },
	{ "question": "農民", "answers": [ "のうみん" ], "comment": "farmer; peasant" },
	{ "question": "農法", "answers": [ "のうほう" ], "comment": "farming methods" },
	{ "question": "農産", "answers": [ "のうさん" ], "comment": "agricultural products" },
	{ "question": "農産物", "answers": [ "のうさんぶつ" ], "comment": "agricultural produce" },
	{ "question": "農相", "answers": [ "のうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Agriculture" },
	{ "question": "農耕", "answers": [ "のうこう" ], "comment": "farming; agriculture; cultivation" },
	{ "question": "農薬", "answers": [ "のうやく" ], "comment": "agricultural chemical (i.e. pesticide, herbicide, fungicide, etc.); agrochemical; agrichemical" },
	{ "question": "辺", "answers": [ "へん", "ほとり" ], "comment": "area; vicinity; region\nside; edge\ncircumstances" },
	{ "question": "辺境", "answers": [ "へんきょう" ], "comment": "remote region; frontier (district); border(land)" },
	{ "question": "辻", "answers": [ "つじ" ], "comment": "intersection; crossing; crossroad; street corner; street" },
	{ "question": "込む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded; to be packed\nto be complex\nto go into; to put into; to remain (seated); to be plunged into (silence); to do thoroughly\nto do intently\nto continue in the same state" },
	{ "question": "込める", "answers": [ "こめる" ], "comment": "to load (a gun, etc.); to charge\nto put into (e.g. emotion, effort)\nto include (e.g. tax in a sales price)\nto hang over; to shroud; to enshroud; to envelop; to screen" },
	{ "question": "迅速", "answers": [ "じんそく" ], "comment": "quick; fast; rapid; swift; prompt; streamlined; expedited; expeditious" },
	{ "question": "迎え", "answers": [ "むかえ" ], "comment": "meeting; greeting; welcome" },
	{ "question": "迎える", "answers": [ "むかえる" ], "comment": "to go out to meet\nto receive; to welcome; to greet; to salute; to hail; to reach; to approach; to enter (a phase, era, etc.)\nto accept (e.g. as a member of a group or family)\nto call for; to summon; to invite\nto approach (a certain time, a point in one's life, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "迎撃", "answers": [ "げいげき" ], "comment": "intercept; interception; counter attack" },
	{ "question": "迎賓館", "answers": [ "げいひんかん" ], "comment": "reception hall (esp. for visiting state dignitaries); guest house\nState Guest House (esp. Akasaka palace, also guest house in Kyoto)" },
	{ "question": "近々", "answers": [ "ちかぢか", "きんきん" ], "comment": "soon; nearness; before long" },
	{ "question": "近い", "answers": [ "ちかい" ], "comment": "near; close; short (distance)\nclose (in time); soon\nclose (relationship); friendly; intimate\nclosely related\nsimilar; likeworthy; almost the same" },
	{ "question": "近く", "answers": [ "ちかく" ], "comment": "near; neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity\nnearly (e.g. \"it took nearly one year\"); close to\nshortly; soon" },
	{ "question": "近づき", "answers": [ "ちかづき" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "近づく", "answers": [ "ちかづく" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to get close\nto get acquainted with; to get closer to; to get to know" },
	{ "question": "近づける", "answers": [ "ちかづける" ], "comment": "to bring near; to put close; to let come near; to associate with" },
	{ "question": "近世", "answers": [ "きんせい" ], "comment": "early modern times (Azuchi-Momoyama period to Edo period, 1568-1867); modern times; recent times" },
	{ "question": "近付く", "answers": [ "ちかづく" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to get close\nto get acquainted with; to get closer to; to get to know" },
	{ "question": "近付ける", "answers": [ "ちかづける" ], "comment": "to bring near; to put close; to let come near; to associate with" },
	{ "question": "近代", "answers": [ "きんだい" ], "comment": "present day; modern times" },
	{ "question": "近代的", "answers": [ "きんだいてき" ], "comment": "modern" },
	{ "question": "近代詩", "answers": [ "きんだいし" ], "comment": "modern poetry; modern-style poetry" },
	{ "question": "近作", "answers": [ "きんさく" ], "comment": "recent work" },
	{ "question": "近寄せる", "answers": [ "ちかよせる" ], "comment": "to bring close to; to associate with" },
	{ "question": "近寄る", "answers": [ "ちかよる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near" },
	{ "question": "近年", "answers": [ "きんねん" ], "comment": "recent years" },
	{ "question": "近所", "answers": [ "きんじょ" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood" },
	{ "question": "近日", "answers": [ "きんじつ" ], "comment": "soon; in a few days" },
	{ "question": "近況", "answers": [ "きんきょう" ], "comment": "recent state; present state; present condition; current status; current circumstances" },
	{ "question": "近海", "answers": [ "きんかい" ], "comment": "coastal waters; adjacent seas" },
	{ "question": "近畿", "answers": [ "きんき" ], "comment": "Kinki (region around Osaka, Kyoto, Nara)" },
	{ "question": "近眼", "answers": [ "ちかめ", "きんがん" ], "comment": "nearsightedness; shortsightedness; myopia" },
	{ "question": "近著", "answers": [ "きんちょ" ], "comment": "recent work" },
	{ "question": "近衛", "answers": [ "このえ" ], "comment": "Imperial Guards" },
	{ "question": "近視", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "myopia; shortsightedness; nearsightedness" },
	{ "question": "近親", "answers": [ "きんしん" ], "comment": "near relative" },
	{ "question": "近距離", "answers": [ "きんきょり" ], "comment": "short distance" },
	{ "question": "近辺", "answers": [ "きんぺん" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity" },
	{ "question": "近道", "answers": [ "ちかみち" ], "comment": "short way; shortcut" },
	{ "question": "近郊", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "suburbs; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "近隣", "answers": [ "きんりん" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity" },
	{ "question": "近頃", "answers": [ "ちかごろ" ], "comment": "lately; recently; nowadays" },
	{ "question": "返す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "to return (something); to restore; to put back\nto turn over; to turn upside down; to overturn\nto pay back; to retaliate; to reciprocate\nto repeat ...; to do ... back" },
	{ "question": "返り咲き", "answers": [ "かえりざき" ], "comment": "comeback (e.g. in business); reinstatement\nsecond blooming (in a season); reflowering; reflorescence" },
	{ "question": "返る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to return; to come back; to go back\nto turn over\n(after the -masu stem of a verb) (to become) extremely; (to become) completely" },
	{ "question": "返上", "answers": [ "へんじょう" ], "comment": "give up; relinquish; serve up; let loose" },
	{ "question": "返事", "answers": [ "へんじ" ], "comment": "reply; answer; response" },
	{ "question": "返信", "answers": [ "へんしん" ], "comment": "reply" },
	{ "question": "返却", "answers": [ "へんきゃく" ], "comment": "return of something; repayment" },
	{ "question": "返品", "answers": [ "へんぴん" ], "comment": "returned goods; returning purchased goods" },
	{ "question": "返済", "answers": [ "へんさい" ], "comment": "repayment; reimbursement; refund; redemption" },
	{ "question": "返答", "answers": [ "へんとう" ], "comment": "reply; answer" },
	{ "question": "返還", "answers": [ "へんかん" ], "comment": "return; restoration" },
	{ "question": "迫る", "answers": [ "せまる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to be imminent\nto press (someone for something); to urge; to compel" },
	{ "question": "迫力", "answers": [ "はくりょく" ], "comment": "impressiveness; impact; force; intensity; appeal; strength; punch; edge; vigor" },
	{ "question": "迫害", "answers": [ "はくがい" ], "comment": "persecution; oppression" },
	{ "question": "迫撃", "answers": [ "はくげき" ], "comment": "close attack" },
	{ "question": "迫撃砲", "answers": [ "はくげきほう" ], "comment": "mortar" },
	{ "question": "述べる", "answers": [ "のべる" ], "comment": "to state; to express; to mention" },
	{ "question": "迷い", "answers": [ "まよい" ], "comment": "hesitation; bewilderment; doubt; indecision\ninability to reach enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "迷う", "answers": [ "まよう" ], "comment": "to lose one's way\nto waver; to hesitate; to be of two minds over; to be puzzled; to be perplexed\nto give into temptation; to lose control of oneself\nto turn in one's grave" },
	{ "question": "迷信", "answers": [ "めいしん" ], "comment": "superstition; superstitious belief" },
	{ "question": "迷子", "answers": [ "まいご" ], "comment": "lost child; lost person; stray child; missing child" },
	{ "question": "迷惑", "answers": [ "めいわく" ], "comment": "trouble; bother; annoyance" },
	{ "question": "迷路", "answers": [ "めいろ" ], "comment": "maze; labyrinth; blind alley" },
	{ "question": "追いかける", "answers": [ "おいかける" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue" },
	{ "question": "追いつく", "answers": [ "おいつく" ], "comment": "to catch up (with); to draw level; to pull even; to reach\nto be compensated; to make up for one's loses" },
	{ "question": "追い上げる", "answers": [ "おいあげる" ], "comment": "to gain on; to put pressure on; to close in on" },
	{ "question": "追い付く", "answers": [ "おいつく" ], "comment": "to catch up (with); to draw level; to pull even; to reach\nto be compensated; to make up for one's loses" },
	{ "question": "追い出す", "answers": [ "おいだす" ], "comment": "to expel; to drive out" },
	{ "question": "追い打ち", "answers": [ "おいうち" ], "comment": "final blow; attacking while pursuing; attacking the routed enemy" },
	{ "question": "追い抜く", "answers": [ "おいぬく" ], "comment": "to pass (a car); to overtake\nto surpass; to outstrip; to outdistance; to outsail" },
	{ "question": "追い掛ける", "answers": [ "おいかける" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue" },
	{ "question": "追い越す", "answers": [ "おいこす" ], "comment": "to pass (e.g. car); to overtake\nto surpass; to outstrip; to get ahead of; to outdistance" },
	{ "question": "追い込み", "answers": [ "おいこみ" ], "comment": "final stage; last spurt\nlive printing area (in publishing)" },
	{ "question": "追い込む", "answers": [ "おいこむ" ], "comment": "to herd; to corner; to drive" },
	{ "question": "追い風", "answers": [ "おいて", "おいかぜ" ], "comment": "tailwind; fair wind; favorable wind (favourable)\nfavorable condition (favourable); advantageous situation" },
	{ "question": "追う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue\nto follow (a set order, a trend, etc.)\nto drive out; to oust; to expel\nto drive (e.g. a herd)\nto be pressed (e.g. for time)" },
	{ "question": "追っかけ", "answers": [ "おっかけ" ], "comment": "chase scene\ngroupie; paparazzo\nsoon; by-and-by" },
	{ "question": "追っかける", "answers": [ "おっかける" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue" },
	{ "question": "追っ掛ける", "answers": [ "おっかける" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue" },
	{ "question": "追伸", "answers": [ "ついしん" ], "comment": "postscript; post scriptum; PS; P.S." },
	{ "question": "追加", "answers": [ "ついか" ], "comment": "addition; supplement; append (e.g. to a file); appendix" },
	{ "question": "追及", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. into someone's guilt); questioning; pressing; hounding; pinning down\ncatching up; overtaking" },
	{ "question": "追徴", "answers": [ "ついちょう" ], "comment": "supplementary charge; additional collection" },
	{ "question": "追悼", "answers": [ "ついとう" ], "comment": "mourning (dead persons); memorial" },
	{ "question": "追撃", "answers": [ "ついげき" ], "comment": "pursuit" },
	{ "question": "追放", "answers": [ "ついほう" ], "comment": "exile; banishment; eviction; deportation; transportation" },
	{ "question": "追求", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "pursuit (of a goal, ideal, etc.); search; chase; seeking after" },
	{ "question": "追究", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. academically, of the unknown); close inquiry (enquiry)" },
	{ "question": "追突", "answers": [ "ついとつ" ], "comment": "rear-end collision" },
	{ "question": "追跡", "answers": [ "ついせき" ], "comment": "chase; pursuit; tracking; stalking\nfollowing up; tracing" },
	{ "question": "追随", "answers": [ "ついずい" ], "comment": "following (in the footsteps of)\ncatching up with; coming level with" },
	{ "question": "退き時", "answers": [ "ひきどき" ], "comment": "a good time to quit" },
	{ "question": "退く", "answers": [ "しりぞく", "ひく" ], "comment": "to step back; to move back; to retreat\nto withdraw (from the presence of a superior); to leave; to exit\nto resign; to retire; to quit\nto concede /\n to move back; to draw back; to recede\nto lessen; to subside; to ebb" },
	{ "question": "退任", "answers": [ "たいにん" ], "comment": "retirement; resignation; stepping down" },
	{ "question": "退去", "answers": [ "たいきょ" ], "comment": "departure; leaving; going away; evacuation\nrecession" },
	{ "question": "退団", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "leaving a group or troupe" },
	{ "question": "退場", "answers": [ "たいじょう" ], "comment": "exit (from a stage); exeunt\nleaving; exit" },
	{ "question": "退学", "answers": [ "たいがく" ], "comment": "dropping out of school; withdrawing from school\nexpulsion from school; dismissal\nleaving school (university, etc.) after completing a course" },
	{ "question": "退官", "answers": [ "たいかん" ], "comment": "retirement from office" },
	{ "question": "退屈", "answers": [ "たいくつ" ], "comment": "tedium; boredom" },
	{ "question": "退廃", "answers": [ "たいはい" ], "comment": "degeneration; decadence; deterioration; laxness; corruption" },
	{ "question": "退廃的", "answers": [ "たいはいてき" ], "comment": "degenerate; decadent" },
	{ "question": "退役", "answers": [ "たいえき" ], "comment": "retiring from military service" },
	{ "question": "退治", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits); elimination; eradication; suppression\nmaking someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings\ncuring illness" },
	{ "question": "退社", "answers": [ "たいしゃ" ], "comment": "resignation; leaving office\nleaving work (e.g. at the end of the day)" },
	{ "question": "退職", "answers": [ "たいしょく" ], "comment": "retirement; resignation" },
	{ "question": "退避", "answers": [ "たいひ" ], "comment": "taking refuge; evacuation\nsaving (a file)" },
	{ "question": "退院", "answers": [ "たいいん" ], "comment": "leaving hospital; discharge from hospital" },
	{ "question": "退陣", "answers": [ "たいじん" ], "comment": "retreat; withdrawal; retirement" },
	{ "question": "送り", "answers": [ "おくり" ], "comment": "seeing off; sending off\nfuneral\nescapement" },
	{ "question": "送り仮名", "answers": [ "おくりがな" ], "comment": "kana written after a kanji to complete the full (usually kun) reading of the word (may inflect); declensional kana ending" },
	{ "question": "送り先", "answers": [ "おくりさき" ], "comment": "forwarding address" },
	{ "question": "送り出し", "answers": [ "おくりだし" ], "comment": "pushing (propelling) (one's opponent) out of the ring from behind" },
	{ "question": "送り込む", "answers": [ "おくりこむ" ], "comment": "to send in" },
	{ "question": "送る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "to send (a thing); to dispatch; to despatch; to transmit\nto take or escort (a person somewhere); to see off (a person)\nto bid farewell (to the departed); to bury\nto spend (time); to live one's life\nto pass (down the line)\nto affix okurigana" },
	{ "question": "送付", "answers": [ "そうふ" ], "comment": "sending (esp. email attachments); forwarding; remitting" },
	{ "question": "送信", "answers": [ "そうしん" ], "comment": "transmission; sending" },
	{ "question": "送別", "answers": [ "そうべつ" ], "comment": "farewell; send-off" },
	{ "question": "送別会", "answers": [ "そうべつかい" ], "comment": "farewell party" },
	{ "question": "送料", "answers": [ "そうりょう" ], "comment": "postage; carriage; shipping charge" },
	{ "question": "送検", "answers": [ "そうけん" ], "comment": "sending the person accused to the prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "送球", "answers": [ "そうきゅう" ], "comment": "throwing a ball\nhandball" },
	{ "question": "送迎", "answers": [ "そうげい" ], "comment": "seeing off and meeting on return" },
	{ "question": "送還", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "sending home; repatriation; deportation" },
	{ "question": "送金", "answers": [ "そうきん" ], "comment": "remittance; sending money" },
	{ "question": "送電", "answers": [ "そうでん" ], "comment": "electric supply" },
	{ "question": "逃がす", "answers": [ "にがす" ], "comment": "to set free; to let go; to release\nto miss (e.g. a chance); to lose; to let get away; to fail to catch" },
	{ "question": "逃げ", "answers": [ "にげ" ], "comment": "escape; getaway; evasion" },
	{ "question": "逃げる", "answers": [ "にげる" ], "comment": "to escape; to run away" },
	{ "question": "逃げ出す", "answers": [ "にげだす" ], "comment": "to run away; to flee; to make off; to take to one's heels; to escape\nto start to run away" },
	{ "question": "逃げ切る", "answers": [ "にげきる" ], "comment": "to get away; to manage to hold on" },
	{ "question": "逃げ足", "answers": [ "にげあし" ], "comment": "running away; escaping on foot" },
	{ "question": "逃げ道", "answers": [ "にげみち" ], "comment": "way out; means to escape; escape route" },
	{ "question": "逃れる", "answers": [ "のがれる" ], "comment": "to escape" },
	{ "question": "逃亡", "answers": [ "とうぼう" ], "comment": "escape; flight; running away; elopement; fleeing" },
	{ "question": "逃走", "answers": [ "とうそう" ], "comment": "flight; desertion; escape" },
	{ "question": "逃避", "answers": [ "とうひ" ], "comment": "escape; evasion; flight" },
	{ "question": "逆", "answers": [ "ぎゃく" ], "comment": "reverse; opposite\nconverse (of a hypothesis, etc.)\ninverse (function)" },
	{ "question": "逆さ", "answers": [ "さかさ" ], "comment": "reverse; inversion; upside down" },
	{ "question": "逆しま", "answers": [ "さかしま" ], "comment": "reverse; inversion; upside down\nunreasonable; absurd; wrong" },
	{ "question": "逆らう", "answers": [ "さからう" ], "comment": "to go against; to oppose; to disobey; to defy" },
	{ "question": "逆効果", "answers": [ "ぎゃっこうか", "ぎゃくこうか" ], "comment": "opposite effect; adverse effect; backfiring" },
	{ "question": "逆境", "answers": [ "ぎゃっきょう" ], "comment": "adversity" },
	{ "question": "逆手", "answers": [ "さかて", "ぎゃくて" ], "comment": "underhand grip; backhand grip (e.g. in tennis)\nunexpected twist; turning the tables (on an opponent)" },
	{ "question": "逆立ち", "answers": [ "さかだち" ], "comment": "handstand; headstand" },
	{ "question": "逆襲", "answers": [ "ぎゃくしゅう" ], "comment": "counterattack" },
	{ "question": "逆転", "answers": [ "ぎゃくてん" ], "comment": "(sudden) change; reversal; turn-around; coming from behind (baseball)" },
	{ "question": "逆転勝ち", "answers": [ "ぎゃくてんがち" ], "comment": "winning after defeat seems certain; coming from behind to win" },
	{ "question": "逆輸入", "answers": [ "ぎゃくゆにゅう" ], "comment": "reimportation" },
	{ "question": "逆風", "answers": [ "ぎゃくふう" ], "comment": "headwind; adverse wind" },
	{ "question": "透き通る", "answers": [ "すきとおる" ], "comment": "to be transparent; to be see-through\nto be clear (voice)" },
	{ "question": "透明", "answers": [ "とうめい" ], "comment": "transparent; clear" },
	{ "question": "透析", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "dialysis" },
	{ "question": "逓信", "answers": [ "ていしん" ], "comment": "communications (e.g. post, tele.)" },
	{ "question": "途", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "way" },
	{ "question": "途上", "answers": [ "とじょう" ], "comment": "en route; half-way\non the road; in the street" },
	{ "question": "途上国", "answers": [ "とじょうこく" ], "comment": "developing country" },
	{ "question": "途中", "answers": [ "とちゅう" ], "comment": "on the way; en route\nin the middle of; midway" },
	{ "question": "途切れる", "answers": [ "とぎれる" ], "comment": "to pause; to be interrupted" },
	{ "question": "途方", "answers": [ "とほう" ], "comment": "way; destination; reason" },
	{ "question": "途端", "answers": [ "とたん" ], "comment": "just (now, at the moment, etc.); just as; in the act of; as soon as; at the moment that" },
	{ "question": "途端に", "answers": [ "とたんに" ], "comment": "just as; in the act of; as soon as; at the moment that" },
	{ "question": "途絶える", "answers": [ "とだえる" ], "comment": "to stop; to cease; to come to an end" },
	{ "question": "這う", "answers": [ "はう" ], "comment": "to creep; to crawl" },
	{ "question": "通", "answers": [ "つう" ], "comment": "connoisseur; authority\ncounter for letters, notes, documents, etc." },
	{ "question": "通い", "answers": [ "かよい" ], "comment": "coming and going; commuting" },
	{ "question": "通う", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "to go to and from (a place); to go back and forth between; to run between (e.g. bus, train, etc.); to ply between\nto go to (school, work, etc.); to attend; to commute; to frequent\nto circulate (e.g. blood, electricity); to be communicated (e.g. thought)\nto resemble" },
	{ "question": "通し", "answers": [ "とおし" ], "comment": "direct; right through; straight\nappetizer; appetiser\nperformance of an entire play" },
	{ "question": "通じ", "answers": [ "つうじ" ], "comment": "understanding\nbowel movement; evacuation" },
	{ "question": "通じる", "answers": [ "つうじる" ], "comment": "to be open (to traffic); to lead to; to communicate (with)\nto flow (liquid, current); to pass; to get through to\nto be understood; to be comprehended\nto be honored; to be good\nto be well versed in; to be well-informed\nto communicate clandestinely; to keep in touch (e.g. with the enemy)\nto form a liaison; to be intimate\nto spread widely; to disseminate" },
	{ "question": "通す", "answers": [ "とおす" ], "comment": "to stick through; to force through\nto spread throughout; to thoroughly diffuse\nto make a path between two points\nto proceed in a logical manner\nto let pass; to allow through\nto lead (someone) into (a house, room, etc.); to show in\nto go through (a middleman)\nto (look, listen) through (a window, wall, etc.)\nto pass (a law, applicant, etc.)\nto force to accept; to force agreement\nto continue (in a state); to persist in\nto do to the entirety of; to cover all of; to span the whole ...\nto do from beginning to end without a break\nto convey (one's ideas, etc.) to the other party\nto do to the end; to carry through; to complete" },
	{ "question": "通り", "answers": [ "どおり", "とおり" ], "comment": "avenue; street; way; road\ncoming and going; street traffic\nflow (of water, air, etc.)\ntransmission (of sound); reach (e.g. of voice)\nfame; reputation; popularity\nthe same status or way; as (e.g. as expected, as I said)\nunderstanding; comprehension\ncounter for sets of things; counter for methods, ways, types /\n in accordance with; following\nroughly; about\nStreet; Avenue" },
	{ "question": "通り過ぎる", "answers": [ "とおりすぎる" ], "comment": "to pass; to pass through" },
	{ "question": "通る", "answers": [ "とおる" ], "comment": "to go by; to go past; to go along; to travel along; to pass through; to use (a road); to take (a route); to go via; to go by way of\nto run (between); to operate (between); to connect\nto go indoors; to go into a room; to be admitted; to be shown in; to be ushered in; to come in\nto penetrate; to pierce; to skewer; to go through; to come through\nto permeate; to soak into; to spread throughout\nto carry (e.g. of a voice); to reach far\nto be passed on (e.g. of a customer's order to the kitchen); to be relayed; to be conveyed\nto pass (a test, a bill in the House, etc.); to be approved; to be accepted\nto go by (a name); to be known as; to be accepted as; to have a reputation for\nto be coherent; to be logical; to be reasonable; to be comprehensible; to be understandable; to make sense\nto get across (e.g. of one's point); to be understood\nto be straight (e.g. wood grain)\nto be well-informed; to be wise\nto do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly" },
	{ "question": "通例", "answers": [ "つうれい" ], "comment": "custom; general rule; convention\nusually; generally; as a rule" },
	{ "question": "通俗的", "answers": [ "つうぞくてき" ], "comment": "plain and popular" },
	{ "question": "通信", "answers": [ "つうしん" ], "comment": "correspondence; communication; transmission; news; signal; telecommunications" },
	{ "question": "通信社", "answers": [ "つうしんしゃ" ], "comment": "news agency" },
	{ "question": "通信網", "answers": [ "つうしんもう" ], "comment": "communications network" },
	{ "question": "通信衛星", "answers": [ "つうしんえいせい" ], "comment": "communication satellite; Broadcast Satellite; BS" },
	{ "question": "通信販売", "answers": [ "つうしんはんばい" ], "comment": "mail order; mail-order sales; shop-by-mail service; on-line shopping service (with delivery by mail)" },
	{ "question": "通勤", "answers": [ "つうきん" ], "comment": "commuting to work" },
	{ "question": "通告", "answers": [ "つうこく" ], "comment": "announcement; notice" },
	{ "question": "通商", "answers": [ "つうしょう" ], "comment": "commerce; trade" },
	{ "question": "通報", "answers": [ "つうほう" ], "comment": "report; notification; tip; bulletin\nmessage (in information and communication theory)" },
	{ "question": "通夜", "answers": [ "つうや", "つや" ], "comment": "all-night vigil over a body; wake" },
	{ "question": "通学", "answers": [ "つうがく" ], "comment": "commuting to school; school commute" },
	{ "question": "通帳", "answers": [ "つうちょう" ], "comment": "passbook; bankbook" },
	{ "question": "通常", "answers": [ "つうじょう" ], "comment": "common; general; normal; usual" },
	{ "question": "通年", "answers": [ "つうねん" ], "comment": "all year; year round" },
	{ "question": "通念", "answers": [ "つうねん" ], "comment": "common idea; common wisdom; generally accepted idea" },
	{ "question": "通産相", "answers": [ "つうさんしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of International Trade and Industry" },
	{ "question": "通産省", "answers": [ "つうさんしょう" ], "comment": "(former) Ministry of International Trade and Industry (now Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry); MITI" },
	{ "question": "通用", "answers": [ "つうよう" ], "comment": "popular use; circulation\nto pass as; to pass for" },
	{ "question": "通知", "answers": [ "つうち" ], "comment": "notice; notification; report; posting" },
	{ "question": "通称", "answers": [ "つうしょう" ], "comment": "popular name; nickname; alias" },
	{ "question": "通算", "answers": [ "つうさん" ], "comment": "total" },
	{ "question": "通行", "answers": [ "つうこう" ], "comment": "passage; passing\ncommon usage" },
	{ "question": "通行止め", "answers": [ "つうこうどめ" ], "comment": "closure (of a road); dead end; blind alley; cul-de-sac; No Through Road (e.g. on a sign)" },
	{ "question": "通訳", "answers": [ "つうやく" ], "comment": "interpretation (i.e. oral translation); interpreter" },
	{ "question": "通話", "answers": [ "つうわ" ], "comment": "telephone call; talking; calling\ncounter for telephone calls" },
	{ "question": "通貨", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "currency" },
	{ "question": "通販", "answers": [ "つうはん" ], "comment": "mail order; online shopping; e-commerce" },
	{ "question": "通路", "answers": [ "つうろ" ], "comment": "passage; pathway; roadway; avenue; aisle" },
	{ "question": "通過", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "passage through (e.g. train skipping a station); transit\npassing (e.g. exam, bill through parliament)" },
	{ "question": "通達", "answers": [ "つうだつ", "つうたつ" ], "comment": "notification; official notice; directive (e.g. from higher to lower levels of the administration)\nbeing well versed (in something)" },
	{ "question": "通関", "answers": [ "つうかん" ], "comment": "customs clearance" },
	{ "question": "通院", "answers": [ "つういん" ], "comment": "going to the hospital for regular treatment" },
	{ "question": "速い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; hasty; brisk\nearly (in the day, etc.); premature\n(too) soon; not yet; (too) early\neasy; simple; quick" },
	{ "question": "速く", "answers": [ "はやく" ], "comment": "early; soon\nquickly; swiftly; rapidly; fast" },
	{ "question": "速さ", "answers": [ "はやさ" ], "comment": "speed; velocity; quickness; rapidity\nearliness" },
	{ "question": "速める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "速やか", "answers": [ "すみやか" ], "comment": "speedy; prompt; smooth" },
	{ "question": "速報", "answers": [ "そくほう" ], "comment": "news flash; prompt report; bulletin; quick announcement" },
	{ "question": "速度", "answers": [ "そくど" ], "comment": "speed; velocity; rate" },
	{ "question": "速攻", "answers": [ "そっこう" ], "comment": "swift attack; quick attack; fast break\nright away; without delay; immediately" },
	{ "question": "速球", "answers": [ "そっきゅう" ], "comment": "fastball" },
	{ "question": "速達", "answers": [ "そくたつ" ], "comment": "express; special delivery" },
	{ "question": "速達便", "answers": [ "そくたつびん" ], "comment": "special delivery mail; express delivery post" },
	{ "question": "造り", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "make-up; structure; physique" },
	{ "question": "造る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "造反", "answers": [ "ぞうはん" ], "comment": "rebellion" },
	{ "question": "造形", "answers": [ "ぞうけい" ], "comment": "molding; moulding; shaping; modelling (i.e. plastic arts); modeling" },
	{ "question": "造成", "answers": [ "ぞうせい" ], "comment": "creation; clearing; reclamation" },
	{ "question": "造船", "answers": [ "ぞうせん" ], "comment": "shipbuilding" },
	{ "question": "造語", "answers": [ "ぞうご" ], "comment": "coined word; coinage; neologism" },
	{ "question": "連なる", "answers": [ "つらなる" ], "comment": "to extend; to stretch out; to stand in a row\nto attend; to participate in\nto enrol; to join\nto have a connection; to be related; to be linked" },
	{ "question": "連ねる", "answers": [ "つらねる" ], "comment": "to line up; to put in a row\nto add (to a group); to accept (as a member of an organization, etc.); to join (e.g. a list)\nto link; to put together; to string together (e.g. compliments); to enumerate\nto take along with; to bring with" },
	{ "question": "連れ", "answers": [ "つれ" ], "comment": "companion; company" },
	{ "question": "連れていく", "answers": [ "つれていく", "つれてゆく" ], "comment": "to take someone (to some place); to take someone along; to lead someone away" },
	{ "question": "連れてくる", "answers": [ "つれてくる" ], "comment": "to bring someone along" },
	{ "question": "連れて来る", "answers": [ "つれてくる" ], "comment": "to bring someone along" },
	{ "question": "連れて行く", "answers": [ "つれていく", "つれてゆく" ], "comment": "to take someone (to some place); to take someone along; to lead someone away" },
	{ "question": "連れる", "answers": [ "つれる" ], "comment": "to lead; to take (a person)" },
	{ "question": "連れ去る", "answers": [ "つれさる" ], "comment": "to take away; to kidnap" },
	{ "question": "連中", "answers": [ "れんちゅう", "れんぢゅう", "れんじゅう" ], "comment": "company; lot; bunch; gang; pack; those guys; group\ntroupe; company (of musicians)" },
	{ "question": "連休", "answers": [ "れんきゅう" ], "comment": "consecutive holidays" },
	{ "question": "連作", "answers": [ "れんさく" ], "comment": "planting a field with the same crop each year; repeated cultivation\ncollaborative literary work; story made up by several writers working on it in turn\nseries (of novels); cycle (of poems, songs); sequence" },
	{ "question": "連係プレー", "answers": [ "れんけいプレー" ], "comment": "good teamwork play" },
	{ "question": "連動", "answers": [ "れんどう" ], "comment": "operating together; working together; gearing; linkage\nlinked; coupled; interlocking" },
	{ "question": "連勝", "answers": [ "れんしょう" ], "comment": "consecutive victories; series of victories" },
	{ "question": "連合", "answers": [ "れんごう" ], "comment": "union; alliance; combination\nRENGO (Japanese Trade Union Confederation)" },
	{ "question": "連合会", "answers": [ "れんごうかい" ], "comment": "association; federation" },
	{ "question": "連名", "answers": [ "れんめい" ], "comment": "joint signature" },
	{ "question": "連峰", "answers": [ "れんぽう" ], "comment": "mountain range" },
	{ "question": "連帯", "answers": [ "れんたい" ], "comment": "solidarity; collective\njoint" },
	{ "question": "連座", "answers": [ "れんざ" ], "comment": "implicated (involved) in (a crime)" },
	{ "question": "連想", "answers": [ "れんそう" ], "comment": "association (of ideas); being reminded (of something); suggestion" },
	{ "question": "連戦", "answers": [ "れんせん" ], "comment": "series of battles" },
	{ "question": "連打", "answers": [ "れんだ" ], "comment": "repeated blows; striking repeatedly; barrage\nconsecutive hits (e.g. boxing, baseball)" },
	{ "question": "連投", "answers": [ "れんとう" ], "comment": "pitching in consecutive games\nmaking multiple posts; posting multiple comments" },
	{ "question": "連携", "answers": [ "れんけい" ], "comment": "cooperation; coordination; link" },
	{ "question": "連敗", "answers": [ "れんぱい" ], "comment": "consecutive defeats; series of defeats" },
	{ "question": "連日", "answers": [ "れんじつ" ], "comment": "day after day; every day" },
	{ "question": "連用", "answers": [ "れんよう" ], "comment": "continuous use" },
	{ "question": "連発", "answers": [ "れんぱつ" ], "comment": "running continuously; firing in rapid succession" },
	{ "question": "連盟", "answers": [ "れんめい" ], "comment": "league; federation; union; alliance" },
	{ "question": "連立", "answers": [ "れんりつ" ], "comment": "alliance; coalition" },
	{ "question": "連結", "answers": [ "れんけつ" ], "comment": "concatenation; coupling; connection; linking; consolidation (e.g. of company accounts)" },
	{ "question": "連絡", "answers": [ "れんらく" ], "comment": "to contact; to get in touch\ncontacting; getting in touch; communication; call; message\nconnection; coordination; junction\nintercalary; intercalaris; internuncial" },
	{ "question": "連絡先", "answers": [ "れんらくさき" ], "comment": "contact address" },
	{ "question": "連続", "answers": [ "れんぞく" ], "comment": "serial; consecutive; continuity; occurring in succession; continuing" },
	{ "question": "連行", "answers": [ "れんこう" ], "comment": "taking (a suspect to the police); dragging (someone) away" },
	{ "question": "連覇", "answers": [ "れんぱ" ], "comment": "successive championships" },
	{ "question": "連載", "answers": [ "れんさい" ], "comment": "serialization; serialisation; serial story" },
	{ "question": "連邦", "answers": [ "れんぽう" ], "comment": "commonwealth; federation of states; confederation; union" },
	{ "question": "連鎖", "answers": [ "れんさ" ], "comment": "chain; chaining; catena; connection\n(genetic) linkage" },
	{ "question": "連関", "answers": [ "れんかん" ], "comment": "connection; relation; linkage" },
	{ "question": "連隊", "answers": [ "れんたい" ], "comment": "regiment" },
	{ "question": "逮捕", "answers": [ "たいほ" ], "comment": "arrest; apprehension; capture" },
	{ "question": "週", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "week" },
	{ "question": "週休", "answers": [ "しゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "weekly holiday" },
	{ "question": "週内", "answers": [ "しゅうない" ], "comment": "by the end of this week; within the week" },
	{ "question": "週刊", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "published weekly" },
	{ "question": "週刊誌", "answers": [ "しゅうかんし" ], "comment": "weekly publication; weekly magazine" },
	{ "question": "週明け", "answers": [ "しゅうあけ" ], "comment": "beginning of the week; new week opening; Monday" },
	{ "question": "週末", "answers": [ "しゅうまつ" ], "comment": "weekend" },
	{ "question": "週間", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "weeks (period of)" },
	{ "question": "進み", "answers": [ "すすみ" ], "comment": "progress" },
	{ "question": "進む", "answers": [ "すすむ" ], "comment": "to advance; to go forward\nto precede; to go ahead (of)\nto make progress; to improve\nto deepen; to heighten\nto be fast (of a clock); to be ahead\nto do of one's own free will" },
	{ "question": "進める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to advance; to promote; to hasten" },
	{ "question": "進入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "entry; approach; penetration" },
	{ "question": "進出", "answers": [ "しんしゅつ" ], "comment": "advance (into a new market or stage of progress); launching (a new career or venture); expanding (into a new market); stepping forward; emerging" },
	{ "question": "進化", "answers": [ "しんか" ], "comment": "evolution; progress" },
	{ "question": "進学", "answers": [ "しんがく" ], "comment": "entering a higher-level school, esp. going on to university" },
	{ "question": "進展", "answers": [ "しんてん" ], "comment": "progress; development" },
	{ "question": "進撃", "answers": [ "しんげき" ], "comment": "advance; charge" },
	{ "question": "進攻", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "attack; drive; advance; invasion" },
	{ "question": "進歩", "answers": [ "しんぽ" ], "comment": "progress; advance; improvement; development" },
	{ "question": "進行", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "moving forward (e.g. vehicle); onward movement\nadvance (work, procedure, etc); advancement; progress\nprogress (of a disease); disease progression\nprogression (harmonic, melodic)" },
	{ "question": "進路", "answers": [ "しんろ" ], "comment": "route; course; path\none's future course (e.g. after graduating high school)" },
	{ "question": "進退", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "movement; course of action; advance or retreat" },
	{ "question": "逸らす", "answers": [ "そらす" ], "comment": "to turn away; to avert" },
	{ "question": "逸脱", "answers": [ "いつだつ" ], "comment": "deviation; departure\nomission" },
	{ "question": "遂げる", "answers": [ "とげる" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out\nto arrive at (a certain outcome); to come to; to end with" },
	{ "question": "遂行", "answers": [ "すいこう" ], "comment": "accomplishment; execution" },
	{ "question": "遅々", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "slow; lagging; tardy" },
	{ "question": "遅い", "answers": [ "おそい" ], "comment": "slow\nlate (e.g. \"late at night\")\ntoo late\ndull; stupid" },
	{ "question": "遅らす", "answers": [ "おくらす" ], "comment": "to retard; to delay" },
	{ "question": "遅れ", "answers": [ "おくれ" ], "comment": "delay; lag; postponement; falling behind" },
	{ "question": "遅れる", "answers": [ "おくれる" ], "comment": "to be late; to be delayed; to fall behind schedule; to be overdue" },
	{ "question": "遅刻", "answers": [ "ちこく" ], "comment": "lateness; late coming" },
	{ "question": "遅延", "answers": [ "ちえん" ], "comment": "delay; latency" },
	{ "question": "遊び場", "answers": [ "あそびば" ], "comment": "playground" },
	{ "question": "遊ぶ", "answers": [ "あそぶ" ], "comment": "to play; to enjoy oneself; to have a good time\nto mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)\nto be idle; to do nothing; to be unused\nto go to (for pleasure or for study)\nto intentionally throw a ball to lower the batter's concentration" },
	{ "question": "遊園地", "answers": [ "ゆうえんち" ], "comment": "amusement park" },
	{ "question": "遊撃", "answers": [ "ゆうげき" ], "comment": "raid; military attack by a mobile unit; hit-and-run attack; search-and-kill mission; search-and-destroy mission; military action without a predetermined target; attacking the enemy or assisting allies as the opportunity arises\nshortstop; short" },
	{ "question": "遊撃手", "answers": [ "ゆうげきしゅ" ], "comment": "shortstop; short" },
	{ "question": "遊歩", "answers": [ "ゆうほ" ], "comment": "walk; promenade" },
	{ "question": "遊牧", "answers": [ "ゆうぼく" ], "comment": "nomadism" },
	{ "question": "遊覧", "answers": [ "ゆうらん" ], "comment": "sightseeing" },
	{ "question": "遊説", "answers": [ "ゆうぜい" ], "comment": "election tour; election campaign; stumping" },
	{ "question": "運", "answers": [ "うん" ], "comment": "fortune; luck" },
	{ "question": "運び", "answers": [ "はこび" ], "comment": "progress; pace; carriage; step; stage" },
	{ "question": "運ぶ", "answers": [ "はこぶ" ], "comment": "to carry; to transport; to move; to convey\nto come; to go\nto wield (a tool, etc.); to use\nto go (well, etc.); to proceed; to progress" },
	{ "question": "運休", "answers": [ "うんきゅう" ], "comment": "service suspended (e.g. trains)" },
	{ "question": "運動", "answers": [ "うんどう" ], "comment": "exercise; physical training; work-out\nappeal; campaign; drive; crusade; movement; lobbying\nmotion; movement" },
	{ "question": "運動会", "answers": [ "うんどうかい" ], "comment": "athletic meet; sports day" },
	{ "question": "運動場", "answers": [ "うんどうじょう", "うんどうば" ], "comment": "sports ground; playing field; playground" },
	{ "question": "運命", "answers": [ "うんめい" ], "comment": "fate; destiny; lot" },
	{ "question": "運営", "answers": [ "うんえい" ], "comment": "management; administration; operation" },
	{ "question": "運搬", "answers": [ "うんぱん" ], "comment": "transport; transportation; conveyance; carriage" },
	{ "question": "運河", "answers": [ "うんが" ], "comment": "canal; waterway" },
	{ "question": "運用", "answers": [ "うんよう" ], "comment": "making use of; application; practical use; investment\noperation; handling; steering (esp. a boat)" },
	{ "question": "運航", "answers": [ "うんこう" ], "comment": "operating (e.g. ships, aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "運良く", "answers": [ "うんよく" ], "comment": "luckily" },
	{ "question": "運行", "answers": [ "うんこう" ], "comment": "service (bus, train); operation\nmotion; revolution; movement" },
	{ "question": "運賃", "answers": [ "うんちん" ], "comment": "(passenger) fare\nfreight rates; shipping expenses" },
	{ "question": "運転", "answers": [ "うんてん" ], "comment": "operation (of a machine, etc.); operating; running; run\ndriving\nworking (capital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "運転士", "answers": [ "うんてんし" ], "comment": "driver; train driver; train engineer; motorman; taxi driver\nmate; (ship's) officer" },
	{ "question": "運転手", "answers": [ "うんてんしゅ" ], "comment": "driver; chauffeur" },
	{ "question": "運輸", "answers": [ "うんゆ" ], "comment": "transportation" },
	{ "question": "運輸省", "answers": [ "うんゆしょう" ], "comment": "Ministry of Transport" },
	{ "question": "運送", "answers": [ "うんそう" ], "comment": "transport; freight; shipping" },
	{ "question": "過ごす", "answers": [ "すごす" ], "comment": "to pass (time); to spend\nto overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption); to drink (alcohol)\nto take care of; to support\nto overdo; to do too much\nto ... without acting on it" },
	{ "question": "過ち", "answers": [ "あやまち" ], "comment": "fault; error; indiscretion; faux pas" },
	{ "question": "過剰", "answers": [ "かじょう" ], "comment": "excess; surplus; over-" },
	{ "question": "過労", "answers": [ "かろう" ], "comment": "overwork; strain" },
	{ "question": "過半数", "answers": [ "かはんすう" ], "comment": "majority" },
	{ "question": "過去", "answers": [ "かこ" ], "comment": "the past; bygone days; the previous\na past (i.e. a personal history one would prefer remained secret); one's past\npast (tense); preterit; preterite\nprevious life" },
	{ "question": "過多", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "excess; superabundance" },
	{ "question": "過大", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "excessive; too much; unreasonable" },
	{ "question": "過失", "answers": [ "かしつ" ], "comment": "error; blunder; accident\nfault; defect" },
	{ "question": "過失致死", "answers": [ "かしつちし" ], "comment": "involuntary manslaughter; accidental homicide; negligent homicide" },
	{ "question": "過密", "answers": [ "かみつ" ], "comment": "overcrowding; crowded; congestion" },
	{ "question": "過小評価", "answers": [ "かしょうひょうか" ], "comment": "underestimation; undervaluation" },
	{ "question": "過度", "answers": [ "かど" ], "comment": "excess; immoderation" },
	{ "question": "過当", "answers": [ "かとう" ], "comment": "excessive; exorbitant" },
	{ "question": "過敏", "answers": [ "かびん" ], "comment": "nervousness; oversensitivity" },
	{ "question": "過渡", "answers": [ "かと" ], "comment": "crossing; ferry\ntransient\nchanging old to new" },
	{ "question": "過渡期", "answers": [ "かとき" ], "comment": "transition period" },
	{ "question": "過激", "answers": [ "かげき" ], "comment": "extreme; radical" },
	{ "question": "過熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "superheating; overheating" },
	{ "question": "過疎", "answers": [ "かそ" ], "comment": "depopulation" },
	{ "question": "過程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "process; course; mechanism" },
	{ "question": "過言", "answers": [ "かげん", "かごん" ], "comment": "exaggeration; saying too much\nmisstatement; slip of the tongue; blunt saying" },
	{ "question": "過酷", "answers": [ "かこく" ], "comment": "severe; harsh; hard; cruel; rigorous" },
	{ "question": "道", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "road; street; way; path; course; route; lane\ndistance; ways (e.g. \"a long ways\")\nthe way (of proper conduct, etc.); one's way; morals\nteachings (esp. Confucian or Buddhist); dogma\nfield (of medicine, etc.); subject\nway; method; means" },
	{ "question": "道のり", "answers": [ "みちのり", "どうてい" ], "comment": "distance; journey; itinerary\nway; process" },
	{ "question": "道具", "answers": [ "どうぐ" ], "comment": "tool; implement; instrument; utensil; apparatus; device\nmeans" },
	{ "question": "道場", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "dojo (hall used for martial arts training)\nmanda (place of Buddhist practice or meditation, esp. the place under the bodhi tree where Buddha attained enlightenment)" },
	{ "question": "道徳", "answers": [ "どうとく" ], "comment": "morals" },
	{ "question": "道理", "answers": [ "どうり" ], "comment": "reason; logic; sense; truth; right" },
	{ "question": "道程", "answers": [ "みちのり", "どうてい" ], "comment": "distance; journey; itinerary\nway; process" },
	{ "question": "道端", "answers": [ "みちばた" ], "comment": "roadside; wayside" },
	{ "question": "道筋", "answers": [ "みちすじ" ], "comment": "path; route; itinerary" },
	{ "question": "道義", "answers": [ "どうぎ" ], "comment": "morality; moral principles" },
	{ "question": "道義的責任", "answers": [ "どうぎてきせきにん" ], "comment": "moral obligation" },
	{ "question": "道草", "answers": [ "みちくさ" ], "comment": "loitering on the way\nwayside grass" },
	{ "question": "道路", "answers": [ "どうろ" ], "comment": "road; highway" },
	{ "question": "道順", "answers": [ "みちじゅん" ], "comment": "itinerary; route" },
	{ "question": "達する", "answers": [ "たっする" ], "comment": "to reach; to get to; to arrive at" },
	{ "question": "達人", "answers": [ "たつじん" ], "comment": "master; expert" },
	{ "question": "達成", "answers": [ "たっせい" ], "comment": "achievement" },
	{ "question": "達筆", "answers": [ "たっぴつ" ], "comment": "skillful writing; speedy writing" },
	{ "question": "達者", "answers": [ "たっしゃ" ], "comment": "in good health; healthy; well; robust; strong\nskilled; clever; proficient" },
	{ "question": "違い", "answers": [ "ちがい" ], "comment": "difference; discrepancy" },
	{ "question": "違いない", "answers": [ "ちがいない" ], "comment": "(phrase) sure; no mistaking it; for certain" },
	{ "question": "違う", "answers": [ "ちがう" ], "comment": "to differ (from); to vary\nto not be in the usual condition\nto not match the correct (answer, etc.)\nto be different from promised\nisn't it?; wasn't it?" },
	{ "question": "違反", "answers": [ "いはん" ], "comment": "violation; offense; offence; breach; transgression; infringement; contravention" },
	{ "question": "違和感", "answers": [ "いわかん" ], "comment": "uncomfortable feeling; feeling out of place; sense of discomfort\nmalaise; physical unease" },
	{ "question": "違憲", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "unconstitutionality" },
	{ "question": "違法", "answers": [ "いほう" ], "comment": "illegal; illegality; invalid; unlawfulness" },
	{ "question": "遠", "answers": [ "とお" ], "comment": "distant" },
	{ "question": "遠い", "answers": [ "とおい" ], "comment": "far; distant" },
	{ "question": "遠く", "answers": [ "とおく" ], "comment": "far away; distant; at a distance; distant place; by far" },
	{ "question": "遠ざかる", "answers": [ "とおざかる" ], "comment": "to go away; to become more distant; to fade away; to die away\nto be estranged" },
	{ "question": "遠山", "answers": [ "えんざん", "とおやま" ], "comment": "distant mountain" },
	{ "question": "遠征", "answers": [ "えんせい" ], "comment": "expedition; campaign; (performer's) tour\naway series" },
	{ "question": "遠慮", "answers": [ "えんりょ" ], "comment": "reserve; constraint; restraint; modesty; diffidence; hesitation; holding back; discretion; tact; thoughtfulness\ndeclining; refraining\nforethought; foresight" },
	{ "question": "遠方", "answers": [ "おちかた", "えんぽう" ], "comment": "long way; distant place" },
	{ "question": "遠足", "answers": [ "えんそく" ], "comment": "excursion; outing; trip" },
	{ "question": "遠距離", "answers": [ "えんきょり" ], "comment": "long distance; tele-" },
	{ "question": "遠隔", "answers": [ "えんかく" ], "comment": "distant; remote; isolated" },
	{ "question": "適する", "answers": [ "てきする" ], "comment": "to fit; to suit" },
	{ "question": "適切", "answers": [ "てきせつ" ], "comment": "pertinent; appropriate; adequate; relevance" },
	{ "question": "適合", "answers": [ "てきごう" ], "comment": "conformity; compatibility; adaptability; congruity; congruence" },
	{ "question": "適宜", "answers": [ "てきぎ" ], "comment": "suitable; appropriate\nappropriately" },
	{ "question": "適度", "answers": [ "てきど" ], "comment": "moderate" },
	{ "question": "適当", "answers": [ "てきとう" ], "comment": "suitable; proper; appropriate; adequate; fit\nnoncommittal; vague; equivocal; unserious; irresponsible" },
	{ "question": "適応", "answers": [ "てきおう" ], "comment": "adaptation; accommodation; conformity" },
	{ "question": "適性", "answers": [ "てきせい" ], "comment": "aptitude" },
	{ "question": "適時", "answers": [ "てきじ" ], "comment": "timely; opportune" },
	{ "question": "適格", "answers": [ "てきかく", "てっかく" ], "comment": "eligible; qualified; competent" },
	{ "question": "適正", "answers": [ "てきせい" ], "comment": "reasonable; suitable" },
	{ "question": "適法", "answers": [ "てきほう" ], "comment": "legality" },
	{ "question": "適用", "answers": [ "てきよう" ], "comment": "applying (e.g. a technology); adoption" },
	{ "question": "適確", "answers": [ "てきかく", "てっかく" ], "comment": "precise; accurate; appropriate; exactly the right" },
	{ "question": "適量", "answers": [ "てきりょう" ], "comment": "proper quantity; proper dose; optimal dose" },
	{ "question": "適齢", "answers": [ "てきれい" ], "comment": "suitable age" },
	{ "question": "適齢期", "answers": [ "てきれいき" ], "comment": "suitable age (esp. for marriage); marriageable age" },
	{ "question": "遭難", "answers": [ "そうなん" ], "comment": "disaster; shipwreck; accident; being stranded" },
	{ "question": "遮る", "answers": [ "さえぎる" ], "comment": "to interrupt; to obstruct (e.g. a view, someone's way); to block (e.g. light, wind); to intercept" },
	{ "question": "遮断器", "answers": [ "しゃだんき" ], "comment": "circuit breaker" },
	{ "question": "遮断機", "answers": [ "しゃだんき" ], "comment": "railway crossing gate" },
	{ "question": "遷都", "answers": [ "せんと" ], "comment": "relocation of the capital; transfer of the capital" },
	{ "question": "選", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "selection; choice; choosing; picking; election" },
	{ "question": "選ぶ", "answers": [ "えらぶ" ], "comment": "to choose; to select" },
	{ "question": "選り分ける", "answers": [ "よりわける", "えりわける" ], "comment": "to classify; to sort out; to sift through" },
	{ "question": "選る", "answers": [ "よる", "すぐる", "える" ], "comment": "to choose; to select" },
	{ "question": "選任", "answers": [ "せんにん" ], "comment": "nomination (of a person to a position); selection; election; assignment; appointment" },
	{ "question": "選出", "answers": [ "せんしゅつ" ], "comment": "election; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "選別", "answers": [ "せんべつ" ], "comment": "selection; classification; sorting; screening; triage" },
	{ "question": "選奨", "answers": [ "せんしょう" ], "comment": "recommendation" },
	{ "question": "選定", "answers": [ "せんてい" ], "comment": "selection" },
	{ "question": "選手", "answers": [ "せんしゅ" ], "comment": "player (in game); team member" },
	{ "question": "選手村", "answers": [ "せんしゅむら" ], "comment": "Olympic village; athlete's village" },
	{ "question": "選手権", "answers": [ "せんしゅけん" ], "comment": "championship; title (of champion)" },
	{ "question": "選抜", "answers": [ "せんばつ" ], "comment": "selection; choice; picking out" },
	{ "question": "選択", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "selection; choice; option" },
	{ "question": "選択肢", "answers": [ "せんたくし" ], "comment": "choices; alternatives; options" },
	{ "question": "選挙", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "election" },
	{ "question": "選挙人", "answers": [ "せんきょにん" ], "comment": "qualified voter" },
	{ "question": "選挙戦", "answers": [ "せんきょせん" ], "comment": "election campaign" },
	{ "question": "選挙権", "answers": [ "せんきょけん" ], "comment": "suffrage; the right to vote" },
	{ "question": "選挙運動", "answers": [ "せんきょうんどう" ], "comment": "election campaign; political campaign; campaigning; electioneering; canvassing" },
	{ "question": "選考", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "selection; screening" },
	{ "question": "選者", "answers": [ "せんじゃ" ], "comment": "judge; selector" },
	{ "question": "遺伝", "answers": [ "いでん" ], "comment": "heredity; inherent" },
	{ "question": "遺伝子", "answers": [ "いでんし" ], "comment": "gene\ngenetic" },
	{ "question": "遺体", "answers": [ "いたい" ], "comment": "corpse; remains" },
	{ "question": "遺作", "answers": [ "いさく" ], "comment": "posthumous works" },
	{ "question": "遺児", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "orphan" },
	{ "question": "遺品", "answers": [ "いひん" ], "comment": "articles of the deceased; article left by the deceased; things that belonged to the deceased" },
	{ "question": "遺失物", "answers": [ "いしつぶつ" ], "comment": "lost article" },
	{ "question": "遺影", "answers": [ "いえい" ], "comment": "portrait of deceased person" },
	{ "question": "遺志", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "dying wish" },
	{ "question": "遺憾", "answers": [ "いかん" ], "comment": "regrettable; unsatisfactory" },
	{ "question": "遺族", "answers": [ "いぞく" ], "comment": "bereaved family" },
	{ "question": "遺書", "answers": [ "いしょ" ], "comment": "note left by dead person; suicide note; testamentary letter; will; testament\nposthumous work" },
	{ "question": "遺棄", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "abandonment; desertion" },
	{ "question": "遺構", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "remains" },
	{ "question": "遺物", "answers": [ "いぶつ" ], "comment": "relic; remains; memento" },
	{ "question": "遺産", "answers": [ "いさん" ], "comment": "inheritance; bequest; legacy; heritage" },
	{ "question": "遺言", "answers": [ "いごん", "いげん", "ゆいごん" ], "comment": "will; testament; last request" },
	{ "question": "遺跡", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "historic ruins (remains, relics); archeological site" },
	{ "question": "遺骨", "answers": [ "いこつ" ], "comment": "remains; ashes of deceased" },
	{ "question": "避ける", "answers": [ "さける", "よける" ], "comment": "to avoid (physical contact with)\nto avoid (situation)\nto ward off; to avert" },
	{ "question": "避妊", "answers": [ "ひにん" ], "comment": "contraception" },
	{ "question": "避暑", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "summering; going to a summer resort" },
	{ "question": "避難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "taking refuge; finding shelter; evacuation; escape" },
	{ "question": "避難民", "answers": [ "ひなんみん" ], "comment": "refugees; evacuees" },
	{ "question": "還付", "answers": [ "かんぷ" ], "comment": "return; restoration; refund; (duty) drawback" },
	{ "question": "還元", "answers": [ "かんげん" ], "comment": "reduction; resolution; deoxidization; deoxidation\nrestoration; return" },
	{ "question": "還暦", "answers": [ "かんれき" ], "comment": "60th birthday" },
	{ "question": "還流", "answers": [ "かんりゅう" ], "comment": "return current; convection; reflux" },
	{ "question": "邦人", "answers": [ "ほうじん" ], "comment": "Japanese national (esp. one living overseas)\nfellow countryman" },
	{ "question": "邦楽", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "Japanese music (esp. traditional Japanese music)" },
	{ "question": "邦画", "answers": [ "ほうが" ], "comment": "Japanese film\nJapanese painting" },
	{ "question": "邪", "answers": [ "よこしま" ], "comment": "wicked; evil" },
	{ "question": "邪魔", "answers": [ "じゃま" ], "comment": "hindrance; obstacle; nuisance\nto visit (somebody's home)\ndemon who hinders Buddhist training; demon who obstructs sentient beings from maintaining moral behaviour" },
	{ "question": "邸", "answers": [ "やしき" ], "comment": "residence; estate; grounds; premises; mansion" },
	{ "question": "邸宅", "answers": [ "ていたく" ], "comment": "mansion; residence" },
	{ "question": "郊外", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "suburb; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "郡", "answers": [ "こおり", "ぐん" ], "comment": "district; county\ndistrict (of 2-20 50-home neighbourhoods or townships, in the ritsuryo period)" },
	{ "question": "郡部", "answers": [ "ぐんぶ" ], "comment": "rural districts; counties" },
	{ "question": "部", "answers": [ "ぶ" ], "comment": "department (in an organization); division; bureau\nclub\npart; component; element\ncategory\ncounter for copies of a newspaper or magazine" },
	{ "question": "部下", "answers": [ "ぶか" ], "comment": "subordinate person" },
	{ "question": "部会", "answers": [ "ぶかい" ], "comment": "section meeting" },
	{ "question": "部位", "answers": [ "ぶい" ], "comment": "part; position (in a whole, i.e. body)" },
	{ "question": "部内", "answers": [ "ぶない" ], "comment": "the staff; inside the department" },
	{ "question": "部分", "answers": [ "ぶぶん" ], "comment": "portion; section; part" },
	{ "question": "部分的", "answers": [ "ぶぶんてき" ], "comment": "partial" },
	{ "question": "部品", "answers": [ "ぶひん" ], "comment": "parts; accessories; components" },
	{ "question": "部員", "answers": [ "ぶいん" ], "comment": "staff; member (club, society, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "部局", "answers": [ "ぶきょく" ], "comment": "department; bureau; section; part" },
	{ "question": "部屋", "answers": [ "へや" ], "comment": "room; chamber\napartment; flat; pad\nstable" },
	{ "question": "部数", "answers": [ "ぶすう" ], "comment": "no. of copies; circulation" },
	{ "question": "部族", "answers": [ "ぶぞく" ], "comment": "tribe; clan; house" },
	{ "question": "部署", "answers": [ "ぶしょ" ], "comment": "one's post; one's station; department; bureau; section" },
	{ "question": "部落", "answers": [ "ぶらく" ], "comment": "hamlet; subunit of village\nburakumin area" },
	{ "question": "部長", "answers": [ "ぶちょう" ], "comment": "head (chief, director) of a section or department\nhead of a (school) club; head of a (school) team" },
	{ "question": "部門", "answers": [ "ぶもん" ], "comment": "division (of a larger group); branch; field; class (subclass); group; category; department" },
	{ "question": "部隊", "answers": [ "ぶたい" ], "comment": "force; unit; corps; echelon; element" },
	{ "question": "郵便", "answers": [ "ゆうびん" ], "comment": "mail service; postal service; mail; post\nmail; postal matter; postal items" },
	{ "question": "郵便局", "answers": [ "ゆうびんきょく" ], "comment": "post office" },
	{ "question": "郵政", "answers": [ "ゆうせい" ], "comment": "postal system" },
	{ "question": "郵政省", "answers": [ "ゆうせいしょう" ], "comment": "(former) Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications (now Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications)" },
	{ "question": "郵貯", "answers": [ "ゆうちょ" ], "comment": "postal (post-office) savings (deposit)" },
	{ "question": "郵送", "answers": [ "ゆうそう" ], "comment": "mailing" },
	{ "question": "郷土", "answers": [ "きょうど" ], "comment": "native place; birth-place; one's old home\nprovince; region; locality" },
	{ "question": "郷愁", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "nostalgia; homesickness" },
	{ "question": "郷里", "answers": [ "きょうり" ], "comment": "birth-place; home town" },
	{ "question": "都", "answers": [ "みやこ" ], "comment": "capital; metropolis" },
	{ "question": "都会", "answers": [ "とかい" ], "comment": "city\nTokyo Metropolitan Assembly" },
	{ "question": "都内", "answers": [ "とない" ], "comment": "metropolitan area" },
	{ "question": "都合", "answers": [ "つごう" ], "comment": "circumstances; condition; convenience\nto arrange; to manage\nto lend money; to raise money\nin all; in total; all told" },
	{ "question": "都営", "answers": [ "とえい" ], "comment": "operated by the metropolitan government" },
	{ "question": "都市", "answers": [ "とし" ], "comment": "town; city; municipal; urban" },
	{ "question": "都市ガス", "answers": [ "としガス" ], "comment": "town gas" },
	{ "question": "都市計画", "answers": [ "としけいかく" ], "comment": "city planning; urban planning; town planning" },
	{ "question": "都庁", "answers": [ "とちょう" ], "comment": "Tokyo Government Office" },
	{ "question": "都度", "answers": [ "つど" ], "comment": "each (every) time; whenever" },
	{ "question": "都心", "answers": [ "としん" ], "comment": "city centre (center) (esp. capital city); urban centre; heart of city a metropolis" },
	{ "question": "都政", "answers": [ "とせい" ], "comment": "the metropolitan government (of Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "都民", "answers": [ "とみん" ], "comment": "city populace; resident of Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "都立", "answers": [ "とりつ" ], "comment": "metropolitan (i.e. established by the Tokyo Metropolitan Government)" },
	{ "question": "都議", "answers": [ "とぎ" ], "comment": "Metropolitan assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "都道府県", "answers": [ "とどうふけん" ], "comment": "administrative divisions of Japan: Tokyo-to, Hokkai-do, Osaka-fu, Kyoto-fu and remaining prefectures" },
	{ "question": "配り物", "answers": [ "くばりもの" ], "comment": "present; gift" },
	{ "question": "配る", "answers": [ "くばる" ], "comment": "to distribute; to deliver; to deal (cards)" },
	{ "question": "配信", "answers": [ "はいしん" ], "comment": "distribution; delivery; transmission; provision" },
	{ "question": "配偶者", "answers": [ "はいぐうしゃ" ], "comment": "spouse; wife; husband; partner" },
	{ "question": "配備", "answers": [ "はいび" ], "comment": "deploy; deployment" },
	{ "question": "配分", "answers": [ "はいぶん" ], "comment": "distribution; allotment" },
	{ "question": "配列", "answers": [ "はいれつ" ], "comment": "arrangement; disposition\narray (programming, programing)" },
	{ "question": "配属", "answers": [ "はいぞく" ], "comment": "assignment (of a person to somewhere); attachment (of a person to another unit, organization, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "配布", "answers": [ "はいふ" ], "comment": "distribution" },
	{ "question": "配当", "answers": [ "はいとう" ], "comment": "allotment; apportionment; share; dividend" },
	{ "question": "配役", "answers": [ "はいやく" ], "comment": "cast (of a play)" },
	{ "question": "配慮", "answers": [ "はいりょ" ], "comment": "consideration; concern; forethought" },
	{ "question": "配本", "answers": [ "はいほん" ], "comment": "distribution of books" },
	{ "question": "配球", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "mixing of pitches" },
	{ "question": "配管", "answers": [ "はいかん" ], "comment": "plumbing; piping" },
	{ "question": "配給", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "distribution (e.g. films, rice)\nrationing (e.g. food, gasoline)\nfood ration" },
	{ "question": "配線", "answers": [ "はいせん" ], "comment": "wiring" },
	{ "question": "配置", "answers": [ "はいち" ], "comment": "arrangement (of resources); deployment; stationing; posting; disposition; configuration; layout" },
	{ "question": "配送", "answers": [ "はいそう" ], "comment": "delivery" },
	{ "question": "配達", "answers": [ "はいたつ" ], "comment": "delivery; distribution" },
	{ "question": "配電", "answers": [ "はいでん" ], "comment": "distribution of electricity" },
	{ "question": "酒", "answers": [ "ささ", "しゅ", "さけ" ], "comment": "alcohol; sake" },
	{ "question": "酒場", "answers": [ "さかば" ], "comment": "bar; pub; tavern" },
	{ "question": "酒屋", "answers": [ "さかや" ], "comment": "liquor store; wine shop; bottle shop\nsake dealer; liquor-store owner; brewer" },
	{ "question": "酒店", "answers": [ "さかだな", "さけてん", "しゅてん", "さかみせ" ], "comment": "alcohol-selling shop" },
	{ "question": "酒税", "answers": [ "しゅぜい" ], "comment": "liquor tax; tax on alcohol" },
	{ "question": "酒造", "answers": [ "しゅぞう" ], "comment": "sake brewing" },
	{ "question": "酒類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "alcoholic drinks; liquor" },
	{ "question": "酔い", "answers": [ "よい" ], "comment": "drunkenness; intoxication\nmotion sickness; travel sickness" },
	{ "question": "酔う", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "to get drunk; to become intoxicated\nto feel sick (e.g. in a vehicle); to become nauseated\nto be elated; to be exalted; to be spellbound; to be in raptures" },
	{ "question": "酔っ払い", "answers": [ "よっぱらい" ], "comment": "drunkard" },
	{ "question": "酔っ払う", "answers": [ "よっぱらう" ], "comment": "to get drunk" },
	{ "question": "酢", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "vinegar" },
	{ "question": "酪農", "answers": [ "らくのう" ], "comment": "dairy (farm)" },
	{ "question": "酵素", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "enzyme" },
	{ "question": "酷", "answers": [ "こく" ], "comment": "severe; harsh; stringent; rigorous; strict; unfair" },
	{ "question": "酷似", "answers": [ "こくじ" ], "comment": "resemblance; resemble" },
	{ "question": "酸", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "acid\nsourness; sour taste" },
	{ "question": "酸っぱい", "answers": [ "すっぱい" ], "comment": "sour; acid" },
	{ "question": "酸化", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "oxidation; oxidization" },
	{ "question": "酸性", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "acidity\nacidic" },
	{ "question": "酸素", "answers": [ "さんそ" ], "comment": "oxygen (O)" },
	{ "question": "醜い", "answers": [ "みにくい" ], "comment": "ugly; unattractive\nunsightly; unseemly" },
	{ "question": "醜女", "answers": [ "しこめ", "しゅうじょ", "ぶおんな" ], "comment": "homely woman; plain-looking woman\nfemale demon" },
	{ "question": "醤油", "answers": [ "しょうゆ" ], "comment": "soy sauce; shoyu" },
	{ "question": "醸成", "answers": [ "じょうせい" ], "comment": "brew; foment; breed" },
	{ "question": "醸造", "answers": [ "じょうぞう" ], "comment": "brewing; distillation" },
	{ "question": "釈放", "answers": [ "しゃくほう" ], "comment": "release; liberation; acquittal" },
	{ "question": "釈明", "answers": [ "しゃくめい" ], "comment": "explanation; vindication" },
	{ "question": "釈迦", "answers": [ "しゃか" ], "comment": "Gautama Buddha; Shakyamuni; the historical Buddha (5th c. BCE?)" },
	{ "question": "里", "answers": [ "り" ], "comment": "Japanese league; ri; old Japanese unit of distance, approx. 3.927km or 2.44 miles\nneighbourhood (under the ritsuryo system; orig. of 50 homes)\nunit of area (approx. 654m by 654m)" },
	{ "question": "里子", "answers": [ "さとご" ], "comment": "foster child" },
	{ "question": "里帰り", "answers": [ "さとがえり" ], "comment": "returning home; visiting one's parents; new bride's first visit to parents" },
	{ "question": "里親", "answers": [ "さとおや" ], "comment": "foster parent; foster parents" },
	{ "question": "重い", "answers": [ "おもい" ], "comment": "heavy; weighty; massive\nheavy (feeling); depressed; gloomy; blue; uneasy\nslow; sluggish; lumbering; ponderous; clumsy\nimportant; serious; grave\nserious; severe; critical\nsolid; established; dignified; sensible" },
	{ "question": "重き", "answers": [ "おもき" ], "comment": "importance; emphasis; stress" },
	{ "question": "重さ", "answers": [ "おもさ" ], "comment": "weight" },
	{ "question": "重し", "answers": [ "おもし" ], "comment": "stone weight (as used on pickle-tub covers)\nweight (as used in balances)" },
	{ "question": "重たい", "answers": [ "おもたい" ], "comment": "heavy; massive; serious; important; severe; oppressed" },
	{ "question": "重なる", "answers": [ "かさなる" ], "comment": "to be piled up; to lie on top of one another\nto come one after another; to happen over and over; to pile up (e.g. stress); to accumulate\nto overlap (each other); to occur at the same time; to happen simultaneously" },
	{ "question": "重ねる", "answers": [ "かさねる" ], "comment": "to pile up; to put something on top of another; to stack up\nto repeat many times over; to go through something repeatedly" },
	{ "question": "重ね合わせ", "answers": [ "かさねあわせ" ], "comment": "superposition" },
	{ "question": "重み", "answers": [ "おもみ" ], "comment": "importance; weight; dignity; emphasis" },
	{ "question": "重る", "answers": [ "おもる" ], "comment": "to get heavy\nto worsen (of illness); to grow serious" },
	{ "question": "重んじる", "answers": [ "おもんじる" ], "comment": "to respect; to honor; to honour; to esteem; to prize" },
	{ "question": "重んずる", "answers": [ "おもんずる" ], "comment": "to honor; to honour; to respect; to esteem; to prize" },
	{ "question": "重体", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "seriously ill; serious condition; critical state" },
	{ "question": "重傷", "answers": [ "おもで", "じゅうしょう" ], "comment": "serious wound; serious injury" },
	{ "question": "重力", "answers": [ "じゅうりょく" ], "comment": "gravity; gravitation; gravitational pull" },
	{ "question": "重加算税", "answers": [ "じゅうかさんぜい" ], "comment": "heavy additional tax(ation)" },
	{ "question": "重厚", "answers": [ "じゅうこう", "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "profound; deep; grave; solid; dignified; stately; solemn; massive; composed" },
	{ "question": "重圧", "answers": [ "じゅうあつ" ], "comment": "strong pressure; heavy pressure" },
	{ "question": "重大", "answers": [ "じゅうだい" ], "comment": "serious; important; significant; grave; weighty" },
	{ "question": "重宝", "answers": [ "じゅうほう", "ちょうほう" ], "comment": "convenient; useful; handy; helpful\npriceless treasure\nvaluing highly; prizing" },
	{ "question": "重層", "answers": [ "じゅうそう" ], "comment": "multistoried; multilayered" },
	{ "question": "重工業", "answers": [ "じゅうこうぎょう" ], "comment": "heavy industry" },
	{ "question": "重度", "answers": [ "じゅうど" ], "comment": "heavy; severe" },
	{ "question": "重役", "answers": [ "おもやく", "じゅうやく" ], "comment": "company director; top management; high executive; (person with) heavy responsibilities" },
	{ "question": "重心", "answers": [ "じゅうしん" ], "comment": "centre of gravity (center)\ncentroid; barycenter\n(one's) balance" },
	{ "question": "重態", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "seriously ill; serious condition; critical state" },
	{ "question": "重油", "answers": [ "じゅうゆ" ], "comment": "heavy oil; fuel oil" },
	{ "question": "重点", "answers": [ "じゅうてん" ], "comment": "important point; emphasis; stress; importance; priority\niteration mark\ncolon (punctuation)" },
	{ "question": "重点的", "answers": [ "じゅうてんてき" ], "comment": "prioritized; focused; concentrated; predominant" },
	{ "question": "重症", "answers": [ "じゅうしょう" ], "comment": "serious illness" },
	{ "question": "重荷", "answers": [ "じゅうか", "おもに" ], "comment": "load; heavy burden; encumbrance; heavy freight; heavy responsibility" },
	{ "question": "重複", "answers": [ "じゅうふく", "ちょうふく" ], "comment": "duplication; repetition; overlapping; redundancy; restoration" },
	{ "question": "重要", "answers": [ "じゅうよう" ], "comment": "important; momentous; essential; principal; major" },
	{ "question": "重要文化財", "answers": [ "じゅうようぶんかざい" ], "comment": "important cultural property; important cultural asset" },
	{ "question": "重視", "answers": [ "じゅうし" ], "comment": "importance; stress; serious consideration\nto take something seriously; to attach importance; to stress" },
	{ "question": "重責", "answers": [ "じゅうせき" ], "comment": "heavy responsibility" },
	{ "question": "重量", "answers": [ "じゅうりょう" ], "comment": "weight\nheavyweight boxer" },
	{ "question": "重鎮", "answers": [ "じゅうちん" ], "comment": "leader; authority; mainstay" },
	{ "question": "野", "answers": [ "や", "の" ], "comment": "plain; field\nhidden (structural) member\nwild\nlacking a political post" },
	{ "question": "野中", "answers": [ "のなか" ], "comment": "in the middle of a field" },
	{ "question": "野党", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "opposition party; political opposition; opposition" },
	{ "question": "野原", "answers": [ "のはら" ], "comment": "field" },
	{ "question": "野合", "answers": [ "やごう" ], "comment": "illicit union; collusion" },
	{ "question": "野外", "answers": [ "やがい" ], "comment": "outdoors; outside; open air\nfields; outskirts; suburbs" },
	{ "question": "野山", "answers": [ "のやま" ], "comment": "hills and fields; hill and dale" },
	{ "question": "野心", "answers": [ "やしん" ], "comment": "ambition; aspiration\nsinister designs; treachery" },
	{ "question": "野性", "answers": [ "やせい" ], "comment": "wildness (plants, animals, etc.); uncouth; rough; unpolished" },
	{ "question": "野手", "answers": [ "やしゅ" ], "comment": "fielder" },
	{ "question": "野放し", "answers": [ "のばなし" ], "comment": "leaving something to take care of itself" },
	{ "question": "野暮", "answers": [ "やぼ" ], "comment": "boorish; unsophisticated; unrefined; uncouth; tasteless; insensitive; thoughtless; dumb" },
	{ "question": "野望", "answers": [ "やぼう" ], "comment": "ambition; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "野末", "answers": [ "のずえ" ], "comment": "corners of a field" },
	{ "question": "野球", "answers": [ "やきゅう" ], "comment": "baseball" },
	{ "question": "野生", "answers": [ "やせい" ], "comment": "wild; growing wild; living in the wild\nI" },
	{ "question": "野菜", "answers": [ "やさい" ], "comment": "vegetable" },
	{ "question": "野蛮", "answers": [ "やばん" ], "comment": "savage; uncivilized; uncivilised; barbarian" },
	{ "question": "野鳥", "answers": [ "やちょう" ], "comment": "wild bird" },
	{ "question": "量", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "quantity; amount; volume; portion (of food)" },
	{ "question": "量る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "量刑", "answers": [ "りょうけい" ], "comment": "judge's sentence; assessment of a case" },
	{ "question": "量産", "answers": [ "りょうさん" ], "comment": "mass production" },
	{ "question": "量的", "answers": [ "りょうてき" ], "comment": "quantitative" },
	{ "question": "量販店", "answers": [ "りょうはんてん" ], "comment": "mass marketer; emporium; volume retailer" },
	{ "question": "金", "answers": [ "きん", "かね" ], "comment": "money\nmetal /\n gold (Au); golden (color); gold (medal, cup)\nvaluable; of highest value\nmoney; gold coin (orig. meaning)\nFriday\nmetal (fourth of the five elements)\nJin (dynasty of China; 1115-1234 CE)\ngold general\ntesticles\nkarat; carat" },
	{ "question": "金がない", "answers": [ "かねがない" ], "comment": "have no money" },
	{ "question": "金もうけ", "answers": [ "かねもうけ" ], "comment": "money-making" },
	{ "question": "金儲け", "answers": [ "かねもうけ" ], "comment": "money-making" },
	{ "question": "金具", "answers": [ "かなぐ" ], "comment": "metal fittings; metal fixtures" },
	{ "question": "金利", "answers": [ "きんり" ], "comment": "interest rates" },
	{ "question": "金品", "answers": [ "きんぴん" ], "comment": "money and goods" },
	{ "question": "金子", "answers": [ "きんす" ], "comment": "money; funds" },
	{ "question": "金屏風", "answers": [ "きんびょうぶ" ], "comment": "folding screen covered with gold leaf" },
	{ "question": "金属", "answers": [ "きんぞく" ], "comment": "metal" },
	{ "question": "金庫", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "safe; strongbox; cashbox; vault; strongroom\ndepository; cash office; treasury; provider of funds" },
	{ "question": "金持ち", "answers": [ "かねもち" ], "comment": "rich person" },
	{ "question": "金星", "answers": [ "きんぼし", "きんせい" ], "comment": "Venus (planet) /\n dazzling victory\nwin of a rank-and-file wrestler over the grand champion" },
	{ "question": "金曜", "answers": [ "きんよう" ], "comment": "Friday" },
	{ "question": "金曜日", "answers": [ "きんようび" ], "comment": "Friday" },
	{ "question": "金権", "answers": [ "きんけん" ], "comment": "power of money; financial influence" },
	{ "question": "金石", "answers": [ "きんせき" ], "comment": "minerals and rocks; metal and stone utensils\nepigraph" },
	{ "question": "金網", "answers": [ "かなあみ" ], "comment": "wire netting; wire mesh; wire screen; chain-link mesh" },
	{ "question": "金脈", "answers": [ "きんみゃく" ], "comment": "vein of gold\nfinancial connections; patron; source of money" },
	{ "question": "金色", "answers": [ "きんいろ", "こんじき" ], "comment": "golden (colour, color)" },
	{ "question": "金融", "answers": [ "きんゆう" ], "comment": "financing; credit transacting; loaning of money; circulation of money" },
	{ "question": "金融市場", "answers": [ "きんゆうしじょう" ], "comment": "money market; financial market" },
	{ "question": "金融機関", "answers": [ "きんゆうきかん" ], "comment": "financial institutions; banking facilities" },
	{ "question": "金貨", "answers": [ "きんか" ], "comment": "gold coin" },
	{ "question": "金銭", "answers": [ "きんせん" ], "comment": "money; cash" },
	{ "question": "金額", "answers": [ "きんがく" ], "comment": "amount of money" },
	{ "question": "金魚", "answers": [ "きんぎょ" ], "comment": "goldfish" },
	{ "question": "釘", "answers": [ "くぎ" ], "comment": "nail (i.e. small metal spike)" },
	{ "question": "釜", "answers": [ "かま" ], "comment": "iron pot; kettle" },
	{ "question": "針", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "needle; pin\nhook\nstinger; thorn\nhand (e.g. clock, etc.); pointer\nstaple (for a stapler)\nneedlework; sewing\nmalice\ncounter for stitches" },
	{ "question": "針金", "answers": [ "はりがね" ], "comment": "wire" },
	{ "question": "釣り合い", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "釣り合う", "answers": [ "つりあう" ], "comment": "to balance; to be in harmony; to be in equilibrium\nto suit; to go well together; to be a good match" },
	{ "question": "釣る", "answers": [ "つる" ], "comment": "to fish; to angle; to catch\nto lure in; to tempt; to attract; to entice; to allure" },
	{ "question": "釣合", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "釣合い", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "鈍い", "answers": [ "にぶい", "のろい" ], "comment": "dull (e.g. a knife); blunt\nthickheaded; obtuse; stupid\ndull (sound, color, etc.); dim (light)\nslow; sluggish; inert; lethargic\nindulgent (esp. to the opposite sex); doting" },
	{ "question": "鈍化", "answers": [ "どんか" ], "comment": "becoming dull; slowing down" },
	{ "question": "鈍感", "answers": [ "どんかん" ], "comment": "thickheaded; insensitive; dull; thick-skinned" },
	{ "question": "鈍間", "answers": [ "のろま" ], "comment": "blockhead; dunce; gullible (person)" },
	{ "question": "鈴", "answers": [ "すず", "りん" ], "comment": "bell (often globular)" },
	{ "question": "鉄", "answers": [ "てつ" ], "comment": "iron (Fe)\nstrong and hard (as iron)\nrailway\nrailway enthusiast" },
	{ "question": "鉄工", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "ironworking; ironworker" },
	{ "question": "鉄板", "answers": [ "てっぱん" ], "comment": "iron plate\nsure thing" },
	{ "question": "鉄棒", "answers": [ "てつぼう" ], "comment": "iron rod; iron bar; iron club\nhorizontal bar (gymnastics)" },
	{ "question": "鉄橋", "answers": [ "てっきょう" ], "comment": "railway bridge; iron bridge" },
	{ "question": "鉄砲", "answers": [ "てっぽう" ], "comment": "gun\nwooden pole that wrestlers strike in practice\nfugu" },
	{ "question": "鉄筋", "answers": [ "てっきん" ], "comment": "rebar; (concrete) iron reinforcing bar" },
	{ "question": "鉄製", "answers": [ "てっせい", "てつせい" ], "comment": "made from iron" },
	{ "question": "鉄道", "answers": [ "てつどう" ], "comment": "railroad; railway; rail transport" },
	{ "question": "鉄鋼", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "iron and steel" },
	{ "question": "鉄骨", "answers": [ "てっこつ" ], "comment": "steel frame; steel beam; steel girder" },
	{ "question": "鉛", "answers": [ "なまり" ], "comment": "lead (Pb)" },
	{ "question": "鉛筆", "answers": [ "えんぴつ" ], "comment": "pencil" },
	{ "question": "鉢", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "bowl; pot; basin\nflowerpot\ncrown; brainpan" },
	{ "question": "鉢植え", "answers": [ "はちうえ" ], "comment": "potted plant" },
	{ "question": "鉱区", "answers": [ "こうく" ], "comment": "mining area; mine lot" },
	{ "question": "鉱山", "answers": [ "こうざん" ], "comment": "mine (ore)" },
	{ "question": "鉱業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "mining industry" },
	{ "question": "鉱物", "answers": [ "こうぶつ" ], "comment": "mineral" },
	{ "question": "銀", "answers": [ "ぎん", "しろがね" ], "comment": "silver (Ag)\nsilver coin; money\nsilver medal\nsilver colour; silver color\nbank\nsilver general" },
	{ "question": "銀座", "answers": [ "ぎんざ" ], "comment": "Ginza (shopping district in Tokyo)\n(Edo period) silver mint" },
	{ "question": "銀河", "answers": [ "ぎんが" ], "comment": "Milky Way\ngalaxy" },
	{ "question": "銀紙", "answers": [ "ぎんがみ" ], "comment": "aluminum foil; aluminium foil; tinfoil; silver paper\nsilver-colored paper" },
	{ "question": "銀色", "answers": [ "ぎんいろ" ], "comment": "silver (color, colour)" },
	{ "question": "銀行", "answers": [ "ぎんこう" ], "comment": "bank" },
	{ "question": "銃", "answers": [ "じゅう" ], "comment": "gun; rifle; small arms" },
	{ "question": "銃器", "answers": [ "じゅうき" ], "comment": "small arms" },
	{ "question": "銃声", "answers": [ "じゅうせい" ], "comment": "gunshot; (gun) report" },
	{ "question": "銃弾", "answers": [ "じゅうだん" ], "comment": "bullet (from a rifle)" },
	{ "question": "銃撃", "answers": [ "じゅうげき" ], "comment": "shooting; gunning (down)" },
	{ "question": "銅", "answers": [ "あかがね", "どう" ], "comment": "copper (Cu)\nbronze (medal)" },
	{ "question": "銅像", "answers": [ "どうぞう" ], "comment": "bronze statue" },
	{ "question": "銅貨", "answers": [ "どうか" ], "comment": "copper coin" },
	{ "question": "銘柄", "answers": [ "めいがら" ], "comment": "brand; make; description\ntrading name of stocks and securities" },
	{ "question": "銚子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "(sake) decanter" },
	{ "question": "銭", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "hundredth of a yen\ncoin made of non-precious materials\none-thousandth of a kan (as a unit of currency)\none-thousandth of a kan (as a unit of mass)" },
	{ "question": "銭湯", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "bath-house; public bath" },
	{ "question": "鋭い", "answers": [ "するどい" ], "comment": "sharp (blade); pointed\nsharp (pain); stabbing; cutting (remark); stinging; pointed (question or look); screeching (noise)\nperceptive; keen; quick (mind); astute; shrewd; discerning\nnimble; agile; quick" },
	{ "question": "鋼", "answers": [ "はがね", "こう" ], "comment": "steel" },
	{ "question": "鋼材", "answers": [ "こうざい" ], "comment": "steel material" },
	{ "question": "鋼板", "answers": [ "こうばん", "こうはん" ], "comment": "steel sheet; steel plate; steel plates" },
	{ "question": "錆", "answers": [ "さび" ], "comment": "rust" },
	{ "question": "錆びる", "answers": [ "さびる" ], "comment": "to rust; to become rusty" },
	{ "question": "錠", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "lock; padlock\ntablet; lozenge; pill" },
	{ "question": "錦", "answers": [ "にしき" ], "comment": "brocade\nfine dress; fine clothes" },
	{ "question": "錨", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "anchor" },
	{ "question": "錯覚", "answers": [ "さっかく" ], "comment": "optical illusion; hallucination\nmisapprehension; delusion" },
	{ "question": "錯誤", "answers": [ "さくご" ], "comment": "mistake; error; discrepancy\ndiscrepancy between one's actions and intentions" },
	{ "question": "録画", "answers": [ "ろくが" ], "comment": "(video) recording" },
	{ "question": "録音", "answers": [ "ろくおん" ], "comment": "(audio) recording" },
	{ "question": "録音テープ", "answers": [ "ろくおんテープ" ], "comment": "audio tape; magnetic tape" },
	{ "question": "鍋", "answers": [ "なべ" ], "comment": "saucepan; pot\nstew; hot pot" },
	{ "question": "鍛える", "answers": [ "きたえる" ], "comment": "to forge; to temper\nto drill; to train; to discipline" },
	{ "question": "鍵", "answers": [ "かぎ" ], "comment": "key\nlock" },
	{ "question": "鎖", "answers": [ "くさり" ], "comment": "chain; chains" },
	{ "question": "鎖国", "answers": [ "さこく" ], "comment": "national isolation; closing the country (to foreigners)\nsakoku; policy of national isolation enacted by the Tokugawa shogunate" },
	{ "question": "鎮まる", "answers": [ "しずまる" ], "comment": "to quieten down; to calm down; to subside; to die down; to abate; to be suppressed" },
	{ "question": "鎮める", "answers": [ "しずめる" ], "comment": "to appease; to suppress; to calm" },
	{ "question": "鎮圧", "answers": [ "ちんあつ" ], "comment": "suppression; subjugation" },
	{ "question": "鎮魂", "answers": [ "ちんごん", "ちんこん" ], "comment": "repose of souls" },
	{ "question": "鏡", "answers": [ "かがみ" ], "comment": "mirror; looking-glass\nbarrel head" },
	{ "question": "鐘", "answers": [ "かね" ], "comment": "bell (often a large hanging bell); chime" },
	{ "question": "鑑定", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; expert opinion; appraisal" },
	{ "question": "鑑賞", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "appreciation (e.g. of art); aesthetic sense" },
	{ "question": "長", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "head; chief; leader; elder\nmerit; strong point\nsuperiority\nmajor" },
	{ "question": "長い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "long (distance)\nlong (time); lengthy" },
	{ "question": "長い間", "answers": [ "ながいあいだ" ], "comment": "long time; long interval; for quite some time" },
	{ "question": "長さ", "answers": [ "ながさ" ], "comment": "length" },
	{ "question": "長らく", "answers": [ "ながらく" ], "comment": "long; (for a) long time" },
	{ "question": "長唄", "answers": [ "ながうた" ], "comment": "long epic song with shamisen accompaniment (developed in Edo in the early 17th century)" },
	{ "question": "長大", "answers": [ "ちょうだい" ], "comment": "very long; great length" },
	{ "question": "長女", "answers": [ "ちょうじょ" ], "comment": "eldest daughter; first-born daughter" },
	{ "question": "長官", "answers": [ "ちょうかん" ], "comment": "secretary (government); director; chief" },
	{ "question": "長寿", "answers": [ "ちょうじゅ" ], "comment": "longevity" },
	{ "question": "長屋", "answers": [ "ながや" ], "comment": "tenement house; row house" },
	{ "question": "長年", "answers": [ "えいねん", "ながねん" ], "comment": "long time; many years" },
	{ "question": "長引く", "answers": [ "ながびく" ], "comment": "to be prolonged; to drag on" },
	{ "question": "長所", "answers": [ "ちょうしょ" ], "comment": "strong point; merit; virtue; advantage" },
	{ "question": "長打", "answers": [ "ちょうだ" ], "comment": "long hit; slugging; extra-base hit" },
	{ "question": "長持ち", "answers": [ "ながもち" ], "comment": "long-lasting; long-wearing; wears well\nnagamochi; large oblong chest (for clothing, personal effects, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "長方形", "answers": [ "ちょうほうけい" ], "comment": "rectangle; oblong" },
	{ "question": "長時間", "answers": [ "ちょうじかん" ], "comment": "long period of time; long playing" },
	{ "question": "長期", "answers": [ "ちょうき" ], "comment": "long-term" },
	{ "question": "長期的", "answers": [ "ちょうきてき" ], "comment": "long-term" },
	{ "question": "長生き", "answers": [ "ながいき" ], "comment": "longevity; long life" },
	{ "question": "長男", "answers": [ "ちょうなん" ], "comment": "eldest son (may be the only son); first-born son" },
	{ "question": "長短", "answers": [ "ちょうたん" ], "comment": "length\nlong and short; advantages and disadvantages; pluses and minuses; strong and weak points; merits and demerits" },
	{ "question": "長続き", "answers": [ "ながつづき" ], "comment": "permanence; continuation; long-lasting\nto last a long time; to continue; to keep at something for a long time" },
	{ "question": "長編", "answers": [ "ちょうへん" ], "comment": "long (e.g. novel, film)" },
	{ "question": "長老", "answers": [ "ちょうろう" ], "comment": "elder; senior\nsenior monk\ndean; presbyter; patriarch" },
	{ "question": "長者", "answers": [ "ちょうざ", "ちょうじゃ", "ちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "millionaire\none's superior; one's elder; one's senior\nvirtuous and gentle person\nfemale owner of a whorehouse in a post town\nchief of a post town" },
	{ "question": "長袖", "answers": [ "ながそで" ], "comment": "long sleeves" },
	{ "question": "長話", "answers": [ "ながばなし" ], "comment": "long talk" },
	{ "question": "長調", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう" ], "comment": "major key" },
	{ "question": "長距離", "answers": [ "ちょうきょり" ], "comment": "long distance; long haul" },
	{ "question": "長身", "answers": [ "ちょうしん" ], "comment": "tall figure; high stature" },
	{ "question": "長雨", "answers": [ "ながあめ", "ながめ" ], "comment": "long spell of rain" },
	{ "question": "門", "answers": [ "かど", "もん" ], "comment": "gate\nbranch of learning based on the teachings of a single master\ndivision; phylum\ncounter for cannons" },
	{ "question": "門下", "answers": [ "もんか" ], "comment": "one's pupil or student or follower" },
	{ "question": "門前", "answers": [ "もんぜん" ], "comment": "before a gate" },
	{ "question": "門前払い", "answers": [ "もんぜんばらい" ], "comment": "turning another away at the gate or front door; refusing to receive a caller" },
	{ "question": "門戸", "answers": [ "もんこ" ], "comment": "door" },
	{ "question": "門扉", "answers": [ "もんぴ" ], "comment": "door(s) of a gate" },
	{ "question": "閉ざす", "answers": [ "とざす" ], "comment": "to shut; to close; to lock; to fasten\nto plunge (in grief)" },
	{ "question": "閉じこもる", "answers": [ "とじこもる" ], "comment": "to seclude oneself; to shut oneself away" },
	{ "question": "閉じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.); to shut" },
	{ "question": "閉じ込める", "answers": [ "とじこめる" ], "comment": "to lock up; to shut up; to imprison" },
	{ "question": "閉まる", "answers": [ "しまる" ], "comment": "to be shut; to close; to be closed\nto be firm (of a body, face, etc.); to be well-knit\nto be locked\nto tighten; to be tightened\nto become sober; to become tense" },
	{ "question": "閉める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to close; to shut" },
	{ "question": "閉会", "answers": [ "へいかい" ], "comment": "closure (of a ceremony, event, meeting, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "閉口", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "dumbfounded; stumped; at one's wits' end; nonplussed\nannoyed" },
	{ "question": "閉幕", "answers": [ "へいまく" ], "comment": "falling of the curtain; coming to an end" },
	{ "question": "閉店", "answers": [ "へいてん" ], "comment": "closing up shop (for the day)\nstopping business; going out of business" },
	{ "question": "閉鎖", "answers": [ "へいさ" ], "comment": "closing; closure; shutdown; lockout" },
	{ "question": "開き", "answers": [ "ひらき" ], "comment": "opening; gap\ndried and opened fish" },
	{ "question": "開き直る", "answers": [ "ひらきなおる" ], "comment": "to become defiant; to turn upon; to become serious" },
	{ "question": "開く", "answers": [ "ひらく", "あく" ], "comment": "to open; to undo; to unseal; to unpack\nto bloom; to unfold; to spread out\nto open (for business, e.g. in the morning)\nto be wide (gap, etc.); to widen\nto hold (meeting, etc.); to give; to open\nto found (nation, dynasty, sect, etc.); to open (a new business); to set up; to establish; to start\nto open (ports, borders, etc.)\nto open (an account)\nto open up (new land, path, etc.); to clear; to develop\nto open (a file, etc.)\nto extract (root); to reduce (equation)\nto cut open (fish)\nto change (kanji into hiragana)\nto flare (e.g. skirt)\nto slacken (into a poor posture) /\n to open (e.g. doors)\nto open (e.g. business, etc.)\nto be empty\nto be vacant; to be available; to be free\nto be open (e.g. neckline, etc.)\nto have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto come to an end\nto open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.)\nto have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)" },
	{ "question": "開ける", "answers": [ "ひらける", "あける" ], "comment": "to open (a door, etc.); to unwrap (e.g. parcel, package); to unlock\nto open (for business, etc.)\nto empty; to remove; to make space; to make room\nto move out; to clear out\nto be away from (e.g. one's house); to leave (temporarily)\nto dawn; to grow light\nto end (of a period, season)\nto begin (of the New Year)\nto leave (one's schedule) open; to make time (for)\nto make (a hole); to open up (a hole) /\n to become opened up; to improve; to get better\nto develop; to progress; to become civilized (civilised); to be up-to-date\nto be enlightened; to be sensible" },
	{ "question": "開会", "answers": [ "かいかい" ], "comment": "opening of a meeting" },
	{ "question": "開催", "answers": [ "かいさい" ], "comment": "holding a meeting; opening an exhibition; hosting (e.g. the Olympics)" },
	{ "question": "開口", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening; aperture (e.g. camera)\nopening one's mouth; beginning to speak\nopen; broad" },
	{ "question": "開国", "answers": [ "かいこく" ], "comment": "founding a country\nopening of a country (e.g. Japan) to the world" },
	{ "question": "開場", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "opening (the doors to an event, etc.)\ninauguration" },
	{ "question": "開始", "answers": [ "かいし" ], "comment": "start; commencement; beginning; initiation" },
	{ "question": "開始時刻", "answers": [ "かいしじこく" ], "comment": "starting time" },
	{ "question": "開局", "answers": [ "かいきょく" ], "comment": "opening of post-office or telephone exchange" },
	{ "question": "開幕", "answers": [ "かいまく" ], "comment": "raising the curtain\nopening (of an event); start of a season" },
	{ "question": "開店", "answers": [ "かいてん" ], "comment": "opening a new shop\nopening a shop (for the day)" },
	{ "question": "開戦", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "outbreak of war; starting a war" },
	{ "question": "開拓", "answers": [ "かいたく" ], "comment": "reclamation (e.g. wasteland); cultivation; development\npioneering; opening up (e.g. new market); breaking new ground; trailblazing" },
	{ "question": "開放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "open; throw open; liberalization; liberalisation" },
	{ "question": "開校", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening a school" },
	{ "question": "開業", "answers": [ "かいぎょう" ], "comment": "opening a business; opening a practice" },
	{ "question": "開業医", "answers": [ "かいぎょうい" ], "comment": "private clinician; physician in private practice; general practitioner" },
	{ "question": "開港", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening a port (seaport, airport, etc.); starting operations at a port\nopening a port to foreign vessels or trade" },
	{ "question": "開演", "answers": [ "かいえん" ], "comment": "curtain raising; starting (e.g. play, concert)" },
	{ "question": "開発", "answers": [ "かいはつ" ], "comment": "development; exploitation" },
	{ "question": "開発元", "answers": [ "かいはつもと" ], "comment": "developer; (software) development agency" },
	{ "question": "開発者", "answers": [ "かいはつしゃ" ], "comment": "developer" },
	{ "question": "開発部", "answers": [ "かいはつぶ" ], "comment": "Development Department" },
	{ "question": "開示", "answers": [ "かいじ" ], "comment": "release (e.g. information); disclosure (legal); show; indication; display" },
	{ "question": "開票", "answers": [ "かいひょう" ], "comment": "counting ballots; tally (of votes)" },
	{ "question": "開花", "answers": [ "かいか" ], "comment": "flowers budding; blooming; flowering\nshowing results; becoming popular; blooming" },
	{ "question": "開設", "answers": [ "かいせつ" ], "comment": "establishment; opening" },
	{ "question": "開通", "answers": [ "かいつう" ], "comment": "opening; open; taking effect; becoming active" },
	{ "question": "開閉", "answers": [ "かいへい" ], "comment": "opening and shutting" },
	{ "question": "開館", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "opening a hall for that day's business (museum, library, etc.)\nopening of new hall (museum, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "閏年", "answers": [ "うるうどし", "じゅんねん" ], "comment": "leap year" },
	{ "question": "閑散", "answers": [ "かんさん" ], "comment": "deserted (esp. store, market, town, streets); quiet; still; hushed; empty\ninactive (business, trade, etc.); slack; flat; off-season; quiet; dull\nidle; free; unoccupied" },
	{ "question": "間", "answers": [ "かん", "あいだ", "ま" ], "comment": "space (between); gap; interval; distance\ntime (between); pause; break\nspan (temporal or spatial); stretch; period (while)\nrelationship (between, among)\nmembers (within, among)\ndue to; because of /\n time; pause\nspace\nroom /\n interval; period of time\namong; between; inter-" },
	{ "question": "間に合う", "answers": [ "まにあう" ], "comment": "to be in time for\nto serve (suit, meet) the purpose; to be good enough; to be enough" },
	{ "question": "間に合せ", "answers": [ "まにあわせ" ], "comment": "makeshift" },
	{ "question": "間に合わせ", "answers": [ "まにあわせ" ], "comment": "makeshift" },
	{ "question": "間に合わせる", "answers": [ "まにあわせる" ], "comment": "to make do; to manage (with something); to make shift\nto (make) get done on time" },
	{ "question": "間一髪", "answers": [ "かんいっぱつ" ], "comment": "hair's breadth" },
	{ "question": "間中", "answers": [ "あいだじゅう" ], "comment": "during" },
	{ "question": "間伐", "answers": [ "かんばつ" ], "comment": "periodic thinning (e.g. forest)" },
	{ "question": "間借り", "answers": [ "まがり" ], "comment": "renting a room" },
	{ "question": "間取り", "answers": [ "まどり" ], "comment": "plan of a house; arrangement of rooms; list of rooms in an apartment, excluding bathroom and toilet, encoded as a string of digits and letters (e.g. \"2DK\" for a two-room apartment with a kitchen/dining area)" },
	{ "question": "間口", "answers": [ "まぐち" ], "comment": "frontage" },
	{ "question": "間接", "answers": [ "かんせつ" ], "comment": "indirection; indirectness" },
	{ "question": "間接的", "answers": [ "かんせつてき" ], "comment": "indirect" },
	{ "question": "間接税", "answers": [ "かんせつぜい" ], "comment": "indirect tax" },
	{ "question": "間柄", "answers": [ "あいだがら" ], "comment": "relationship; relation; terms (good, friendly, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "間近", "answers": [ "まぢか" ], "comment": "proximity; nearness; soon; nearby" },
	{ "question": "間違い", "answers": [ "まちがい" ], "comment": "mistake; error; blunder\naccident; mishap; trouble\nimproper conduct (e.g. between man and woman); indiscretion" },
	{ "question": "間違いない", "answers": [ "まちがいない" ], "comment": "certain; sure; doubtless\nI have no doubt; You can depend on it; It's a safe bet" },
	{ "question": "間違う", "answers": [ "まちがう" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to be incorrect; to be mistaken" },
	{ "question": "間違える", "answers": [ "まちがえる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake (in); to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)\nto confuse; to mistake something for something else" },
	{ "question": "間隔", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "space; interval; SPC" },
	{ "question": "間際", "answers": [ "まぎわ" ], "comment": "on the verge of; just before; on the point of" },
	{ "question": "間食", "answers": [ "かんしょく" ], "comment": "eating between meals; snacking" },
	{ "question": "関", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "barrier; gate\nseki (in go); mutual life" },
	{ "question": "関する", "answers": [ "かんする" ], "comment": "to concern; to be related" },
	{ "question": "関わる", "answers": [ "かかわる" ], "comment": "to be affected; to be influenced\nto be concerned with; to have to do with\nto stick to (opinions)" },
	{ "question": "関与", "answers": [ "かんよ" ], "comment": "participation; taking part in; participating in; being concerned in" },
	{ "question": "関係", "answers": [ "かんけい" ], "comment": "relation; relationship; connection\nparticipation; involvement; concern\ninfluence; effect\nsexual relations; sexual relationship\nrelated to ...; connected to ..." },
	{ "question": "関係者", "answers": [ "かんけいしゃ" ], "comment": "authorized people; authorised people; person(s) concerned; officials; staff" },
	{ "question": "関取", "answers": [ "せきとり" ], "comment": "ranking wrestler in the makuuchi (senior-grade) or juryo (junior-grade) divisions" },
	{ "question": "関心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "concern; interest" },
	{ "question": "関心事", "answers": [ "かんしんじ" ], "comment": "matter of concern and interest" },
	{ "question": "関知", "answers": [ "かんち" ], "comment": "concern; business" },
	{ "question": "関税", "answers": [ "かんぜい" ], "comment": "tariff (import tax); duty; customs" },
	{ "question": "関節", "answers": [ "かんせつ" ], "comment": "joints (knee joint, elbow joint, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "関脇", "answers": [ "せきわけ" ], "comment": "wrestler of the third highest rank" },
	{ "question": "関西", "answers": [ "かんさい", "かんせい" ], "comment": "Kansai; region consisting of Osaka, Kobe, Kyoto and surrounding prefectures\nKansai; south-western half of Japan (during the feudal era)" },
	{ "question": "関連", "answers": [ "かんれん" ], "comment": "relation; connection; relevance" },
	{ "question": "関門", "answers": [ "かんもん" ], "comment": "barrier; checkpoint; gateway\nhurdle; obstacle; trial" },
	{ "question": "閣僚", "answers": [ "かくりょう" ], "comment": "cabinet ministers" },
	{ "question": "閣内", "answers": [ "かくない" ], "comment": "(inside the) Cabinet" },
	{ "question": "閣議", "answers": [ "かくぎ" ], "comment": "cabinet meeting" },
	{ "question": "閲覧", "answers": [ "えつらん" ], "comment": "inspection; reading\nbrowsing (the WWW, Internet); web browsing" },
	{ "question": "閾値", "answers": [ "いきち", "しきいち" ], "comment": "threshold (amount, dose, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "闇", "answers": [ "やみ" ], "comment": "darkness; the dark; dark\nbewilderment; despair; hopelessness\nblack-marketeering; shady; illegal; under-the-table" },
	{ "question": "闘う", "answers": [ "たたかう" ], "comment": "to make war (on); to wage war (against); to go to war (with); to fight (with); to do battle (against)\nto compete (against)\nto struggle (against adversities, etc.); to fight; to contend; to resist" },
	{ "question": "闘争", "answers": [ "とうそう" ], "comment": "strife; conflict" },
	{ "question": "闘士", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "fighter (for); militant; champion (of); boxer" },
	{ "question": "闘志", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "fighting spirit; (will to) fight" },
	{ "question": "闘病", "answers": [ "とうびょう" ], "comment": "fighting against an illness" },
	{ "question": "阪神", "answers": [ "はんしん" ], "comment": "Osaka-Kobe\nHanshin (company name: railway, dept. store, baseball team, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "防ぐ", "answers": [ "ふせぐ" ], "comment": "to defend against; to protect against\nto prevent; to avert; to avoid" },
	{ "question": "防弾", "answers": [ "ぼうだん" ], "comment": "bulletproof; bombproof" },
	{ "question": "防御", "answers": [ "ぼうぎょ" ], "comment": "defense; defence; safeguard; protection" },
	{ "question": "防戦", "answers": [ "ぼうせん" ], "comment": "defensive fight (battle)" },
	{ "question": "防止", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "prevention; check" },
	{ "question": "防水", "answers": [ "ぼうすい" ], "comment": "waterproofing; making watertight" },
	{ "question": "防波堤", "answers": [ "ぼうはてい" ], "comment": "breakwater; mole" },
	{ "question": "防火", "answers": [ "ぼうか" ], "comment": "fire prevention; fire fighting; fire proof" },
	{ "question": "防災", "answers": [ "ぼうさい" ], "comment": "disaster prevention" },
	{ "question": "防犯", "answers": [ "ぼうはん" ], "comment": "prevention of crime" },
	{ "question": "防犯カメラ", "answers": [ "ぼうはんカメラ" ], "comment": "security camera" },
	{ "question": "防疫", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "communicable disease control (e.g. by quarantine, disinfection, etc.); prevention of epidemics" },
	{ "question": "防空", "answers": [ "ぼうくう" ], "comment": "air defense; air defence" },
	{ "question": "防衛", "answers": [ "ぼうえい" ], "comment": "defense; defence; protection; self-defense; self-defence" },
	{ "question": "防衛庁", "answers": [ "ぼうえいちょう" ], "comment": "Japan Defense Agency (Defence) (became Japanese Ministry of Defense in Jan. 2007)" },
	{ "question": "防衛施設庁", "answers": [ "ぼうえいしせつちょう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) Defense Facilities Administration Agency (Defence)" },
	{ "question": "防護", "answers": [ "ぼうご" ], "comment": "protection" },
	{ "question": "防音", "answers": [ "ぼうおん" ], "comment": "soundproof(ing)" },
	{ "question": "阻む", "answers": [ "はばむ" ], "comment": "to keep someone from doing; to stop; to prevent; to check; to hinder; to obstruct; to oppose; to thwart" },
	{ "question": "阻害", "answers": [ "そがい" ], "comment": "obstruction; inhibition" },
	{ "question": "阻止", "answers": [ "そし" ], "comment": "obstruction; check; hindrance; prevention; impediment; interdiction; preemption; blocking" },
	{ "question": "附属", "answers": [ "ふぞく" ], "comment": "attached; belonging (to); included; enclosed; affiliated; annexed; associated; subordinate; incidental; dependent; auxiliary" },
	{ "question": "降りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "降る", "answers": [ "ふる" ], "comment": "to precipitate; to fall (e.g. rain)" },
	{ "question": "降ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "降伏", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "capitulation; surrender; submission\nyield" },
	{ "question": "降参", "answers": [ "こうさん" ], "comment": "surrender; submission; capitulation\nbeing defeated (e.g. by a problem); giving up; giving in" },
	{ "question": "降板", "answers": [ "こうばん" ], "comment": "leaving the mound; being knocked out\nresigning from a role or position" },
	{ "question": "降格", "answers": [ "こうかく" ], "comment": "demotion" },
	{ "question": "降水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "rainfall; precipitation" },
	{ "question": "降水量", "answers": [ "こうすいりょう" ], "comment": "amount of precipitation; precipitation" },
	{ "question": "降雨", "answers": [ "こうう" ], "comment": "rainfall; rain" },
	{ "question": "降雪", "answers": [ "こうせつ" ], "comment": "snowfall; snow" },
	{ "question": "限り", "answers": [ "かぎり" ], "comment": "limit; limits; bounds\ndegree; extent; scope\nas far as possible; as much as possible; to the best of one's ability; very much\nunless (after neg. verb)\nthe end; the last\nas long as; only" },
	{ "question": "限りない", "answers": [ "かぎりない" ], "comment": "eternal; unlimited; endless" },
	{ "question": "限る", "answers": [ "かぎる" ], "comment": "to restrict; to limit; to confine\nto be restricted to; to be limited to; to be confined to" },
	{ "question": "限定", "answers": [ "げんてい" ], "comment": "limit; restriction" },
	{ "question": "限度", "answers": [ "げんど" ], "comment": "limit; bounds" },
	{ "question": "限度額", "answers": [ "げんどがく" ], "comment": "credit limit (on a credit card)" },
	{ "question": "限界", "answers": [ "げんかい" ], "comment": "limit; bound" },
	{ "question": "陛下", "answers": [ "へいか" ], "comment": "your Majesty; his Majesty; her Majesty" },
	{ "question": "院内", "answers": [ "いんない" ], "comment": "inside the House (Diet)\ninside the hospital" },
	{ "question": "院長", "answers": [ "いんちょう" ], "comment": "director" },
	{ "question": "陣中", "answers": [ "じんちゅう" ], "comment": "in camp; at the front" },
	{ "question": "陣営", "answers": [ "じんえい" ], "comment": "camp (group of same ideological beliefs); faction (of political party)\nmilitary camp; encampment; cantonment" },
	{ "question": "陣地", "answers": [ "じんち" ], "comment": "encampment; position" },
	{ "question": "陣容", "answers": [ "じんよう" ], "comment": "battle formation; battle array\nlineup (of a team, etc.); cast; staff; team structure" },
	{ "question": "陣痛", "answers": [ "じんつう" ], "comment": "labour pains; labor pains; birth pains; contractions" },
	{ "question": "陣頭", "answers": [ "じんとう" ], "comment": "head of an army" },
	{ "question": "除いて", "answers": [ "のぞいて" ], "comment": "except; save" },
	{ "question": "除く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to eliminate; to eradicate\nto exclude; to except" },
	{ "question": "除去", "answers": [ "じょきょ" ], "comment": "removal; getting rid of" },
	{ "question": "除名", "answers": [ "じょめい" ], "comment": "expulsion; excommunication" },
	{ "question": "除外", "answers": [ "じょがい" ], "comment": "exception; exclusion" },
	{ "question": "除草", "answers": [ "じょそう" ], "comment": "weeding" },
	{ "question": "除菌", "answers": [ "じょきん" ], "comment": "bacteria elimination" },
	{ "question": "陥る", "answers": [ "おちいる" ], "comment": "to fall into (e.g. a hole)\nto fall into (chaos, depression, dilemma, illness, etc.)\nto fall into (a trap, etc.)\nto fall; to surrender; to capitulate" },
	{ "question": "陥没", "answers": [ "かんぼつ" ], "comment": "cave-in; collapse; sinking; depression (e.g. of the skull); subsidence" },
	{ "question": "陥落", "answers": [ "かんらく" ], "comment": "fall; sinking; surrender; capitulation" },
	{ "question": "陪審", "answers": [ "ばいしん" ], "comment": "jury" },
	{ "question": "陰", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "shade; shadow\nother side; back; background" },
	{ "question": "陰り", "answers": [ "かげり" ], "comment": "shadow or cloud (e.g. on someone's happiness); shade; gloom" },
	{ "question": "陰口", "answers": [ "かげぐち" ], "comment": "malicious gossip; backbiting; speaking ill behind someone's back" },
	{ "question": "陰気", "answers": [ "いんき" ], "comment": "gloomy; dismal; miserable; melancholy\nspirit of yin" },
	{ "question": "陰謀", "answers": [ "いんぼう" ], "comment": "plot; intrigue; scheme\nconspiracy; agreement between two or more people to commit an unlawful act" },
	{ "question": "陳列", "answers": [ "ちんれつ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display; putting on show" },
	{ "question": "陳情", "answers": [ "ちんじょう" ], "comment": "petition; appeal" },
	{ "question": "陳腐", "answers": [ "ちんぷ" ], "comment": "stale; hackneyed; cliched" },
	{ "question": "陳謝", "answers": [ "ちんしゃ" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "陳述", "answers": [ "ちんじゅつ" ], "comment": "statement; declaration" },
	{ "question": "陵", "answers": [ "りょう", "みささぎ", "みはか" ], "comment": "imperial mausoleum; Emperor's tomb\nbig hill" },
	{ "question": "陶器", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "porcelain (esp. soft-paste porcelain); china; chinaware; earthenware; pottery; ceramics; crockery" },
	{ "question": "陶磁器", "answers": [ "とうじき" ], "comment": "porcelain; china; chinaware; ceramics; pottery" },
	{ "question": "陶芸", "answers": [ "とうげい" ], "comment": "ceramic art; ceramics" },
	{ "question": "陶酔", "answers": [ "とうすい" ], "comment": "intoxication" },
	{ "question": "陸", "answers": [ "りく", "おか" ], "comment": "land; shore" },
	{ "question": "陸上", "answers": [ "りくじょう" ], "comment": "land; ground; shore\ntrack-and-field events" },
	{ "question": "陸上競技", "answers": [ "りくじょうきょうぎ" ], "comment": "track-and-field events" },
	{ "question": "陸上自衛隊", "answers": [ "りくじょうじえいたい" ], "comment": "Ground Self-Defense Forces (Defence)" },
	{ "question": "陸橋", "answers": [ "りっきょう", "りくきょう" ], "comment": "viaduct; overhead bridge; overpass\nland bridge (biogeography)" },
	{ "question": "陸海", "answers": [ "りくかい" ], "comment": "land and sea" },
	{ "question": "陸路", "answers": [ "りくろ" ], "comment": "overland route; land route" },
	{ "question": "陸軍", "answers": [ "りくぐん" ], "comment": "army" },
	{ "question": "険しい", "answers": [ "けわしい" ], "comment": "precipitous; rugged; inaccessible; impregnable; steep\ngrim; severe; stern" },
	{ "question": "険悪", "answers": [ "けんあく" ], "comment": "dangerous; perilous; threatening; stormy; volatile; tense; critical; serious\nstern (expression); hostile (attitude); sharp; harsh" },
	{ "question": "陽", "answers": [ "ひ", "よう" ], "comment": "day; days\nsun; sunshine\nyang (i.e. the positive)\nthe open (i.e. a visible place)" },
	{ "question": "陽光", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "sunshine; sunlight" },
	{ "question": "陽子", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "proton" },
	{ "question": "陽性", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "positivity" },
	{ "question": "陽気", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "cheerful; jovial; merry; lively\nweather; season\nspirit of yang" },
	{ "question": "隅", "answers": [ "すみ", "すま" ], "comment": "corner; nook; recess\ndownstage right (on a noh stage)" },
	{ "question": "隅々", "answers": [ "すみずみ", "くまぐま" ], "comment": "nooks; corners" },
	{ "question": "隆盛", "answers": [ "りゅうせい" ], "comment": "prosperity; flourishing; thriving" },
	{ "question": "隊員", "answers": [ "たいいん" ], "comment": "troops; group members; team members" },
	{ "question": "隊長", "answers": [ "たいちょう" ], "comment": "commanding officer" },
	{ "question": "階", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "storey; story; floor\nstairs\nstage (in chronostratigraphy)\ncounter for storeys and floors of a building" },
	{ "question": "階層", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "class; level; stratum; layer; hierarchy" },
	{ "question": "階段", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "stairs; stairway; staircase" },
	{ "question": "階級", "answers": [ "かいきゅう" ], "comment": "(social) class; rank; grade" },
	{ "question": "随一", "answers": [ "ずいいち" ], "comment": "best; greatest; first" },
	{ "question": "随員", "answers": [ "ずいいん" ], "comment": "member of an entourage or retinue or party; attendant" },
	{ "question": "随所", "answers": [ "ずいしょ" ], "comment": "everywhere; at every turn" },
	{ "question": "随時", "answers": [ "ずいじ" ], "comment": "as needed; as occasion demands\nat any time" },
	{ "question": "随筆", "answers": [ "ずいひつ" ], "comment": "essays; miscellaneous writings; literary jottings" },
	{ "question": "隔たり", "answers": [ "へだたり" ], "comment": "distance; interval; gap; difference; estrangement" },
	{ "question": "隔て", "answers": [ "へだて" ], "comment": "partition; distinction" },
	{ "question": "隔てる", "answers": [ "へだてる" ], "comment": "to separate (by distance, time, etc.); to isolate; to partition; to divide\nto interpose; to have between\nto alienate; to estrange" },
	{ "question": "隔月", "answers": [ "かくげつ" ], "comment": "every second month; every other month" },
	{ "question": "隔週", "answers": [ "かくしゅう" ], "comment": "every other week" },
	{ "question": "隔離", "answers": [ "かくり" ], "comment": "isolation; segregation; separation; quarantine" },
	{ "question": "隙", "answers": [ "すきけ", "げき", "ひま", "すき" ], "comment": "gap; space\nbreak; interlude; interval\nchink (in one's armor, armour); chance; opportunity; weak spot\nbreach (of a relationship between people)" },
	{ "question": "隙間", "answers": [ "すきま" ], "comment": "crevice; crack; gap; opening; clearance\nspare moment; interval; break; pause; spare time\nchink (in one's armor, armour); unpreparedness; carelessness" },
	{ "question": "際", "answers": [ "さい", "きわ" ], "comment": "on the occasion of; circumstances; juncture\nedge; brink; verge; side\ntime; moment of" },
	{ "question": "際会", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "meeting; facing; confronting" },
	{ "question": "際立つ", "answers": [ "きわだつ" ], "comment": "to be prominent; to be conspicuous" },
	{ "question": "際限", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "limits; end; bounds" },
	{ "question": "障る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "to be harmful to; to hinder; to interfere with; to irritate" },
	{ "question": "障壁", "answers": [ "しょうへき" ], "comment": "enclosing wall; boundary fence\nobstacle; barrier" },
	{ "question": "障子", "answers": [ "しょうじ" ], "comment": "shoji (paper sliding door)" },
	{ "question": "障害", "answers": [ "しょうがい", "しょうげ" ], "comment": "obstacle; impediment; hindrance; difficulty; barrier\nhandicap; impairment; disability; disorder; malfunction" },
	{ "question": "障害者", "answers": [ "しょうがいしゃ" ], "comment": "(physically) handicapped person; disabled person" },
	{ "question": "隠し引き出し", "answers": [ "かくしひきだし" ], "comment": "secret drawer; hidden drawer" },
	{ "question": "隠す", "answers": [ "かくす" ], "comment": "to hide; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "隠れる", "answers": [ "かくれる" ], "comment": "to hide; to be hidden; to conceal oneself; to disappear" },
	{ "question": "隠滅", "answers": [ "えんめつ", "いんめつ" ], "comment": "destruction (esp. of evidence); spoliation; suppression\nhiding; concealment" },
	{ "question": "隣", "answers": [ "となり" ], "comment": "neighbor (neighbour); next to (esp. living next door to)" },
	{ "question": "隣り合う", "answers": [ "となりあう" ], "comment": "to adjoin each other; to sit side by side" },
	{ "question": "隣り合わせ", "answers": [ "となりあわせ" ], "comment": "adjoining each other" },
	{ "question": "隣人", "answers": [ "りんじん" ], "comment": "neighbour; neighbor; neighbourhood; neighborhood" },
	{ "question": "隣合う", "answers": [ "となりあう" ], "comment": "to adjoin each other; to sit side by side" },
	{ "question": "隣合わせ", "answers": [ "となりあわせ" ], "comment": "adjoining each other" },
	{ "question": "隣国", "answers": [ "りんごく", "りんこく" ], "comment": "neighbouring country; neighboring country; neighbouring state; neighboring state" },
	{ "question": "隣室", "answers": [ "りんしつ" ], "comment": "next or adjoining room" },
	{ "question": "隣家", "answers": [ "りんか" ], "comment": "neighbouring house; neighboring house" },
	{ "question": "隣接", "answers": [ "りんせつ" ], "comment": "adjacency; contiguity; being adjoined" },
	{ "question": "雀", "answers": [ "すずめ" ], "comment": "tree sparrow (Passer montanus)\ntalkative person; knowledgeable person" },
	{ "question": "雄大", "answers": [ "ゆうだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; majestic; great; sublime" },
	{ "question": "雄弁", "answers": [ "ゆうべん" ], "comment": "oratory; eloquence" },
	{ "question": "雅致", "answers": [ "がち" ], "comment": "artistry; good taste; elegance; grace" },
	{ "question": "集", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "collection; compilation" },
	{ "question": "集い", "answers": [ "つどい" ], "comment": "meeting; get-together (e.g. among friends)" },
	{ "question": "集まり", "answers": [ "あつまり" ], "comment": "gathering; meeting; assembly; collection; attendance" },
	{ "question": "集まる", "answers": [ "あつまる" ], "comment": "to gather; to collect; to assemble" },
	{ "question": "集める", "answers": [ "あつめる" ], "comment": "to collect; to assemble; to gather" },
	{ "question": "集中", "answers": [ "しゅうちゅう" ], "comment": "concentration; convergence; centralization; integration; gathering together" },
	{ "question": "集中豪雨", "answers": [ "しゅうちゅうごうう" ], "comment": "local downpour; severe rain fall" },
	{ "question": "集会", "answers": [ "しゅうかい" ], "comment": "meeting; assembly; gathering; congregation; convention; rally" },
	{ "question": "集合", "answers": [ "しゅうごう" ], "comment": "gathering; assembly; meeting\nset" },
	{ "question": "集団", "answers": [ "しゅうだん" ], "comment": "group; mass" },
	{ "question": "集大成", "answers": [ "しゅうたいせい" ], "comment": "compilation; culmination; grand sum" },
	{ "question": "集散", "answers": [ "しゅうさん" ], "comment": "collection (gathering) and distribution" },
	{ "question": "集票", "answers": [ "しゅうひょう" ], "comment": "gathering votes" },
	{ "question": "集積", "answers": [ "しゅうせき" ], "comment": "accumulation" },
	{ "question": "集約", "answers": [ "しゅうやく" ], "comment": "intensiveness\ncollecting; summarizing; putting together; aggregating; integrating" },
	{ "question": "集荷", "answers": [ "しゅうか" ], "comment": "collection of cargo (esp. produce, etc.); cargo booking" },
	{ "question": "集落", "answers": [ "じゅらく", "しゅうらく" ], "comment": "village; community; settlement; town; colony (animals, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "集計", "answers": [ "しゅうけい" ], "comment": "totalization; totalisation; aggregation; tally (e.g. votes)" },
	{ "question": "集金", "answers": [ "しゅうきん" ], "comment": "money collection" },
	{ "question": "雇う", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "to employ\nto hire; to charter" },
	{ "question": "雇主", "answers": [ "こしゅ", "やといぬし" ], "comment": "employer" },
	{ "question": "雇用", "answers": [ "こよう" ], "comment": "employment (long term); hire" },
	{ "question": "雑", "answers": [ "ざつ" ], "comment": "rough; crude; sloppy; messy\nmiscellaneous" },
	{ "question": "雑居", "answers": [ "ざっきょ" ], "comment": "living together; mixed residence; sharing living quarters\nmulti-tenant; community" },
	{ "question": "雑巾", "answers": [ "ぞうきん" ], "comment": "house-cloth; dust cloth" },
	{ "question": "雑木林", "answers": [ "ぞうぼくりん", "ぞうきばやし" ], "comment": "grove of mixed trees; copse" },
	{ "question": "雑煮", "answers": [ "ぞうに" ], "comment": "soup containing rice cakes and vegetables (New Year's dish)" },
	{ "question": "雑草", "answers": [ "ざっそう" ], "comment": "weed" },
	{ "question": "雑誌", "answers": [ "ざっし" ], "comment": "journal; magazine; periodical" },
	{ "question": "雑談", "answers": [ "ざつだん" ], "comment": "chatting; idle talk" },
	{ "question": "雑貨", "answers": [ "ざっか" ], "comment": "miscellaneous goods; general goods; sundries" },
	{ "question": "雑踏", "answers": [ "ざっとう" ], "comment": "hustle and bustle; throng; crowd; congestion; traffic jam" },
	{ "question": "雑音", "answers": [ "ざつおん" ], "comment": "noise (usu. unpleasant)\ninterference (e.g. radio); static; noise\ngossip; irresponsible criticism" },
	{ "question": "離す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "to separate; to part; to divide; to keep apart" },
	{ "question": "離れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "to be separated; to be apart; to be distant\nto leave; to go away\nto leave (a job, etc.); to quit; to give up\nto lose connection with; to drift away from" },
	{ "question": "離党", "answers": [ "りとう" ], "comment": "secession from a political party" },
	{ "question": "離反", "answers": [ "りはん" ], "comment": "estrangement; alienation; disaffection" },
	{ "question": "離婚", "answers": [ "りこん" ], "comment": "divorce" },
	{ "question": "離宮", "answers": [ "りきゅう" ], "comment": "imperial villa; royal villa; detached palace" },
	{ "question": "離島", "answers": [ "りとう" ], "comment": "isolated island; outlying island\nleaving an island" },
	{ "question": "離散", "answers": [ "りさん" ], "comment": "dispersal; scattering\ndiscrete" },
	{ "question": "離着陸", "answers": [ "りちゃくりく" ], "comment": "takeoff and landing" },
	{ "question": "離職", "answers": [ "りしょく" ], "comment": "employment separation; leaving one's job; losing one's job" },
	{ "question": "離脱", "answers": [ "りだつ" ], "comment": "withdrawal; secession; separation; breakaway" },
	{ "question": "離陸", "answers": [ "りりく" ], "comment": "takeoff" },
	{ "question": "難", "answers": [ "なん" ], "comment": "difficulty; trouble; hardship\naccident; disaster; danger\nfault; defect\ncriticism" },
	{ "question": "難しい", "answers": [ "むずかしい", "むつかしい" ], "comment": "difficult; hard; troublesome; complicated; serious (disease, problem, etc.)\nfussy; particular; fastidious; hard to please; displeased\ngloomy; glum; sullen; serious (look)\ndirty; unclean; filthy; detestable\nunpleasant; uncomfortable; creepy; spooky" },
	{ "question": "難なく", "answers": [ "なんなく" ], "comment": "easily" },
	{ "question": "難問", "answers": [ "なんもん" ], "comment": "perplexity; difficult question; difficult problem" },
	{ "question": "難局", "answers": [ "なんきょく" ], "comment": "difficult situation" },
	{ "question": "難易", "answers": [ "なんい" ], "comment": "difficulty; relative difficulty" },
	{ "question": "難民", "answers": [ "なんみん" ], "comment": "refugee; displaced person\nperson unable to achieve some goal (marriage, shopping, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "難点", "answers": [ "なんてん" ], "comment": "fault; weakness" },
	{ "question": "難病", "answers": [ "なんびょう" ], "comment": "incurable disease" },
	{ "question": "難聴", "answers": [ "なんちょう" ], "comment": "hardness of hearing; bradyacusia; deafness" },
	{ "question": "難航", "answers": [ "なんこう" ], "comment": "difficult voyage; hard flight\nrough going; rough passage; running into trouble; stormy passage" },
	{ "question": "難色", "answers": [ "なんしょく" ], "comment": "disapproval" },
	{ "question": "難解", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "difficult to understand; unintelligible; abstruse" },
	{ "question": "難関", "answers": [ "なんかん" ], "comment": "barrier; obstacle; difficulty; hurdle; deadlock" },
	{ "question": "難題", "answers": [ "なんだい" ], "comment": "difficult problem; challenge" },
	{ "question": "雨", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "rain" },
	{ "question": "雨具", "answers": [ "あまぐ" ], "comment": "rain gear" },
	{ "question": "雨垂れ", "answers": [ "あまだれ" ], "comment": "raindrops (dripping from eaves, branches, etc.)\nexclamation point; exclamation mark" },
	{ "question": "雨天", "answers": [ "うてん" ], "comment": "rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雨季", "answers": [ "うき" ], "comment": "rainy season" },
	{ "question": "雨宿り", "answers": [ "あまやどり" ], "comment": "taking shelter from rain" },
	{ "question": "雨戸", "answers": [ "あまど" ], "comment": "sliding storm shutter" },
	{ "question": "雨期", "answers": [ "うき" ], "comment": "rainy season" },
	{ "question": "雨水", "answers": [ "あまみず", "うすい" ], "comment": "rain water\n\"rain water\" solar term (approx. Feb 19)" },
	{ "question": "雨漏り", "answers": [ "あまもり" ], "comment": "roof leak" },
	{ "question": "雨量", "answers": [ "うりょう" ], "comment": "rainfall" },
	{ "question": "雨降り", "answers": [ "あめふり" ], "comment": "rainfall; rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雪", "answers": [ "ゆき" ], "comment": "snow" },
	{ "question": "雪国", "answers": [ "ゆきぐに" ], "comment": "snow country" },
	{ "question": "雪崩", "answers": [ "なだれ" ], "comment": "avalanche; snowslide" },
	{ "question": "雪解け", "answers": [ "ゆきどけ" ], "comment": "snow thaw; thawing" },
	{ "question": "雪辱", "answers": [ "せつじょく" ], "comment": "vindication of honour; vindication of honor; making up for loss; revenge" },
	{ "question": "雰囲気", "answers": [ "ふんいき" ], "comment": "mood; ambience; ambiance; aura; feel\na certain air; presence; special aura; something (about someone)\nair; atmosphere" },
	{ "question": "雲", "answers": [ "くも" ], "comment": "cloud" },
	{ "question": "雲行き", "answers": [ "くもゆき" ], "comment": "weather; look of the sky\nsituation; turn of affairs; signs; way the wind is blowing" },
	{ "question": "零下", "answers": [ "れいか" ], "comment": "below zero; sub-zero" },
	{ "question": "零時", "answers": [ "れいじ" ], "comment": "twelve o'clock; midnight; noon" },
	{ "question": "零細", "answers": [ "れいさい" ], "comment": "insignificant; trifling; paltry; cottage (industry); tiny (company)" },
	{ "question": "雷", "answers": [ "いかずち", "らい", "かみなり" ], "comment": "lightning; thunder; thunderbolt\ngod of thunder; god of lightning\nanger; fit of anger" },
	{ "question": "雷雨", "answers": [ "らいう" ], "comment": "thunderstorm" },
	{ "question": "電信", "answers": [ "でんしん" ], "comment": "telegraph" },
	{ "question": "電光", "answers": [ "でんこう" ], "comment": "lightning" },
	{ "question": "電力", "answers": [ "でんりょく" ], "comment": "electric power" },
	{ "question": "電動", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "electric" },
	{ "question": "電化", "answers": [ "でんか" ], "comment": "electrification" },
	{ "question": "電卓", "answers": [ "でんたく" ], "comment": "calculator (electronic)" },
	{ "question": "電器", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electric (goods)" },
	{ "question": "電圧", "answers": [ "でんあつ" ], "comment": "voltage" },
	{ "question": "電報", "answers": [ "でんぽう" ], "comment": "telegram" },
	{ "question": "電子", "answers": [ "でんし" ], "comment": "electron\nelectronic" },
	{ "question": "電子メール", "answers": [ "でんしメイル", "でんしメール" ], "comment": "email; e-mail; electronic mail" },
	{ "question": "電子部品", "answers": [ "でんしぶひん" ], "comment": "electronic parts (components)" },
	{ "question": "電撃", "answers": [ "でんげき" ], "comment": "electric shock\nblitz; lightning attack\nsudden and without warning; shocking" },
	{ "question": "電柱", "answers": [ "でんちゅう" ], "comment": "utility pole; power pole; telephone pole; telegraph pole; lightpole" },
	{ "question": "電極", "answers": [ "でんきょく" ], "comment": "electrode" },
	{ "question": "電機", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electrical machinery; appliances" },
	{ "question": "電気", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electricity\n(electric) light" },
	{ "question": "電気製品", "answers": [ "でんきせいひん" ], "comment": "electronic goods" },
	{ "question": "電池", "answers": [ "でんち" ], "comment": "battery; cell" },
	{ "question": "電池切れ", "answers": [ "でんちぎれ" ], "comment": "flat battery" },
	{ "question": "電波", "answers": [ "でんぱ" ], "comment": "electromagnetic wave; radio wave; reception; signal\nsaying strange things" },
	{ "question": "電流", "answers": [ "でんりゅう" ], "comment": "electric current" },
	{ "question": "電源", "answers": [ "でんげん" ], "comment": "source of electricity; electrical power\npower (button on TV, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "電源ケーブル", "answers": [ "でんげんケーブル" ], "comment": "power cable; power lead" },
	{ "question": "電源開発", "answers": [ "でんげんかいはつ" ], "comment": "development of electrical power resources" },
	{ "question": "電灯", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "electric light" },
	{ "question": "電球", "answers": [ "でんきゅう" ], "comment": "light bulb" },
	{ "question": "電線", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "electric line; electric cable; power cable\ntelephone line; telegraph wire" },
	{ "question": "電話", "answers": [ "でんわ" ], "comment": "telephone call; phone call\ntelephone (device); phone" },
	{ "question": "電話帳", "answers": [ "でんわちょう" ], "comment": "telephone book; telephone directory" },
	{ "question": "電話機", "answers": [ "でんわき" ], "comment": "telephone instrument" },
	{ "question": "電車", "answers": [ "でんしゃ" ], "comment": "train; electric train" },
	{ "question": "電通大", "answers": [ "でんつうだい" ], "comment": "University of Electro-Communications" },
	{ "question": "電鉄", "answers": [ "でんてつ" ], "comment": "electric railway" },
	{ "question": "需給", "answers": [ "じゅきゅう" ], "comment": "supply and demand" },
	{ "question": "需要", "answers": [ "じゅよう" ], "comment": "demand; request" },
	{ "question": "震える", "answers": [ "ふるえる" ], "comment": "to shiver; to shake; to quake; to tremble; to quaver; to quiver" },
	{ "question": "震動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "shock; tremor; impact; vibration" },
	{ "question": "震度", "answers": [ "しんど" ], "comment": "seismic intensity" },
	{ "question": "震源", "answers": [ "しんげん" ], "comment": "hypocentre (of an earthquake); hypocenter" },
	{ "question": "霊", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "soul; spirit; departed soul; ghost" },
	{ "question": "霊園", "answers": [ "れいえん" ], "comment": "cemetery" },
	{ "question": "霜", "answers": [ "しも" ], "comment": "frost" },
	{ "question": "霧", "answers": [ "きり" ], "comment": "fog; mist\nspray" },
	{ "question": "霧雨", "answers": [ "きりさめ" ], "comment": "drizzle; light rain" },
	{ "question": "露", "answers": [ "つゆ" ], "comment": "dew\ntears\n(not) a bit; (not) at all" },
	{ "question": "露店", "answers": [ "ろてん" ], "comment": "street stall; stand; booth" },
	{ "question": "露顕", "answers": [ "ろけん" ], "comment": "discovery; detection; exposure" },
	{ "question": "露骨", "answers": [ "ろこつ" ], "comment": "frank; blunt; plain; outspoken\nconspicuous; open\nbroad; suggestive; lewd" },
	{ "question": "青", "answers": [ "あお" ], "comment": "blue\ngreen\ngreen light\nblack (horse coat color)\nimmature; unripe; young" },
	{ "question": "青い", "answers": [ "あおい" ], "comment": "blue; green\npale\nunripe; inexperienced" },
	{ "question": "青ざめる", "answers": [ "あおざめる" ], "comment": "to become pale; to turn pale" },
	{ "question": "青写真", "answers": [ "あおじゃしん" ], "comment": "blueprint; plan" },
	{ "question": "青少年", "answers": [ "せいしょうねん" ], "comment": "youth; young person" },
	{ "question": "青山", "answers": [ "あおやま", "せいざん" ], "comment": "lush mountain; green mountain\ngrave; burial place" },
	{ "question": "青年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "youth; young man" },
	{ "question": "青年団", "answers": [ "せいねんだん" ], "comment": "young persons' association" },
	{ "question": "青春", "answers": [ "せいしゅん" ], "comment": "youth; springtime of life; adolescent" },
	{ "question": "青木", "answers": [ "あおき" ], "comment": "Japanese laurel; spotted laurel; Aucuba japonica\nlive tree" },
	{ "question": "青果", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "fruit(s) and vegetables; produce" },
	{ "question": "青柳", "answers": [ "あおやぎ", "あおやなぎ" ], "comment": "green willow (i.e. one that has budded)\nmeat of the trough shell (Mactra chinensis)" },
	{ "question": "青梅", "answers": [ "あおうめ" ], "comment": "unripe plum" },
	{ "question": "青田買い", "answers": [ "あおたがい" ], "comment": "speculatively buying a rice harvest, while the fields are still green\nrecruiting of university students before the agreed date" },
	{ "question": "青白い", "answers": [ "あおじろい" ], "comment": "pale; pallid\nbluish-white" },
	{ "question": "青空", "answers": [ "あおぞら" ], "comment": "blue sky" },
	{ "question": "青葉", "answers": [ "あおば" ], "comment": "fresh leaves" },
	{ "question": "青雲", "answers": [ "せいうん" ], "comment": "blue sky\nerudition; detachment from the world; high rank" },
	{ "question": "静か", "answers": [ "しずか" ], "comment": "quiet; silent\nslow; unhurried\ncalm; peaceful" },
	{ "question": "静けさ", "answers": [ "しずけさ" ], "comment": "stillness; silence; hush; calm; serenity" },
	{ "question": "静まる", "answers": [ "しずまる" ], "comment": "to quieten down; to calm down; to subside; to die down; to abate; to be suppressed" },
	{ "question": "静寂", "answers": [ "せいじゃく", "しじま" ], "comment": "silence; stillness; quietness" },
	{ "question": "静止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "stillness; repose; standing still" },
	{ "question": "静粛", "answers": [ "せいしゅく" ], "comment": "silent" },
	{ "question": "静脈", "answers": [ "じょうみゃく" ], "comment": "vein" },
	{ "question": "静観", "answers": [ "せいかん" ], "comment": "watchful waiting; careful supervision" },
	{ "question": "静養", "answers": [ "せいよう" ], "comment": "(convalescent) rest" },
	{ "question": "非", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "fault; error; mistake\ngoing poorly; being disadvantageous; being unfavorable\nun-; non-; an-" },
	{ "question": "非公式", "answers": [ "ひこうしき" ], "comment": "informal; unofficial" },
	{ "question": "非公開", "answers": [ "ひこうかい" ], "comment": "private; exclusive; secret" },
	{ "question": "非合法", "answers": [ "ひごうほう" ], "comment": "illegal; unlawful" },
	{ "question": "非常", "answers": [ "ひじょう" ], "comment": "emergency\nextraordinary; unusual" },
	{ "question": "非常に", "answers": [ "ひじょうに" ], "comment": "very; extremely; exceedingly" },
	{ "question": "非常勤", "answers": [ "ひじょうきん" ], "comment": "part-time work" },
	{ "question": "非常口", "answers": [ "ひじょうぐち" ], "comment": "emergency exit" },
	{ "question": "非常識", "answers": [ "ひじょうしき" ], "comment": "lack of common sense; thoughtlessness; senselessness; irrationality; absurdity" },
	{ "question": "非行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "delinquency; misconduct" },
	{ "question": "非鉄金属", "answers": [ "ひてつきんぞく" ], "comment": "nonferrous metals" },
	{ "question": "非難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "criticism; blame; censure; attack; reproach" },
	{ "question": "面", "answers": [ "おもて", "めん", "おも", "つら" ], "comment": "face\nsurface\nmask (esp. a noh or kyogen mask) /\n face; mug\nsurrounding area\ncheek; cheeks /\n face\nmask; face guard\n(in kendo) striking the head\nsurface (esp. a geometrical surface)\npage\naspect; facet; side\nchamfer\ncounter for broad, flat objects, levels or stages, e.g. in a video game" },
	{ "question": "面々", "answers": [ "めんめん" ], "comment": "each one; all; every direction" },
	{ "question": "面する", "answers": [ "めんする" ], "comment": "to face on; to look out on to" },
	{ "question": "面会", "answers": [ "めんかい" ], "comment": "meeting (face-to-face); interview" },
	{ "question": "面倒", "answers": [ "めんどう" ], "comment": "trouble; bother\ntrouble; difficulty\ncare; attention" },
	{ "question": "面子", "answers": [ "メンツ" ], "comment": "face; honour; honor\ncombination of three tiles that form a set\npersonnel; members; lineup\nmaking up a four to play mahjong" },
	{ "question": "面影", "answers": [ "おもかげ" ], "comment": "face; looks; vestiges; trace" },
	{ "question": "面持ち", "answers": [ "おももち" ], "comment": "expression; look; countenance; face" },
	{ "question": "面接", "answers": [ "めんせつ" ], "comment": "interview (e.g. for a job)" },
	{ "question": "面白", "answers": [ "おもしろ" ], "comment": "amusing; interesting" },
	{ "question": "面白い", "answers": [ "おもしろい" ], "comment": "interesting; fascinating; intriguing; enthralling\namusing; funny; comical\npleasant; enjoyable; agreeable; fun" },
	{ "question": "面目", "answers": [ "めんもく", "めんぼく" ], "comment": "face; honour; honor; reputation; prestige; dignity; credit\nappearance; look" },
	{ "question": "面積", "answers": [ "めんせき" ], "comment": "square measure; size (e.g. of land); area; surface" },
	{ "question": "面談", "answers": [ "めんだん" ], "comment": "interview" },
	{ "question": "面識", "answers": [ "めんしき" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "革", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "leather" },
	{ "question": "革命", "answers": [ "かくめい" ], "comment": "revolution\n58th year of the sexagenary cycle (in Onmyōdō)" },
	{ "question": "革新", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "reform; innovation" },
	{ "question": "靴", "answers": [ "くつ" ], "comment": "shoes; boots; footwear; footgear" },
	{ "question": "靴下", "answers": [ "くつした" ], "comment": "socks; sock; stockings; stocking" },
	{ "question": "韓国", "answers": [ "かんこく" ], "comment": "South Korea; Republic of Korea\nKorean Empire (1897-1910)" },
	{ "question": "音", "answers": [ "ね", "おと", "おん" ], "comment": "sound; noise; report\nnote\nfame\nChinese-derived character reading" },
	{ "question": "音声", "answers": [ "おんせい", "おんじょう" ], "comment": "voice; (the concept of) sound" },
	{ "question": "音楽", "answers": [ "おんがく" ], "comment": "music; musical movement" },
	{ "question": "音楽家", "answers": [ "おんがっか", "おんがくか" ], "comment": "musician" },
	{ "question": "音色", "answers": [ "おんしょく", "ねいろ" ], "comment": "tone color; tone colour; tone quality; timbre\nsynthesizer patch; synthesiser patch" },
	{ "question": "音読", "answers": [ "おんどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud\non'yomi (adopted Chinese reading of a kanji)" },
	{ "question": "音読み", "answers": [ "おんよみ" ], "comment": "on (Chinese) reading of kanji" },
	{ "question": "音質", "answers": [ "おんしつ" ], "comment": "tone quality; sound quality" },
	{ "question": "音量", "answers": [ "おんりょう" ], "comment": "volume (sound)" },
	{ "question": "音響", "answers": [ "おんきょう" ], "comment": "sound; noise; echo; acoustics; audio" },
	{ "question": "音頭", "answers": [ "おんど" ], "comment": "leading a group of people; someone who leads others into a song by singing the leading notes\nworkmen's songs; marching songs" },
	{ "question": "響", "answers": [ "ひびき" ], "comment": "echo; reverberation\nsound (esp. the distinctive sound of an object or activity, e.g. rain, gun, gallop, drum); noise\nquality of a sound (e.g. a fine phrase, clear voice, resonant bell); feeling of a sound; emotion or feeling inspired by something heard or read" },
	{ "question": "響き", "answers": [ "ひびき" ], "comment": "echo; reverberation\nsound (esp. the distinctive sound of an object or activity, e.g. rain, gun, gallop, drum); noise\nquality of a sound (e.g. a fine phrase, clear voice, resonant bell); feeling of a sound; emotion or feeling inspired by something heard or read" },
	{ "question": "響く", "answers": [ "ひびく" ], "comment": "to resound; to be heard far away\nto reverberate; to shake; to vibrate\nto come (home); to remain (with someone)\nto have an effect; to make an impression" },
	{ "question": "頂", "answers": [ "いただき" ], "comment": "crown (of head); summit (of mountain); spire\neasy win for one\nsomething received" },
	{ "question": "頂上", "answers": [ "ちょうじょう" ], "comment": "top; summit; peak" },
	{ "question": "頂点", "answers": [ "ちょうてん" ], "comment": "top; summit\nvertex" },
	{ "question": "項目", "answers": [ "こうもく" ], "comment": "(data) item; entry" },
	{ "question": "順", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "order; turn\nobedient; docile; submissive; meek" },
	{ "question": "順々に", "answers": [ "じゅんじゅんに" ], "comment": "in order; in turn" },
	{ "question": "順に", "answers": [ "じゅんに" ], "comment": "in order; in turn; one by one" },
	{ "question": "順位", "answers": [ "じゅんい" ], "comment": "order; rank; position (e.g. in a race); precedence" },
	{ "question": "順守", "answers": [ "じゅんしゅ" ], "comment": "compliance; adherence (to a set of rules); (religious) observance" },
	{ "question": "順序", "answers": [ "じゅんじょ" ], "comment": "order; sequence; procedure" },
	{ "question": "順当", "answers": [ "じゅんとう" ], "comment": "proper; right; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "順次", "answers": [ "じゅんじ" ], "comment": "in order; sequential; seriatim" },
	{ "question": "順番", "answers": [ "じゅんばん" ], "comment": "turn (in line); order of things; sequential order" },
	{ "question": "順調", "answers": [ "じゅんちょう" ], "comment": "favourable; favorable; doing well; OK; all right" },
	{ "question": "順路", "answers": [ "じゅんろ" ], "comment": "(regular) route" },
	{ "question": "預かり", "answers": [ "あずかり" ], "comment": "under custody; under supervision\nundecided match; draw; tie" },
	{ "question": "預かり所", "answers": [ "あずかりじょ", "あずかりしょ" ], "comment": "cloakroom; parcel room" },
	{ "question": "預かり証", "answers": [ "あずかりしょう" ], "comment": "claim check; baggage check; luggage check; deposit receipt" },
	{ "question": "預かる", "answers": [ "あずかる" ], "comment": "to look after; to take care of; to keep; to hold on to; to keep in custody\nto take charge of; to be entrusted with; to receive on deposit\nto reserve (judgment); to leave undecided" },
	{ "question": "預ける", "answers": [ "あずける" ], "comment": "to give into custody; to leave (a child) in the care of; to entrust; to deposit\nto lean on; to put one's weight on" },
	{ "question": "預け入れる", "answers": [ "あずけいれる" ], "comment": "to make a deposit" },
	{ "question": "預託", "answers": [ "よたく" ], "comment": "depositing (of money, valuables, etc.); deposition" },
	{ "question": "預貯金", "answers": [ "よちょきん" ], "comment": "deposits and savings; bank account" },
	{ "question": "預金", "answers": [ "よきん" ], "comment": "deposit; bank account" },
	{ "question": "頑丈", "answers": [ "がんじょう" ], "comment": "solid; firm; stout; burly; strong; sturdy" },
	{ "question": "頑固", "answers": [ "がんこ" ], "comment": "stubborn; obstinate; pigheaded" },
	{ "question": "頑張って", "answers": [ "がんばって" ], "comment": "do your best; go for it; hold on; keep at it" },
	{ "question": "頑張り", "answers": [ "がんばり" ], "comment": "tenacity; endurance" },
	{ "question": "頑張る", "answers": [ "がんばる" ], "comment": "to persevere; to persist; to keep at it; to hang on; to hold out; to do one's best\nto insist that; to stick to (one's opinion)\nto remain in a place; to stick to one's post; to refuse to budge" },
	{ "question": "領事", "answers": [ "りょうじ" ], "comment": "consul" },
	{ "question": "領事館", "answers": [ "りょうじかん" ], "comment": "consulate" },
	{ "question": "領内", "answers": [ "りょうない" ], "comment": "(within a) territory; domains" },
	{ "question": "領収", "answers": [ "りょうしゅう" ], "comment": "receipt; voucher\nto receive" },
	{ "question": "領収書", "answers": [ "りょうしゅうしょ" ], "comment": "(formal) receipt" },
	{ "question": "領土", "answers": [ "りょうど" ], "comment": "dominion; territory; possession" },
	{ "question": "領域", "answers": [ "りょういき" ], "comment": "area; domain; territory; field; range; region; regime" },
	{ "question": "領有", "answers": [ "りょうゆう" ], "comment": "possession (esp. of a territory)" },
	{ "question": "領海", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "territorial waters" },
	{ "question": "領空", "answers": [ "りょうくう" ], "comment": "territorial airspace" },
	{ "question": "領袖", "answers": [ "りょうしゅう" ], "comment": "leader; chief; boss" },
	{ "question": "頬", "answers": [ "ほほ", "ほお" ], "comment": "cheek (of face)" },
	{ "question": "頭", "answers": [ "かしら", "とう", "あたま" ], "comment": "counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle) /\n head\nhair (on one's head)\nmind; brains; intellect\nleader; chief; boss; captain\ntop; tip\nbeginning; start\nhead; person\ntop structural component of a kanji" },
	{ "question": "頭上", "answers": [ "ずじょう" ], "comment": "overhead; above one's head; high in the sky" },
	{ "question": "頭取", "answers": [ "とうどり" ], "comment": "(bank) president\ngreenroom manager (in a theater)" },
	{ "question": "頭打ち", "answers": [ "ずうち", "あたまうち" ], "comment": "reaching a peak; reaching the limit; plateauing; maxing out" },
	{ "question": "頭文字", "answers": [ "かしらもじ" ], "comment": "initials; initialism\nfirst letter of a word\nacronym\ncapital letter" },
	{ "question": "頭痛", "answers": [ "ずつう" ], "comment": "headache" },
	{ "question": "頭脳", "answers": [ "ずのう" ], "comment": "head; brains\nintellect; understanding" },
	{ "question": "頭角", "answers": [ "とうかく" ], "comment": "distinguishing oneself; standing out; top of the head" },
	{ "question": "頭部", "answers": [ "とうぶ" ], "comment": "head; cranium\ncephalic" },
	{ "question": "頭金", "answers": [ "あたまきん" ], "comment": "down payment; deposit" },
	{ "question": "頭髪", "answers": [ "とうはつ" ], "comment": "hair (of head)" },
	{ "question": "頷く", "answers": [ "うなづく", "うなずく" ], "comment": "to nod; to bow one's head in assent; to agree" },
	{ "question": "頻度", "answers": [ "ひんど" ], "comment": "frequency (of occurrence)" },
	{ "question": "頻発", "answers": [ "ひんぱつ" ], "comment": "frequency; frequent occurrence" },
	{ "question": "頻繁", "answers": [ "ひんぱん" ], "comment": "frequent; incessant" },
	{ "question": "頼み", "answers": [ "たのみ" ], "comment": "request; favor; favour\nreliance; dependence; trust" },
	{ "question": "頼む", "answers": [ "たのむ" ], "comment": "to request; to beg; to ask\nto call; to order; to reserve\nto entrust to\nto rely on" },
	{ "question": "頼もしい", "answers": [ "たのもしい" ], "comment": "reliable; trustworthy\nhopeful; promising" },
	{ "question": "頼り", "answers": [ "たより" ], "comment": "reliance; dependence" },
	{ "question": "頼りない", "answers": [ "たよりない" ], "comment": "unreliable; undependable; indefinite; vague\nhelpless; forlorn; forsaken" },
	{ "question": "頼る", "answers": [ "たよる" ], "comment": "to rely on; to have recourse to; to depend on" },
	{ "question": "題", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "title; subject; theme; topic\nproblem (on a test); question\ncounter for questions (on a test)" },
	{ "question": "題する", "answers": [ "だいする" ], "comment": "to be titled (e.g. a book); to be named" },
	{ "question": "題名", "answers": [ "だいめい" ], "comment": "title" },
	{ "question": "題字", "answers": [ "だいじ" ], "comment": "letters in a title" },
	{ "question": "題材", "answers": [ "だいざい" ], "comment": "subject; theme" },
	{ "question": "額", "answers": [ "がく", "ひたい" ], "comment": "picture (framed)\namount or sum (of money) /\n forehead; brow" },
	{ "question": "額面", "answers": [ "がくめん" ], "comment": "face value; par" },
	{ "question": "顔", "answers": [ "かお" ], "comment": "face; visage\nlook; expression; countenance\nhonor; honour; face\ninfluence; notoriety" },
	{ "question": "顔つき", "answers": [ "かおつき" ], "comment": "(outward) looks; features; face; countenance; expression" },
	{ "question": "顔なじみ", "answers": [ "かおなじみ" ], "comment": "acquaintance; friend; familiar face" },
	{ "question": "顔ぶれ", "answers": [ "かおぶれ" ], "comment": "personnel; members; lineup (of a team); roster; cast (of a play)\nannouncement of next day's match-ups" },
	{ "question": "顔を出す", "answers": [ "かおをだす" ], "comment": "to turn up; to make an appearance; to put in an appearance" },
	{ "question": "顔を潰す", "answers": [ "かおをつぶす" ], "comment": "to make somebody lose face; to embarrass someone; to make someone look foolish" },
	{ "question": "顔付き", "answers": [ "かおつき" ], "comment": "(outward) looks; features; face; countenance; expression" },
	{ "question": "顔合わせ", "answers": [ "かおあわせ" ], "comment": "meeting together; introduction" },
	{ "question": "顔立ち", "answers": [ "かおだち" ], "comment": "looks; features" },
	{ "question": "顔色", "answers": [ "がんしょく", "かおいろ" ], "comment": "complexion; one's colour; one's color\ncountenance; expression; one's face" },
	{ "question": "顔見知り", "answers": [ "かおみしり" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "顔触れ", "answers": [ "かおぶれ" ], "comment": "personnel; members; lineup (of a team); roster; cast (of a play)\nannouncement of next day's match-ups" },
	{ "question": "顔負け", "answers": [ "かおまけ" ], "comment": "feeling embarrassed; being put to shame; bowing to" },
	{ "question": "顔面", "answers": [ "がんめん" ], "comment": "face (of person)" },
	{ "question": "顕在", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "actual (as opposed to hidden or obscured); obvious; clear; manifest; explicit; overt; apparent; evident; actualized; actualised" },
	{ "question": "顕彰", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "honouring (publicly); honoring; making someone's good deeds or achievements well-known" },
	{ "question": "顕微鏡", "answers": [ "けんびきょう" ], "comment": "microscope" },
	{ "question": "顕著", "answers": [ "けんちょ" ], "comment": "remarkable; striking; obvious" },
	{ "question": "願", "answers": [ "がん" ], "comment": "prayer; wish; vow" },
	{ "question": "願い", "answers": [ "ねがい" ], "comment": "desire; wish; request; prayer; petition; application" },
	{ "question": "願う", "answers": [ "ねがう" ], "comment": "to desire; to wish; to hope\nto beg; to request; to implore; to pray\nto have something done for oneself" },
	{ "question": "願わくは", "answers": [ "ねがわくは" ], "comment": "I pray; I wish" },
	{ "question": "願書", "answers": [ "がんしょ" ], "comment": "written application or petition; application form" },
	{ "question": "願望", "answers": [ "がんぼう", "がんもう" ], "comment": "desire; wish; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "類", "answers": [ "るい", "たぐい" ], "comment": "kind; sort; type; class; genus; order; family\nsimilar example; parallel; the like" },
	{ "question": "類似", "answers": [ "るいじ" ], "comment": "resemblance; similarity; analogous; quasi\nto resemble; to be similar; to be alike" },
	{ "question": "類推", "answers": [ "るいすい" ], "comment": "analogy\nanalogical reasoning; analogical inference" },
	{ "question": "顧みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "顧問", "answers": [ "こもん" ], "comment": "adviser; advisor; consultant" },
	{ "question": "顧客", "answers": [ "こかく", "こきゃく" ], "comment": "customer; client; patron" },
	{ "question": "顧客満足", "answers": [ "こきゃくまんぞく", "こかくまんぞく" ], "comment": "customer satisfaction" },
	{ "question": "風", "answers": [ "ふう", "かぜ" ], "comment": "wind; breeze; draught; draft\nmanner; behaviour; behavior\ncold; influenza /\n method; manner; way; style\nappearance; air\ntendency\nfolk song (genre of the Shi Jing)\nwind (one of the five elements)" },
	{ "question": "風上", "answers": [ "かざかみ" ], "comment": "windward; upwind" },
	{ "question": "風下", "answers": [ "かざしも" ], "comment": "leeward; lee; downwind" },
	{ "question": "風俗", "answers": [ "ふうぞく", "フーゾク" ], "comment": "manners; customs\nsex service; sex industry; sex-oriented entertainment" },
	{ "question": "風刺", "answers": [ "ふうし" ], "comment": "satire; irony; sarcasm" },
	{ "question": "風力", "answers": [ "ふうりょく" ], "comment": "wind power\nforce (level on the Beaufort wind speed scale)" },
	{ "question": "風向き", "answers": [ "かぜむき", "かざむき" ], "comment": "wind's direction" },
	{ "question": "風呂", "answers": [ "ふろ" ], "comment": "bath; bathtub\nbathroom; bathhouse\nroom for drying lacquerware\nbase (wooden joint connecting the blade of a hoe, spade, etc., to the handle)" },
	{ "question": "風呂場", "answers": [ "ふろば" ], "comment": "bathroom" },
	{ "question": "風呂屋", "answers": [ "ふろや" ], "comment": "public bathhouse\nbathhouse proprietor" },
	{ "question": "風呂敷", "answers": [ "ふろしき" ], "comment": "wrapping cloth; cloth wrapper" },
	{ "question": "風味", "answers": [ "ふうみ" ], "comment": "taste; flavor; flavour" },
	{ "question": "風土", "answers": [ "ふうど" ], "comment": "natural features; topography; climate; spiritual features" },
	{ "question": "風当たり", "answers": [ "かぜあたり" ], "comment": "exposure to wind\nsevere criticism" },
	{ "question": "風情", "answers": [ "ふうじょう", "ふぜい" ], "comment": "taste; elegance; charm\nappearance; air\nthe likes of ...; lowly people such as ..." },
	{ "question": "風景", "answers": [ "ふうけい" ], "comment": "scenery; scene; landscape; view; sight\nscene (e.g. of a crime)" },
	{ "question": "風格", "answers": [ "ふうかく" ], "comment": "personality; style; appearance" },
	{ "question": "風流", "answers": [ "ふうりゅう" ], "comment": "elegance; taste; refinement" },
	{ "question": "風潮", "answers": [ "ふうちょう" ], "comment": "tide; current\ntendency" },
	{ "question": "風物詩", "answers": [ "ふうぶつし" ], "comment": "thing that reminds one of a particular season\npoem about natural scenery; poem about a particular season" },
	{ "question": "風穴", "answers": [ "かぜあな", "かざあな" ], "comment": "air hole; windhole; ventilator" },
	{ "question": "風習", "answers": [ "ふうしゅう" ], "comment": "custom" },
	{ "question": "風船", "answers": [ "ふうせん" ], "comment": "balloon (esp. small, toy variety)" },
	{ "question": "風通し", "answers": [ "かざとおし", "かぜとおし" ], "comment": "ventilation\ncommunication (within an organisation); openness" },
	{ "question": "風速", "answers": [ "ふうそく" ], "comment": "wind speed" },
	{ "question": "風邪", "answers": [ "ふうじゃ", "かぜ" ], "comment": "common cold; cold; influenza; flu; ague" },
	{ "question": "風邪をひく", "answers": [ "かぜをひく" ], "comment": "to catch a cold" },
	{ "question": "風邪薬", "answers": [ "かぜぐすり", "かざぐすり" ], "comment": "remedy for a cold; cold medicine" },
	{ "question": "風鈴", "answers": [ "ふうりん" ], "comment": "wind chime; wind bell" },
	{ "question": "飛ばし", "answers": [ "とばし" ], "comment": "selling or divesting in unwanted stocks; hiding bad loans" },
	{ "question": "飛ばす", "answers": [ "とばす" ], "comment": "to fly; to fire; to hurl; to launch; to make fly\nto skip over; to omit; to drop (e.g. stitch)\nto run or drive fast; to gallop\nto spread a rumour (rumor); to tell a story; to tell a joke\nto remove; to get rid of; to transfer\nto attack; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "飛び上がる", "answers": [ "とびあがる" ], "comment": "to spring; to jump up; to fly up; to skip" },
	{ "question": "飛び下りる", "answers": [ "とびおりる" ], "comment": "to jump down; to jump off; to jump from; to jump out of" },
	{ "question": "飛び交う", "answers": [ "とびかう" ], "comment": "to fly about; to flutter about; to flit about; to fly past each other" },
	{ "question": "飛び出し", "answers": [ "とびだし" ], "comment": "something that leaps or thrusts out" },
	{ "question": "飛び出す", "answers": [ "とびだす" ], "comment": "to jump out; to rush out; to fly out\nto appear (suddenly)\nto protrude; to project\nto butt in" },
	{ "question": "飛び地", "answers": [ "とびち" ], "comment": "scattered landholdings; detached land; enclave; exclave" },
	{ "question": "飛び火", "answers": [ "とびひ" ], "comment": "leaping flames; shower of flying sparks\nspreading fire\nrepercussions in unanticipated areas; spilling over; effects of an incident spreading to those seemingly uninvolved\nimpetigo contagiosa" },
	{ "question": "飛び込み", "answers": [ "とびこみ" ], "comment": "jump; plunge; dive\nappearing without an appointment; bursting in; arriving unannounced; cropping up suddenly" },
	{ "question": "飛び込む", "answers": [ "とびこむ" ], "comment": "to jump in; to leap in; to plunge into; to dive\nto burst in; to barge in" },
	{ "question": "飛び降りる", "answers": [ "とびおりる" ], "comment": "to jump down; to jump off; to jump from; to jump out of" },
	{ "question": "飛ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "to fly; to soar\nto jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop" },
	{ "question": "飛球", "answers": [ "ひきゅう" ], "comment": "fly (ball)" },
	{ "question": "飛行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "aviation; flight; flying\nto fly; to take a flight" },
	{ "question": "飛行場", "answers": [ "ひこうじょう" ], "comment": "airfield; airport" },
	{ "question": "飛行士", "answers": [ "ひこうし" ], "comment": "pilot" },
	{ "question": "飛行機", "answers": [ "ひこうき" ], "comment": "aeroplane; airplane; aircraft" },
	{ "question": "飛行船", "answers": [ "ひこうせん" ], "comment": "airship; blimp" },
	{ "question": "飛躍", "answers": [ "ひやく" ], "comment": "leaping; activity\nleapfrog (over a problem); making a leap (e.g. in logic)\nmaking great strides; making rapid progress\nemerging\nbecoming active; playing an active part" },
	{ "question": "飛車", "answers": [ "ひしゃ" ], "comment": "rook" },
	{ "question": "食", "answers": [ "しょく" ], "comment": "meal; (one's) diet; food; foodstuff; foodstuffs\neclipse (solar, lunar, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "食い下がる", "answers": [ "くいさがる" ], "comment": "to hang on to; to hang from; to cling to\nto hound; to keep after (someone); to refuse to back down; to persist; to tenaciously face (someone); to doggedly oppose\nto grab the front of the opponent's mawashi, place one's head against their chest, and lower one's hips" },
	{ "question": "食い止める", "answers": [ "くいとめる" ], "comment": "to check; to hold back" },
	{ "question": "食い込む", "answers": [ "くいこむ" ], "comment": "to bite into (e.g. rope into skin); to cut into; to dig into (e.g. of fingernails)\nto eat into; to encroach; to make inroads; to penetrate (e.g. a market); to break into (e.g. first place); to erode; to cut into (e.g. time, savings)\nto be wedged (i.e. underwear pulled from the back, driving it between the buttocks)" },
	{ "question": "食い違い", "answers": [ "くいちがい" ], "comment": "discrepancy; different or conflicting opinions" },
	{ "question": "食い違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "to cross each other; to run counter to; to differ; to clash; to go awry" },
	{ "question": "食う", "answers": [ "くう" ], "comment": "to eat\nto live; to make a living; to survive\nto bite; to sting (as insects do)\nto tease; to torment; to taunt; to make light of; to make fun of\nto encroach on; to eat into; to consume\nto defeat a superior; to threaten a position\nto consume time and-or resources\nto receive something (usu. an unfavourable event)\nto have sexual relations with a woman, esp. for the first time" },
	{ "question": "食べる", "answers": [ "たべる" ], "comment": "to eat\nto live on (e.g. a salary); to live off; to subsist on" },
	{ "question": "食べ歩き", "answers": [ "たべあるき" ], "comment": "trying the food at various restaurants; eating tour\nwalking while eating; eating while walking" },
	{ "question": "食べ物", "answers": [ "たべもの" ], "comment": "food" },
	{ "question": "食み出す", "answers": [ "はみだす" ], "comment": "to protrude; to stick out; to hang out; to jut out; to bulge out; to overflow; to be forced out; to be crowded out; to be pushed out; to exceed; to go over; to go beyond" },
	{ "question": "食パン", "answers": [ "しょくパン" ], "comment": "(loaf of) bread; bread in a rectangular shape" },
	{ "question": "食中毒", "answers": [ "しょくちゅうどく" ], "comment": "food poisoning" },
	{ "question": "食事", "answers": [ "しょくじ" ], "comment": "meal\nto eat" },
	{ "question": "食卓", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "dining table" },
	{ "question": "食品", "answers": [ "しょくひん" ], "comment": "food; food products; foodstuffs" },
	{ "question": "食品添加物", "answers": [ "しょくひんてんかぶつ" ], "comment": "food additive" },
	{ "question": "食器", "answers": [ "しょっき" ], "comment": "tableware" },
	{ "question": "食堂", "answers": [ "しょくどう" ], "comment": "dining room; dining hall; cafeteria; messroom\nrestaurant; eatery; snack bar; diner" },
	{ "question": "食塩", "answers": [ "しょくえん" ], "comment": "table salt" },
	{ "question": "食後", "answers": [ "しょくご" ], "comment": "after a meal" },
	{ "question": "食料", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "food" },
	{ "question": "食料品", "answers": [ "しょくりょうひん" ], "comment": "foodstuff; groceries" },
	{ "question": "食欲", "answers": [ "しょくよく" ], "comment": "appetite (for food)" },
	{ "question": "食止める", "answers": [ "くいとめる" ], "comment": "to check; to hold back" },
	{ "question": "食物", "answers": [ "しょくもつ" ], "comment": "food; foodstuff" },
	{ "question": "食生活", "answers": [ "しょくせいかつ" ], "comment": "eating habits" },
	{ "question": "食用", "answers": [ "しょくよう" ], "comment": "for use as food; edible" },
	{ "question": "食管法", "answers": [ "しょっかんほう" ], "comment": "law governing food quality" },
	{ "question": "食糧", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "food (esp. staple food such as rice or wheat); provisions; rations; food supply" },
	{ "question": "食糧庁", "answers": [ "しょくりょうちょう" ], "comment": "food agency" },
	{ "question": "食肉", "answers": [ "しょくにく" ], "comment": "meat (for consumption)" },
	{ "question": "食費", "answers": [ "しょくひ" ], "comment": "food expense" },
	{ "question": "食道", "answers": [ "しょくどう" ], "comment": "esophagus; gullet; esophageal" },
	{ "question": "食違い", "answers": [ "くいちがい" ], "comment": "discrepancy; different or conflicting opinions" },
	{ "question": "食違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "to cross each other; to run counter to; to differ; to clash; to go awry" },
	{ "question": "飢え", "answers": [ "うえ" ], "comment": "hunger; starvation" },
	{ "question": "飢える", "answers": [ "かつえる", "うえる" ], "comment": "to starve; to thirst; to be hungry" },
	{ "question": "飢え死に", "answers": [ "かつえじに", "うえじに" ], "comment": "(death from) starvation; starving to death" },
	{ "question": "飢餓", "answers": [ "きが" ], "comment": "starvation; famine; hunger" },
	{ "question": "飢饉", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "famine; drought; shortage; crop failure" },
	{ "question": "飯", "answers": [ "めし" ], "comment": "cooked rice\nmeal; food\none's livelihood" },
	{ "question": "飲み水", "answers": [ "のみみず" ], "comment": "drinking water; potable water" },
	{ "question": "飲み物", "answers": [ "のみもの" ], "comment": "drink; beverage" },
	{ "question": "飲み込む", "answers": [ "のみこむ" ], "comment": "to gulp down; to swallow deeply\nto understand; to take in; to catch on to; to learn; to digest\nto engulf; to swallow up\nto be filled with (people); to be crowded\nto hold back from saying something; to swallow (one's words)" },
	{ "question": "飲む", "answers": [ "のむ" ], "comment": "to drink; to gulp; to swallow; to take (medicine)\nto smoke (tobacco)\nto engulf; to overwhelm\nto keep down; to suppress\nto accept (e.g. demand, condition)\nto make light of; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "飲料", "answers": [ "いんりょう" ], "comment": "beverage; drink" },
	{ "question": "飲料水", "answers": [ "いんりょうすい" ], "comment": "drinking water" },
	{ "question": "飲物", "answers": [ "のみもの" ], "comment": "drink; beverage" },
	{ "question": "飲酒", "answers": [ "いんしゅ" ], "comment": "drinking alcohol (sake)" },
	{ "question": "飲食", "answers": [ "いんしょく" ], "comment": "food and drink; eating and drinking" },
	{ "question": "飲食店", "answers": [ "いんしょくてん" ], "comment": "restaurant; shops serving food and drink" },
	{ "question": "飴", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "(hard) candy; toffee\nrice-sugar; sugar made from the starch of rice, potatoes, etc.\namber; yellowish-brown" },
	{ "question": "飼い主", "answers": [ "かいぬし" ], "comment": "shepherd; (pet) owner" },
	{ "question": "飼う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "to keep (a pet or other animal); to raise; to have; to own; to feed" },
	{ "question": "飼料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "fodder; feed" },
	{ "question": "飼育", "answers": [ "しいく" ], "comment": "breeding; raising; rearing" },
	{ "question": "飽き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "weariness; tiresomeness" },
	{ "question": "飽きる", "answers": [ "あきる" ], "comment": "to get tired of; to lose interest in; to have enough" },
	{ "question": "飽和", "answers": [ "ほうわ" ], "comment": "saturation" },
	{ "question": "飽食", "answers": [ "ほうしょく" ], "comment": "gluttony; satiation; engorgement" },
	{ "question": "飾り", "answers": [ "かざり" ], "comment": "decoration" },
	{ "question": "飾る", "answers": [ "かざる" ], "comment": "to decorate; to ornament; to adorn" },
	{ "question": "餃子", "answers": [ "チャオズ", "ぎょうざ", "ギョーザ" ], "comment": "gyoza; pot sticker; crescent-shaped pan-fried dumplings stuffed with minced pork and vegetables" },
	{ "question": "養う", "answers": [ "やしなう" ], "comment": "to support; to maintain; to provide for\nto bring up; to raise; to rear; to feed\nto adopt (a child)\nto cultivate (a habit, a quality, etc.); to develop; to build up; to foster\nto recuperate (from injury, illness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "養子", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "adopted child (usu. male); son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "養成", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "training; development" },
	{ "question": "養殖", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "aquaculture (e.g. fish, shellfish, seaweed); culture (e.g. pearls); raising; cultivation" },
	{ "question": "養父", "answers": [ "ようふ" ], "comment": "foster father; adoptive father" },
	{ "question": "養父母", "answers": [ "ようふぼ" ], "comment": "adoptive parents" },
	{ "question": "養老", "answers": [ "ようろう" ], "comment": "making provision for the elderly\nYourou era (717.11.17-724.2.4)" },
	{ "question": "養老院", "answers": [ "ようろういん" ], "comment": "home for the aged; old people's home" },
	{ "question": "養育", "answers": [ "よういく" ], "comment": "bringing up; rearing; upbringing" },
	{ "question": "養護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "nursing; (protective) care" },
	{ "question": "餌", "answers": [ "え", "えさ" ], "comment": "(animal) feed; fodder; pet food\nbait; lure; enticement" },
	{ "question": "餓死", "answers": [ "がし" ], "comment": "(death from) starvation; starving to death" },
	{ "question": "餡", "answers": [ "あん" ], "comment": "red bean paste; red bean jam; anko\nkudzu sauce\nfilling (of a dumpling, bun, etc., e.g. ground meat, vegetables, bean paste)\nfilling (generally); a substance wrapped in something else (e.g. cushion stuffing)" },
	{ "question": "館内", "answers": [ "かんない" ], "comment": "in the building" },
	{ "question": "館長", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "superintendent; director; curator; chief librarian" },
	{ "question": "首位", "answers": [ "しゅい" ], "comment": "first place; head position; leading position" },
	{ "question": "首唱", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "advocacy; promotion" },
	{ "question": "首席", "answers": [ "しゅせき" ], "comment": "head; chief\nchairman; governor; president\ntop student; head of the class\ntop seat; first desk (in orchestra)" },
	{ "question": "首班", "answers": [ "しゅはん" ], "comment": "head; leader; prime minister" },
	{ "question": "首相", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "Prime Minister; Chancellor (Germany, Austria, etc.); Premier" },
	{ "question": "首脳", "answers": [ "しゅのう" ], "comment": "head; leader; leading spirit\nimportant part" },
	{ "question": "首脳部", "answers": [ "しゅのうぶ" ], "comment": "executives; top management; governing body" },
	{ "question": "首謀", "answers": [ "しゅぼう" ], "comment": "plotting; planning (crime, intrigue)\nringleader; mastermind; leader (of a plot)" },
	{ "question": "首都", "answers": [ "しゅと" ], "comment": "capital city; metropolis" },
	{ "question": "首都圏", "answers": [ "しゅとけん" ], "comment": "the capital city (often Tokyo) area (typically within 50 km of city's centre) (center)" },
	{ "question": "首長", "answers": [ "しゅちょう" ], "comment": "head (of organization, organisation); chief" },
	{ "question": "首領", "answers": [ "しゅりょう" ], "comment": "head; chief; boss; leader" },
	{ "question": "香ばしい", "answers": [ "こうばしい" ], "comment": "fragrant; aromatic; sweet-smelling\nsavory (smelling); savoury" },
	{ "question": "香り", "answers": [ "かおり" ], "comment": "aroma; fragrance; scent; smell" },
	{ "question": "香る", "answers": [ "かおる" ], "comment": "to smell sweet; to be fragrant" },
	{ "question": "香水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "perfume" },
	{ "question": "香港", "answers": [ "ほんこん" ], "comment": "Hong Kong; Hongkong" },
	{ "question": "香辛料", "answers": [ "こうしんりょう" ], "comment": "spices; condiment" },
	{ "question": "馬", "answers": [ "うま" ], "comment": "horse\nhorse racing\npromoted bishop" },
	{ "question": "馬主", "answers": [ "ばぬし", "ばしゅ", "うまぬし" ], "comment": "(race)horse owner" },
	{ "question": "馬券", "answers": [ "ばけん" ], "comment": "(horse racing) betting ticket" },
	{ "question": "馬場", "answers": [ "ばば" ], "comment": "horse-riding ground" },
	{ "question": "馬車", "answers": [ "ばしゃ" ], "comment": "(horse-drawn) coach; carriage; wagon; cart" },
	{ "question": "馬鹿らしい", "answers": [ "バカらしい", "ばからしい" ], "comment": "absurd" },
	{ "question": "馴れ馴れしい", "answers": [ "なれなれしい" ], "comment": "over-familiar" },
	{ "question": "駄菓子屋", "answers": [ "だがしや" ], "comment": "small-time candy store" },
	{ "question": "駅", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "station" },
	{ "question": "駅伝", "answers": [ "えきでん" ], "comment": "long-distance relay race\nstagecoach; post horse" },
	{ "question": "駅前", "answers": [ "えきまえ" ], "comment": "in front of station" },
	{ "question": "駅員", "answers": [ "えきいん" ], "comment": "station attendant" },
	{ "question": "駅弁", "answers": [ "えきべん" ], "comment": "boxed lunch bought at a station (often a local specialty)\nvariety of sexual position" },
	{ "question": "駅長", "answers": [ "えきちょう" ], "comment": "station master" },
	{ "question": "駆けつける", "answers": [ "かけつける" ], "comment": "to run to; to come running; to rush (someplace); to hasten" },
	{ "question": "駆ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to run (race, esp. horse); to dash\nto gallop (one's horse); to canter\nto advance (against one's enemy)" },
	{ "question": "駆け引き", "answers": [ "かけひき" ], "comment": "bargaining; haggling\ntactics; strategy" },
	{ "question": "駆け足", "answers": [ "かけあし" ], "comment": "running fast; double time\ncantering\ndoing things in a hurry" },
	{ "question": "駆け込み", "answers": [ "かけこみ" ], "comment": "last-minute rush; stampede" },
	{ "question": "駆使", "answers": [ "くし" ], "comment": "free use\nto use freely; to make free use of; to have good command (e.g. of a language)\nto drive someone on" },
	{ "question": "駆動", "answers": [ "くどう" ], "comment": "driving force" },
	{ "question": "駆逐艦", "answers": [ "くちくかん" ], "comment": "destroyer (ship)" },
	{ "question": "駆除", "answers": [ "くじょ" ], "comment": "extermination (esp. pests); expulsion; destruction" },
	{ "question": "駐在", "answers": [ "ちゅうざい" ], "comment": "residence; stay; (job) posting; being stationed (overseas, etc.)\nresidential police box; residential police box officer" },
	{ "question": "駐屯", "answers": [ "ちゅうとん" ], "comment": "stationing (troops); occupancy" },
	{ "question": "駐日", "answers": [ "ちゅうにち" ], "comment": "resident in Japan" },
	{ "question": "駐留", "answers": [ "ちゅうりゅう" ], "comment": "stationing (e.g. of troops); garrison" },
	{ "question": "駐車", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "parking (e.g. car)" },
	{ "question": "駐車場", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃじょう" ], "comment": "parking lot; parking place" },
	{ "question": "駒", "answers": [ "こま" ], "comment": "piece (in shogi, chess, etc.)\nhorse; foal\nbridge (of a violin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "騎士", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "knight" },
	{ "question": "騎手", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "horseman; rider" },
	{ "question": "騎馬", "answers": [ "きば" ], "comment": "horse riding; horseback riding; horseback rider" },
	{ "question": "騒々しい", "answers": [ "そうぞうしい" ], "comment": "noisy; boisterous" },
	{ "question": "騒がしい", "answers": [ "さわがしい" ], "comment": "noisy; boisterous\nturbulent (era, etc.); troubled" },
	{ "question": "騒ぎ", "answers": [ "さわぎ" ], "comment": "uproar; disturbance" },
	{ "question": "騒ぐ", "answers": [ "さわぐ" ], "comment": "to make noise; to make racket; to be noisy\nto rustle; to swoosh\nto make merry\nto clamor; to clamour; to make a fuss; to kick up a fuss\nto lose one's cool; to panic; to act flustered\nto feel tense; to be uneasy; to be excited" },
	{ "question": "騒乱", "answers": [ "そうらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; riot; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "騒動", "answers": [ "そうどう" ], "comment": "strife; riot; rebellion; turmoil\n(media) uproar; brouhaha; (public) outcry; scandal; controversy\nfeud; tussle; quarrel; dispute" },
	{ "question": "騒然", "answers": [ "そうぜん" ], "comment": "noisy; confused; uproarious" },
	{ "question": "騒音", "answers": [ "そうおん" ], "comment": "noise" },
	{ "question": "騙す", "answers": [ "だます" ], "comment": "to trick; to cheat; to deceive\nto coax; to wheedle; to soothe and humor (humour)" },
	{ "question": "騰貴", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "rise (in price or value); inflation; appreciation (economic)" },
	{ "question": "驚かす", "answers": [ "おどろかす" ], "comment": "to surprise; to frighten; to create a stir" },
	{ "question": "驚き", "answers": [ "おどろき" ], "comment": "surprise; astonishment; wonder; amazement" },
	{ "question": "驚く", "answers": [ "おどろく" ], "comment": "to be surprised; to be astonished" },
	{ "question": "驚くほど", "answers": [ "おどろくほど" ], "comment": "to a surprising degree; to a remarkable extent; surprisingly; astonishingly; amazingly; alarmingly" },
	{ "question": "驚異", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "wonder; miracle; amazement; prodigy" },
	{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね" ], "comment": "bone\nframe\noutline; core\nbackbone; spirit; fortitude\nlaborious; troublesome; difficult" },
	{ "question": "骨子", "answers": [ "こっし" ], "comment": "main point; gist; essentials; bones (e.g. of an idea); pith" },
	{ "question": "骨折", "answers": [ "こっせつ" ], "comment": "bone fracture" },
	{ "question": "骨抜き", "answers": [ "ほねぬき" ], "comment": "boned (e.g. fish, etc.)\nwatered down (e.g. plan, bill, etc.); mutilated\nlacking integrity or moral backbone" },
	{ "question": "骨格", "answers": [ "こっかく" ], "comment": "skeleton; skeletal structure; build; frame; physique\nframework" },
	{ "question": "骨髄", "answers": [ "こつずい" ], "comment": "bone marrow; medulla\ntrue spirit; one's mind" },
	{ "question": "骸骨", "answers": [ "がいこつ" ], "comment": "skeleton" },
	{ "question": "高", "answers": [ "だか", "たか" ], "comment": "quantity; amount; volume; number; amount of money" },
	{ "question": "高い", "answers": [ "たかい" ], "comment": "high; tall\nexpensive" },
	{ "question": "高さ", "answers": [ "たかさ" ], "comment": "height; altitude; elevation; level\naltitude; height" },
	{ "question": "高まり", "answers": [ "たかまり" ], "comment": "rise; swell; elevation; upsurge" },
	{ "question": "高まる", "answers": [ "たかまる" ], "comment": "to rise; to swell; to be promoted" },
	{ "question": "高める", "answers": [ "たかめる" ], "comment": "to raise; to lift; to boost; to enhance" },
	{ "question": "高らか", "answers": [ "たからか" ], "comment": "loud; sonorous; ringing" },
	{ "question": "高位", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "dignity; eminent; high ranking\nhigh-order (digit, bit, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "高低", "answers": [ "こうてい", "たかひく" ], "comment": "high and low; rise and fall" },
	{ "question": "高価", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "high price" },
	{ "question": "高値", "answers": [ "たかね" ], "comment": "high price" },
	{ "question": "高卒", "answers": [ "こうそつ" ], "comment": "high school graduate" },
	{ "question": "高原", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "tableland; plateau" },
	{ "question": "高収入", "answers": [ "こうしゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "high income" },
	{ "question": "高台", "answers": [ "たかだい" ], "comment": "elevation; high ground" },
	{ "question": "高名", "answers": [ "こうみょう", "こうめい" ], "comment": "fame; renown" },
	{ "question": "高品質", "answers": [ "こうひんしつ" ], "comment": "high quality" },
	{ "question": "高圧", "answers": [ "こうあつ" ], "comment": "high voltage; high pressure" },
	{ "question": "高地", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "high ground; plateau; heights" },
	{ "question": "高学年", "answers": [ "こうがくねん" ], "comment": "upper grades of primary school (sixth, fifth, and sometimes fourth grades)" },
	{ "question": "高官", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "high official" },
	{ "question": "高層", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "multistory; multistoried; high-rise; high; tall" },
	{ "question": "高山", "answers": [ "こうざん" ], "comment": "high mountain; alpine" },
	{ "question": "高度", "answers": [ "こうど" ], "comment": "altitude; height; elevation\nadvanced; sophisticated; high-grade; strong" },
	{ "question": "高性能", "answers": [ "こうせいのう" ], "comment": "high efficiency; high fidelity; high power" },
	{ "question": "高所", "answers": [ "こうしょ" ], "comment": "high altitude; heights; elevation\nbroad view" },
	{ "question": "高揚", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "enhancement; exaltation; promotion; uplift" },
	{ "question": "高架", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "overhead structure" },
	{ "question": "高校", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "senior high school; high school" },
	{ "question": "高校生", "answers": [ "こうこうせい" ], "comment": "senior high school student" },
	{ "question": "高気圧", "answers": [ "こうきあつ" ], "comment": "high (atmospheric) pressure; high-pressure system; anticyclone" },
	{ "question": "高水準", "answers": [ "こうすいじゅん" ], "comment": "high level" },
	{ "question": "高波", "answers": [ "たかなみ" ], "comment": "high waves" },
	{ "question": "高温", "answers": [ "こうおん" ], "comment": "high temperature" },
	{ "question": "高瀬", "answers": [ "たかせ" ], "comment": "shallow river; shallows\nflatboat; river boat" },
	{ "question": "高炉", "answers": [ "こうろ" ], "comment": "blast furnace" },
	{ "question": "高熱", "answers": [ "こうねつ" ], "comment": "high fever\npyro-" },
	{ "question": "高率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "high rate" },
	{ "question": "高等", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "high class; high grade" },
	{ "question": "高等学校", "answers": [ "こうとうがっこう" ], "comment": "senior high school; high school" },
	{ "question": "高級", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "high class; high grade\nhigh rank; seniority" },
	{ "question": "高給", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "high salary" },
	{ "question": "高血圧", "answers": [ "こうけつあつ" ], "comment": "high blood pressure; hypertension" },
	{ "question": "高裁", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "High Court" },
	{ "question": "高見", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "watching with detachment" },
	{ "question": "高速", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "high speed; high gear\nhighway; freeway; expressway; motorway" },
	{ "question": "高速度", "answers": [ "こうそくど" ], "comment": "high speed" },
	{ "question": "高速道路", "answers": [ "こうそくどうろ" ], "comment": "highway; freeway; expressway; motorway" },
	{ "question": "高音", "answers": [ "こうおん", "たかね" ], "comment": "high-pitched tone; soprano" },
	{ "question": "高額", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "large sum (money)" },
	{ "question": "高騰", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "sudden price jump; steep price rise" },
	{ "question": "高麗", "answers": [ "こうらい", "こま" ], "comment": "Goryeo (dynasty of Korea; 918-1392 CE)\nKorea (esp. the Goguryeo kingdom or the Goryeo dynasty)\n(stone) guardian lion-dogs at Shinto shrine" },
	{ "question": "高齢", "answers": [ "こうれい" ], "comment": "advanced (old) age" },
	{ "question": "高齢者", "answers": [ "こうれいしゃ" ], "comment": "old person; old people" },
	{ "question": "髪", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "hair (on the head)" },
	{ "question": "髪の毛", "answers": [ "かみのけ" ], "comment": "hair (head)" },
	{ "question": "髪形", "answers": [ "かみがた" ], "comment": "hair style; coiffure; hairdo" },
	{ "question": "鬼", "answers": [ "き", "おに" ], "comment": "oni; ogre; demon\nspirit of a deceased person\nogre-like person (i.e. fierce, relentless, merciless, etc.)\nit (in a game of tag, hide-and-seek, etc.)\nChinese \"ghost\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nvery; extremely; super-" },
	{ "question": "鬼神", "answers": [ "きしん", "おにがみ", "きじん" ], "comment": "fierce god" },
	{ "question": "魂", "answers": [ "たま", "たましい", "だましい" ], "comment": "soul; spirit" },
	{ "question": "魅了", "answers": [ "みりょう" ], "comment": "fascination\nto charm; to fascinate; to mesmerize" },
	{ "question": "魅力", "answers": [ "みりょく" ], "comment": "charm; fascination; glamour; glamor; attraction; appeal" },
	{ "question": "魅力的", "answers": [ "みりょくてき" ], "comment": "charming; fascinating; attractive" },
	{ "question": "魅惑", "answers": [ "みわく" ], "comment": "attraction; fascination; lure; captivation; charm" },
	{ "question": "魔", "answers": [ "ま" ], "comment": "demon; devil; evil spirit; evil influence\nsomeone who (habitually) performs some (negative) act" },
	{ "question": "魔女", "answers": [ "まじょ" ], "comment": "witch" },
	{ "question": "魔法", "answers": [ "まほう" ], "comment": "magic; witchcraft; sorcery" },
	{ "question": "魔術", "answers": [ "まじゅつ" ], "comment": "black magic; sorcery\nmagic tricks; juggling" },
	{ "question": "魚", "answers": [ "うお", "さかな" ], "comment": "fish" },
	{ "question": "魚介類", "answers": [ "ぎょかいるい" ], "comment": "marine products; seafood; fish and shellfish" },
	{ "question": "魚類", "answers": [ "ぎょるい" ], "comment": "fish; fishes" },
	{ "question": "鮮やか", "answers": [ "あざやか" ], "comment": "vivid; bright; brilliant; clear; fresh; vibrant\nskillful; skilful; adept; adroit; deft; brilliant; beautiful; fine; excellent" },
	{ "question": "鮮度", "answers": [ "せんど" ], "comment": "(degree of) freshness" },
	{ "question": "鮮明", "answers": [ "せんめい" ], "comment": "vivid; clear; distinct" },
	{ "question": "鮮烈", "answers": [ "せんれつ" ], "comment": "vivid; striking" },
	{ "question": "鮮魚", "answers": [ "せんぎょ" ], "comment": "fresh fish" },
	{ "question": "鯉", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "common carp (Cyprinus carpio); koi carp" },
	{ "question": "鳥", "answers": [ "とり" ], "comment": "bird\nbird meat (esp. chicken meat); fowl; poultry" },
	{ "question": "鳥居", "answers": [ "とりい" ], "comment": "torii; Shinto shrine archway" },
	{ "question": "鳥獣", "answers": [ "ちょうじゅう" ], "comment": "birds and wild animals; wildlife" },
	{ "question": "鳥類", "answers": [ "ちょうるい" ], "comment": "birds" },
	{ "question": "鳩", "answers": [ "はと" ], "comment": "pigeon; dove" },
	{ "question": "鳴き声", "answers": [ "なきごえ" ], "comment": "cry (esp. animal); roar; chirp; tweet; bark; whine; meow" },
	{ "question": "鳴く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "to sing (bird)\nto make sound (animal); to call; to cry; to chirp\nto make a meld call (e.g. pung, kong)" },
	{ "question": "鳴らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to ring; to sound; to chime; to beat; to snort (nose); to snap (fingers)\nto be popular; to be esteemed; to be reputed\nto state; to insist; to complain\nto fart (loudly)" },
	{ "question": "鳴り", "answers": [ "なり" ], "comment": "ringing; sound" },
	{ "question": "鳴る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "to sound; to ring; to resound; to echo; to roar; to rumble" },
	{ "question": "鳴門", "answers": [ "なると" ], "comment": "strait with a roaring tidal ebb and flow; whirlpool; maelstrom\nkamaboko with a spiral whirlpool-like pattern\ncooking technique where ingredients are cut in a spiral pattern\nNaruto; city in NE Tokushima pref\nNaruto Strait\nNaruto wakame" },
	{ "question": "鶏", "answers": [ "にわとり", "とり" ], "comment": "(domestic) chicken\nchicken (meat)" },
	{ "question": "鶏肉", "answers": [ "けいにく", "とりにく" ], "comment": "chicken meat" },
	{ "question": "鶴", "answers": [ "つる", "たず" ], "comment": "crane (any bird of the family Gruidae, esp. the red-crowned crane, Grus japonensis)" },
	{ "question": "鹿", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "deer (esp. the sika deer, Cervus nippon)" },
	{ "question": "麦", "answers": [ "むぎ" ], "comment": "wheat; barley; oat (oats)" },
	{ "question": "麹", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "mould grown on rice, barley, beans, etc. as a starter to make sake, miso, soy sauce, etc. (mold); malted rice; malt" },
	{ "question": "麻", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "cannabis (Cannabis sativa); hemp (plant)\nhemp (fiber); linen; flax; jute" },
	{ "question": "麻布", "answers": [ "あさぬの", "まふ" ], "comment": "hemp cloth; linen" },
	{ "question": "麻痺", "answers": [ "まひ" ], "comment": "paralysis; palsy; numbness; stupor" },
	{ "question": "麻薬", "answers": [ "まやく" ], "comment": "narcotic drugs; narcotic; opium; dope" },
	{ "question": "麻酔", "answers": [ "ますい" ], "comment": "anaesthesia; anesthesia" },
	{ "question": "麻雀", "answers": [ "マージャン", "まあじゃん", "まーじゃん" ], "comment": "mahjong; mah-jongg" },
	{ "question": "黄", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "yellow" },
	{ "question": "黄昏", "answers": [ "たそがれ", "こうこん" ], "comment": "dusk; twilight\ntwilight years\nmelancholia; melancholic nostalgia" },
	{ "question": "黄色", "answers": [ "こうしょく", "おうしょく", "きいろ" ], "comment": "yellow; amber" },
	{ "question": "黄色い", "answers": [ "きいろい" ], "comment": "yellow\nhigh-pitched (voice); shrill" },
	{ "question": "黄金", "answers": [ "こがね", "おうごん" ], "comment": "gold" },
	{ "question": "黄金時代", "answers": [ "おうごんじだい" ], "comment": "Golden Age" },
	{ "question": "黒", "answers": [ "くろ" ], "comment": "black\nblack go stone\nguilt; guilty person" },
	{ "question": "黒い", "answers": [ "くろい" ], "comment": "black\ndark\nillicit; wicked; underground" },
	{ "question": "黒っぽい", "answers": [ "くろっぽい" ], "comment": "dark; blackish" },
	{ "question": "黒人", "answers": [ "こくじん" ], "comment": "black person\nwoman in the nightlife business; demimondaine; geisha and prostitutes" },
	{ "question": "黒字", "answers": [ "くろじ" ], "comment": "balance (figure) in the black" },
	{ "question": "黒幕", "answers": [ "くろまく" ], "comment": "black curtain\nwire puller; mastermind; political fixer; power broker" },
	{ "question": "黒星", "answers": [ "くろぼし" ], "comment": "black spot; black dot; bull's-eye\nfailure mark" },
	{ "question": "黒木", "answers": [ "くろき" ], "comment": "unbarked lumber" },
	{ "question": "黒板", "answers": [ "こくばん" ], "comment": "blackboard" },
	{ "question": "黒海", "answers": [ "こっかい" ], "comment": "Black Sea" },
	{ "question": "黒潮", "answers": [ "くろしお" ], "comment": "Japan Current; Kuroshio Current" },
	{ "question": "黒煙", "answers": [ "こくえん", "くろけむり" ], "comment": "black smoke" },
	{ "question": "黒色", "answers": [ "こくしょく" ], "comment": "black (colour, color)" },
	{ "question": "黒衣", "answers": [ "こくえ", "くろぎぬ", "こくい" ], "comment": "black clothes" },
	{ "question": "黒鉛", "answers": [ "こくえん" ], "comment": "graphite" },
	{ "question": "黙祷", "answers": [ "もくとう" ], "comment": "silent prayer" },
	{ "question": "黙る", "answers": [ "だまる" ], "comment": "to be silent" },
	{ "question": "鼻", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "nose" },
	{ "question": "鼻息", "answers": [ "びそく", "はないき" ], "comment": "nasal breathing\nperson's pleasure; excitement" },
	{ "question": "鼻水", "answers": [ "はなみず" ], "comment": "nasal mucus; dripping nose; snot" },
	{ "question": "鼻紙", "answers": [ "はながみ" ], "comment": "tissue paper; facial tissue; paper handkerchief" },
	{ "question": "齢", "answers": [ "よわい" ], "comment": "(one's) age" }
]
}
